<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001029A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001029A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001029</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893816</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B05B015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>542000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>547000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>569000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>239</class>
<subclass>271000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Self-discharging drip irrigation</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mohammad</given-name>
<family-name>Neyestani</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Woodland Hinns</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>David and Raymond Patent Group</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1050 Oakdale Lane</address-1>
<city>Arcadia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>91006</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A self-discharging drip irrigation system includes at least an elongated drip irrigation hose for operatively extending from a water supply, an emitter for directing water from the drip irrigation hose to a cultivating area, wherein the emitter comprises a flow regulating passage, wherein the flow regulating passage has at least an inlet section operatively connected to the irrigation hose, at least an outlet section for dripping the water to the cultivating area and a laminar flow region between the inlet section and the outlet section. The emitter further may comprises at least a venturi accelerator mounted on the inlet section. Whereby according to the &ldquo;Bernoulli&apos;s Theorem&rdquo; due to the land slop between the water supply and the cultivating area, which creates a gravity potential water is flowed from the water supply through the drip irrigation hose through the emitter and dripping to the cultivating area. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a drip irrigation system, and more particularly to a self-discharging drip irrigation system which can eliminate the energy consumption while being cost effective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Arts </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Drip irrigation is recognized as an advanced technology in the field of irrigation methodology for various cultivation. The advantages of the drip irrigation are that can minimize the water consumption, reduce energy and labor costs, irrigate plant more frequent, so as to increase the quantity and quality of crop production, improve soil aeration, reduces risk of drainage and salinity problems, water can be applied more uniform in the root zone, nutrition can be used more efficient through the system and control weed growth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> During the last four decades an extremely large numbers of drippers, emitters, bubblers, micro-jets, micro-sprayers, etc. have been designed, manufactured, and used to irrigate orchards, vegetables, row crops, nurseries and green houses. Reviewing the development of drip irrigation technology shows a reasonable improvement in practicing drip irrigation methodology. However unfortunately, not any appreciable effort has been made to review, or reconsider the economical feasibility in the field of drip irrigation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A conventional drip irrigation system comprises a supply line operatively extended from a water source, at least a feeding pipe having a drip irrigation hose extended from a manifold for distributing the water to a cultivating area, and at least a valve for controlling a flow of water through the connecting pipe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To operate a conventional drip irrigation system the water has to be transported from the water source to the cultivating area, by applying a predetermined pressure, and the pressure must be applied by the water pump to pump the water through the supply and feeding lines. Practically, the average pressure required to properly operate the conventional drip irrigation system is in the range of 45 to 70 psi (3 to 5 atmospheres), and the average demanding power is in the range of 0.5.0 to 1.0 horse-power per hectare. Accordingly, the supply pipe, main line, sub-main, lateral, and manifold must be strong enough to operate under such high pressure. The conventional drip irrigation system, also requires a filtration unit as well a power plant to operate the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the other hand, the applied pressure must be dissipated through a complicated pressure compensating emitters or drip tubes to control the steady flow rate of water and to provide a reasonable distribution uniformity of water. So, the initial investment costs of the conventional drip irrigation system will be extremely high including the installation cost and maintenance cost. Besides, the energy consumption of the conventional drip irrigation system is relatively high so as to increase the operational costs of the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Consequently, with regards to the foregoing disadvantages, practicing of a conventional drip irrigation system, economically is not feasible to be used by most low income farmers, so it is only applicable and affordable for growers of high value crops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> As a result, the growers tend to refuse to use the conventional drip irrigation system which causes the slow development of drip irrigation system especially in undeveloped countries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, The FAO statistical claimed and census 1998 of the United State Department of Agriculture (USDA) of drip irrigation development show that less than one percent (1%) of irrigated lands in the world; 4.2% of irrigated farms, and 8.6% of horticultural land in the United States are pr0acticing drip irrigation methodology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The foregoing record is a good index that shows drawbacks of the conventional drip irrigation technology, after a half century of practicing this methodology. It is well known by those experts in agricultural economy, that the most problems involved in slow development of drip irrigation system arise from high investment and operational costs </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is necessary to review and reconsider the economical feasibility of drip irrigation system and introduce a simplified and new technology to overcome disadvantages of the conventional drip irrigation system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A main object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system, which can reduce the energy consumption while being coast effective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system, which is capable of transporting a predefined flow of water from a water supply or reservoir to a cultivating area under gravity potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system for eliminating costly pumping plant and annual energy costs, which are essential to operate the conventional drip irrigation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system which is adapted to eliminate filtration unit and reduces investment and maintenance costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system that drips at high emission uniformity (EU) over a wide range of hydraulic head or gravity potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system which is simple to install and easy to use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a simple, inexpensive and easy manufactured self-discharging drip irrigation system to be affordable for low-income farmers and low educated growers in all other countries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system which is reliable to eliminate clogging and plugging of the system by dirt and debris. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system that can operate in boat surface and subsurface installation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a self-discharging drip irrigation system to accelerate the development of this art in the United States and in the other countries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, in order to accomplish the above objects, the present invention provides a self-discharging drip irrigation system to solve the technological and economical problems involved in the field of conventional drip irrigation systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The self-discharging drip irrigation system is directed to an elongated drip irrigation hose having a transiting waterway for operatively extending from a water reservoir and at least an external emitter having a flow regulating passage extended from the drip irrigation hose, wherein the flow regulating passage has a laminar flow region, wherein a cross-sectional area of the laminar flow region is smaller than that of the transiting waterway. The emitter can be non-pressure compensating emitter to save the pressure applied and to eliminate sedimentation of debris through the emitter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The emitter has at least one inlet section connected to the drip irrigation hose for communicating the flow regulating passage with the transiting waterway, at least one outlet section for dripping the water to a cultivating area, and at least one laminar flow region defined between the inlet section and the outlet section. The emitter further may comprises at least one venturi accelerator mounted between the inlet section and the outlet section for accelerating the water flow from the inlet section to the outlet section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In operation, the water flows from a water reservoir through a conventional supply pipe to the drip irrigation hose by gravity potential. Then, the water enters the emitter from the inlet section thereof and exits at the outlet section to the cultivating area to water plants. It is obvious by one expert in fluid mechanics, wherein the gravity potential is attainable in all irrigated farms and dry lands. However, the self-discharging drip irrigation system of the present invention is capable of operating over a wide range of hydraulic head incorporated with a water pump or any other hydraulic pressurized device </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a self-discharging drip irrigation system according to a first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a first alternative mode of an emitter of the self-discharging drip irrigation system according to the above first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a second alternative mode of the emitter of the self-discharging drip irrigation system according to the above first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a third alternative mode of the emitter of the self-discharging drip irrigation system according to the above first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a fourth alternative mode of the emitter of the self-discharging drip irrigation system according to the above first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a fifth alternative mode of the emitter of the self-discharging drip irrigation system according to the above first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a self-discharging drip irrigation system according to a second preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In describing a preferred system of the invention illustrated in the drawings, specific terminology will be restored to for the sake of clarity. However, the invention is not intended to be limited to the specific terms so selected, and it is to be understood that each specific term includes all technical equivalents which operates in a similar manner to accomplish a similar purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> of the drawings, a self-discharging drip irrigation system according to a first preferred embodiment of the present invention is illustrated, which is applicable in large size farms as well as small farms, orchard fruits, row crops and green houses, The self-discharging drip irrigation system is capable of effectively directing the water from a water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to a cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for irrigating water plants thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, such as a conventional water supply, comprises a water reservoir and at least a water supply pipe (not shown) that enables water being transported from the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the self-discharging drip irrigation system wherein the water supply reservoir <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is located in a higher position than the cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, so as to create a gravity potential between the water supply reservoir <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In other words, the water in the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> tends to flow downward to the cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by the gravity potential. The water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> further comprises a control switch (not shown) for selectively controlling the water flowing from the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the self-discharging drip irrigation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The self-discharging drip irrigation system as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> comprises an elongated drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having a transiting waterway <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for operatively extending from a water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and at least a non-pressure compensating emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> comprises an elongated flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has at least one inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> connected to the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for communicating the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with the transiting waterway <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and at least one outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for dripping the water to a cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a straight shaped conduit and defines a laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> between the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, wherein a cross-sectional area of the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is smaller than that of the transiting waterway <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to not only decreases the dissipating of the hydraulic head which is created by gravity potential but also eliminates the sedimentation of dirt and debris through the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has at least an opening <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> formed on a wall thereof wherein the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is operatively connected to the opening <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, so as to communicate the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with the transiting waterway <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In operation, the water flows from the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, through the water supply pipes (not shown) to the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Then, the water enters the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from the opening <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> into the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, through the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> thereof and exits at the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to the cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be a conduit, a manifold, a pipe, or the like. The purpose of the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is to provide a tubular structure for the water passing therethrough and directing the water to the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by gravity potential or by a pressurized device such as incorporating a water pump with the water supply. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> can be formed from an elongated strip <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of plastic film having a thickness from 0.1 to 0.5 millimeters. It is worth to mention that since the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is operated under a low pressure condition, the thickness of the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the supply pipes of the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be further reduced in comparison with the thickness of the conventional drip irrigation system, so as to minimize the total investment costs of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be made by any suitable method known to those skilled in the art. The strip <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be folded longitudinally to form overlapping inner and outer longitudinal margins. A longitudinal rib seals the margins. Alternatively, the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be made of any suitable material, such as polyethylene or polyethylene blend. The irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be in tape form or in hard hose form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is a unibody emitter, in essence, a single-piece emitter that forms as inseparable assembly. Alternatively, the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be made by two or more materials to form a single piece, which can be achieved, by injection, or sequential molding. Preferably, the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be made by polyethylene, silicone, or thermoplastic. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be rigid or flexible, but preferably is semi-rigid, i.e. capable of deforming to the desire shape. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be made by any other method known to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is securely attached to an exterior of the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The attachment can be made by any suitable connection, for example connector or adapter. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be located entirely the exterior of the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> It is worth to mention that the dimensions of the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has a significant effect on the flow rate of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Based on the principle of hydraulic, the designed length L of the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the invented emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is directly proportional to the gravity potential P, whereby P is in essence and by definition a hydraulic head created by gravity potential between the water supply <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the cultivating area <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and mathematically can be shown as:(LfP). And the designed diameter D of the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is inversely proportional to the gravity potential P, and mathematically can be shown as:(Df1/P). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> It is well known in fluid mechanics, pipes are used for transporting water. According to the &ldquo;Bernoulli&apos;s Equation&rdquo;, the flow rate of water passing through the irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the present invention under gravity potential, which is created by land slope can be determined as follow: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;</italic></highlight>(0.0191)(<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>0.54</superscript></highlight>)(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2.6274</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(1)(PVC-pipe) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Where Q is the flow rate passing through drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, in liter/sec.; S is defined as the land slope in %; and D is the diameter of the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in centimeter. It is worth to know, that the foregoing mathematical formula is applicable wherein the hose is made of PVC material or the like. The formula for PE hose or tubing can be determined as follow: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;</italic></highlight>(0.0178)(<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>0.54</superscript></highlight>)(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2.6274</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(2)(PE-pipe) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> According to the &ldquo;Christiansen&apos;s Mathematical Development&rdquo;, the flow rate of water through the drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, feeding with a number of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> along its length under gravity potential the equations (1) and (2) can be determined, respectively as follow: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;</italic></highlight>(0.0191)((<highlight><italic>S/F</italic></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>0.54</superscript></highlight>)(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2.6274</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(3)(PVC-pipe) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;</italic></highlight>(0.0178)((<highlight><italic>S/F</italic></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>0.54</superscript></highlight>)(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2.6274</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(4)(PE-pipe) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>where <highlight><italic>F&equals;</italic></highlight>(&frac13;)&plus;(&frac12;<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>)&plus;1/(6<highlight><italic>N</italic></highlight>2)&emsp;&emsp;(5) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> and where N&equals;the number of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the preset invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> And according to the &ldquo;Torricelli&apos;s Theorem&rdquo;, the mathematical model for flow rate through the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be written as: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;C</italic></highlight>(&pgr;<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/4)(2<highlight><italic>GP</italic></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>0.5</superscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(6) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> where G is the gravitational acceleration, in centimeter/s<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>; P is defined as the gravity potential in centimeter; and C is a coefficient of discharge and depends on the technical criterion and configuration of the non-pressure compensating emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which is determined by experiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The simplified form of the equation (6) can be shown as: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Q&equals;</italic></highlight>0.03477<highlight><italic>C</italic></highlight>(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)(<highlight><italic>P</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>0.5</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(7) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>or <highlight><italic>Q&equals;K</italic></highlight>(<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(<highlight><italic>P</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>0.5</superscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(8) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Where K value for the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been figured out experimentally and for five more desirable model of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention are given as follow: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>1&equals;0.001877; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>2&equals;0.002294; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>3&equals;0.002744; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>4&equals;0.003333; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>5&equals;0.005377 </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> To convert the value of Q from liter/sec. to liter/hour, the K&apos;s value changes to: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>1&equals;6.76; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>2&equals;8.26; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>3&equals;9.88; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>4&equals;12.00; <highlight><italic>K</italic></highlight>5&equals;19.36 </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Consequently, based on the result I have accomplished through a comprehensive research work, the validity and applicability of the &ldquo;Bernoulli&apos;s Equation, and Torricelli&apos;s Theorem&rdquo; in practicing: &ldquo;self-discharging drip irrigation methodology&rdquo; and the objects of the present invention is achieved, so as hopefully and confidently, in 2001 a technological breakthrough will be resulted in this art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a first alternative mode of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A which has at least one inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A, at least one outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>A, and at least one laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A further comprises at least one venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A mounted on the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A of the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A for accelerating the velocity of water and decreasing the high pressure created by gravity potential. The venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A has an entrance end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A and an exit end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A, wherein a diameter of the entrance end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A of the venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A is larger than that of the exit end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A, and wherein a diameter of the exit end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A is equal a diameter of the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A having a tubular shaped is securely attached to the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A of the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, The venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A has a cone shaped interior such that an inner diameter of the venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A is gradually decreasing from the entrance end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A to the exit end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A thereof. As it is obvious by one skilled in the art, the venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>A at the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>A is capable of speeding up the velocity of the water while entering the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A of such criterion is useful for gravity potential in the range of a few centimeters to 50 centimeters, (1&Prime; to 20&Prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a second alternative mode of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B which has at least one inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>B, at least one outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B, and at least one laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B further comprises two venturi accelerators <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>B mounted on the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>B and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B respectively. Therefore, the venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>B at the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>B is capable of speeding up the velocity of the water from the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>B to the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. The venturi accelerator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>B at the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B is also capable of speeding up the velocity of the water while entering the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, so as to eliminate the effect of back-flow and prevent the sedimentation of any suspended dirt and debris clogged at the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B of such specification is used when the gravity potential is in the range of 50 to 100 centimeters, (20&Prime; to 40&Prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a third alternative mode of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C which has at least one inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>C, at least one outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>C, and one laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>C. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>C having a curved shaped defined between the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>C and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>C, wherein the two venturi accelerators <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>C are mounted on the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>C and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>C respectively. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C of such criterion preferably is used to dissipate higher range of gravity potential, for example 100 to 200 centimeters, (40&Prime; to 80&Prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a fourth alternative mode of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D which has at least one inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>D, at least one outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D, and one laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>D As depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> the laminar flow region <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>D having a spiral shaped defined between the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>D and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D, wherein the two venturi accelerators <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>D are mounted on the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>D and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>D respectively. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D of such criterion preferably is used to dissipate very high range of gravity potential, for example 200 to 500 centimeters, (80&Prime; to 200&Prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a fifth alternative mode of the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E which has an elongated turbulent flow region <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>E defined between the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>E and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E, wherein the two venturi accelerators <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>E are mounted on the inlet section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>E and the outlet section <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>E respectively. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E further comprises a plurality of protrusion <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>E spacedly and radially protruded with in the turbulent flow region <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>E for further dissipating the gravity potential through the turbulent flow region <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>E. The protrusions <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>E can be any suitable shape such as triangular, rectangular, or square shape functions as water resistors to provide a pressure compensating emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E. The emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E with such technical specification is more useful in the case of extremely high hydraulic potential, for example over 0.5 atmosphere (7 psi). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> of the drawings, a second embodiment of a self-discharging drip irrigation system illustrates an alternative mode of the first embodiment of the present invention. According to the second embodiment, the non-pressure compensating emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above, do not have to be formed in a discrete non-pressure compensating emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, but can be located anywhere inside or outside of drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. For example the non-pressure compensating emitters <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; can be formed in the margin of drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;, and the flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; can be used in continuous and integral flow regulating passage <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; along the length of drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the emitter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; is attached to the inside of drip irrigation hose <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;. The self-discharging drip irrigation system of the second embodiment is more useful for installation in sub-surface ground and particularly for row crops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The foregoing is considered as illustrative only of the principals of the invention. Further, since numerous modifications and changes will readily occur to those skilled in the art, it is not desired to limit the invention to the exact construction and operation shown and described, and accordingly all suitable modifications may be restored to, falling within the scope of the invention as claimed. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A self-discharging drip irrigation system, comprising: 
<claim-text>at least an elongated drip irrigation hose, having a transiting waterway, for operatively extending from a water supply; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a non-pressure compensating emitter for directing water from said drip irrigation hose to a cultivating area, wherein said emitter comprises a flow regulating passage, wherein said flow regulating passage has at least an inlet section operatively connected to said drip irrigation hose and at least an outlet section for dripping water to said cultivating area, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises a laminar flow region defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein a cross-sectional area of said laminar flow region is smaller than diameter of said transiting waterway; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby, said water supply is located in a position higher than said cultivating area so as to create a gravity potential therebetween to transport the water. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises at least a cone shaped venturi accelerator mounted on said inlet section, wherein said venturi accelerator has an exit end having a diameter equal a diameter of said laminar flow region and an entrance end having a diameter larger than that of said exit end so as to speed up a water velocity thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises a second venturi accelerator, wherein said first and second venturi accelerators are mounted on said water inlet section and said water dripping outlet respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprising a second venturi accelerator, wherein said first and second venturi accelerators are mounted on said water inlet section and said water dripping outlet respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a straight shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a straight shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a straight shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a curved shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a curved shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a curved shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a spiral shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a spiral shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage comprises a laminar flow region having a spiral shaped conduit defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein said laminar flow region has a smooth interior surface for reducing a friction thereof so as to eliminate risk of sedimentation through said laminar flow region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises a turbulent flow region defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein a plurality of protrusions spacedly and radially protruded within said turbulent flow region to compensate applied pressure so as to increase the velocity of flow through said turbulent flow region and eliminates the risk of sedimentation thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises a turbulent flow region defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein a plurality of protrusions spacedly and radially protruded within said turbulent flow region to compensate applied pressure so as to increase the velocity of flow through said turbulent flow region and eliminates the risk of sedimentation thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said flow regulating passage further comprises a turbulent flow region defined between said inlet section and said outlet section, wherein a plurality of protrusions spacedly and radially protruded within said turbulent flow region to compensate applied pressure so as to increase the velocity of flow through said turbulent flow region and eliminates the risk of sedimentation thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said emitter is formed in a margin of said drip irrigation hose and extended parallel thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said emitter is formed in a margin of said drip irrigation hose and extended parallel thereto. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The self-discharging drip irrigation system, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said emitter is formed in a margin of said drip irrigation hose and extended parallel thereto.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001029A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
