<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004997A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004997A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004997</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09991679</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011126</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2,351,780</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>707</class>
<subclass>513000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>027000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>014000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for online personalization of greeting cards</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Steven</given-name>
<family-name>Parker</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Toronto</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Charles</given-name>
<family-name>Jennings</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Toronto</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DENNISON ASSOCIATES</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>133 RICHMOND STREET WEST</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 301</address-2>
<city>TORONTO</city>
<state>ON</state>
<postalcode>M5H 2L7</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system and method for providing convenient manufacture and delivery of customized greeting cards uses the convenience and ready access of the Internet or other widely available network. The website allows a user to enter information used to assist in the selection of an appropriate expression and image. An advertisement, sales promotion or product sale can be associated with the greeting card and used to subsidize the cost of the greeting card. In one embodiment an advertisement is associated with the greeting card and printed as part of the greeting card. The printed greeting card and advertisement are delivered by mail or other delivery service. The website is also designed to allow users to seek assistance from others with respect to expressions and images. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a method and system for creating and producing customized greeting cards over a wide area wired or wireless network, in particular the Internet. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Greeting cards have become an important element for expressing good wishes with respect to the celebration of a particular event. In some cases, a greeting card alone is used and in other cases a gift is associated with the greeting card. Conventional card and gift shops have a host of preprinted greeting cards (including the text sentiment or expression) for different occasions. The purchaser attends at the store location, reviews the various cards in the appropriate seasonal or everyday category, and purchases the selected card. Typically, the card is sold in the range of US $2.00 to US $4.00. This price for a printed substrate of card stock initially appears expensive relative to the cost of the card, however, when one considers the required overhead for operating the store, the amount of waste and the turnover rate for the store the price is somewhat more appropriate. In many cases, the availability of an appropriate card that suits the person and the occasion renders the price tolerable. Typically, these types of retail outlets also include giftware in the hope that a secondary higher prices sale can occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Electronic systems offering forms of card personalization started appearing in the late 1980s and throughout the 1990s. Specialty greeting card stores such as Your Expression established in 1988 provided personalized greeting cards through a local area network system. From a database of expressions categorized by occasions, the greeting card messages would be further personalized by interaction between the customer and the retail attendant and then printed on a paper insert which would be affixed inside a blank greeting card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Standalone kiosks of Hallmark Cards or American Greetings Corporation presented retail customers with the ability to select a card image and type a personalized message with the resulting greeting card printed on-demand while the customer waited. These electronic systems did not offer an extensive database of messages categorized by occasion or by card face. The card fronts were graphic &ldquo;vector&rdquo; images. These systems were not capable of printing high-resolution, photographic &ldquo;bitmap&rdquo; images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> More recently, a number of websites are available which allow the personalization of an electronic or e-card which is transmitted to the recipient by e-mail. These cards allow for the selection of a particular image, the selection or creation of a particular expression and also sometimes include audio or video files associated therewith as part of the presentation. These cards are not normally printed and are transmitted by e-mail to the recipient. Although e-cards have become popular, they are generally recognized as being in addition to the conventional card exchange and/or card gift exchange process. Therefore, generally e-cards have not been accepted as a replacement or substitute for the conventional printed card, particularly on important occasions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In addition to e-cards, greeting card online services over the Internet offer web customers the ability to select an image or graphic for the front of a greeting card and offer a standard greeting to be printed with the selected card or alternatively offer the ability to type in a personalized message. These sites do not, however, offer a wide selection of alternative messages or expressions associated with multiple cards or occasions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Although the selection of a card and the mailing of a card to the recipient provides recognition of the thought and good wishes of the sender, the card alone may not be sufficient. Flower delivery and other gift delivery services provide a convenient service which provides a further indication of the sender&apos;s recognition of the event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In many cases, the card sender or senders are quite busy and although they wish to give the most appropriate card and the most appropriate gift, there are too many factors with respect to the individual&apos;s taste, size, wardrobe and other circumstances which complicate the issue and often lead to a selected gift being returned. Gift certificates partially overcome this issue but are not recognized as being personal or representing considerable thought. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In the case of greeting cards for corporate use and occasions, corporations have had to purchase greeting cards through the same retail channels as consumer greeting card purchasers. Typically, consumer cards do not lend themselves to use for corporate occasions. The requirement to go to retail outlets is usually not time effective for corporations, and the cards and expressions do not tend be appropriate for corporate use. As a result, the corporate market has not been particularly well serviced by the greeting card industry. New Internet-based personalized greeting card services have offered alternatives that meet some of the shortcomings of the retail consumer chain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention seeks to address a number of these issues and provide a method and system which allows the card selection and message personalization over the Internet and with the resulting card printed card on-demand and mailed to the recipient in a cost effective manner. Optionally, the present invention allow a customized combination greeting card and gift certificate or gift to be delivered to the recipient. It also seeks to address the special needs of corporations sending greeting or acknowledgement cards on a private-label basis with optional marketing and other information printed as part of the card. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A system for creating customized greeting cards according to the present invention comprises a web server having associated therewith a database of categorized expressions, a database of categorized images, a selection process for entering user information used to search each database to form a reduced portion of each database that may be appropriate for selection by the user, means for a user to identify a particular expression and a particular image to thereby define a customized greeting card, an arrangement for associating with the customized greeting card a related sale or promotion, a printing arrangement for printing the customized greeting card and a delivery arrangement for delivering the printed greeting card to a recipient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The delivery arrangement of said system according to an aspect of the invention uses a postal address. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to a further aspect of said invention the customized greeting is associated with a sale of a gift product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In yet a further aspect of said invention the customized greeting card is associated with an advertisement of a party or parties different from the manufacturer of the card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In yet a further aspect of the invention the advertisement is a sales and marketing promotion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In a different aspect of the invention the customized greeting card is associated with a gift certificate delivered with the card. Preferably the gift certificate is attached to said card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In yet a further aspect of the invention the gift certificate is attached as a third panel of a normal two panel greeting card. In one aspect of the invention the greeting card is provided free to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect of the invention, the system is adapted for use by corporations. In this case, a database of corporate marketing information is included. The resulting card for corporations included customized marketing information selected from the database. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the invention a cost of manufacture of said greeting card is partially funded by said associated sale or promotion by advertisers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the invention said website includes advertisements viewed when using said website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the invention an email to the sender and the recipient confirming the completion of the printing of the card and/or mailing of the card will include additional marketing or promotional information provided by the advertiser including a link to the advertiser&apos;s website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In yet a further aspect of the invention, a corporate customer will have their logo and slogan printed on the back of the greeting card creating a private-labeled version for corporations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In a feature of the private-labeled corporate greeting cards, the corporation will also have the option to print additional marketing or promotional information on panels of the greeting card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to a feature of the system the website, based on user provided information, makes a series of recommendations of appropriate gifts available using said website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to a feature of the system at least one of said images and said expressions are categorized by occasion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> According to a further feature the categorization of said expressions is used as part of the categorization of said images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> According to a further feature the card images will be linked to specific expressions appropriate for the card image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to a further feature, the creation a new expression or further personalization of an existing expression from the database will be completed by keyboard entry or by voice activation software. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The online system will be accessible over a wired or a wireless wide area network including the Internet.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiments of the invention are shown in the drawings wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a perspective view of a customized card and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows a card with a paper insert. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a customized card showing the back panel; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the inside of a three panel greeting card gift certificate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective rear view of the a three panel greeting card gift certificate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view of a printed envelope; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a modified three panel greeting card with associated printed advertising or promotional material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a previously sealed envelope which opens exposing the printing on an interior surface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an envelope with advertising or a promotion printed thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate a three panel &ldquo;private-labeled&rdquo; greeting card for use by corporations with associated printing of corporate marketing and promotional information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic overview of users accessing an online greeting card website providing custom printed greeting cards </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic of the custom expression creation process </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic of the custom card front creation process </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic overview of a website offering custom consumer greeting cards with and without advertising </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic overview of a corporate greeting card website offering private-labeled personalized greeting cards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic of a personalized greeting card gift certificate website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a schematic overview of the retailer&apos;s website with respect to processing custom printed greeting card gift certificates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a schematic overview of the fulfillment process.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION ACCORDING TO THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE PRESENT INVENTION IN WHICH </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The present system embodies an Internet website where in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> greeting card users access the website through their browser <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> or their Personal Digital Assistants (&ldquo;PDA&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. At the website <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> the users can create custom greeting cards. FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> show the customized greeting card <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a selected image customized with or without text <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> on a front panel <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the card and a customized expression <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> on the inside of the inside panel <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the card. Alternatively, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) the customized expression <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is printed on a paper insert that is affixed inside the greeting card. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In the custom card creation process at <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> the user, or card sender, elects to start at either the custom expression creation process <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or the card front creation process <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In either case, the user will be requested for additional Personal Information at <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11, 12</cross-reference> for purposes of customizing the card expression (or message) and the card front. This Personal Information would include selection or indication of the card occasion (birthday, anniversary, Christmas, Valentines, etc), the relationship of recipient to the sender (eg mother, father, niece, stepson, etc.), the emotional mood (eg humorous, romantic, complimentary, religious, etc.) and number of years celebrated by an event (eg birthday, anniversary). This Personal Information <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> will be used at various stages to simplify the customization process through a reduction <highlight><bold>455</bold></highlight> of the expression database <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, and a reduction <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> of the image database <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> text expressions may be stored generically in the database <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> without, for example, inclusion of the recipient&apos;s name, the birthday date or anniversary date. The user can be requested to provide certain information before searching the expressions database. Personal Information such as the sender-recipient relationship, whether the card is being sent from one person or more than one person to one or more than one person, where applicable whether the occasion celebrates a specific number of years, etc. This information will be used to automatically transform the generic expression stored in the database to a personalized version when presented to the user through their browser. For example, &ldquo;Wishing you a Happy Birthday&rdquo; could be presented to the user as &ldquo;Brother, We wish you a Happy 21<highlight><superscript>st </superscript></highlight>Birthday on this Special Day Jun. 28, 2001 &rdquo;. The verb tense will also be automatically changed depending on the number of people representing the sender information. The user can also have the ability to further edit the expression to suit their situation <highlight><bold>475</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the text expression may be stored with a specific relationship (eg brother, mother, etc) but based on the specified actual relationship information as provided at <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> a search and replace activity will be performed transforming the expression database relationship to the required relationship. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> It is also possible for the user to enter a chat room indicated at <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> to provide further customization and/or suggestion by other users. In addition to being used by the greeting card sender in their personalized greeting cards, these expressions can also be submitted by the sender for inclusion in the entire expression database <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> with recognition as the author. The website would permit visitors to search the databases by the name of a creator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> A database of clipart images <highlight><bold>471</bold></highlight> can be used to add imagery to the text expression, for example, a drawing of a heart for romantic expressions, a birthday cake or candles for birthday&apos;s, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> At <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> the user can edit the text presentation by choosing font sizes, styles, color, spacing and layout positioning. By default the text is center justified. It is also possible to allow the sender to vary the types of signatures using different fonts and colors available from the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The alternate arm of the process is shown at the customized selection <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>. At this point the user is preferably presented with a free form text creation process where the user can simply create their own expression without first selecting an expression from the database <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The customized expression can also include customized signatures <highlight><bold>491</bold></highlight> of the sender created electronically from a sample signature of the sender and stored in a database <highlight><bold>492</bold></highlight>. The system can include uploading of signatures to the website or receipt of signature by e-mail or by facsimile and scanning them, into a database. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> the card front can be selected or customized at <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Based on certain of the Personal Information such as the card occasion or search by keyword, the user is provided a reduced database <highlight><bold>415</bold></highlight> of image choices which are tagged internally by identification subject categories (golf, flowers, etc). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> A keyword search based on image content also provides a reduced database of image choices. As well, the user can post certain criteria or proposals and free lance photographers or graphic artists at <highlight><bold>421</bold></highlight> can provide uploaded electronic images for use by the sender in creating the greeting card with recognition of the photographer-donor of the image being given on the card or the website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> It is possible as indicated at operation <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> to allow the sender to upload a particular image for their own use in creating the card. The system also includes the ability for visitors to the website to submit their images for inclusion in the database <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> for general use of all visitors. In certain cases, the donors may be compensated if desired. The database of expressions and images would include information identifying the creator-donor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> At <highlight><bold>425</bold></highlight> the images can also be edited by the user to include and position text overlay, for example, &ldquo;Happy 49<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>Birthday&rdquo; John, or to also edit the image itself using certain templates <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> to facilitate the ease of the editing or combining images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> It can be appreciated from the above that a customized card including a customized image and customized expression is defined by a series of steps on the website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In another version of the custom greeting card, the exterior surface of the back panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> includes an advertisement or corporate logo and slogan <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of someone other than the card manufacturer. This advertisement and advertiser&apos;s logo preferably relates to the greeting card event. For example, a bon voyage card with a travel company advertisement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> This advertisement can take many forms but the basic concept is part of the card preferably the back panel of a two-panel greeting card is used as an advertising or marketing surface. Preferably the advertiser and the particular advertisement are selected based on the particular card celebration or event. In addition to associating particular advertisers with particular events, advertisers could be selected based on the particulars of the recipient of the card, the geographical location of the recipient of the card and/or other information that is derived during the customizing process of the greeting card or otherwise available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> One of the problems facing advertisers is the ability to reach a particular target market. It is often difficult to have all of the information with respect to a particular target market and reaching the target market at the time an event might trigger a purchasing decision. Most systems for reaching a particular target market additionally contact a large part of the population which is outside the target group or not close to the time that a buying decision is being made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the Personal Information obtained from the sender in the Custom Card Process <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 &amp; 12</cross-reference> is used to select an appropriate advertiser for the consumer custom greeting card. Age, address and personal information with respect to the recipients, as well as knowledge about possible purchasing opportunities related to the greeting card occasion determined in the personal information process allow classification of senders and recipients such that advertisers have increased confidence that the target market is being reached. The advertisement allows the cost of the card and possibly the delivery of the card to be partially or fully funded by advertising revenues. It is also possible that general goodwill promotions without a specific offer to the recipient will be of particular interest to international companies or larger companies. Such advertisements promote general goodwill <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and branding with respect to the corporate entity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing instance, the advertisement is chosen by the website for the sender based on pre-determined criteria <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> related to the Personal Information. In another instance, the sender may be presented with a choice of advertisers. The sender then considering the interests of the recipient may wish to select a particular advertisement or advertiser from a subset of those identified within the database <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> of advertisers who are prepared to subsidize the cost of the card. The sender may know that the recipient has a particular like or dislike with respect to one corporate entity and the sender could choose an advertiser as appropriate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> It is anticipated that certain advertisers will be prepared to fully fund the cost of the card associated therewith rendering the card free to the sender. Possibly the advertiser would be prepared to fund the delivery cost as well. Thus to the sender who is prepared to accept some type of acceptable advertisement on the back panel of the card, the cost of the card and the delivery of the card to the recipient may be free. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the user can opt for a customized printed greeting card without advertising and merely arrange to pay an appropriate retail price determined by the website. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows an alternate arrangement where the customized card of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> can be used in combination with the customized envelope <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The inside of the envelope can include a coupon or other advertisement as shown as <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> on the inside of the envelope. This coupon could be for redemption of free merchandise or a special two for one offer as two examples. This advertisement can also be customized by the information required to personalize the card and transmit the card to the recipient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> the coupon or advertisement is provided on the envelope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. This can be used in conjunction with the customized card of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> or the combination greeting card/gift certificate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> or any of the other embodiments as discussed later. It can also be appreciated that if one wishes to send a traditional card without any advertising support on the rear surface or as part of a removable panel, this is also possible and a standard envelope can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In another instance of online custom printed greeting cards, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> defines an online system to provide three-paneled, private-labelled greeting cards. Corporations may want their employees to send private-labelled personalized greeting cards thus promoting their corporate brand and providing corporate marketing information to the recipient of the card who may be a customer, potential customer, supplier, or other important contact of the corporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In this case, visitors to the website would be identified by a corporate and employee identification number <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. They would use the online greeting card service including the customization of greeting card messages and card images as described but have the cards printed with their corporate logo and slogan <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the middle panel of the exterior side of the card shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Additionally, they may choose to have pre-determined corporate marketing and other information <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> printed on the left interior panel <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and/or the right interior panel <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). The recipient address <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and sender return address <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> would be printed on the left exterior panel. The three-panel card would be folded and sealed at the edge such that the address panel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> would provide the mailing information without necessarily the need for an envelope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The corporate customer would have the benefit of its employees sending private-labelled greeting cards and promoting the company and its products and services to recipients of the cards and to others who may view the card in the delivery process. Customer corporations would be able to upload their corporate marketing information tailored to the website&apos;s specifications and added to the database <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and automatically available for use by their employees. The custom private-labelled, marketing card would be viewed on the website at <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, accepted at <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and printed, folded, sealed and mailed in the Fulfilment process defined in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> as discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In another instance of the three-paneled greeting card, a personalized greeting card gift certificate is defined in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> where at <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight> a host of different retailers can be selected from and different amounts can be provided as part of the gift certificate which preferably includes a high-quality, photographic image of the particular product which the sender thought would be appropriate. This gift certificate can be produced on the additional panel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Gift certificates typically do not provide an image of a suggested gift made by the sender on behalf of the recipient of the gift certificate. The addition of a photographic quality image of the gift selected from a retailer&apos;s website elevates the typical impersonal nature of a gift certificate for money to a very personal gift certificate akind to actually giving a physical gift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Because it alters to the gift giving process such that the recipient confirms the acceptance of the actual gift before physically receiving the gift, it has the added advantage to the retailer of avoiding costly returns of physical goods and has the advantage to the recipient of the gift certificate of avoiding the time required to return the gift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In other circumstances, it may be desirable to introduce a gift certificate that may include the image of a product from a particular retailer but has more universal application. This could include a gift certificate which will be accepted by a number of retailers which can be identified on the gift certificate but is offered in combination with a financial institute. The recipient can use this effectively as part of the cash payment or in the event that the suggested gift is not appropriate the gift certificate can be deposited at his own financial institute. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The gift certificate greeting card promotes the associated retailer who is willing to at least partially subsidize the cost of the card. Depending upon the value of the gift or the gift certificate this could include the full subsidy of the card including the delivery costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> shows a combination greeting card and gift certificate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The greeting card is similar to the greeting card <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> but includes a third panel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which includes a gift certificate. In a preferred embodiment of the invention the gift certificate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a high quality photographic bitmap image <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the particular gift that the sender has chosen as appropriate for the recipient. The gift certificate also includes the corporate identity <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the retailer where the product in the image <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> can be purchased and optionally includes alternative retailers where the gift certificate can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The combined customized card and the customized gift certificate are placed in the envelope <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> which includes the address <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the recipient, the return address of the sender <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the appropriate postage or payment of delivery services is provided as indicated by the postage stamp <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the greeting card or greeting card gift certificate are printed with the name and mailing address of the recipient of the mailing such that this information will show through a window envelope eliminating the need to print on the envelop or label and also eliminating the need to match specific envelopes with specific greeting cards. Alternatively, the greeting card is folded and sealed such that the address at <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> provides the mailing information without the need for an envelope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> With the combination of greeting card/gift certificate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> the recipient receives from the sender a customized greeting card which includes the gift certificate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which can be separated from the card by tearing along the perforated line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The sender has provided not only a customized card but has also provided a gift certificate with a suggested gift and photographic quality image of the gift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> A personalized greeting card gift certificate user could enter the process to purchase the gift certificate through the card website <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> or alternatively through the retailer&apos;s website <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. If entering through the card website the user will be directed to the retailer&apos;s website <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> in order to go through the process of identifying which product they would like to have printed on the gift certificate as their suggested gift to the recipient of the gift certificate. The product is printed based on a system of capturing the image file reference information from the retailer&apos;s website <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> as the user chooses the product to be added to the retailer&apos;s shopping cart and chooses the gift certificate delivery method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The gift certificate portion has a printed web URL address that links the recipient directly to the product visual (<highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>) and information as shown and described on the retailer&apos;s website where the recipient of the gift certificate can then proceed to select the suggested product or alternatively choose another and proceed to checkout at <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> using the unique gift certificate number printed on the gift certificate as the form of payment. Alternatively, the gift certificate can be detached from the greeting card and redeemed for the product or other product at the retailer&apos;s store at <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> thereby using the web to promote traffic back to its brick and mortar retail chain. The system would also include for the benefit of the recipient of the gift certificate a means whereby the retailer would keep the product item printed as a suggested gift on the gift certificate in stock for a specific number of days. If this is determined not to be appropriate the gift certificate can be used for redemption at the preferred retailer identified as <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and preferably a number of alternative retailers are provided at <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> A variation of the gift certificate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> where a smaller removable panel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is attached to the back panel <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. This type of removable panel could be used to promote a two for one movie option or a two for one dinner arrangement or perhaps a special buying incentive. This buying incentive could be tied to the celebration and could even include an expiry date. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> shows the fulfillment process whereby the customized consumer greeting card <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the private-labeled corporate custom greeting card <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, or personalized greeting card gift certificate <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> will be printed by a high quality printer either locally or remotely from the information collected during the custom card processes and captured into PDF files. It is also apparent that a number of printing locations can be networked and a printing location that has capacity or geographic preference can be selected. A printing system can also be associated with one or more stores such as florists. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The card will be sent by the website directly to the recipient, or alternatively to the user to be delivered to the recipient, using an appropriate delivery service such as mail or courier <highlight><bold>825</bold></highlight>. Some users of the website will only wish to send a customized card or a standard card to the recipient, whereas other users may wish to associate a gift, gift certificate or a more universal gift certificate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> The website shows transactions stored in various databases <highlight><bold>835</bold></highlight> generating various reports as additional services for members. For example, a transaction history of the details of cards sent by a member <highlight><bold>840</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>845</bold></highlight>. The transaction history could contain the date, the recipient name, which card image and the text of the expression. The website could also provide an e-mail or other reminder service permitting users to set up dates on which to be reminded that a card should be sent to a specific recipient. Invoicing reports to retailers for gift certificates <highlight><bold>850</bold></highlight> and advertising subsidy reporting <highlight><bold>855</bold></highlight> are other reporting examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Additionally, e-mail confirmation <highlight><bold>830</bold></highlight> including a copy of the card or link to display of the card to the sender can be provided when the card and any gift or certificate is completed and delivered or placed in the hands of the delivery service. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Although various preferred embodiments of the present invention have been described in detail, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that variations may be made without departing from the spirit of the invention or the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined as follows: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for creating customized greeting cards comprising a web server having associated therewith a database of categorized expressions, a database of categorized images, a selection process for entering user information used to search each database to form a reduced portion of each database that may be appropriate for selection by the user, means for a user to identify a particular expression and a particular image to thereby define a customized greeting card, an arrangement for associating with the customized greeting card a related sale or promotion, a printing arrangement for printing the customized greeting card, and a delivery arrangement for delivering the printed greeting card to a recipient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said delivery arrangement uses a postal address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said customized greeting is associated with a sale of a gift product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said customized greeting card is associated with an advertisement of a party different from the manufacturer of the card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said advertisement is a sales promotion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein customized greeting card is associated with a gift certificate delivered with the card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said gift certificate is attached to said card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said gift certificate is attached as a third panel of a two panel greeting card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a gift is sent with said card and said gift is selected using said website. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said greeting card and the delivery thereof are free to said user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a cost of manufacture of said greeting card is partially funded by said associated sale or promotion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said website includes advertisements viewed when using said website. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said website based on user provided information makes a series of recommendations of appropriate gifts available using said website. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one of said images and said expressions are categorized by occasion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the categorization of said expressions is used as part of the categorization of said images. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said sale or promotion is an advertisement partial selected based on the information entered by the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said website includes a database of advertisers and related criteria used to pair an advertisement with an appropriate customized greeting card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cost of the advertisement paired to a greeting card is used to subsidize the cost of the greeting card charged to the user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> including a database of corporate marketing information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> including databases of categorized expressions and categorized images appropriate for corporate greeting or acknowledgement cards. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A process of creating customized corporate communications comprising 
<claim-text>accessing a web server having associated therewith a database containing a series of specific corporate communications associated with a particular corporate/client event and a database containing a series of marketing communications associated with the wares and/or services of the corporation, </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting an appropriate specific corporate communication and providing client information to allow sending of said corporate communication to at least one client, </claim-text>
<claim-text>producing a printed customized corporate communication having said selected specific corporate communication and at least one marketing communication associated with the wares and/or services of the corporation, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>sending said printed customized corporate communication to an address associated with said client information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> including said web server including a database of corporations authorized to produce customized communications and said database of specific corporate communications and said database containing said series of marketing communications are divided to be specific to particular corporation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each printed customized communication includes identification of the corporation as the producer of the printed customized communication. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said printed customized communication is a greeting card or an acknowledgement card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said specific corporate communication includes a database of images and said process includes selecting of an image of said database of images as part of the printed customized communication.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>11</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030004997A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
