<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002687A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002687A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002687</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10145097</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020515</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>9927131.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991116</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F011/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G10K011/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H03B029/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>381</class>
<subclass>071100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus for acoustically improving an environment and related method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10145097</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020515</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/GB00/02360</doc-number>
<document-date>20000616</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>UNKNOWN</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andreas</given-name>
<family-name>Raptopoulos</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>London</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<family-name>Kieslinger</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Vienna</city>
<country-code>AT</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BROBECK, PHLEGER &amp; HARRISON, LLP</name-1>
<name-2>ATTN: INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY DEPARTMENT</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1333 H STREET, N.W. SUITE 800</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention provides an apparatus and related method for acoustically improving an environment. In an embodiment of the invention, an apparatus comprises a partitioning means in the form of a curtain for producing a discontinuity in a sound conducting medium, such as air, and for absorbing sound. One or more microphones serve for receiving acoustic energy and for converting it into electrical signals for supply to a digital signal processor. The processor employs an algorithm for analyzing the electrical signals and providing a control signal based on such analysis. In response to the control signal, an electrical output signal is generated and converted into sound. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present application is a continuation-in-part of International Application PCT/GB00/02360, with an international filing date of Jun. 16, 2000, published in English under PCT Article 21(2) and now abandoned.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an apparatus for acoustically improving an environment and to a related method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Noise has been recognized as a major problem in industrial, office, and domestic environments for many years now. Advances in materials technology have provided some solutions. However, the solutions have all addressed the problem in the same way, namely: the sound environment has been improved by decreasing noise levels in a controlled space. This relatively inflexible approach has been regarded as a major design guideline in the design of spaces as far as noise abatement is concerned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In particular, U.S. Pat. No. 5,355,418 describes a hearing aid for wearing as an ear piece, which is designed to monitor ambient noise for frequency components above a pre-selected threshold level and to filter out such frequencies utilizing an adaptive digital filter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,105,377 concerns an active noise cancellation system arranged to sense residual noise and to generate an electronic waveform for activating an acoustic activator to produce an acoustic cancellation signal. In this system, an adaptive filter is employed whose filtering characteristics are adjusted on the basis of the residual noise and of the estimated effects of the cancellation signal as well as the system impulse response. The adaptive filter thus filters the estimated noise to generate the cancellation signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,315,661 concerns an arrangement for sound reduction employing a passive sound absorbing panel, a sensor, and an activator for actively attenuating sound signals received by the sensor. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention seeks to provide a more adaptable apparatus for, and method of, acoustically improving an environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment of the invention, an apparatus for acoustically improving an environmental space comprises: a partitioning screen for producing a discontinuity in a sound conducting medium in the environmental space, the partitioning screen acting as a sound absorber; means for receiving acoustic energy from the environmental space and for converting the acoustic energy into an electric input signal; means for analyzing the input signal and for providing a control signal based on such analysis; means responsive to the control signal for generating an electrical output signal; and output means for converting said output signal into sound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Sounds are interpreted as pleasant or unpleasant, i.e., wanted or unwanted, by the human brain. For ease of reference, unwanted sounds are hereinafter referred to as &ldquo;noise&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The means for analyzing may include a micro-processor or digital signal processor (DSP). A desktop or laptop computer can also be used. In either case an algorithm is employed to define the response of the apparatus to sensed noise. Noise to sound transformation is advantageously based on the algorithm, which is executed by the processor or computer chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The algorithm advantageously works on the basis of building a real time transformation of ambient noise to create a more pleasing sound environment. The algorithm analyzes the structural elements of the ambient noise and produces a transformation that either masks the original noise or emphasizes harmonic elements in it in order to produce a pleasant sound environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A preferred algorithm employs a series of band-pass filters, whose center frequencies are multiples of a base frequency (i.e. lowest frequency). The algorithm is capable of recording the mean energy of the frequency bands positioned symmetrically around those frequencies and of using those indexes to adjust the relative levels of output of the corresponding filtering functions in order to create a smoother sound output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In a particularly preferred embodiment, the algorithm is modeled on the human auditory perception system and relevant experimental data available in handbooks of experimental psychology of hearing. Several case studies have been carried out in different situations/locations with diverse sound/noise environments. Digital recordings were made and the sound signals were then played back in different locations. The sound signals were also analyzed with spectrograms and their results were compared to spectrograms of pieces of music and recordings of natural sounds. The analysis of the data has resulted in design criteria that were incorporated into the algorithm. The algorithm tunes the sound signal by analyzing, in real time, incoming noise and produces a sound output which can be tuned by the user to match different environments, activities, or aesthetic preferences. In an embodiment of the invention, the algorithm is programmed in MAX, a programming language available for Apple Macintosh&trade; computers. However, other programming languages can be used, the identification and implementation of which is apparent to one of skill in the art. An example of the algorithm is described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The digital signal processing unit may be any conventional programmable processor. In an embodiment of the invention, the physical size of the processor is approximately 100 by 150 mm. Such a unit may include circuitry for data input through a PC using a parallel port. In an alternative embodiment of the invention, a non-reprogrammable DSP chip may be used instead and the parallel port would be omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The apparatus preferably has a partitioning device in the form of a flexible curtain. However, it will be appreciated that such device may also be solid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The curtain preferably has one or more rigid or semi-rigid portions, which carry the output means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The curtain may be formed from a plurality of modules manufactured from a flexible material, such as polyurethane or silicon rubber. Preferably each module has a substantially constant thickness of between 1 and 2 mm. Modules can be assembled together to form screens or space dividers of different heights and constant width. A basic module size is typically 1200&times;400-450 mm (width by height). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Each module advantageously includes an electrically conductive pathway molded integrally within or deposited on the curtain. In an embodiment of the invention, the conductive pathway is deposited on the curtain via a screen printing technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Two different modules may be used to create a screen: the first curtain module may have conductive pathways and incorporate the audio output means, and the second may also have conductive pathways and may connect to a power supply via a transformer, and to other curtain module(s) via the conductive pathways. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the second module(s) may include a DSP unit which performs digital signal processing on the input signal to produce a transformed signal, which is then output to one or more output devices. Power may be provided by a rechargeable lithium battery or a main voltage supply via a transformer. Optionally the DSP unit may be configured to accept an infra-red input, e.g., remote control device, to the curtain, thereby allowing a user to tune or switch on/off the output pleasant sound environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The curtain may also comprise two or more materials of differing acoustic properties. The materials may be separated by a space or volume, which may be evacuated or filled with a fluid, such as air or other material. At least one of the surfaces may be relatively stiff so as to act as a sound reflector. Examples of a stiff material include: glass, steel, and laminates, such as carbon-fiber epoxy or Kevlar&trade; epoxy. Such a stiff material may also be combined with a sound absorption material such as foam or woven fabrics, such as velvet or woven Kevlar&trade;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A particularly effective curtain includes a semi-flexible modular curtain formed from a sandwich material of aluminum honeycomb core and having a latex, polyurethane, or elastomer, e.g., rubber, skin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The partitioning medium may be translucent for visual appeal. However, it will be appreciated that it may also be opaque or transparent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> According to another embodiment of the invention, a method of manufacturing a curtain comprises the steps of: embedding an electrically conductive pathway in, or on, a flexible material, the electrical pathway being adapted to connect to a means for receiving audio energy and a means for converting said energy into a signal, so as to modify its composition and to provide, in use, a pathway for said modified signal to an audio output means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The electronic sound screening system of the present invention provides a pleasant sound environment by transforming noise into non-disturbing sound. The partitioning device can be seen as a smart textile that has a passive and an active element incorporated. The passive element acts as a sound absorber bringing the noise level down by several decibels. The active element then transforms the remaining noise into pleasant sound. The latter is achieved by recording and then processing the original sound signal with the use of an electronic system. The transformed sound signal may then be played back through speakers connected to the partitioning device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The invention has a myriad of applications. For example, it may be used in shops, offices, hospitals, or schools as an active noise treatment system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Instead of resolving complex equations in order to construct a system that cancels noise in well described and controlled cavities (like the interiors of a car or the cavity of the human ear), a universal system is provided that functions in any sound environment by modifying its output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the invention reduces the noise level down by 6-12 decibels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The foregoing, and other features and advantages of the invention, will be apparent from the following, more particular description of the preferred embodiments of the invention, the accompanying drawings, and the claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention, the objects and advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in connection with the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a general schematic diagram illustrating operation of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> show spectrograms of street noise prior to and after acoustic transformation by the invention respectively; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a first embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a curtain module employed in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of an exciter or vibrator mounted on the curtain module of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view along the line AA in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a mold for producing the curtain module of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a plurality of the curtain modules of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> connected together to form a curtain; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing how the edges of respective curtain modules are mechanically connected together; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block circuit diagram representing the electrical circuitry employed in the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are flow diagrams representing an algorithm employed in the electrical circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows a curtain module employed in the second embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> shows a plurality of curtain modules that are connected together and include the curtain module of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> shows a curtain module employed in the third embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a panel employed in the curtain module of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> shows a modification of the mechanical connection shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> for joining curtain modules together; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> show circuit blocks representing the operation of the algorithm employed in the electrical circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the present invention and their advantages may be understood by referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, wherein like reference numerals refer to like elements. The inventive concept is directed to acoustically improving a sound environment. Generally, the system comprises three elements: a microphone for sensing environmental sound; a processing unit for transforming it or analyzing it, and generating responses; and an output such as a speaker for outputting the responsive sound back into the environment. Although the embodiments described herein integrate these elements on a sound reflecting and/or absorbing medium that provides a physical separation of the user from the noise source, the inventive concept, nevertheless, can be adapted such that the elements are arranged freely in space or within a medium not separating the user from the noise source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an apparatus for acoustically improving an environment comprises a partitioning device in the form of, for example, a curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus also comprises a number of microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which may be positioned at a distance from the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or which may be mounted on, or integrally formed in, a surface of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to a digital signal processor (DSP) <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and thence to a number of loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, which again may be positioned at a distance from the curtain or mounted on, or integrally formed in, a surface of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> produces a discontinuity in a sound conducting medium, such as air, and acts primarily as a sound absorbing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a flexible material, for example a translucent velvet textile woven from a transparent nylon or monofilament polyester yarn, or a molded synthetic rubber or polyurethane sheet. Other suitable materials include woven fabrics and laminates formed from KEVLAR&trade; or carbon-fiber epoxy. Such materials all have good sound absorbing properties. The material may also be woven or overprinted with visual designs, information or colors, to provide an aesthetically pleasing result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> receive ambient noise from the surrounding environment and convert such noise into electrical signals for supply to the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A spectrogram <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> representing such noise is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and an example of such a spectrogram is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> employs an algorithm for analyzing the electrical signals received from microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and for providing a control signal based on such analysis. An output signal is generated responsive to the control signal for supply to the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A spectrogram <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> representing such modified electrical signals is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and an example of such a spectrogram is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The sound issuing from the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is preferably an acoustic signal representing either the original ambient noise from which unwanted sounds and noise have been filtered out or masked and/or to which harmonic elements have been added to produce a pleasing quality. However, it is also possible for the sound issuing from the loudspeakers to be anti-noise for canceling out the original noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> A first embodiment of the present invention will now be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in this first embodiment, the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are both mounted on the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> itself. Otherwise this embodiment is as described in relation to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, like parts being designated by the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which may constitute the whole of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or which, as in the present instance, may simply form a portion of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed from a flexible rubber material and has molded within it a plurality of electrical wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, each extending from an upper edge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to a lower edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> cross one another respectively at nodes <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> where the wires are electrically interconnected and at intersections <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> where the associated wires remain electrically isolated. At the upper and lower edges <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the curtain module, certain of the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> terminate respectively in connectors <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by which they may be electrically connected to wires in adjacent curtain modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In addition to the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also carries a respective microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a respective loudspeaker <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the form of a power amplifier <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and an exciter or vibrator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The exciter <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, which is mounted on a stiffened portion of the material of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. As shown, the exciter comprises a cup-shaped housing <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> containing a core <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and an excitation coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The housing <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is arranged to be mounted on the stiffened portion of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by way of a rigid annular ring <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, which is connected to the rim of the cup-shaped housing <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by means of a resiliently flexible angled washer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. When the coil <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is excited, the core <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> vibrates to cause the stiffened portion of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to vibrate at an acoustic frequency. More particularly, the annular ring <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be attached onto the stiffened portion of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via superglue or any other conventional means, the identification and implementation of which is apparent to one of skill in the art, so that when the core <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> vibrates the stiffened portion is subjected to pressure waves in the audible range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The following is a description of how the curtain module may be manufactured relatively cheaply by molding a synthetic rubber material: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> a) Rotational molding: In this case, polyurethane (PU) rubber is poured into a rotating drum which spins and also applies heat to the PU rubber. This procedure produces sheets of substantially constant thickness, but has a limitation in the size of the PU sheet, which is restricted by the size of the drum (the biggest sheet found in a U.K. manufacturer was 2400 mm long by 900 mm wide). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> b) Sheet molding: A lump of PU rubber of nearly the weight required to fill a flat mold is set on the center of the mold in a semi-solid state, before being vulcanized. A steel tool presses the PU rubber to close the mold letting the PU rubber escape from certain outlets. Heat is applied and the PU rubber sets. The advantage of this procedure is that both sides of the PU sheet can be textured and can also have extruded characteristics (as opposed to only one part of the sheet being textured in the rotational molding process). The obvious disadvantage is the fact that the bigger the size of the sheet to be cast, the higher the cost of the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a specific mold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for producing the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The mold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> comprises a lower mold part <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> containing a well <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> for receiving a liquid to be molded. The well <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is surrounded by a spacer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> on which a network of flat braided copper wires for forming the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are supported and held by way of two longitudinally extending clamps <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The copper wires serve not only for providing the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the finished curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> but also to reinforce the PU sheet and inhibit tensile elongation under load without restricting the flexibility of the molded sheet. The mold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> also comprises an upper mold part <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for lowering on to and closing the first mold part <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> during molding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In the present instance, a transparent two-part polyurethane (PU) rubber compound is employed in the molding process. The compound is mixed as a liquid, passed through a vacuum chamber to be degassed, and then poured into the lower part <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and spread by means of aluminum straps (not shown) spanning the full width of the mold in order to obtain an even thickness. The mold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is then closed for molding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;spark&rdquo; or sandblasted finish may be applied to an inner surface of the mold to render the sheet translucent instead of transparent and/or to produce desired visual qualities. The polyurethane employed in the compound may if desired be pigmented to generate different colors in selected areas of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to produce aesthetic designs. The liquid compound employed in the molding process may also be modified with fire retardant for enhancing safety. Ultra-violet stabilizers may also be added. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are integrated into curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in such a way that the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can not be seen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In order to produce stiffened portions in the material of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to provide structural areas for carrying the various electrical components, a number of different approaches are possible. For example, hardeners can be added to selected regions of the fluid compound prior to or during molding, or such regions can be cured or heat treated or resin may be applied following molding. Alternatively, stiffened panels may be applied to the mold prior to introduction of the polyurethane compound, or polyurethane compounds of different hardness can be molded together by means of a double molding process. Another possibility is for the curtain to be formed from two or more layers of polyester or Mylar&trade; screen printed with the conductive pathways and layered together to incorporate rigid panels between them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a plurality of the curtain modules <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> connected together to form the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Adjacent modules are mechanically connected together along their respective upper and lower edges <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by means of a connection as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, in which the upper edge <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of one module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed with a channel <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for receiving a rib <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> along the lower edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the adjacent module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The rib <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is slotted into the channel <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> during assembly and is subsequently held in place by means of a pair of flanges <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> flanking the opening of the channel <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In another embodiment of the invention, adjacent modules are connected together by conventional attaching techniques, the identification and implementation of which are apparent to one of skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Respective wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of each curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are electrically inter-connected by way of the connectors <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to respective wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the adjacent curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. It will be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> that not all of the wires <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are so connected but that the arrangement of the connection nodes <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and connectors <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is such that at the foot of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> there are provided first and second pairs of connectors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The first pair of connectors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> serve for electrically coupling the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to a microphone pre-amplifier <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and thence to the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> determine the quality of the input signal, which in turn determines the quality of the transformation and of the output sound, and the provision of a pre-amplifier ensures a good quality signal. The second pair of connectors <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> serve for electrically coupling the exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and power amplifiers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A power supply <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, for example a lithium battery, connected to a power source (not shown) supplies power to all of the different circuit elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows the electrical circuitry for the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> more clearly. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, each microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is connected between a pair of lines <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so that the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are all connected in parallel. The lines <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are connected to the microphone pre-amplifier <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to supply the electrical signals from the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as an input. A pair of lines <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> lead from the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to supply an output signal to the power amplifiers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. As before, each power amplifier <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and associated exciter <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is connected between the lines <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> so that the exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are all arranged in parallel. A further pair of lines <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> leading from the power supply <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> serve for supplying power to the power amplifiers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> serves to transform the electrical signals supplied from the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into modified electrical signals for driving the exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. For this purpose, the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> employs an algorithm programmed in, for example, but not limited to Opcode MAX/MSP software, which is available in Macintosh&trade; computers. The DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> implements a series of digital filters arranged to be active one at a time. Each digital filter comprises a number of bandpass filters, one of which has a low center frequency and the others of which have frequencies which are multiples of this base frequency. A graphical interface is provided for a user to facilitate tuning of the parameters of each filtering function, and the algorithm is programmed to make decisions in order to change the filtering function according to the incoming noise signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The algorithm serves firstly to adjust the output level in order to modify or not modify peaks of the input noise signal. When sound incidents are happening, the output signal is increased to mask them. In this case, it is preferable for the overall sound energy for the controlled environment to increase, because that decreases the effect of noise disturbance caused to the brain. The same effect is achieved by producing a steady tone, like a constant hum, so as to concentrate on something when somebody is speaking. The algorithm serves secondly to adjust the filtering according to the quality of the incoming noise signal. This feature involves pattern recognition embedded in the software and enables the software to distinguish speech from traffic noise and thereby to adjust the filtering. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The sound transformation is based on principles derived from the psychology of hearing and the study of the human auditory perception. On the one hand, the algorithm is based on masking principles, which are well documented in the science of auditory perception. This effect relates to the incapability of the human auditory system to perceive certain sounds &lsqb;the maskee sounds&rsqb; in the presence of other sounds &lsqb;the masker sounds&rsqb; with a specific frequency and amplitude relationship. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The frequency and amplitude content of the filtered output are such that the filtered signal can mask the noise signal, thus rendering parts of the noise spectrum inaudible. The achieved masking weakens the &ldquo;sound identity&rdquo; of certain disturbing sound events, which become unrecognizable, and therefore does not bring any unpleasant connotations to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the algorithm output is built on known principles of the human auditory system that relate to the grouping of sound events. The close relation between the sensed and the transformed signals ensures that the two are grouped together by the listeners auditory system and are perceived as the new sound environment in the space, which is generated by the co-existence of the environmental noise and the harmonic output. This, in effect the algorithm redefines the sound context into which noise events are experienced and groups unpleasant sound events with more pleasing sounds with aesthetic content favorable to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Another important aspect relates to the effects of noise that are associated with control. The algorithm provides the user with a way to tune their sound environment by exercising an increased level of control on how the new sound environment is generated. This alleviates the disturbance and noise related stress associated with the lack of control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The algorithm will now be described in greater detail with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and to FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> represent flow diagrams showing the steps involved in the algorithm. FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> represent corresponding circuit blocks. For ease of understanding, the latter figures are designated by the same reference numerals with the suffice &lsquo;a&rsquo; added. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the noise received by each microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is converted to a digital electrical signal in an A/D converter (not shown) and is supplied as an input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The input is passed to an active decision sub-routine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> for analysis, and parameters of the input are extracted for subsequent use. Details of the subroutine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are displayed in a display in step <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The signal provided by the input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then passed though a first series of stages L for recreating the ambient sound environment and through a second series of stages R for generating a musical output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The first stages of R will be described first. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a ratio for the relative output level of the two filter groups is determined and is set. The input signal <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is then supplied in step <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to two groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of five filters: the steepness (q-factor) and the gain of each filter are automatically adjusted, as described below, according to the criteria in sub-routine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The center frequencies F<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>to F<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>of the five filters of each filter group are arranged to have a harmonic relation to one another. The center frequencies are selected within the algorithm by first selecting a base frequency, which is the center frequency of the first filter, and the multiplying this value by four numbers that correspond to a chord. For each selected frequency, there is identified a set of possible chords that the algorithm may use, determined by the programmer/composer. In this way, the tonal possibilities of the system can be controlled to achieve the desired aesthetic result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment of the invention, exemplary chords used in the algorithm are as follows &lsqb;chord name followed by 4 multipliers, one for each filter center frequency&rsqb;: Fifth, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Octave, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>; Fifth_Through, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>; Major_Triad, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Major_Extended, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Minor_Triad, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; Minor_Extended, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Major<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Maj<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>th_<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>rd, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; Minor<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; Dominant<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Sus<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Flat<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Flat<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Aug<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Alt<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Aug<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Augmented, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; Dim<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Closed, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>; Dim<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>_Open, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Sixth, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>; Minor_Sixth, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>; Sixth_Add<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Dominant<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Major<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Minor<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>th, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>_Sus<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>_Aug<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>_Flat<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; Dom<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>_Flat<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>; Thirteenth, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>; and Thirteenth_Flat<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. For instance, for a base frequency of <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> Hz and a Major_Triad selected, the center frequencies of the 5 filters of one filter group would be 60 Hz, 240 Hz, 420 Hz, 720 Hz, and 960 Hz. The sequences corresponding to the two filter groups can have the same or a different amount of members to produce a fixed or a virtually indefinite number of possible harmonic transitions when transitions between the two filter groups occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The signal output from the two groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of filters in step <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is passed in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to further filters for adding reverberation and echo frequencies, and this signal is mixed back in with the output of the two groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of filters in step <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The resultant signal has its amplitude controlled in step <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> according to a predetermined level set by the user in step <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Finally, the signal is passed in step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> through a high pass filter for output in step <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> In the series of stages L, the signal from the output <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is passed through a control step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in which it is determined whether the original noise is to be heard in the output or not. If not, the input signal is filtered out in step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. If it is, the signal is passed through a gate in step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. The determination in step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is effected by the user by way of manual control and, if the user indicates that the original noise is to be heard, then they will also set a level of control in step <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The signal output from the gate in step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is then controlled to the desired level in step <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> according to the predetermined amount set in step <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Finally, the resultant signal is passed through another high pass filter in step <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> for output in step <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The signals obtained in steps <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are combined in step <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and are passed through a D/A converter to supply to the amplifiers to drive the exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The active decision sub-routine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> will now be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. Firstly, the input signal from step <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is supplied to a sub-routine input <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. This input is analyzed in step <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> within five frequency bands for evaluating the amplitude required for each of the five filters in the two filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. For example, the mean amplitude of the sensed input in each of the five frequency bands is computed as defined by the center frequencies specified by the harmonic progression for a frequency band of a given width, which may be set by trial and error. Following this analysis, a control output is supplied in step <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> for setting the gain of each of the five filters in the two filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The control output is also supplied in step <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> to a circuit for setting the steepness or q-factor in each of the filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. For example, step <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> can be a simple curve that defines that the steepness of each filter is conversely proportional to the gain, i.e., when the gain is high, the steepness is low. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> If desired, a further control may be imposed on the control output through a harm control sub-routine <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, which is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. This sub-routine monitors the input signal to trigger a change of one filter group to the other in certain circumstances as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the input signal from step <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is supplied to a harm control input <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and passed through a series of steps <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> in order to detect peaks in the input noise signal. In response to such peaks, the harm control sub-routine triggers in step <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> a change-over command. The trigger command <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is supplied to the filter group weighting subroutine <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that cross fades between the two filter groups by adjusting their respective amplitudes over the time specified in step <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. The timing of the trigger commands is monitored in step <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and adjusted in step <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> if it is considered to be too rapid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Turning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the electrical circuitry for performing the algorithm will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>, the noise received by each microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is converted to a digital electrical signal in an A/D converter (not shown) and is supplied as an input signal to an input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The signal from the input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is passed to a circuit <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> for analysis, and parameters of the input signal are extracted for subsequent use. Details of the analysis are displayed on a display <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The input signal is also passed through a first series of stages L for modifying and outputting the sensed sound and through a second series of stages R for generating a musical output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The first series of stage R will be described first. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> These stages include the groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of five band-pass filters, designated as filter groups <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, arranged to receive the signal from the input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. A cross fader <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>determines a ratio for the level of original to transformed noise and sets the relative output levels of the two groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of five filters in the filter groups <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>anywhere between 0% for group <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and 100% for group <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to 100% for group <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and 0% for group <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the steepness (q-factor) and the gain of each filter are automatically adjusted, and the center frequencies F<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>to F<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>of the five filters of each filter group <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are arranged to have a harmonic relation to one another, in dependence upon outputs from the circuit <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The signals output from the two groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of filters in filter groups <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are mixed in a mixer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and passed through an effects processor <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for adding reverberation and echo frequencies, and the output from this processor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is mixed back in with the output of the mixer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in a further mixer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The resultant signal from the mixer <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is amplified in an amplifier <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>whose gain is set to a predetermined level through a user input <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Finally, the amplified signal is passed through a high pass filter <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to an output D/A converter <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In the series of stages L, the signal from the input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is passed to a gate <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>where a user control input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>determines whether the original noise is to be heard in the output or not. If not, the input signal is filtered out at the gate <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. If it is, the signal is passed through the gate <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The user control input <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is effected by the user by way of a manual control and, if the user indicates that the original noise is to be heard, then they will also set a level of control applied as a user control input <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to an amplifier <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The signal output from the gate <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is then amplified to the desired level in amplifier <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>according to the control input <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Finally, the resultant signal is passed through another high pass filter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for output by the D/A converter <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The signals from the high pass filters <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are combined in the D/A converter and are supplied to the amplifiers <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to drive the exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The analysis circuit <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>will now be described in further detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>. Firstly, the input signal from the input <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is supplied to a sub-routine input <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and thence to a processor <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, comprising an harmonic frequency generator <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and a filter amplitude evaluator <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. The harmonic frequency generator <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> is arranged to select a respective base frequency for each group <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of five filters, and to set this frequency as the center frequency for the first filter in the associated group. The harmonic frequency generator <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> then identifies four further frequencies representing multiples of the respective base frequency corresponding to a chord, and sets this set as the center frequencies for the second to fifth filters in the associated group. Outputs from the harmonic frequency generator <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> are applied directly to the filter groups <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and also to the filter amplitude evaluator <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> The filter amplitude evaluator <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> is arranged to receive the input signal from the input <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and to compute the mean amplitude of the sensed input in each of five frequency bands determined according to the center frequencies output by the harmonic frequency generator <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and according to a band width set by a control input <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Following the analysis, the filter amplitude evaluator <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> supplies, as an output from the processor <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a control output which is passed firstly to an amplifier <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and secondly to a setting circuit <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The output from the amplifier <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>serves to set the gain of each of the five filters in the two filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The circuit <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is arranged to supply an output for setting the steepness or q-factor in each of the filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, for example on the basis of a simple function defining the steepness of each filter as inversely proportional to the gain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> If desired, a further control may be imposed on the signal supplied to the filter groups <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through a harm control circuit <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which is arranged to receive the signal from the input <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. This circuit <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>monitors the input signal to trigger a change from one filter group to the other in certain circumstances as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24, a</cross-reference> control output from the processor <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is supplied to a harm control input <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and passed through a peak detection mechanism <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in order to detect peaks in the input noise signal. In response to such peaks, the circuit <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>activates a trigger generator <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to generate a change-over command <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to effect a change between the two filter groups <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The timing of the trigger is monitored in a timing circuit <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and adjusted by an output <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>if it is considered to be too rapid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the invention will now be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. This second embodiment constitute a modification of the first embodiment and like parts are designated by the same reference numerals. Only the differences will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In the second embodiment, the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are mounted on a portion of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as well as the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the power supply <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, in the form of a rechargeable battery and/or an AC/DC transformer, are also mounted on the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows a curtain module <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for use in the second embodiment, carrying both a microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, it is envisaged in the second embodiment that the curtain module <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> will be employed with a further series of curtain modules <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, each bearing only a respective power amplifier <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and exciter <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> but no further microphone <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> A third embodiment of the invention is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. Again, like parts are designated by the same reference numerals and only the differences in relation to the first embodiment will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment, the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the DSP <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are spaced at a distance from the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are mounted on the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In this instance, each loudspeaker comprises an exciter <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> mounted on a rigid panel <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, which is inserted into the mold during molding of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or which is produced as a part of the curtain with a double molding process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> One possible form of the rigid panel <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> and comprises first and second skins <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> with a honeycomb core <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> mounted between them. The combination of the honeycomb core <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> with the two skins <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> results in a substantially rigid structure providing the panel <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Finally, a modification of the connection means illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> for connecting curtain modules together is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. According to this modification, the upper and lower edges <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of each curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are formed to be identical and to have a wedge-shaped portion <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> that thickens towards the edge of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each wedge shaped portion <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> terminates in a planar surface <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> arranged perpendicular to the main plain of the curtain module <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and a groove <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> is provided in a side surface <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> of the wedge-shaped portion <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and extends towards the planar surface <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. An elongate connector strip <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> formed with a pair of converging flanged edges <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> can be slotted into the groove <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> of adjacent curtain modules <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for joining the curtain modules together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that a number of further modifications are possible in the invention as described without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> In particular, the wiring, and electrical circuit components, may be screen printed on to the surface of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, rather than molded in situ as described. Conductive inks are commercially available providing a very flexible, low resistance, screen printable medium. In this instance, the ink may need to be heat Treated for a short time, for example 5 to 15 seconds, at a raised temperature in the range, for example, of 80 to 120 degrees centigrade. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The described exciters <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may also be replaced by alternative loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, for example, piezo-electric speakers or other small sized flat speaker arrangements. Another possibility is to employ flexible piezo speaker film for the whole surface of the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, to act as the loudspeaker. The film may be stretched or curved in order to increase output quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> In the embodiments described above, stiffened portions have been provided in the curtain <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for mounting the loudspeakers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. If the curtain material is stiff enough, however, such portions may be omitted altogether for ease of manufacture. Alternatively, if stiffened portions are provided, they may be selected to have a range of stiffnesses as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the panel shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> and proposed for providing a stiffened curtain portion may alternatively be used in its own right as curtain module or as a partitioning device, since such a construction would be particularly effective at reducing the noise level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> According to the described embodiments of the present invention, ambient noise detected by the microphones <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is replaced with a particular quality of relaxing, soothing or musical sound. The present invention records environmental sound, applies simple transformations to signals representing the sensed sound using a filtering process, for example by means of digital filters, and provides an output thus based on the received sound. There are many types of filtering arrangements that can be used to achieve such a transformation, including the filter groups described above, the use of delay circuitry or delay lines, and many others, all designed to process and preserve a substantial amount of information from the input sound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> Other embodiments and uses of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein. All references cited herein, including all U.S. patents, are hereby incorporated herein by reference in their entirety. Although the invention has been particularly shown and described with reference to several preferred embodiments thereof, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes in form and details may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Apparatus for acoustically improving an environmental space comprising: 
<claim-text>a partitioning screen for producing a discontinuity in a sound conducting medium in the environmental space, wherein the partitioning screen acts as a sound absorber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for receiving acoustic energy from the environmental space and for converting the acoustic energy into an electrical input signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for analyzing the input signal and for providing a control signal based on such analysis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means responsive to the control signal for generating an electrical output signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>output means for converting the output signal into sound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partitioning screen comprises a curtain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the curtain is translucent and comprises a woven or molded material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the curtain comprises flexible and inflexible portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the output means is mounted on the inflexible portions of the curtain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partitioning means comprises electrically conductive pathways. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electrically conductive pathways are integrally molded within the partitioning screen or are defined by electrically conductive ink printed on the surface thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the receiving means is mounted on the partitioning screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partitioning screen comprises at least two materials of differing acoustic properties. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the materials of differing acoustic properties are separated by a space. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partitioning screen comprises a rigid panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for generating an electrical output signal comprises a series of filters for filtering the input signal, and in which the control signal is arranged to adjust the filtering functions of the filters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising means for modifying a transfer function of at least one of the filters so that incoming noises are manipulated to select harmonics which are then output as audio sound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for analyzing the input signal and for generating the control signal include a microprocessor or digital signal processor operating under the control of an algorithm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ambient noise level is reduced by 6 to 12 decibels by means of a partitioning screen and/or the means for generating an electrical output signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing the apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the steps of. 
<claim-text>providing electrically conductive pathways in or on a flexible material, the electrical pathways being adapted to connect to means for receiving audio energy and for converting such audio energy into an electrical signal for processing and being adapted also to provide a pathway for the processed electrical signal to an audio output means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A system for improving a sound environment comprising 
<claim-text>a number of microphones for sensing environmental sound; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing unit for processing the sensed environmental sound; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a number of speakers for outputting the processed environmental sound back into said sound environment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said microphones, said processing unit, and said speakers are integrated into a medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said medium comprises a sound absorbing medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sound absorbing medium is selected from the group consisting of: nylon, polyester, rubber, polyurethane, Kevlar, carbon-fiber epoxy, or a combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said medium comprises a sound reflecting medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sound reflecting medium is selected from the group consisting of: steel, plastic, or a combination thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said microphones, said processing unit, and said speakers are arranged freely in space. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said medium comprises a sound curtain. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sound curtain comprises a number of curtain modules affixed to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a power amplifier for amplifying said sensed environmental sound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said number of microphones is greater than one, said microphones electrically connected in parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said number of speakers is greater than one, said speakers electrically connected in parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a number of digital filters. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said number of digital filters comprises a set of bandpass filters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said bandpass filters has a center frequency, with one of said bandpass filters having a center frequency designated as a base frequency, and each of the other bandpass filters having a center frequency substantially equal to an integer multiple of said base frequency. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said center frequencies are associated with a musical chord. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method for acoustically improving an environment comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>receiving sound from an environment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting said sound into electrical signals; </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing said electrical signals to obtain a processed signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting said processed signal into an analog signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>driving an exciter with said analog signal, wherein said analog signal comprises a portion of said received sound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>filtering out a number of frequency bands in the received sound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>masking a number of frequency bands in the received sound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>generating a number of tonal sequences, wherein said processed signal comprises said tonal sequences. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said number of tonal sequences are associated with a number of musical chords. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said analog signal in combination with said received sound produces a sound spectrum with a decreased effect of noise disturbance to a human auditory system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>filtering said electrical signals through application of a series of digital filters. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each digital filter comprises a number of bandpass filters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of 
<claim-text>adjusting said filtering according to a quality of said received sound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adjusting step is based on pattern recognition that distinguishes between speech and noise. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said number of bandpass filters are harmonically related to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>applying echo or reverb functions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said processing step comprises the step of 
<claim-text>running said electrical signals through a series of delay lines with variable delay times. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A sound curtain comprising: 
<claim-text>a sound partitioning screen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a number of exciters affixed to said sound partitioning screen; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing circuitry for transforming sensed sound of an environment of said sound partitioning screen into an output sound, wherein said output sound drives said exciters. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising 
<claim-text>a number of sensors for sensing said sound of an environment of said sound partitioning screen, wherein said sensors are affixed to said sound partitioning screen. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors comprise microphones. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said number of sensors and said number of exciters are respectively affixed on opposite sides of said sound partitioning screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said exciters comprise speakers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sound partitioning screen comprises a sound absorber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sound partitioning screen comprises a sound reflector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>electrically conductive pathways. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrically conductive pathways connect said exciters to said processing circuitry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrically conductive pathways are integrally molded within said sound partitioning screen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The sound curtain of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrically conductive pathways are defined by electrically conductive ink printed on the surface of said sound partitioning screen.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030002687A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
