<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002032A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002032A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002032</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895333</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01N021/41</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>356</class>
<subclass>128000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for production line screening</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ofer</given-name>
<family-name>Du-Nour</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Timrat</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Tevet Process Control Technologies Ltd.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>G.E. EHRLICH (1995) LTD.</name-1>
<name-2>c/o ANTHONY CASTORINA</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>SUITE 207</address-1>
<address-2>2001 JEFFERSON DAVIS HIGHWAY</address-2>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The use of an intensity spectrum as a fingerprint to determine the layer structure of a semiconductor wafer product or partial product, thereby to determine the routing history of the product through a production line and prevent routing errors. Also, a production line having a plurality of successive stages for construction of a product such as a semiconductor wafer, and routers for transferring partly constructed product between the stages such that each stage receives a respective predefined partly constructed product as its input. The production line comprises: a predetermined intensity spectrum for at least one stage representing the respective part construction for the stage, an intensity spectrum deriver located at said at least one stage operable to obtain intensity spectra of incoming partly constructed product, and a comparator, for comparing said obtained intensity spectra with said predetermined intensity spectrum, to determine whether said incoming partly constructed products correspond with said respective predefined part construction for the stage. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method and apparatus for production line screening and more particularly but not exclusively to screening of semiconductor wafer products at intermediate stages in a multi-tool semiconductor wafer production line. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor chip manufacturing process generally involves forming a silicon wafer and then carrying out a sequence of operations that essentially involves addition and selective removal of layers to build the functionality of the chip. The process may typically involve several hundred individual operations including deposition of dielectric and metal layers. Coating of photoresist, photolithography using a mask, etching of layers, ashing etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In a manufacturing production line, it is not untypical that something of the order of a thousand wafers may move together through the same sequence of operations at any one time using parallel paths amongst a set of tools. Different tools at different stages take different amounts of time to carry out their processes and thus it is generally found necessary to carry out intelligent routing operations to ensure maximum throughput of wafers. In any kind of routing operation, unless totally straightforward, there is a danger that a batch (or lot) of wafers are misrouted such that operations are carried out in the wrong sequence. Such misrouting leads to scrapping of the entire batch of wafers, generally a very expensive kind of an error just in terms of the batch alone. In addition, entering wafers into the wrong process tools at the wrong time can lead to damage of the process tool, for example due to contamination of the process chamber or the wafer breaking whilst inside the chamber and the like. Damage to the process tool may involve considerable down time, and a repair or replacement cost which is not inconsiderable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> At present the only solutions to routing errors lie in producing more effective and robust routing algorithms. For the vast majority of combinations of steps there is nothing on the wafers themselves that is available for a simple and rapid determination as to whether the wafer approaching a given tool has been through the correct preceding combination of steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> PCT Patent Application No. WO 0012958 describes a measurement system known as TMS which uses light beams reflected from within layers of a wafer surface to make measurements of the thicknesses of transparent layers and in particular photoresist layers. The measurement is transformed typically into the frequency domain from which it is possible to determine the photoresist layer thickness very accurately. The measurement is quick but typically relates to the thickness or refractive index of a single transparent layer such as a photoresist layer, or to a set of thicknesses of a series of trenches but the system as described does not provide clear overall information that would enable a determination as to where the wafer is in the production line process. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the embodiments hereinbelow to provide a solution to the above problem and to allow rapid and practical measurements to be made to a wafer to determine overall what layers it has and thus where it has been in the production process, from which it is possible to determine whether or not it is being correctly routed through the production process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to a first aspect of the present invention there is thus provided a production line having a plurality of successive stages for construction of a product comprising at least one layer on a substrate, and routers for transferring partly constructed products between the stages such that each stage receives a respective predefined partly constructed product as its input, the production line comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> a predetermined reflected light intensity spectrum for at least one stage representing the respective predefined part construction for the stage, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> a reflected light intensity spectrum deriver located at said at least one stage operable to obtain reflected light intensity spectra of incoming partly constructed product, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> a comparator, for comparing said obtained reflected light intensity spectra with said predetermined reflected light intensity spectrum, to determine whether said incoming partly constructed products correspond with said respective predefined part construction for the stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The production line preferably further comprises a routing error indicator operatively associated with said comparator for indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The production line preferably further comprises a production interruption mechanism operatively associated with said routing error indicator for interruption of operation of said production line in the event of indication of a routing error. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage comprises a reflected light intensity spectrum deriver and has a predetermined intensity spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said comparator is further operable to compare said obtained reflected light intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of at least one other stage to reroute said product to said other stage if said spectra match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said intensity spectrum deriver comprises an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities spectrum into a frequency spectrum thereof, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> a layer property determiner for determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said frequency spectrum by Fourier transformation of said analyzed intensity spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to a second aspect of the present invention there is provided a tool guard for restricting input to a production tool for carrying out a stage in the production of a layered product, the tool guard comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> a predetermined intensity spectrum representing an expected part construction for the stage, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> an intensity spectrum deriver located at said tool operable to obtain an intensity spectrum of an incoming partly constructed product, and a comparator, for comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with said predetermined intensity spectrum, to determine whether said incoming partly constructed product corresponds with said respective predefined part construction for the stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The tool guard preferably further comprises a routing error indicator operatively associated with said comparator for indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The tool guard preferably further comprises a production interruption mechanism operatively associated with said routing error indicator for interruption of operation of said tool in the event of indication of a routing error. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said tool is a semiconductor wafer production tool for use in a production line producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said intensity spectrum deriver comprises </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities into a frequency spectrum of the intensities, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> a layer property determiner for determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said frequency spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the present invention there is provided a production line router for routing intermediate inputs around a multiple stage production line, the intermediate inputs comprising substrates with at least one superimposed layer, the router comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> predetermined intensity spectra for each of a plurality of said stages representing a respective intermediate construction for the stage, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> at least one intensity spectrum deriver located within said production line for obtaining intensity spectra of intermediate inputs, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> a comparator, for obtaining a closest match between said obtained intensity spectrum and any of said predetermined spectra, said router being operable to route said intermediate input to a stage corresponding to said closest matching spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage comprises an intensity spectrum deriver and has a predetermined intensity spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said intensity spectrum deriver comprises </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities into a frequency spectrum of the intensities spectrum, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> a layer property determiner for determining, from said spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said intermediate input includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> According to a fourth aspect of the present invention there is provided a wafer production history determiner for determining the production history of a semiconductor wafer product, the determiner comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> a plurality of predetermined intensity spectra for semiconductor wafer products having completed respective stages of a multiple stage semiconductor wafer production process, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> an intensity spectrum deriver for obtaining an intensity spectrum of an incoming semiconductor wafer product, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> a comparator, for comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with each of said predetermined intensity spectra, to determine a closest match between said obtained spectrum and one of said predetermined spectra, said determiner inferring said production history as including the respective completed stage corresponding to said closest match predetermined spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> According to a fifth aspect of the present invention there is provided the use of a spectrum obtained by reflecting multiple wavelength light from a plurality of points on a layered product, to determine a production history of said layered product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect, in a production line having a plurality of successive stages for construction of a product comprising at least one at least semi-transparent layer on a substrate, and routers for transferring partly constructed product between the stages such that each stage receives a respective predefined partly constructed product as its input, and having a predetermined intensity spectrum associated with at least one stage representing the respective part construction for the stage, there is provided a method comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> obtaining intensity spectra of partly constructed products incoming to said stage, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> comparing said obtained intensity spectra with said predetermined intensity spectrum, and thereby determining whether said incoming partly constructed product corresponds with said respective predefined part construction for the respective stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Preferably the method further comprises indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Preferably the method further comprises interrupting operation of said production line in the event of indication of a routing error. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Preferably the method further comprises obtaining intensity spectra for incoming partly constructed products to each stage, each said stage having a predetermined intensity spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Preferably the method further comprises comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of at least one other stage to reroute said product to said other stage if said spectra match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Preferably, obtaining said intensity spectrum comprises </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength, thereby to produce a spectrum of intensities at respective wavelengths, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> converting said spectrum of intensities into a frequency spectrum, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said converting comprises producing said spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> For a better understanding of the invention and to show how the same may be carried into effect, reference will now be made, purely by way of example, to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a simplified diagram of a layered wafer product, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a simplified diagram of the layered wafer product of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> at a later stage in the production process, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a simplified ray diagram illustrating how light reflection can be used to obtain information of layer thicknesses in a layered wafer product, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a simplified schematic diagram of a reflection-based measuring device associated with a spinner in a semiconductor wafer production line, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a typical graph of inverse wavelength against intensity obtained by measuring a semiconductor wafer using the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is the energy or intensity spectrum obtained by performing a Fourier transform on the graph of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a typical graph of wavelength against intensity for another semiconductor wafer, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is the energy or intensity spectrum obtained by performing a Fourier transform on the graph of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a simplified schematic diagram of a part of a production line comprising numerous tools arranged as a series of stages, each stage comprising a plurality of tools in parallel, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a simplified cross-section of a wafer that could typically be constructed by the production line of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an intensity spectrum obtained from the wafer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a simplified flow chart illustrating operation at a single tool of the routing mechanism of a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> As an introduction to the present invention, the measurement method of PCT Patent Application No. WO 0012958 is discussed in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, which is a simplified diagram showing a cross section of a silicon wafer at an intermediate stage in the production process. A silicon wafer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a photoresist layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> attached thereon. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is uniform and only a single measurement is necessary to determine the thickness of the layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, which is a simplified diagram showing a cross section of another silicon wafer at another intermediate stage in the production process. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> the wafer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a series of silicon dioxide structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and a continuous polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> covered by a photoresist layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The TMS measurement system, as will be explained in more detail below, is particularly suitable for measuring the thickness of a transparent film. In the present case the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has differences in thickness at different places due to the silicon dioxide structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. There may thus be identified three different layer thickness d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>-d<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>in a typical wafer. The above differences in thickness are not accurately measurable in a conventional measurement system. The TMS system however, is capable of measuring such thickness variations in wafer layers that are applied or layers that have been removed, and furthermore the measurement is in situ and in real-time. The following description of the basic theory of operation of the TMS process will be helpful in understanding how this may be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, which is a simplified ray diagram showing incidence of light at an angle onto a series of layers having different refractive indices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> material comprising three transparent layers, 0, 1, and 2, are subjected to light radiation. An incident ray <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> strikes a first layer boundary <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to be split into a reflected ray <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a refracted ray <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The refracted ray <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> strikes a second layer boundary <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is again split. This time only the reflected ray <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is shown. As the refracted ray <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> strikes the first boundary <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> it is refracted again to comprise a third refracted ray <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Several methods are known for measuring thickness of transparent films using the reflected pattern of multi-wavelength light. When the beam shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a monochromatic (single wavelength) light beam, and it arrives at a transparent film, part of the beam is reflected from the upper face (Layer 0/Layer 1 interface), and part is reflected from the bottom face (Layer 1/Layer 2 interface). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Expressing mathematically what is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> &lgr; is the wavelength of the light; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> &phgr;<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>is the phase angle of the incident light (and of the light reflected from the Layer 0/Layer 1 interface): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> &phgr;<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>&plus;&phgr;<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>is the phase angle of the light reflected from the Layer 1/Layer 2 interface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> r<highlight><subscript>01 </subscript></highlight>is the reflection coefficient of the Layer 0/Layer 1 interface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> r<highlight><subscript>12 </subscript></highlight>is the reflection coefficient of the Layer 1/Layer 2 interfaces; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> I is the intensity of the incident light </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>I&equals;Io </italic></highlight>cos(2<highlight><italic>&pgr;ct/&lgr;&plus;</italic></highlight>4<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. 1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Where I<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>is the maximum intensity amplitude and c is the speed of light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> For light arriving perpendicularly at the film surface, the reflection coefficients from the top and bottom surfaces are: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>01</subscript></highlight>&equals;(<highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&minus;n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>)/(<highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1&plus;</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>) <highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight>&equals;(<highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&minus;n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)/(<highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&plus;n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> wherein n<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>, n<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, n<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>are the refractive indices of layers 0, 1 and 2, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> The light reflected from the upper face interferes with the light reflected from the bottom face, giving an overall reflection coefficient (R) which is a function of the layer thickness and the layer refractive index. This reflection can be described by the, well-known, Frenel equation. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>R</italic></highlight>&equals;(<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>01</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&plus;r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&plus;2<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>01</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>12 </subscript></highlight>cos 2&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>01</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&plus;2<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>01</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>12 </subscript></highlight>cos 2&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. 3) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> where: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;2<highlight><italic>&pgr;n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>/&lgr;&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. 4) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> where: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&mdash;layer thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Illuminating the film with multi-wavelength light (white light), and measuring the reflectance at each wavelength (&lgr;), gives R as a function of &lgr;, i.e., R(&lgr;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Illuminating a product wafer having a complex (i.e. laterally varying) topography with a large spot of multi-wavelength light causes a reflected beam which is a composition of the separate reflection of each of the thicknesses taken alone. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>R</italic></highlight>(&lgr;,<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>, . . . ,d</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>)&equals;&Sgr;<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>(<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&plus;r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&plus;2<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1) </subscript></highlight>cos 2&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>)/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&plus;2<highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1) </subscript></highlight>cos 2&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>)&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. 5) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> By simple mathematical operations it is possible to express the reflection coefficient by: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>R</italic></highlight>(&lgr;,<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>, . . . , d</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>)&equals;&Sgr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&lsqb;1&minus;<highlight><italic>A</italic></highlight>/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>B </italic></highlight>Cos(2&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>))&rsqb;&emsp;&emsp;(EQ. 6) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> where: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>A</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&equals;(1&minus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)(1&minus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>) and </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>B</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&equals;2<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight>/(1&plus;<highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>(i&minus;1),i</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><italic>r</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>i(i&plus;1)</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Applying ways of frequency decomposition of the reflection coefficient may provide each of the arguments (&PHgr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>) and from Eq 3 &amp; 4 it is possible to determine the layer thickness assuming that the layer refractive index is known. Alternatively it is possible to determine the layer refractive index, if the layer thickness is known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> There are several ways to perform frequency decomposition, some of which are suggested below: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Mathematical Decompositions </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> 1) The family of orthogonal transform methods, for example Fourier transforms, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> 2) The family of methods based on the maximum likelihood principle, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> 3) The family of methods based on parametric models </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> 4) The family of subspace decomposition methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Electrical Decomposition: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> Electrical frequency filters are widely used in electrical systems. Such filters serve to define windows in the frequency domain and output the amplitude of the component of the input signal within the range of the window. Passing the reflected signal (translated into electrical signal) through a set of filters or a single filter with variable frequency gives the desired decomposition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which is a simplified block diagram showing an arrangement for measuring the thickness variations of a transparent layer on a semiconductor substrate. The measurement arrangement is mounted on a photoresist coating track. The coating track comprises a spinning bowl <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The spinning bowl <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises a spinner chuck <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for receiving a wafer W, and a motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> having an encoder <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, for rotating the chuck, and the wafer thereon, while a photoresist applicator <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) dispenses photoresist material at the center of the wafer. The wafer W is first rotated at a low speed as photoresist material is dispensed at its center, and then is rotated at high speed (e.g., 300-5000 rpm) by electric motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which produces centrifugal forces causing the photoresist liquid to flow towards the edge of the wafer W. Most of the photoresist (e.g. about 95%) is spilled off the wafer and is collected in a bowl (not shown)to be drained later, while the adhesion forces between the wafer surface and the photoresist hold smaller amounts of the photoresist as a coating on the wafer. As briefly described earlier, the final thickness of the photoresist coating is produced when a balance is achieved between the centrifugal forces, the adhesion to the surface, and the shear forces caused by the viscosity of the photoresist liquid. During the spinning process the solvent contained in the photoresist evaporates and the viscosity increases. Thus, a final thickness is reached which is also a function of the solvent evaporation rate, and is affected by the temperature, air flow and other environmental conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the apparatus further includes an illuminating device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for illuminating the photoresist coating with a beam of light of multiple wavelengths (white light), and a detector <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for detecting the intensity of the light reflected from the photoresist coating for each wavelength. Preferably, the detector <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is connected to a photodiode array spectrum analyzer. The spectrum analyzer is able to detect interference patterns over a range of wavelengths and, using the equations as given above, is able to obtain data of the layer thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> In order to obtain information on the thickness or refractive index of more then one spot on the wafer, multiple detecting heads <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be placed at different locations above the wafers. The outputs of the detecting heads <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are preferably multiplexed for sending to the spectrum analyzer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, for example by mechanically switching between each of the optical fibers. Data acquisition is thus enabled from different sites on the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> The illuminating device preferably applies a beam of white light in any suitable manner, e.g., via an optical fiber <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, to the optical head <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> mounted above the wafer W, thereby projecting a beam of light onto the photoresist coating of the wafer W as the wafer is rotated. The light reflected from the photoresist coating is directed in any suitable manner, e.g., via another optical fiber <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, to the spectrum analyzer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, thereby to detect the intensity of the light reflected from the photoresist coating for each wavelength. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> The outputs of the spectrum analyzer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are preferably fed to a processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> which processes the outputs according to the basic theory of operation described above, and displays the outputs on a screen <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In addition, an output of processor <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may also be used, for example as a feedback input, for controlling the application of the photoresist coating <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> onto the wafer W. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the optical head <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is mounted for movement along the radial axis, to enable the optical head to be located at any selected radius of the wafer W under test. During the wafer rotation the angular position of the wafer is identified by the encoder <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, which, combined with the radial position, gives the location of a desired measurement spot on the wafer. Preferably, the beam of light <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is large enough to cover at least one complete die of a plurality of dies carried by the wafer W. The use of such a beam of light large enough to cover a complete die, or a multiple thereof, provides a number of advantages. For example it better ensures that the combined reflected light detected by detector <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> will not change substantially between measurements, irrespective of the difference in the exact measurement position. Furthermore, the large spot size increases the signal collected by the optical head and also increases the speed of detection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, which is a simplified graph illustrating inverse wavelength against amplitude for a typical set of measurements involving a simulation of the above-described process when applied to a wafer coated with a photoresist coating having two different thicknesses (d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, d<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) at different points, for example as the result of an etching operation. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> thus illustrates the sum R of the reflectance coefficients r<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and r<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>as a function of thickness d<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and d<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>respectively and the wavelength. In the example, d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.95&mgr;; d<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&equals;1.25&mgr;, and the ratio of the intensity of the separated signals&equals;1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> which is a simplified graph showing the data of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> to which a Fourier transform has been applied, that is to say a Fourier transform is applied to the signal R which defines the overall reflection. The Fourier transform produces a series of Fourier coefficients for the signal frequencies, from which the thickness of the transparent film can be determined for each respective signal frequency. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the two thicknesses of the photoresist coating produce two quite distinct peaks, each representing the frequency related to one of the thicknesses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, which are simplified graphs illustrating how the system described above may be used to measure thicknesses of two layers superimposed upon each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows intensity against wavelength for a reflection signal from a wafer with a pattern of metal lines covered by an inter-metal dielectric on Silicon dioxide (Oxide). Two thicknesses of oxide are present at the vicinity of a measurement spot: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> 1) oxide on top of the metal lines, with d<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&equals;1556 nm, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> 2) oxide on top of previously deposited dielectric of thickness of d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&equals;722 nm. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates the signal received after processing by a frequency transformation process similar to that mentioned above. The results show the peaks at frequencies related to d<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and d<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&plus;d<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, which is a simplified diagram illustrating a length <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of a production line for producing semiconductor wafers. In production line length <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, five stages <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of a production process are carried out by sets of tools operating in parallel. The different stages each have different numbers of tools, typically because the tools at each stage operate at different rates. Thus to achieve a given wafer throughput requires four tools at a first stage <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, five tools at a second stage <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, two tools at a third stage <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, five tools at a fourth stage <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and three tools at a fifth stage <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Wafers are routed between stages, in batches of 25 wafers (lots), typically by robot shuttles or conveyor arrangements, or by human operators. Any lot finishing a given stage is preferably routed to the next available tool in the next stage. For certain production runs one or more of the stages may not be needed and certain of the tools may be down for maintenance at any given time. Thus routing of wafers amongst the tools is not a trivial problem. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> For each stage of the production process, a wafer that has been correctly routed will already have a given configuration of layers. A measurement device as described above may thus be placed at the input to each tool or each stage to obtain a Fourier transform indicating layer thicknesses in the wafer. Provided that the transform shows the expected number of peaks indicating the expected frequencies, the wafer is admitted to the respective stage of the process. If a wafer arrives at a particular stage and a Fourier transform is obtained indicating an unexpected layer configuration then a routing error is inferred and the wafer is not admitted to the respective stage of the process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> It is noted at this point that a deep layer history is only possible with transparent or semi-transparent layers. However surface information at least can be obtained even in the case of opaque layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> In the event of a routing error, the Fourier transform is generally sufficient to indicate the routing history of the wafer so that the wafer can be reinserted at the correct point in the process, as will be explained in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, which is a simplified cross section of a semiconductor wafer at an intermediate stage in a wafer production process. The cross-section comprises numerous layers and numerous different thicknesses and refractive index which may be expected to appear in the transform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, which is a simplified graph of the Fourier transform of the thickness measurement carried out on the wafer of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The transform is essentially an energy spectrum of the light falling on the wafer and provides a fingerprint as to the layer structure of the wafer. The spectrum of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> can be compared manually or electronically with an expected spectrum to determine whether a routing error has or has not occurred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Comparison between spectra may be carried out automatically using pattern matching or other image analysis techniques or even by simple measurements of peak levels, which may then be compared statistically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> The optical thickness (or refractive index) measurement is simple and rapid to make and thus does not slow down production throughput. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> In the event of a routing error the process may be shut down or the wafers rerouted. Rerouting may be carried out automatically by comparing the spectra indicated in the routing error with spectra expected at other stages in the process. The wafers are then rerouted to a stage given a spectral match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> A production line according to an embodiment of the present invention may have successive stages for construction of a product, such as a semiconductor wafer product. The wafer product typically has one or more transparent or semi-transparent layers on a substrate, the layers being added at certain stages of the production process and removed or selectively removed at other stages such that each stage of the production process is characterised by a given set of layer thicknesses on the wafer surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> The production line, as mentioned above, preferably comprises routers for transferring partly constructed product between the stages. Preferably each stage should receive a part product having a given previous production history so that each stage is reached by the wafers in a given sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> One or more of the stages is supplied with a predetermined intensity spectrum corresponding to the respective part construction or production history for the stage, The stages are additionally supplied with an intensity spectrum deriver for obtaining intensity spectra of incoming partly constructed wafers arriving at the stage. The deriver may be a single device supplied for the entire stage or several such devices may be provided, in particular if the stage comprises several tools operating in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> A comparator is additionally supplied for comparing the obtained intensity spectra with the predetermined intensity spectrum, to determine whether the incoming partly constructed products correspond with the respective predefined part construction for the stage. The comparison may be carried out using, for example, pattern matching techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> If the spectra do not match then a routing error indicator preferably indicates a routing error (miss-process). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment a production interruption mechanism is connected with the routing error indicator to interruption operation of the production line in the event of indication of a routing error. Thus it is possible to automatically prevent insertion of semiconductor wafers into the wrong part of the process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment, in the event of a failure to match, the comparator is further operable to compare the obtained intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of other stages. The wafer can then be automatically rerouted to any other stage giving a spectral match. The embodiment is thus usable as an automatic rerouter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that as well as carrying out spectral matching automatically, spectral matching can be carried out manually. Additionally or alternatively, decisions on rerouting or on interrupting the process may be made manually. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Preferably, and as discussed above, the intensity spectrum deriver comprises the following features: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> 1) an irradiator or illuminator for irradiating a wafer at one or points thereon with a multiple wavelength radiation source, typically white light, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> 2) an intensity detector for detecting intensities of reflections of the irradiation, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> 3) an analyzer operatively connected to the intensity detector for analyzing the intensities in terms of wavelength and converting the analyzed intensities into a frequency spectrum, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> 4) a layer property determiner for determining, from the spectrum, layer properties of layers on the part product. The layer property is typically a thickness or a refractive index, the spectrum typically showing each thickness around the points measured as a separate peak. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> The analyzer may include comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing the spectrum by Fourier transform of the analyzed intensities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> The above described arrangement may be provided at an individual tool to serve as a tool guard for restricting input to the tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> The above-described arrangement may be provided at each tool or at each stage of a production line or part thereof to serve as an automatic or semiautomatic production line router for routing intermediate inputs around a multiple stage production line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> The above-described arrangement may alternatively be provided, perhaps independently of a production line, as a wafer production history determiner for determining the production history of a semiconductor wafer product. The history determiner is useful as a process diagnostic tool, for example by a process or control engineer. The history determiner is supplied with a series of spectra, each relating to different stages in the production process and wafers are compared with the series of spectra to obtain a closest match, thereby to determine their production history. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, which is a simplified flow chart showing operation of the wafer acceptance arrangement at a given tool or stage in the production line. An incoming wafer is obtained and irradiated at several points using multiple wavelength light. The light for each of the points is detected and analyzed into separate wavelengths, preferably using the analyzer described above. The analyzed data are then transformed, preferably using Fourier analysis, to produce a frequency domain spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> The spectrum obtained as described above may then be compared with the prestored intensity spectrum associated with the respective tool or stage. The comparison may be automatic, involving pattern matching or any other suitable technique or it may be manual and the result of the comparison may be used to determine whether the incoming wafer should be accepted or rejected by the respective tool or stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> In an embodiment rejecting the incoming wafer comprises indicating a routing error when the spectra do not match. Alternatively or additionally, rejecting the incoming wafer may involve interrupting operation of the production line in the event of indication of a routing error. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each stage has its own predetermined intensity spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, following rejection of a wafer at a given tool an additional step may be provided of comparing the obtained intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of other stages to reroute the wafer to whichever of the other stages gives a match. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> According to the above embodiments there is thus provided use of an intensity spectrum as a &lsquo;fingerprint&rsquo; to determine the layer structure of a semiconductor wafer product or partial product, thereby to determine the routing history of the product through a production line and prevent routing errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> It is appreciated that certain features of the invention, which are, for clarity, described in the context of separate embodiments, may also be provided in combination in a single embodiment. Conversely, various features of the invention which are, for brevity, described in the context of a single embodiment, may also be provided separately or in any suitable subcombination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated by persons skilled in the art that the present invention is not limited to what has been particularly shown and described hereinabove. Rather the scope of the present invention is defined by the appended claims and includes both combinations and subcombinations of the various features described hereinabove as well as variations and modifications thereof which would occur to persons skilled in the art upon reading the foregoing description. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A production line having a plurality of successive stages for construction of a product comprising at least one layer on a substrate, and routers for transferring partly constructed products between the stages such that each stage receives a respective predefined partly constructed product as its input, the production line comprising: 
<claim-text>a predetermined reflected light intensity spectrum for at least one stage representing the respective predefined part construction for the stage, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflected light intensity spectrum deriver located at said at least one stage operable to obtain reflected light intensity spectra of incoming partly constructed product, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator, for comparing said obtained reflected light intensity spectra with said predetermined reflected light intensity spectrum, to determine whether said incoming partly constructed products correspond with said respective predefined part construction for the stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a routing error indicator operatively associated with said comparator for indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a production interruption mechanism operatively associated with said routing error indicator for interruption of operation of said production line in the event of indication of a routing error. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each stage comprises a reflected light intensity spectrum deriver and has a predetermined intensity spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said comparator is further operable to compare said obtained reflected light intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of at least one other stage to reroute said product to said other stage if said spectra match. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said intensity spectrum deriver comprises 
<claim-text>an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities spectrum into a frequency spectrum thereof, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a layer property determiner for determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said frequency spectrum by Fourier transformation of said analyzed intensity spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A tool guard for restricting input to a production tool for carrying out a stage in the production of a layered product, the tool guard comprising: 
<claim-text>a predetermined intensity spectrum representing an expected part construction for the stage, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intensity spectrum deriver located at said tool operable to obtain an intensity spectrum of an incoming partly constructed product, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator, for comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with said predetermined intensity spectrum, to determine whether said incoming partly constructed product corresponds with said respective predefined part construction for the stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a routing error indicator operatively associated with said comparator for indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a production interruption mechanism operatively associated with said routing error indicator for interruption of operation of said tool in the event of indication of a routing error. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said tool is a semiconductor wafer production tool for use in a production line producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said intensity spectrum deriver comprises 
<claim-text>an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities into a frequency spectrum of the intensities, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a layer property determiner for determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A tool guard according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said frequency spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A production line router for routing intermediate inputs around a multiple stage production line, the intermediate inputs comprising substrates with at least one superimposed layer, the router comprising: 
<claim-text>predetermined intensity spectra for each of a plurality of said stages representing a respective intermediate construction for the stage, </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one intensity spectrum deriver located within said production line for obtaining intensity spectra of intermediate inputs, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator, for obtaining a closest match between said obtained intensity spectrum and any of said predetermined spectra, said router being operable to route said intermediate input to a stage corresponding to said closest matching spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each stage comprises an intensity spectrum deriver and has a predetermined intensity spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said intensity spectrum deriver comprises 
<claim-text>an illuminator for irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intensity detector for detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analyzer operatively associated with said intensity detector for analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength and converting said analyzed intensities into a frequency spectrum of the intensities spectrum, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a layer property determiner for determining, from said spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A production line router according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said intermediate input includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said analyzer comprises a Fourier transform calculator for producing said spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A wafer production history determiner for determining the production history of a semiconductor wafer product, the determiner comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of predetermined intensity spectra for semiconductor wafer products having completed respective stages of a multiple stage semiconductor wafer production process, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intensity spectrum deriver for obtaining an intensity spectrum of an incoming semiconductor wafer product, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator, for comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with each of said predetermined intensity spectra, to determine a closest match between said obtained spectrum and one of said predetermined spectra, said determiner inferring said production history as including the respective completed stage corresponding to said closest match predetermined spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The use of a spectrum obtained by reflecting multiple wavelength light from a plurality of points on a layered product, to determine a production history of said layered product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In a production line having a plurality of successive stages for construction of a product comprising at least one at least semi-transparent layer on a substrate, and routers for transferring partly constructed product between the stages such that each stage receives a respective predefined partly constructed product as its input, and having a predetermined intensity spectrum associated with at least one stage representing the respective part construction for the stage, a method comprising: 
<claim-text>obtaining intensity spectra of partly constructed products incoming to said stage, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing said obtained intensity spectra with said predetermined intensity spectrum, and thereby determining whether said incoming partly constructed product corresponds with said respective predefined part construction for the respective stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising indicating a routing error when said spectra do not match. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising interrupting operation of said production line in the event of indication of a routing error. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each stage comprises a plurality of production tools operating in parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising obtaining intensity spectra for incoming partly constructed products to each stage, each said stage having a predetermined intensity spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising comparing said obtained intensity spectrum with predetermined spectra of at least one other stage to reroute said product to said other stage if said spectra match. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said production line is a semiconductor wafer production line for producing a layered semiconductor wafer product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein obtaining said intensity spectrum comprises 
<claim-text>irradiating a part product at at least one point thereof with a multiple wavelength radiation source, </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting intensities within reflections of said source from said point, </claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing said intensities in terms of wavelength, thereby to produce a spectrum of intensities at respective wavelengths, </claim-text>
<claim-text>converting said spectrum of intensities into a frequency spectrum, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, from said frequency spectrum, layer properties of layers on said part product. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said property is one of a group comprising a thickness and a refractive index. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said part product includes at least one at least partly transparent layer and said reflections include reflections from an upper and a lower surface of said at least partly transparent layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A production line according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said converting comprises producing said spectrum by Fourier transform of said analyzed intensities.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002032A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
