<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000093A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000093A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000093</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10191047</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F41G001/467</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>033</class>
<subclass>265000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Archery bow sight</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301911</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marlow</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Larson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ogden</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BRIAN C. TRASK</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3601 EAST HERMES DRIVE</address-1>
<city>SALT LAKE CITY</city>
<state>UT</state>
<postalcode>84124</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An improved sight for an archery bow providing a mechanism operable to convert a rotational input to a purely translational output. The mechanism may be adapted simultaneously and uniformly to adjust the windage of a plurality of sight pins. In another embodiment, the mechanism may be operable to adjust a vertical position of an individual sight pin carrying a fiber optic pickup. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. 119(e) of the filing date of Provisional Application Serial No. 60/301,911, filed Jul. 2, 2001, for &ldquo;ARCHERY BOW SIGHT&rdquo;.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention pertains to sight assemblies for use with archery bows. It is particularly directed to such assemblies which utilize rotatable elements to adjust the vertical position of illuminated sight pins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. State of the Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Aiming sights of various designs are commonly used in the sport of archery. Such sights typically comprise an assembly, which includes a bracket supported by structure fixed to the handle riser of the bow. With the bow held in its normal position of use, its limbs are considered to be oriented approximately vertically. References in this disclosure to &ldquo;vertical&rdquo; or &ldquo;horizontal&rdquo; orientations are with reference to such vertical bow limbs. The sight bracket generally supports a plurality of vertically spaced sighting elements (often called &ldquo;pins&rdquo;), each of which extends approximately horizontally to terminate in an end (sometimes called a &ldquo;sighting bead&rdquo;) near a vertical sight plane. Each sight element corresponds to a distinct target distance, depending upon its precise vertical position along the sight plane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Various mechanisms have been relied upon to adjust the horizontal position of the sight plane or the sight beads. Such adjustments are advantageous to account for the influence of wind and/or the shooting idiosyncrasies of individuals, and are commonly referred to as &ldquo;windage adjustments.&rdquo; Similarly, various mechanisms have been utilized to adjust the vertical positions of the respective sight elements. Such adjustments are commonly referred to as &ldquo;distance adjustments.&rdquo; One class of mechanisms for providing distance adjustment capability mounts individual pins in an assembly which translates rotation of a knob into vertical linear motion, up or down. This arrangement is particularly advantageous, providing for infinite and stable adjustability superior to most other arrangements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Representative of this class is the sighting assembly disclosed by U.S. Pat. No. 4,449,303, the disclosure of which is incorporated as a portion of this disclosure. The sighting elements of that assembly comprise pins individually threaded into a central bore of a cylindrical carriage element. Each carriage element is adjustable up and down within a particular slot of a bracket in a rack-and-pinion type of engagement. The carriage element has a knob portion and a pinion portion. The pinion portion engages a rack element within the slot. Rotation of the knob is thus translated into vertical adjustment, without affecting the horizontal (windage) adjustment of the sighting bead. Windage adjustment is made by turning individual pins within their respective cylindrical elements. In this construction, the pins inherently rotate during any adjustment of either elevation or windage. Because the pins are cylindrical, this rotation is immaterial to the functioning of the sight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Both target shooting and hunting are frequently practiced under low light conditions in which visibility of the sight element becomes poor. There has thus evolved a variety of sight assemblies structured to gather ambient light to illuminate the sight beads. This light gathering function is generally performed by special plastic or glass elements. Notable among these light gathering/transmitting elements are fiber optic strands. U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,442,861; 5,201,124; 5,168,631 and 4,928,394, the disclosures of which are incorporated as a portion of this disclosure, identify a number of light gathering elements and sighting pin structures incorporating those elements. Incorporation of these elements in sight systems in which the pins rotate during either windage or distance adjustments has not been feasible, however, because of the necessity for the light gathering elements to remain in a fixed rotational orientation. This design constraint is particularly significant in the case of fiber optic strands. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> This invention provides a sight assembly for archery bows which is constructed to translate rotation of an adjustment knob into linear travel of a sighting pin, without rotating the pin. It is thereby feasible for the sighting pins to carry a light gathering element, including a fiber optic element. Preferred versions of the assembly provide for infinite windage adjustment of the sighting plane, also without rotating the sighting pins. Other embodiments provide a pin assembly wherein an adjustment knob is associated with a locking mechanism. In preferred arrangements, both the adjusting knob and the locking mechanism are structured for operation by a simple tool comprising an element of the sight assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> While this invention is described with primary focus upon rack and pinion arrangements, it is recognized that many alternative mechanical expedients are available to translate the rotation of an adjustment knob into linear motion of a sight pin. For example, a cylindrical element may be substituted for the pinion and a smooth slot may be substituted for the rack in the arrangements disclosed by the &apos;303 patent. Frictional engagement of these substituted elements provides the same translation of knob rotation to linear pin travel, but in a less positive fashion. The improvement of this invention is broadly applicable to any structure operative to provide linear vertical movement of a sight pin in response to rotational movement of an adjustment fixture, such as a screw or knob. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Similarly, the windage adjustment feature of this invention may be provided by various mechanical arrangements. A screw thread assembly is generally preferred because of its simplicity and ease of manufacture and assembly. Any other mechanism capable of adjusting the position of the pins of the assembly along the horizontal sight plane without rotating the individual sight pins could be utilized. Among such arrangements are rack and pinion assemblies, belt drives, chain drives, piston drives and various fluid drive assemblies. It is even feasible to utilize a manually operable telescopic boom arrangement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the invention, at least one mechanism is associated with the sight and operable to convert a rotatational user input into a purely translational output operable to adjust a component of the sight. A first preferred such mechanism is a windage adjustment mechanism operable simultaneously and uniformly to effect a horizontal adjustment of a plurality of sight pins. A second preferred such mechanism is an elevation adjustment mechanism operable to effect a vertical adjustment of at least one sight pin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Preferred mechanisms generally include: a knob element adapted to receive rotational input from a user; a slide member configured and arranged in harmony with holding structure to resist rotation of the slide member and permit translational movement of the slide member with respect to the holding structure; and linkage structure between the knob and the slide member, with the linkage structure being operable to move the slide member responsive to rotation of the knob. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An operable elevation adjustment mechanism can include a plurality of sight pins carried on a base structure that is adapted for attachment, at a plurality of vertically disposed positions, to structure carried by a support arm of the sight assembly whereby to permit a simultaneous and uniform displacement of the pins in a vertical direction. One preferred elevation mechanism includes a pinion engaging a rack, with the pinion being operated by a driven interface adapted to receive a rotational driving input from a user effective to change a vertical position of a sight pin with respect to the sight. Since the sight pins do not rotate during their adjustment in elevation, it is feasible to dispose a light gathering element in association with a sight pin for purely vertical translation between first and second elevations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It generally is desirable also to include a lock adapted to resist changes in the vertical position of the pin in an elevation mechanism. Such a lock can be operated by a lock interface that is adapted to receive rotational locking and unlocking input from a user. A convenient tool to make adjustments to a sight includes a wrench adapted on a first end to apply a rotational input to a lock interface. Ideally, the wrench will be adapted on a second end to apply a rotational input to a driven interface to effect an adjustment of a sight component. Some sights further include storage structure adapted to hold such a wrench in a snap-fit engagement.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the drawings, which illustrate what are currently regarded as the best modes for carrying out the invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of a bow sight assembly of this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of a sight pin windage subassembly of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of the subassembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in association with a mounting sub assembly of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of a sight pin bracket assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a pictorial partially exploded view of the bracket assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exploded view of a sight pin assembly of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an exploded view of an sight pin bracket and sight pin assembly from an alternative embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a plan view of a the bracket portion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and a component of the sight pin assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an exploded view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a plan view of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> in partially assembled condition, with the fiber optic component and its support detached; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a view in perspective of an elevation adjustment mechanism and an adjustment tool; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a sectional view on keeper structure to hold an adjustment tool; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a view in perspective of alternative keeper structure to hold an adjustment tool; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a support element component of a sight; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a view in section through a support element and a windage control housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a peg; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a plan view of an alternative bracket configured for simultaneous vertical adjustment of a plurality of sight pin assemblies.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> One preferred sight assembly, generally <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, illustrated by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, includes a mounting structure, generally <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, constructed and arranged appropriately to attach the sight assembly <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to the handle riser of an archery bow (not shown.) A plurality of sight pin assemblies, generally <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, typically are carried on a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> at the distal end of a boom assembly, generally <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, extending in cantilever fashion from the mounting structure <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A sight window <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is defined by a cage element <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> carried by the bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The cage element <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be separate parts or integral. While a cage element <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> generally is desired to protect one or more pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> from incidental damage, a cage <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is not essential for operation of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the illustrated mounting structure <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> includes a fixture <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> adapted for connection to a handle riser (not shown), and an upstanding support element <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> detachably connectable to the fixture <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. In practice, these elements may be integral. As illustrated, the proximal end of the boom <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> carries a windage adjustment knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> of a windage adjustment mechanism, generally <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Turning the knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> effects a linear movement (extension or retraction, depending upon direction of rotation of knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) of a peg component <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> from a housing component <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> of the boom assembly <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, certain details of construction of a mechanism operable to convert a user&apos;s rotational input to a pure translational output to adjust a component of a sight <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> will be discussed. Peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> carries one or more flat surfaces <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> for engagement with one or more interior surfaces of a bore, generally <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, passing through support element <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. Peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> therefore is structured in harmony with bore <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to resist rotation of peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, and also to permit a pure translation of peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> relative to support <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A threaded shaft <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> interfaces in engagement with internal threads aligned with an axis of peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Shaft <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and internal threads in peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> are one version of a linkage system operable to move peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> responsive to a user&apos;s rotational input onto knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Such a cooperating interface between such threaded and similarly acting surfaces can be described as an inclined plane interface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a sight cage element <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> to shield, or protect, a plurality of sight pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> installed on bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime;. As illustrated, cage <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is integral with bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime;. Cage element <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> is structured to provide a deeper sight window <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> compared to cage element <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A deeper window <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can provide shade on sight pins <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> to prevent glare when shooting a bow outside. More secure protection is also provided by a deeper cage <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> further to resist incidental contact induced damage to light gathering elements associated with one or more of pins <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference> illustrate certain components of one embodiment of a sight assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A threaded stud <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> holdingly passes through the base of sight pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> and a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for engagement with knurled nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. Structure, generally <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, on the base of pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> is adapted to slide, and to resist rotation of pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>, in engagement with a slot through the bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime;. In the illustrated embodiment <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>, structure <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> includes flat surfaces configured in harmony with sides of slot structure through bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime; to permit only pure translational movement of a pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> as an output consequential to a user&apos;s adjusting input. A washer <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and elevation adjustment structure, generally <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>, are trapped by nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> on an opposite side of bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime; from pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Washer <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> may also carry alignment structure to resist rotation of washer <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> as the elevation of a pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> is changed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Illustrated elevation structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> includes a pinion gear adapted to engage a rack formed in one side of a slot through a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&prime;. A user can apply a rotational input to elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> to effect a purely translational vertical adjustment of sight pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a light gathering element, such as fiber strand <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> carried by pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>, will maintain a uniform orientation, without rotating, as the pin&apos;s elevation changes. Undesired motion of the sight pin assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be restrained by cinching nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> snugly into engagement against elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> to cause a friction engagement operable to resist rotation of structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> and resulting displacement of assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> effectively acts as part of a locking arrangement to resist motion of a sight pin assembly on a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates an additional alternative embodiment of structure that may be included in a sight pin assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An alternative base structure, generally <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, supportingly carries a fiber optic sight structure (not illustrated). Base <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is mounted on bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> in a similar fashion to the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. Threaded post <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> passes through a slot <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> through bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, and is retained by nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. It is currently preferred to provide an indicator structure, such as the arrow-shaped protrusion, generally <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, to provide an indication for installed sight position to an archer. In use of the indicator, an archer may sight in a pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> for a certain distance, then make a mark on bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> at the current location of arrow <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. Alignment of a mark, generally <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and an arrow <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. In the event the sight assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is knocked out of such position in the field, the archer may confidently return the sight pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> to the sighted-in position by aligning the arrow <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and the drawn indicating line <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates an installed operating orientation between a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and elevation adjusting structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. Teeth on pinion gear <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> engage gear teeth of rack <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> in a rack and pinion interaction. Rotation of elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> causes a change in vertical position of elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> along slot <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> through bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A sight post <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> assembled onto structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> would similarly translate in a vertical direction, either up or down, depending upon direction of rotation of structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. Side walls of slot <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are convenient structure operable in harmony with alignment structure <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to resist rotation of a pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> during an elevation adjustment of the pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. A light gathering element carried on pin <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> therefore undergoes pure translational displacement effected by a user&apos;s rotational input to elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference> further illustrate details of assembly for one embodiment of a sight pin assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and as also illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. A distal end of fiber <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> is oriented and held by a distal end of post <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> to provide an illuminated spot to an archer for use as an aiming point. Pin support <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> carries fiber optic support element or post <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> without rotation as the elevation of support <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is changed with respect to bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Correspondingly, fiber element <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, carried by post <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, is displaced vertically, up or down, without rotating, as the post <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> is displaced under influence of elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> A tool, generally <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, can be helpful to assist in adjusting small components of a mechanism to effect a positional adjustment of components of a sight assembly, such as assembly <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. One end <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of illustrated tool <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> carries a splined bore <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> configured in harmony with splined shaft section <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> of elevation adjustment structure <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. Splined socket <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight> is sufficiently deep to receive nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and still engage surface <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. Splined shaft section <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> may be characterized as an embodiment of a driven interface to receive rotational input from a user. An oposite end <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of tool <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> carries a faceted bore <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> configured to receive nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. Facets on nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> may be considered as forming an embodiment of a lock interface to receive rotational locking and unlocking input from a user to fix a sight pin assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> at a desired position. Of course, any mutually engageable surfaces between a tool and a component forming a driven or locking interface would be workable, including surfaces providing structural interferences, or even simple frictional interaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> When a tool <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is provided for use with a sight assembly, it is advantageous also to provide a way to store the tool <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> for quiet transportation, and ready access for the user. One such storage structure, generally <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> grips reduced diameter shaft section <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> in a snap-fit engagement between arm <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> and arm <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Such arms <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be integral to sight structure, such as the support arm <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, or may be installed at any other convenient location. One storage structure, generally <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, is capable of installation on a bracket, bow handle or riser, or any other convenient component. Storage structure <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> may be bonded to a surface, or mechanically fastened, such as through hole <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Resilient arms <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> capture shaft section <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> of tool <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in bore <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> for quiet transportation, and convenient, removable retention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> It is generally preferred to provide a way to fix a sight component at a sighted-in position. Locking arrangements typically are included in both elevation and windage adjusting mechanisms. Nut <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> clamps a vertical, or elevation adjusting mechanism <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> to form a friction lock for a sight pin assembly <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> at a desired position in a slot <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Similarly, a locking bolt, generally <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, forms a lock interface for windage adjustment mechanism <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Rotation of bolt <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> in a tightening direction squeezes arm <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> toward arm <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>, reduces a spacing <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> between the arms, and reduces a size of bore <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. A peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> journaled in bore <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> can therefore be clamped, or fixed, at a desired position. Peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> may be marked to indicate a known, sighted-in, position, in similar fashion to making the indicator mark <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. A surface edge of bracket <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> can operate as a workable reference structure for such a mark on peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> A windage adjustment mechanism <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is operable to make a global adjustment of all installed sight pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> at the same time. Such pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> carried on a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> desirably are moved in a horizontal direction by precisely the same amount as a windage mechanism <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is adjusted. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16, a</cross-reference> windage mechanism <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may include a housing <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, threaded shaft <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, and a control knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Rotation of knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> correspondingly rotates threaded shaft <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> inside threaded bore <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> of peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> therefore slides in, or out, transversely through bore <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> in support bracket <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, depending upon direction of rotation of knob <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> carried at distal end <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> of peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> therefore effects a global horizontal, or transverse, displacement of its mounted sight pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> A similar global change in elevation of sight pin assemblies <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can be made on certain embodiments of the invention. As illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a dowel <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> further may be included on a peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Such a dowel may index with a hole <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> in a bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&Prime;. The peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> may be affixed to the bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&Prime; by a fastener passing through a second hole <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> for engagement with bore <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>. A global change in elevation of a plurality of sight pin assemblies may be accomplished by attaching the peg <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> at a different indexed location on bracket <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in particular with reference to certain illustrated embodiments, such is not intended to limit the scope of the invention. The present invention may be embodied in other specific forms without departing from its spirit or essential characteristics. The described embodiments are to be considered in all respects only as illustrative and not restrictive. The scope of the invention is, therefore, indicated by the appended claims rather than by the foregoing description. All changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are to be embraced within their scope. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In an archery bow sight of the type in which a sight pin is included in a pin assembly, mounted within a slot in a bracket, as a mechanism structured and arranged such that an elevation of the sight pin is adjusted by turning elevation adjustment structure of the sight pin assembly either clockwise or counterclockwise, the improvement comprising: 
<claim-text>mounting a light gathering element in association with said sight pin assembly through linkage constructed and arranged to hold said element in a fixed rotational position without regard to rotation of said elevation adjustment structure; whereby: 
<claim-text>said light gathering element travels vertically with said sight pin proximate a sight plane. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sight pin assembly includes a pinion member, a side edge of said slot is fashioned as a rack member, and said pinion member and said rack member are mutually arranged to adjust the elevation of said sight pin through a rack and pinion interaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of sight pins disposed in association with said bracket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said bracket is configured and arranged in harmony with structure carried by a support arm for attachment of said bracket in a plurality of vertical positions with respect to said support arm, whereby moving said bracket between two such vertical positions simultaneously effects a corresponding uniform displacement on all said sight pins. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a windage adjustment mechanism including a peg extending from said bracket and reciprocally mounted within a housing carried by said support arm, said housing further containing a mechanism constructed and arranged to couple with said peg such that rotation of a knob associated with said housing effects linear extension or retraction of said peg with respect to said housing, depending upon a direction of rotation of said knob. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In an archery bow sight of the type in which a plurality of sight pins are included in a plurality of pin assemblies mounted within one or more slots in a bracket by structure arranged such that the elevation of the sight pins are individually adjustable, the improvement comprising: 
<claim-text>mounting said bracket to an archery bow by means of a mounting assembly including a support arm having a distal end carrying a windage adjustment mechanism including a peg extending from said bracket and reciprocally mounted within a housing at said distal end, said housing further containing a mechanism constructed and arranged to couple with said peg such that rotation of a knob associated with said housing is translated to effect a linear extension or retraction of said peg with respect to said housing and thereby to effect a corresponding horizontal movement of all said pins, depending upon a direction of rotation of said knob. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said mechanism includes an inclined plane interface between a first component associated with said peg and a second component associated with said knob. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said inclined plane interface is provided by an internal threaded surface of said peg interacting with the external threads of a shaft driven by said knob. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said inclined plane interface is provided by an external threaded surface of said peg interacting with the internal threads of a shaft driven by said knob. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The improvement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said inclined plane interface is provided by an external surface of said peg adapted for interacting with the external threads carried by a shaft driven by said knob. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In an improved sight for an archery bow, the improvement comprising: 
<claim-text>a mechanism associated with said sight and operable to convert a rotatational user input into a purely translational output operable to adjust a component of said sight. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said mechanism comprises a windage adjustment mechanism operable simultaneously and uniformly to effect a horizontal adjustment of a plurality of sight pins. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said plurality of pins are carried on a base structure adapted for attachment, at a plurality of vertically disposed positions, to structure carried by a support arm of said sight whereby to permit a simultaneous and uniform displacement of said pins in a vertical direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said mechanism comprises an elevation adjustment mechanism operable to effect a vertical adjustment of a sight pin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said elevation mechanism comprises a pinion engaging a rack, said pinion being operated by a driven interface adapted to receive a rotational driving input from a user effective to change a vertical position of said pin with respect to said sight. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said elevation mechanism further comprises a lock adapted to resist changes in said vertical position of said pin, said lock being operated by a lock interface that is adapted to receive rotational locking and unlocking input from a user. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, in combination with a wrench adapted on a first end to apply a rotational input to said driven interface, and adapted on a second end to apply a rotational input to said lock interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said sight further comprises storage structure adapted to hold said wrench in a snap-fit engagement. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a light gathering element disposed in association with said sight pin for purely vertical translation between first and second elevations. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The sight of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said mechanism comprising: 
<claim-text>a knob element adapted to receive rotational input from a user; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide member configured and arranged in harmony with holding structure to resist rotation of said slide member and to permit translational movement of said slide member with respect to said holding structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>linkage structure between said knob and said slide member, said linkage structure being operable to move said slide member responsive to rotation of said knob.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000093A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
