<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000478A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000478A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000478</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178402</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020624</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A01K001/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A01K005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A01K039/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>119</class>
<subclass>061000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Pet accessories</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60300920</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kris</given-name>
<family-name>Lynch</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brightwaters</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KEUSEY, TUTUNJIAN &amp; BITETTO, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>14 VANDERVENTER AVENUE, SUITE 128</address-1>
<city>PORT WASHINGTON</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>11050</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A device for indicating the presence of an electrical path on a pet accessory includes a first contact disposed on a probe, and a second contact disposed in a spaced apart arrangement relative to the first contact. An activation device is responsive to the presence of an electrical path or lack thereof between the first and second contacts. The activation device provides an indication of the state of the electrical path between the first and second contacts. The device preferably includes a pet dish and the probe extends into the dish to indicate a desired level for liquid in the dish, and the indication of state is performed by at least one of an audio message, a visual effect and a mechanical motion. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATION DATA </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present disclosure claims priority to U.S. provisional application serial No. 60/300,920 filed on Jun. 28, 2001, which is hereby incorporated by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A portion of the disclosure of this patent document contains material, which is subject to copyright protection. The copyright owner has no objection to the facsimile reproduction by anyone of this patent document or the patent disclosure, as it appears in the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office patent file or records, but otherwise reserves all copyrights whatsoever. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This disclosure relates to pet accessories, and more particularly, to pet communication devices, leashes and pet toys. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> While pets may be trained to obey commands given by humans, it is difficult at times for pets to clearly communicate with humans to express their needs. While some pets are trained to ring a bell or scratch a door when it is time to go out, a need exists for better ways to clearly indicate a pets needs to humans. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Pets do not have an understanding of safety issues. For example, being on a dark road or crossing a busy street is very dangerous for pets since the same danger perceived by humans is not understood by the pet. Therefore, alerting humans of the pet&apos;s presence alone or with their owner on, for example, a roadway is advantageous. In this way, humans will be made aware of dangerous conditions for pets and take appropriate action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Pets do not understand their nutritional needs. Vitamins and dietary supplements are often administered to pets by hiding these supplements in their food. The pets often detect these supplements and avoid eating the food. Therefore, a need exists for alternate ways of supplying nutritional supplements. These and other pet needs will be described in greater detail below along with pet accessories, which address these needs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides pet accessories, which communicate to humans, the needs of their pets. In one embodiment, a combination wind blocker and an indicator that the pet must go out is provided. In another embodiment, a device for determining the level of liquid in a pet dish is provided, which alerts people in the vicinity that the liquid levels are low. In still other embodiments, pet or human leashes are provided with a plurality of accessories. For example, a combination leash and radio is provided. Other leashes include powered lights and/or reflectors. The powered lights may include optical fibers woven into the leash. The reflectors may include heat stamped designs stamped onto the material of the leash. Other devices disclosed herein include teether designs, which include edible or ingestible portions. The present invention will now be described in greater detail with reference to illustrative examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A device for indicating the presence of an electrical path on a pet accessory includes a first contact disposed on a probe, and a second contact disposed in a spaced apart arrangement relative to the first contact. An activation device is responsive to the presence of an electrical path or lack thereof between the first and second contacts. The activation device provides an indication of the state of the electrical path between the first and second contacts. The device preferably includes a pet dish and the probe extends into the dish to indicate a desired level for liquid in the dish, and the indication of state is performed by at least one of an audio message, a visual effect and a mechanical motion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A liquid level indicator for a vessel, includes a probe extending to a first depth in the vessel. A first contact is disposed on the probe, wherein one at least one contact is located at the first depth such that when the vessel is filled with a liquid, an electrical connection is made between the first contact and a second contact until a level of the liquid falls below the first depth. An activation device is includes and provides an action when the level of liquid has fallen below the first depth. The vessel preferably includes a pet dish and a housing may include a shape of an animal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A pet warning device, includes an elongated base unit configured and dimensioned to fit at a base of a doorway so as to prevent a draft. A deformable enclosure is removably attached to the base, and a switching device is disposed within the enclosure housing which permits a pet to depress the enclosure to trigger a warning indicator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A restraining device, such as a belt or strap, includes a base material, an illuminating feature disposed in or on the base material, and an adjustment mechanism to adjust a fit of the fabric to conform to a wearer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A chew toy includes a polymer matrix formed into a shape, one or more holes or divots formed in the matrix and at least one of a nutritional supplement, medication, and flavoring provided in the holes or divots. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of illustrative embodiments thereof, which is to be read in connection with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> This disclosure will present in detail the following description of preferred embodiments with reference to the following figures wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a combination pet indicator and wind blocker showing partially removed sections to show inner materials in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of a pad portion of the combination device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> show an illustrative script for audio responses of the combination device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a liquid level indicator in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing a circuit for the liquid level indicator of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> show an illustrative script for audio responses of the combination device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> depicts an illustrative teether having edible portions inserted or attached thereto in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> depicts four styles of collars/leashes (also, e.g., harnesses or restraining devices) having highly reflective material formed in a shape and heat-seal stamped onto the collar/leash material in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-C depict the formation of shapes, e.g., dots, to be stamped onto the collars/leashes as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> depicts three styles of collars/leashes having highly reflective ink formed in a shape and showing a container device for transporting objects in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows the container device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> depicts a collar/leash having optical fibers for transmitting light integrated therein and showing a control unit for powering the fiber optic lights in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a printed wiring board of the control unit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a collar and a leash having a control unit/radio (or other device) attached thereto in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> shows another view of the control unit/radio (or other device) in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> depicts a collar/leash having optical fibers for transmitting light along side of the collar/leash and showing a control unit for powering the fiber optic lights in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> depicts a collar/leash having light emitting diodes (LEDs) for transmitting light from within the collar/leash in different selectable sequences and durations and showing a control unit for powering the LEDs in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides pet accessories, which communicate to humans, the needs of their pets. In one embodiment, a combination wind blocker/indicator that the pet must go out is provided. In another embodiment, a device for determining the level of liquid in a pet dish is provided, which alerts people in the vicinity that the liquid levels are low. In still other embodiments, pet or human leashes, collars, cuffs or straps are provided with a plurality of accessories. For example, a combination leash and radio is provided. Other leashes include powered lights and/or reflectors. The powered lights may include optical fibers woven into the leash. The reflectors may include heat stamped designs stamped onto the material of the leash. Other devices disclosed herein include teether designs, which may include edible portions. These edible portions may include nutritional supplements or medications for the pet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The present invention will now be described in greater detail with reference to illustrative examples. It is to be understood that the present invention is not limited to the illustrative examples and may be employed with other configurations within the scope and spirit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Referring now in specific detail to the drawings in which like reference numerals identify similar or identical elements throughout the several views, and initially to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> pet reminder device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> preferably includes a soft flexible outer surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes at least one elongated portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Elongated portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may include a height of a few inches and a length of about 3 feet to be suitable as, for example, a wind/draft blocker at the base of a door <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Other dimensions are also contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes weighted portions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which may include a non-skid material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, such as rubber, to prevent device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being easily dragged. Alternately, device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may have its weight distributed throughout, and material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be continuous on elongated portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Weighted portions <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may include materials <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, such as polyethylene, or any other material, which provides weight to device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> without endangering a pet&apos;s health if ingested. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Elongated portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> preferably is filled with insulation material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (e.g., polyester, etc.). Insulation material <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> prevents heat transfer from a dwelling or building from escaping/entering under a doorway when device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is employed as a wind/draft blocker. Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include an ornamental portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Ornamental portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may include a dog&apos;s head, a cat&apos;s head, likenesses of famous characters, other animal or human forms, etc. Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> preferably includes a washable surface and may include different textures, such as a smooth texture (e.g., vinyl), a furry texture, etc. Other portions of device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be ornamented as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provides an attachment <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to a pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Attachment <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> between portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may include arrangements, such as a hook and loop arrangement (e.g., VELCRO&reg;), magnetic connections, mechanical connection (e.g., a zipper), etc. Pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes circuitry and mechanical switches, which can be activated by a pet to indicate that it is time for the pet to go out or indicate other pet needs or emotions. In an alternate embodiment, pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is permanently fixed to portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. However, having pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> detachable permits surface washing and/or easier maintenance of pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In addition, the use of pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be desired without elongated portions <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or elongated portions <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may include a loop <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> so that device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be conveniently hung on a doorknob while the pet is being walked, etc. Activation of pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is completed by pressing one or more switches included therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may also be employed as a wind blocker alone, with or without pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may include lettering <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> thereon. Lettering <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may include a pet&apos;s name, a saying or any other expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, an exploded view of pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is shown in accordance with the present invention. Pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> preferably includes an outer surface or case <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Case <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> preferably includes a machine washable fabric or a durable surface washable material. Pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a board <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which includes a plurality of switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are attached on the underside of board <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>). Board <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is rotatably connected to a fulcrum <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> such that a simple teeter-totter effect is provided so that when a pet steps on pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> a mechanical advantage is gained to activate one or more switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In other words, no matter where the pet steps on pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> the top balance piece will tilt and/or pivot (like a teeter-totter) and activate one or more of switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may include contact switches, which are biased in the open position. When switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are closed a sound chip <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> on circuit card <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is activated to indicate that the pet wishes to go out or to communicate other needs or emotions of the pet. A speaker <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> (e.g., a 29 mm speaker) is employed to provide loud and clear sound in accordance with sound chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A power source <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> may include batteries or the ability to be plugged into a wall outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the activated sound recorded in chip is a random selection of originally recorded voice phrases from an originally programmed chip. Alternately, custom-made sound chips may be provided or the user may also program the recordings. Chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may include a random combination of phrases (see, e.g., phrases <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Combinations A-K as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> may be randomly selected by chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> when activated by closing one or more switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Pad <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes an on/off switch <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to turn pad on/off. Alternate embodiments include lights or mechanical motion devices, which are activated by switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in accordance with the pet&apos;s triggering switches <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, an illustrative flow chart for activation of chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is shown. After activation in block <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, combination A is played by chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, followed by one of combinations B-K. The combinations B-K are randomly selected in chip <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. After a delay, e.g., 5 seconds, one of phrases <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) is played in block <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, frequency of occurrence of phrases may be predetermined (by percentage chance or otherwise) or randomly selected. In block <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the unit waits for the next activation and returns to block <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> when activated. Many other combinations, times, phrases and sequences are contemplated and would be useful in accordance with the present invention. These or other phrases and combinations may be played randomly or in a predetermined order. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Another way of communication by a pet may include indicating when a water dish needs to be filled. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> cross-sectional view of a liquid level indicator device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is shown in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. A pet dish wall <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> has liquid level indicator device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> attached thereto. Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be integrally formed with dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> or attached to dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> by a plurality of different attachment mechanisms. These mechanisms may include mechanical snaps, clips, screws, rivets, magnetic pads (for steel or iron dishes), glue, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is detachable from dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may include clasps or hooks <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> which are adapted to clip over a rim of dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and feet <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> which contact a side of dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to provide attachment of device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Clasps <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> may provide a force against dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to increase frictional forces and increase the stability of the attachment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a probe portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, which extends over the rim of dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to provide further stability if in contact with dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> includes contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which sense the level of water or liquid <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> in dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, liquid <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> in dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> provides a conductive path, which closes a circuit in device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. When liquid <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> drops below contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, the circuit is opened and a sound chip or light in device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is activated to indicate that more liquid needs to be added to dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, preferably including a plastic or water-resistant material and is sealed by gaskets or other water excluding devices. In one embodiment, an injection molded ABS and/or PVC housing <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is provided. Contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be insert molded to insert stainless steel or other compatible wire through probe portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> allowing at least two small and inconspicuous contacts to remain exposed. Contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be plated or coated with conductive materials to prevent corrosion. For example, contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be gold plated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a sound module chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) with a recorded voice(s) which gives reminders when there is a lack of water or liquid in dish <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Alternately, reminders may be given when the dish is full of liquid, empty or both. The programming of chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) permits a random selection of the sayings, expressions or sounds. In one embodiment, device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> will activate one saying for example, then progress to a next saying in, say, 5 minutes if no water is added, then again in 10 minutes, then again in 15 minutes, then the unit will shut off. Other times and sequences are also contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be employed as a feedback unit for detecting a level of water in a dish. Device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may be attached to a water source and permit water to fill a dish by opening a valve <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to permit water flow when a low level of water is detected. Valve <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is closed when water is replenished. Water may be added either manually or by an automatic release. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Another device <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> may be activated upon a connection or lack of connection between contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Device <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> may be a spinner, a light, a container with a door that opens or closes based on the state of the contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (e.g., connected or not connected) or any other audio, visual or mechanical motion device. In one embodiment, a connection maybe made between contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> by a pet&apos;s saliva, i.e., by licking the contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. This may trigger, e.g., a container of food to open, water to be released to fill the dish, or any other mechanical motion, audio or visual effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, an illustrative circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> is shown for implementing device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Contacts <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are shown as a switch <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. When switch <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is open, chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is activated which creates and audio sequences which is played over speaker <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, e.g., a 27 mm speaker. A valve switch or solenoid <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> may be included which is activated when switch is opened to provide water and closed when switch is closed. A battery or other energy source <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is included for powering circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. An additional on/off switch can be provided to deactivate circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. Other devices <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> or mechanical motions may be activated in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, sound chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> can provide a plurality of different responses for device <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> show illustrative responses for one embodiment of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows phrases <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> (for dogs) and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> (for cats). Phrases <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> (and/or <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A) maybe randomly combined using chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to provide combinations A-L. These audio responses are triggered in the manner described above. Other responses, such as visual responses or mechanical motions may also be employed. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows an illustrative flow chart for implementing chip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the present invention may be employed for any pet, for example, dogs, cats, hamsters, birds, reptiles, rabbits, etc. Larger units can be added to water troths of farm animals, etc. Smaller units may remind owners to add water manually or by automatic water release into a fish tank as well. Electrical contact or lack thereof of switch <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> may be employed be trigger food release, water release or other effects, such as activation of a spinner, raising a flag, opening a container, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is shown in accordance with the present invention. Teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes bumps <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> of insert-molded material and/or mixture of materials to create specific flavor or scents, which are pleasing to pets. For example, bumps <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may include scented or flavored plastics, food or pet treats, which are molded into teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In addition, teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may include edible sections <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> preferably includes a soft durometer material (matrix), e.g., polyurethane, such as, injection molded virgin polyurethane, for massaging of the gums of newly cutting teeth of dogs, for example. With continual play the material and texture thereof can help keep teeth clean and eliminate tartar buildup in dogs. Bumps or divots <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and sections <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be insert molded into teether <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or attached after molding. Bumps <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may include nutritional supplements or medication. Bumps <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be manually added to teether/chew toy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> or molded directly into toy <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, reflective restraining devices <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> are shown. Devices <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may be employed as collars, leashes, or other restraints to be used on animals or humans. Devices <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may include, e.g., nylon, cotton, leather and/or a polyester material decorated with multi-colored highly reflective materials. The highly reflective material may be patterned into dots <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> or other shapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the restraining devices as described herein as collars or leashes also include harnesses, straps, (e.g., bra straps), belts or other materials which may be worn on a human or pet. In addition, the collars, leashes, restraining devices, etc. as described herein also include attachments or extenders for conventional restraining devices, i.e., belt extenders, strap extensions or accessories that attache to belts, collars, leashes, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-C, reflective material <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is preferably manufactured in sheets of tinted clear material then backed by a solid opaque white vinyl <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Special and unique shapes and designs may then be silk screened for added detail and heat die-cut from these sheets to cause the edges to seal together (see top view of dot <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference>). The heat cut may also be designed to not cut all the way through, thus creating recessed areas <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> within the created shape to form additional details of such shape (See e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11C</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A-C, die cut shapes or dots <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> are then applied to the nylon, cotton, leather or polyester materials <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> of leash by heat stamping and sealing in place. With the use of high temperature, the vinyl will melt and seal onto the desired material. The reflectivity of the material (e.g., reflective PVC) <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> can be seen up to 500 ft when hit with a beam of light from oncoming cars, etc. Leashes <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> may include a dog tag <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and/or a dog tag reflector <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. Dog tag <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and reflector <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> may include a metal (stainless steel, or copper with stainless steel plating) and have pressure stamped and etched wordings, such as, the name of a company, etc. or symbols, such a company logo. Reflector <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> may be silk-screened with graphics including but not limited to the company logo, etc. Reflector <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> maybe included in combination with any restraining device as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, reflective restraining devices <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, such as collars, leashes to be used on animals, humans, etc. includes nylon and/or polyester material belts <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> decorated with reflective inks in accordance with the present invention. Ink <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is stamped or silk-screened onto belt <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Ink <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, which may include highly reflective ink available commercially from 3M&trade; or other suppliers, is applied to desired fabrics by a cylindrical roller and pressure stamping process. These inks include materials visible up to 700 ft when hit with a beam of light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference>, a closure unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> preferably includes a soft durometer (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) rotational molded unit that has a clean cut or slit <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> across about &frac13; of the bottom or back. When the unit is squeezed, the pressure opens the cut allowing the consumer to store change, coins or other small essentials inside unit. The leashes of the present invention may include unit <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> attached to the leash to provide a storage area. The illustrative embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 19 and 20</cross-reference> show a fire hydrant, but any shaped closure may be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, light-up restraining devices <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> or accessories such as collars or leashes to be used on animals or humans are shown. Although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows leash <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> only with simple reflective embroidered stars, it should be noted that outer surface of leash/collar may be decorated with numerous materials to create graphics for added aesthetics and reflectivity (including but not limited to silk screen glow-in-the-dark material, reflective PVC, embroidered with reflective threads etc.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> A power source/control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is provided to activate light emitting diodes <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> in leash/collar <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, 0.5 mm thick fiber optic strands are passed through material of leash to create patterns, graphics or words. Fibers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> permit each star <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> to light up. The fiber is then stitched into place on the back of the material of leash <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. The leash material may include nylon, polyester etc., an additional sheet of leash material is placed over the exposed fibers, and the edges are permanently stitched closed. Control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is preferably made of injection molded ABS or other durable housing material and is permanently secured to the leash/collar etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> A metal clasp <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and a buckle (not shown), &ldquo;d&rdquo; ring (dog snap) <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and grommeted buckle holes (not shown) are provided. As is known in the art, these features are provided on all leashes/collars. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15, a</cross-reference> schematic diagram is shown for a control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. A programmed chip <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> permits the consumer to control fiber lights to blink on/off at different time intervals or sequences, e.g., 0.5 sec intervals lighting the fiber optic throughout the length of the collar/leash or other designed unit. An on/off switch <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight> is also provided to power control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and its functions by turning a power source <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> on or off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The bundle of fibers are then inserted into control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, which houses batteries <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, a printed circuit board (PCB) <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, integrated circuit <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> for driving the LEDs, and super bright LEDs <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> for illuminating the bundle of fibers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> may also include a flashlight <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>. Flashlight <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> remains attached to collar/leash and provides visibility, for example, from up to 750 feet away. Control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> may include multiple LEDs for different bundles of fibers (see also, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>). Chip <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> permits the consumer to turn on the flashlight <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> alone or simultaneously with the other LED&apos;s, which can blink on/off, for example, in intervals, lighting the fiber optic through the length of the collar/leash or other designed unit. This and other functions may be provided by employing a switch <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> may include an AM/FM radio <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> or other electronic device. Radio <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> may be included instead of or in addition to blinking lights, flashlight and/or LEDS. Radio or device <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> may be included on any leash of the present disclosure or as an accessory to conventional leashes and collars. Radio <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> and light/LEDs may be selected individually or used together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference>, radio <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> is shown on a leash <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. Radio <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> may include a bone shaped housing, although any other suitable shapes are also contemplated. Radio <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> includes controls <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight>, which may include a tuner/scanner, volume control and off and on switches. Radio <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> includes an &ldquo;on&rdquo; light <highlight><bold>513</bold></highlight> and a speaker <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>. The controls <highlight><bold>511</bold></highlight> preferably include a low profile to prevent unintended activation of controls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Additional entertainment and/or health features may be applied to any or all of the leashes/collars described herein. For added value and interactivity between pet and owner, the following devices may be incorporated into control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, including but not limited to AM/FM radio, digital FM, MP3 player, pedometer, cell phone, personal digital assistant (PDA), calorie meter, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, an alternate embodiment of restraining device (e.g., leash, collar, strap, harness belt, etc.) <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is shown. It should be noted that the outer surface of leash/collar <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be decorated with graphics for added aesthetics and reflectivity, e.g., silk screen glow in dark material, embroidered with reflective threads, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Leash <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> includes a control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, which provides light to one or more clear extruded tubes <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> of PVC or equivalent materials, which are attached to edges of the collar/leash <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. Multi-strands of optical fibers <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> are inserted into tubes <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, different styles of fiber optics maybe used and cut in lengths increasing by approximately, e.g., 2&Prime; so that when placed inside tubes <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, many lights will appear down the length of each tube <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, a notched style fiber may be employed. Notched style fiber may be, for example, approximately 1 mm in diameter. The notched fiber includes notches <highlight><bold>603</bold></highlight> on an angle down the length of the fiber. This permits the light in the fiber to refract from the numerous angled cuts as well as from the tip of the fiber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, another embodiment of the present invention includes a blinking lights leash/collar <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight>. One or more bright LED&apos;s <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> are placed throughout leash/collar <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> and controlled through a control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. LED&apos;s are exposed throughout the material of leash/collar and may be surrounded by a metal finishing grommet. Chip <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> in control unit <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>) allows a user to control the blinking sequence of the LEDs e.g., fast blink on/off 0.5 sec, slow blink on/off 1 sec, chasing sequence, etc. LEDs <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> are visible up to mile. Control unit <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> for the embodiment of the present invention, which employs LEDs, powers LEDs <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> by including conductive wires to power LEDS <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> instead of optical fibers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. LEDs <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> are lit in the same way as LEDs <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Having described preferred embodiments for pet or human accessories (which are intended to be illustrative and not limiting), it is noted that modifications and variations can be made by persons skilled in the art in light of the above teachings. It is therefore to be understood that changes maybe made in the particular embodiments of the invention disclosed which are within the scope and spirit of the invention as outlined by the appended claims. Having thus described the invention with the details and particularity required by the patent laws, what is claimed and desired protected by Letters Patent is set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A device for indicating the presence of an electrical path on a pet accessory, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first contact disposed on a probe; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second contact disposed in a spaced apart arrangement relative to the first contact; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an activation device responsive to the presence of an electrical path or lack thereof between the first and second contacts, the activation device providing an indication of the state of the electrical path between the first and second contacts. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pet accessory includes a pet dish and the probe extends into the dish to indicate a desired level for liquid in the dish. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the indication of state is performed by at least one of an audio message, a visual effect and a mechanical motion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the pet accessory includes a pet dish and the probe extends into the dish to indicate a desired level for liquid in the dish. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electrical path is closed by one of a tongue and saliva of a pet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second contacts are included on the probe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A liquid level indicator for a vessel, comprising: 
<claim-text>a probe extending to a first depth in the vessel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first contact disposed on the probe, wherein one at least one contact is located at the first depth such that when the vessel is filled with a liquid, an electrical connection is made between the first contact and a second contact until a level of the liquid falls below the first depth; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an activation device coupled to the contacts, which provides an action when the level of liquid has fallen below the first depth. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the vessel includes a pet dish. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the activation device includes a speaker which outputs audible warnings that the liquid in the vessel is below the first depth. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the activation device includes a circuit, which selects a pre-recorded message to play when the liquid falls below the first depth. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit includes a chip having a plurality of messages recorded therein which are randomly selected to be played. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the probe is integrally formed with the vessel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The indicator as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the activation device includes at least one of a light and a mechanical motion device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A pet warning device, comprising: 
<claim-text>an elongated base unit configured and dimensioned to fit at a base of a doorway so as to prevent a draft; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a deformable enclosure removably attached to the base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching device disposed within the enclosure housing which permits a pet to depress the enclosure to trigger a warning indicator. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The warning device, as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching device includes a fulcrum which supports a board, the board having a plurality of switches disposed at a periphery such that when a pet steps on the board at least one of the plurality of switches triggers the warning indicator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The warning device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warning indicator includes a circuit, which selects a pre-recorded message to audibly play when the switching device is triggered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The warning device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the circuit includes a chip having a plurality of messages recorded therein which are randomly selected to be played. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The warning device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the warning indicator includes at least one of a light, a mechanical motion device and a speaker. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The warning device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the base includes friction pads to resist motion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A restraining device, such as a belt or strap, comprising: 
<claim-text>a base material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an illuminating feature disposed in or on the base material; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment mechanism to adjust a fit of the fabric to conform to a wearer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The restraining device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the illuminating feature includes at least one of a heat-seal stamped reflective material stamped onto a surface of the fabric, an optical fiber and a light source coupled to illuminate the optical fiber and light emitting diodes disposed in the fabric. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The restraining device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical fiber includes notches formed therein to disperse light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The restraining device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical fiber includes a plurality of optical fibers having a plurality of different lengths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The restraining device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a processing chip, which lights the light emitting diodes in a sequence. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The restraining device as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a container comprising a flexible material and having a slit, which opens when the container is squeezed to provide access to the container, the container for storing an item. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A chew toy, comprising 
<claim-text>a polymer matrix formed into a shape; </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more holes or divots formed in the matrix; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of a nutritional supplement, medication, and flavoring provided in the holes or divots.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030000478A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
