<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000702A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000702A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000702</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894559</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E21B043/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>278000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>051000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>166</class>
<subclass>281000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Steven</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Streich</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Glenwood</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tommy</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Grigsby</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Houma</city>
<state>LA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES, INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 819052</address-1>
<city>Dallas</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75381-9052</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus (<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) and method for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) is disclosed. The apparatus (<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) comprises a cross-over assembly (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) having first and second exit ports (<highlight><bold>58, 62</bold></highlight>). The cross-over assembly (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) has a fracturing configuration wherein the first exit port (<highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>) is open and the second exit port (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) is closed and a gravel packing configuration wherein the first exit port (<highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>) is closed and the second exit port (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) is open. The apparatus (<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) also includes a gravel packing assembly (<highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>) that has an inlet that receives the gravel packing slurry from the second exit port (<highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>) and a plurality of outlets (<highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>) that allow for the delivery the gravel slurry to a plurality of locations along the length of a sand control screen (<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates in general to the treatment of a production interval of a wellbore to stimulate hydrocarbon production and prevent the production of fine particulate materials and, in particular, to an apparatus and method for sequentially fracturing the production interval then substantially completely gravel packing the wellbore adjacent to the production interval. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> It is well known in the subterranean well drilling and completion art that relatively fine particulate materials may be produced during the production of hydrocarbons from a well that traverses an unconsolidated or loosely consolidated formation. Numerous problems may occur as a result of the production of such particulates. For example, the particulates cause abrasive wear to components within the well, such as tubing, pumps and valves. In addition, the particulates may partially or fully clog the well creating the need for an expensive workover. Also, if the particulate matter is produced to the surface, it must be removed from the hydrocarbon fluids using surface processing equipment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One method for preventing the production of such particulate material to the surface is gravel packing the well adjacent the unconsolidated or loosely consolidated production interval. In a typical gravel pack completion, a sand control screen is lowered into the wellbore on a workstring to a position proximate the desired production interval. A fluid slurry including a liquid carrier and a relatively coarse particulate material, which is typically sized and graded and which is referred to herein as gravel, is then pumped down the workstring and into the well annulus formed between the sand control screen and the perforated well casing or open hole production zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The liquid carrier either flows into the formation or returns to the surface by flowing through a wash pipe or both. In either case, the gravel is deposited around the sand control screen to form the gravel pack, which is highly permeable to the flow of hydrocarbon fluids but blocks the flow of the fine particulate materials carried in the hydrocarbon fluids. As such, gravel packs can successfully prevent the problems associated with the production of these particulate materials from the formation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> It is sometimes desirable to perform a formation fracturing and propping operation prior to or simultaneously with the gravel packing operation. Hydraulic fracturing of a hydrocarbon formation is sometimes necessary to increase the permeability of the production interval adjacent the wellbore. According to conventional practice, a fracture fluid such as water, oil, oil/water emulsion, gelled water or gelled oil is pumped down the work string with sufficient pressure to open multiple fractures in the production interval. The fracture fluid may carry a suitable propping agent, such as sand or gravel, which is referred to herein as a proppant, into the fractures for the purpose of holding the fractures open following the fracturing operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The fracture fluid must be forced into the formation at a flow rate great enough to fracture the formation allowing the entrained proppant to enter the fractures and prop the formation structures apart, producing channels which will create highly conductive paths reaching out into the production interval, and thereby increasing the reservoir permeability in the fracture region. As such, the success of the fracture operation is dependent upon the ability to inject large volumes of hydraulic fracture fluid into the surrounding formation at a high pressure and at a high flow rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For most hydrocarbon formations, a successful fracture and propping operation will require injection flow rates that are much higher than those required for gravel packing. For example, in typical gravel packing, a single pump capable of delivering one to ten barrels per minute may be sufficient. On the other hand, for a successful fracturing operation, three or four large capacity pumps may be required in order to pump at rates higher than the formation fracture gradient which may range up to 60 barrels per minute or more. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It has been found that it is difficult to achieve a complete gravel pack of the desired production interval as part of or following a fracturing operation and particularly in long or inclined/horizontal production intervals. These incomplete packs are commonly a result of the liquid carrier entering the permeable portions of the production interval causing the gravel to form a sand bridge in the annulus. Thereafter, the sand bridge prevents the gravel pack slurry from flowing to the remainder of the annulus which, in turn, prevents the placement of sufficient gravel in the remainder of the annulus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Therefore a need has arisen for an apparatus and method that are capable of fracturing a production interval. A need has also arisen for such an apparatus and method that produce a complete gravel pack of the wellbore adjacent to the production interval following the fracturing of the production interval. Further, a need has arisen for an apparatus and method that are capable of sequentially stimulating of the production interval then gravel packing the production interval to prevent the production of fine particulate materials when production commences. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention disclosed herein comprises an apparatus and method that are capable of fracturing a production interval and producing a complete gravel pack of the wellbore adjacent to the production interval following the fracturing operation. Specifically, the apparatus and method of the present invention are used to sequentially pack the interval of a wellbore by first delivering a large volume of fracture fluids at a high flow rate and at a pressure above the fracture pressure of the formation then delivering a gravel packing slurry at a lower flow rate. The gravel packing slurry is delivered through a gravel packing apparatus which allows for the complete gravel packing of the interval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Even though the present invention utilizes a gravel packing assembly to deliver the gravel packing slurry, the high flow rate fracture fluid is not delivered through the gravel packing assembly as prior art attempts to deliver both the fracture fluids at the high flow rates then the gravel packing slurry at the lower flow rate through a gravel packing assembly have not been successful and have resulted in low quality fractures of the formation, incomplete gravel packs or both. Instead, the present invention allows high volume fluid delivery of fracture fluids directly into the wellbore but also allows lower volume delivery of the gravel packing slurry into the wellbore via a gravel packing assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore comprises a cross-over assembly partially disposed within a cross-over packer assembly. The cross-over assembly has a set of fracture fluid exit ports and a set of gravel packing exit ports positioned on one side of the packer and a return port positioned on the other side of the packer. The cross-over assembly has a fracturing configuration wherein the fracture fluid exit ports are open, the gravel packing exit ports are closed and the return port either open or closed depending upon the service tool setup. In the fracturing configuration, fracture fluids are delivered through the cross-over assembly via the fracture fluid exit ports directly into the wellbore such that the formation can be fractured. The return ports may be opened to allow for surface pressure monitoring of the annulus between the casing and the work string. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The cross-over assembly also has a gravel packing configuration wherein the fracture fluid exit ports are closed, the gravel packing slurry exit ports are open and the return port is open. In the gravel packing configuration, the gravel slurry is delivered through the gravel packing exit ports into a gravel packing assembly. The gravel packing assembly, which is positioned adjacent to a sand control screen, has a plurality of outlets that are located proximate the sand control screen and that extend along the gravel packing assembly substantially the length of the sand control screen such that the gravel packing slurry is delivered to multiple locations within the wellbore bypassing any sand bridge formation. In the gravel packing configuration, a wash pipe may be disposed within the sand control screen to take returns. The wash pipe is in fluid communication with the return port when the cross-over assembly is in the gravel packing configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Operation of the cross-over assembly from the fracturing configuration to the gravel packing configuration may be achieved in a variety of ways such as through the use of a sliding sleeve, the operation of valves and the like. Likewise, the gravel packing assembly may have a variety of configuration so long as it is capable of overcoming the formation of sand bridges. For example, the distribution of the gravel slurry to multiple location along the length of the sand control screen may be accomplished using a gravel packing assembly having a plurality of conduits having numerous outlets, using a gravel packing assembly having an axially extending slurry passageway and an axially extending production pathway between inner and outer tubulars or using other similar gravel packing assemblies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In the method of the present invention, sequential fracturing and gravel packing an interval of a wellbore is achieved by traversing a formation with the wellbore, locating a sand control screen within the wellbore proximate the formation, disposing a sequential packing apparatus proximate the sand control screen, positioning the sequential packing in a first position wherein a first exit port is open and a second exit port is closed, pumping a fluid slurry containing propping agents into the sequential packing apparatus such that the fluid slurry containing propping agents exits through the first port at a pressure above the fracture pressure of the formation, operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position wherein the first exit port is closed and the second exit port is open, pumping a fluid slurry containing gravel into the sequential packing apparatus such that the fluid slurry containing gravel exits through the second port and discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a gravel packing assembly. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the features and advantages of the present invention, reference is now made to the detailed description of the invention along with the accompanying figures in which corresponding numerals in the different figures refer to corresponding parts and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of an offshore oil and gas platform operating an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a half sectional view of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention in its fracturing position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a half sectional view of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention in its gravel packing position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an isometric view of an internal sleeve of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an isometric view of an internal sleeve having an inner profile of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partial cutaway view of a gravel packing apparatus of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of the gravel packing apparatus taken along line <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a side elevation view of a gravel packing apparatus of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a half sectional view of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention in its fracturing position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a half sectional view of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention in its gravel packing position. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> While the making and using of various embodiments of the present invention are discussed in detail below, it should be appreciated that the present invention provides many applicable inventive concepts which can be embodied in a wide variety of specific contexts. The specific embodiments discussed herein are merely illustrative of specific ways to make and use the invention, and do not delimit the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring initially to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore operating from an offshore oil and gas platform are schematically illustrated and generally designated <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A semi-submersible platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is centered over a submerged oil and gas formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> located below sea floor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A subsea conduit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> extends from deck <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to wellhead installation <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> including blowout preventers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a hoisting apparatus <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a derrick <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for raising and lowering pipe strings such as work sting <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extends through the various earth strata including formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is cemented within wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by cement <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes various tools including apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> for sequentially packing an interval of wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> adjacent to formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> includes a cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> which is used to gravel pack annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> between packers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. When it is desired to treat formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is lowered through casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> until apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent to formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> including perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, treatment fluids are pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to stimulate formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and gravel pack annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts a vertical well, it should be noted by one skilled in the art that the apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is equally well-suited for use in deviated wells, inclined wells or horizontal wells. Also, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts an offshore operation, it should be noted by one skilled in the art that the apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention is equally well-suited for use in onshore operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, therein is depicted a more detailed illustration of apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> includes cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, a screen assembly <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is connected to work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending from the surface, which lowers apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> into wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> until screen assembly <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is properly positioned adjacent formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> To begin the completion process, the interval adjacent formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is isolated. Packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> seals the upper end of the production interval and packer <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) seals the lower end of the production interval. Cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is located above screen assembly <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and partially above and partially below packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. During the fracture treatment, the fracture fluid is pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, into apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and through cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is in its fracture position. In the fracture position, the top of wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is closed at port <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> so fluids cannot return to the surface. During the fracturing operation, the fracture fluid passes through cross-over ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> below packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, flowing down annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The fracture fluid is then forced at a high flow rate through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The fracture fluid tends to fracture or part the rock to form open void spaces in formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As more rock is fractured, the void space surface area increases in formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The fracture operation continues until an equilibrium is reached where the amount of fluid introduced into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> approximates the amount of fluid leaking off into the rock, whereby the fracture stops propagating. The proppant material in the fracture fluid maintains the voids in an open position for production. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Once the fracture treatment is complete, the gravel packing operation commences. During gravel packing, the objective is to uniformly fill annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> with gravel along the entire production interval. Prior to introducing the gravel pack slurry, apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is placed in the gravel pack position, as best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In its gravel packing position, port <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is open to wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, cross-over ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are closed and cross-over ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are open. The gravel pack slurry is then pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The slurry exits cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> through cross-over ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> before entering gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The slurry then travels down gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> before being discharged through ports <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Some of the carrier fluid in the slurry leaks off through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> while the remainder of the fluid passes through screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that is sized to prevent the gravel in the slurry from flowing therethrough. The fluid flowing back through screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, depicted as arrows <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, enters the inner annular area formed between screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and flows through the lower end of wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> up the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The return fluids flow out through cross-over port <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> into annulus <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> above packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, then back to the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Preferably the gravel in the slurry is very uniform in size and has a very high permeability. As the carrier fluid leaks off through the screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the gravel drops out of the slurry and builds up from the formation fractures back toward wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, filling perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> around screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to form a gravel pack. The size of the gravel in the gravel pack is selected to prevent formation fines and sand from flowing into wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> with the produced fluids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> It has been found that a high leak off of fluid through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may occur during a typically gravel packing operation, particularly following a fracture operation in a highly deviated or long production interval. More specifically when leak off into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> occurs, the gravel tends to deposit around the adjacent perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> thus forming a node. The node is a build up of gravel that grows radially and may grow so large that it forms a bridge and completely blocks annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The resulting incomplete annular pack has sections of screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that remain uncovered, which can lead to formation sand production, screen erosion and eventual failure of the completion. This problem is overcome in the present invention by injecting the gravel slurry into gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. To prevent the problems caused by sand bridge formation, as explained above, the gravel slurry travels within gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> with portions of the gravel slurry exiting gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> through exit ports <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> along the length of gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, which extends along the length of sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> It should be apparent to those skilled in the art that the use of directional terms such as above, below, upper, lower, upward, downward and the like are used in relation to the illustrative embodiments as they are depicted in the figures, the upward direction being toward the top of the corresponding figure and the downward direction being toward the bottom of the corresponding figure. It should be noted, however, that the apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore is not limited to such orientation as it is equally-well suited for use in inclined and horizontal orientations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring next to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, therein is depicted a sleeve of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> that is generally designated <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is positioned within the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and is axially slidable therein. Sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes a return port <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> that extends through the side wall of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Return port <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is coupled to the upper end of wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> as best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>. Sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> also includes a plurality of fluid conduits that receive the fluid pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, two such fluid conduits are depicted and are designated <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Fluid conduits <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are in fluid communication with a first set of ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> used to deliver the fracturing fluid and a second set of ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> used to deliver the gravel pack slurry. Ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> selectively discharge the fluids from conduits <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Disposed on either side of ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is a pair of o-rings <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> that provide a seal between sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Likewise, on either side of ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> there is a pair of o-rings <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> that also provide such a seal. Sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of shear pins, two of which are shown and are designated <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. Shear pins <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> are used to selectively prevent the axial movement of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> relative to the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> has a plurality of threads <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at its upper end that may be threadedly coupled to work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring collectively to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, when apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is in its fracture position, sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is secured within the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by shear pins <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> such that ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are aligned with ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> in the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In this position, port <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is not aligned with port <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are not aligned with ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Thus, when the fracture fluid is pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the slurry enters conduits <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and exits sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> through ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which are aligned with ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> such that the fracture fluids enter annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Once the fracture operation is complete, apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may be shifted from its fracturing position to its gravel packing position by upwardly shifting sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> such that port <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> becomes aligned with port <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> become aligned with ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and such that ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are no longer aligned with ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In the illustrated embodiment, this upward shifting of sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is achieved by pulling upwardly on work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with sufficient force to shear pins <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> allowing sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to slide axially relative to the outer housing of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> wireline pulling tool may be landed and locked within a profile <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of sleeve <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The pulling tool is then used to upwardly urge sleeve <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> causing shear pins <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> to shear and allowing sleeve <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to shift from the fracturing position to the gravel packing position of apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, once apparatus <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> has been shifted to its gravel packing position, the gravel packing slurry may be injected down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> such that it enters conduits <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and exits sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> via ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Upon exiting ports <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, the gravel slurry passes through ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and enters gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Once in gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gravel slurry travels downwardly as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> exiting through ports <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. As described above, the gravel in the gravel packing slurry is deposited in annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> between casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Some of the fluid from the gravel packing slurry enters screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and travels up through wash pipe <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and into annulus <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> between work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> above packer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> has depicted sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as having two sets of ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> for delivering fluid, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> could alternatively have a single set of ports that is first aligned with a set of fracture fluid discharge ports in the outer housing of the cross-over assembly then shifted to be aligned with a set of gravel packing slurry discharge ports of the outer housing of the cross-over assembly for gravel packing operations. Likewise, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> has depicted ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> being in fluid communication with one another via conduits <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that ports <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> could alternatively be isolated from one another by receiving fluids from different conduits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Also, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> have depicted sleeve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as being shifted upwardly to operate cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from its fracturing configuration to its gravel packing configuration, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that a sleeve could alternatively be shifted downwardly or rotated to operate a cross-over assembly from its fracturing configuration to its gravel packing configuration. Further, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> have depicted the fracture fluid discharge ports as being above the gravel pack slurry discharge ports, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that the position of these ports could alternatively be reversed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, therein is depicted a partial cut away view of an apparatus for sequential packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention that is generally designated <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the lower portion of a cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is depicted including ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for the discharge of a fracturing fluid into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for the discharge of a gravel packing slurry into gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. It should be noted by those skilled in the art that alternate port configurations such as ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> being located below ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> may also be used without departing from the principle of the present invention. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> has an outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. A portion of the side wall of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is an axially extending production section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> that includes a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Another portion of the side wall of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is an axially extending nonproduction section <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that includes one or more outlets <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. For reasons that will become apparent to those skilled in the art, the density of opening <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> within production section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is much greater than the density of outlets <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in nonproduction section <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Also, it should be noted by those skilled in the art that even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> has depicted openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and outlets <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> as being circular, other shaped openings may alternatively be used without departing form the principles of the present invention. Likewise, even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> has depicted openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as being the same size as outlets <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> could alternatively be larger or smaller than outlets <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> without departing from the principles of the present invention. In addition, the exact number, size and shape of openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are not critical to the present invention, so long as sufficient area is provided for fluid production therethrough and the integrity of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Disposed within outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is an inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. A portion of the side wall of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is an axially extending production section <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that is substantially circumferentially aligned with production section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Production section <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> has a plurality of opening <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> therethrough. Again, the exact number, size and shape of openings <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> are not critical to the present invention, so long as sufficient area is provided for fluid production and the integrity of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is maintained. Another portion of the side wall of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is an axially extending nonproduction section <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> that is substantially circumferentially aligned with nonproduction section <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Nonproduction section <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> has no openings therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Disposed within an annulus <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> between outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is an isolation member <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. Isolation member <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> includes a pair of substantially parallel, circumferentially spaced apart, axially extending members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> that radially extend between outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. In fact, members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> provide circumferential fluid isolation between production section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and nonproduction section <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In addition, members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> provide circumferential fluid isolation between production section <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and nonproduction section <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. As such, members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> define the circumferential boundary between a gravel packing slurry passageway <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, having radial boundaries defined by nonproduction section <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and nonproduction section <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, and a production pathway <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, having radial boundaries defined by production section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and production section <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. Isolation member <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> also includes a pair of substantially parallel, axially spaced apart, circumferentially extending members, only member <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> being visible, that radially extend between outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and inner tubular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and that complete the isolation between gravel packing slurry passageway <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and production pathway <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In operation, when apparatus <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is in the gravel packing position, the gravel packing slurry is discharged into gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> from ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The slurry enters assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and travels down slurry passageway <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Portions of the slurry exit assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through exit ports <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The gravel from these portions of the slurry is then deposited in annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A portion of the slurry reenters assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through openings <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> in outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The liquid in this portion of the slurry travels through the sand control screen (not pictured) positioned within assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The gravel, however, is filtered out by the screen and deposited in production pathway <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. As exit ports <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are spaced along the length of gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> or the numerous sections of gravel packing assemblies that are necessary for most production intervals, the entire production interval is uniformly packed even if sand bridges form between casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> during the gravel packing operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> as delivering the gravel slurry into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> exclusively via exit ports <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may additionally have discharge ports in outer tubular <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> proximate ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> that allow some or substantially all of the gravel slurry to be discharged directly into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. In such a configuration, if a sand bridge forms between gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as the pressure within annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> increases, the gravel slurry will preferentially travel through slurry passageway <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to bypass the sand bridge. As described above, portions of the slurry exit assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through exit ports <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> such that the gravel is deposited in annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> until a complete gravel pack is achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As should be apparent to those skilled in the art, gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may have a variety of configurations having, for example, additional slurry passageways such as two, four or more slurry passageways without departing from the principles of the present invention. In addition, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that use of various configurations of the gravel packing assembly in the same interval is likely and may be preferred. Specifically, it may be desirable to have a volumetric capacity within the slurry passageways that is greater toward the top, in a vertical well, or heel, in an inclined or horizontal well, of a string of consecutive gravel packing assemblies than toward the bottom or toe of the interval. This may be achieved by using gravel packing assemblies having more slurry passageways near the top or heel of the interval and less slurry passageways near the bottom or toe of the interval. This may also be achieved by using gravel packing assemblies of the present invention having wider slurry passageways near the top or heel of the interval and narrower slurry passageways near the bottom or toe of the interval. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, therein is depicted another embodiment of an apparatus for sequential packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention that is generally designated <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the lower portion of a cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is depicted including ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for the discharge of a fracturing fluid into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for the discharge of a gravel packing slurry into gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. Gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is positioned around sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes a base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> that has a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> which allow the flow of production fluids into the production tubing. The exact number, size and shape of openings <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> are not critical to the present invention, so long as sufficient area is provided for fluid production and the integrity of base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Spaced around base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> is a plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> are generally symmetrically distributed about the axis of base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> Ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> are depicted as having a cylindrical cross section, however, it should be understood by one skilled in the art that ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> may alternatively have a rectangular or triangular cross section or other suitable geometry. Additionally, it should be understood by one skilled in the art that the exact number of ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> will be dependent upon the diameter of base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> as well as other design characteristics that are well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Wrapped around ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is a screen wire <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. Screen wire <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> forms a plurality of turns each having a gap therebetween through which formation fluids flow. The number of turns and the gap between the turns are determined based upon the characteristics of the formation from which fluid is being produced and the size of the gravel to be used during the gravel packing operation. Together, ribs <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and screen wire <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> may form a sand control screen jacket which is attached to base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> by welding or other suitable technique. It should be understood by those skilled in the art that while ribs <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> and screen wire <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> are depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, other type of filtration systems may alternatively be used in the present invention, including, but not limited to, placing a wire mesh over a plurality of ribs or directly on base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> or wrapping screen wire <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> directly around base pipe <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, which is positioned around sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, includes a manifold <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> that is in fluid communication with ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a plurality of conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> extend along the length of sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> or the several sections of sand control screens <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> that may be required in a production interval. Conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> include a plurality of openings <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> along the length of sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. In operation, when apparatus <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is in the gravel packing position, the gravel packing slurry is discharged into gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> from ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The slurry enters assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and travels down conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Portions of the slurry exit assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> through opening <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>. The liquid in this portion of the slurry travels through sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and is returned to the surface. The gravel, however, is filtered out by sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and deposited in annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. As openings <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> are spaced along the length of conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, the entire production interval is uniformly packed even if sand bridges form between casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> during the gravel packing operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Even though <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> depicts gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> as delivering the gravel slurry into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> exclusively via openings <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> in conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> may have discharge ports in the manifold that allow some or substantially all of the gravel slurry to be discharged directly into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. In such a configuration, if a sand bridge forms between sand control screen <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and casing <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as the pressure within annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> increases, the gravel slurry would enter conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> either at manifold <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> or through opening <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> above the sand bridge then travel down conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> to a point beyond the sand bridge. As described above, portions of the gravel slurry would then exit conduits <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> via openings <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> such that a complete gravel pack can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Also, it should be noted by those skilled in the art that even though FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> have depicted exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> as being circular, other shaped openings may alternatively be used without departing form the principles of the present invention. Additionally, even though exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> have been depicted as being below exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, these exit ports could have alternate configurations such as exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> being above exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> or exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> being circumferentially spaced apart from but at the same axial position as exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Likewise, even though the same number of exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> have been depicted, there could alternatively be a different number of exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> as compared to exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> without departing from the principles of the present invention. Similarly, even though exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> have been depicted as being the same size, exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> could alternatively be different sizes without departing from the principles of the present invention. Specifically, it is likely that there may be a greater number of exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> than exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> or that exit port <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> may be larger than exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> as exit ports <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are intended to deliver the fracture fluids in a larger volume and at a higher flow rate than exit ports <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> will deliver the gravel packing slurry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As should be apparent to those skilled in the art, the present invention has numerous advantages over prior art fluid delivery systems. Specifically, the apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore of the present invention allows for the delivery of large volumes of fracture fluids at a high flow rate and at a pressure above the fracture pressure of the formation without requiring that the fracture fluids travel through a gravel packing assembly. Since a more uniform and complete gravel pack is achieved using flow rates that are lower than the flow rates used for fracturing the formation, the gravel packing assembly of the present invention is designed to deliver the gravel packing slurry at these lower flow rates and is not intended for delivering the large fluid volumes required during fracturing operation. Prior art attempts to deliver both the fracture fluids, at the high flow rates, then the gravel packing slurry, at the lower flow rate, through a gravel packing assembly have not been successful and have resulted in low quality fractures of the formation, incomplete gravel packs or both. Accordingly, the present invention overcomes this problem by allowing high volume fluid delivery of fracture fluids followed by lower volume fluid delivery of gravel packing slurries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, therein is depicted another embodiment of an apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore that is generally designated <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, a screen assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a packer assembly <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and a wash pipe <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is connected to work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending from the surface, which lowers apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> into wellbore <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> until screen assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is properly positioned adjacent formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As explained above, to begin the completion process, the interval adjacent formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is isolated using packers at the top and bottom of the production interval, only packer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> being shown here. Cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is located above screen assembly <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and partially above and below packer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. During the fracture treatment, the fracture fluid is pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, into apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and through cross-over assembly <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is in its fracture position wherein valve <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is closed, valve <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is open and valve <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> is closed. Thus, the fracture fluid passes through cross-over ports <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> below packer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, flowing into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Fluids cannot return to the surface through wash pipe <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> due to closed valve <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> or a closed valve at the surface (not pictured). Likewise, the fracture fluid does not pass through cross-over port <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> due to closed valves <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. During the fracturing operation, the fracture fluid is forced at a high flow rate through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Once the fracture treatment is complete, the gravel packing operation commences. Prior to introducing the gravel pack slurry, apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is placed in the gravel packing position, as best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In its gravel packing position, valve <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is open, valve <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is closed and valve <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> is open. The valves may be operated in a variety of known ways. Preferably, the valves are coupled to electronic actuators that may be operated by sending signals downhole. For example, the signals to operate the valves between their open and closed positions may be sent downhole via a direct wire, fiber optics, hydraulics, mud pulses, acoustic telemetry, electromagnetic telemetry or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The gravel pack slurry is then pumped down work string <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The slurry moves along the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, out cross-over ports <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, through gravel packing assembly <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, and into annulus <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. Some of the carrier fluid in the slurry leaks off through perforations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into formation <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> while the remainder of the fluid passes through screen <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> that is sized to prevent the gravel in the slurry from flowing therethrough. The fluid flowing back through screen <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, depicted as arrows <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>, enters the inner annular area formed between screen <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and wash pipe <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and flows through the lower end of wash pipe <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> up the path indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>. The return fluids flow out through cross-over port <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> into annulus <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> above packer <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, as indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, then back to the surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been described with reference to illustrative embodiments, this description is not intended to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications and combinations of the illustrative embodiments as well as other embodiments of the invention, will be apparent to persons skilled in the art upon reference to the description. It is, therefore, intended that the appended claims encompass any such modifications or embodiments. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>traversing a formation with the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>locating a sand control screen within the wellbore proximate the formation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a sequential packing apparatus proximate the sand control screen, the sequential packing apparatus having a first exit port and a second exit port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the sequential packing in a first position wherein the first exit port is open and the second exit port is closed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping a first fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the first fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the first port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position wherein the first exit port is closed and the second exit port is open; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping a second fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the second fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the second port. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of pumping a first fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the first fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the first port further comprises the step of pumping the first fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the first fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the first port at a pressure above the formation fracture pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of pumping a first fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the first fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the first port further comprises the step of pumping a fluid slurry containing propping agents into the sequential packing apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising, after the step of pumping a first fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the first fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the first port, the step of fracturing the formation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising shifting a first section of the sequential packing apparatus relative to a second section of the sequential packing apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising operating a first valve from an open position to a closed position to prevent fluid flow through the first exit port and operating a second valve from a closed position to an open position to allow fluid flow through the second exit port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising shifting a sleeve within the sequential packing apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of pumping a second fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the second fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the second port further comprises the step of pumping a fluid slurry containing gravel into the sequential packing apparatus and out through the second port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of terminating pumping the fluid slurry containing gravel when an annulus between the sand control screen and the wellbore is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of pumping a second fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the second fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the second port further comprises the step of discharging the second fluid into a gravel packing assembly comprising a plurality of conduits extending substantially the length of the sand control screen, each conduit having a plurality of discharge ports in a sidewall section thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of pumping a second fluid into the sequential packing apparatus such that the second fluid exits the sequential packing apparatus through the second port further comprises the step of discharging the second fluid into a gravel packing assembly substantially positioned around the sand control screen to form a first annulus between the gravel packing assembly and the wellbore, the gravel packing assembly comprising an outer tubular and an inner tubular disposed within the outer tubular forming a second annulus therebetween, the second annulus including an axially extending slurry passageway and an axially extending production pathway, the slurry passageway being in fluid isolation from the production pathway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of discharging the second fluid into a gravel packing assembly further comprises discharging the second fluid into the slurry passageway such that the second fluid exits the slurry passageway through an outlet in the outer tubular, the inner tubular having no openings adjacent the slurry passageway, both the outer and inner tubulars adjacent the production pathway having a plurality of openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of disposing an isolation member within the second annulus to define the slurry passageway and the production pathway and to prevent fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of disposing an isolation member within the second annulus further comprises disposing an isolation member within the second annulus having a pair of substantially parallel, circumferentially spaced apart, axially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars and a pair of substantially parallel, axially spaced apart, circumferentially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first fluid and the second have the same composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method for sequentially fracturing and gravel packing an interval of a wellbore comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>traversing a formation with the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>locating a sand control screen within the wellbore proximate the formation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a sequential packing apparatus proximate the sand control screen, the sequential packing apparatus having first and second exit ports; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the sequential packing in a first position wherein the first exit port is open and the second exit port is closed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping a fluid slurry containing propping agents into the sequential packing apparatus such that the fluid slurry containing propping agents exits through the first port at a pressure above the fracture pressure of the formation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position wherein the first exit port is closed and the second exit port is open; </claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping a fluid slurry containing gravel into the sequential packing apparatus such that the fluid slurry containing gravel exits through the second port; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a gravel packing assembly. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising, after the step of pumping a fluid slurry containing propping agents into the sequential packing apparatus such that the fluid slurry containing propping agents exits through the first port at a pressure above the fracture pressure of the formation, the step of fracturing the formation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising shifting a first section of the sequential packing apparatus relative to a second section of the sequential packing apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising shifting a sleeve within the sequential packing apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of operating the sequential packing apparatus from the first position to the second position further comprising operating a first valve from an open position to a closed position to prevent fluid flow through the first exit port and operating a second valve from a closed position to an open position to allow fluid flow through the second exit port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of terminating pumping the fluid slurry containing gravel when an annulus between the sand control screen and the wellbore is substantially completely packed with the gravel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a gravel packing assembly further comprises the step of discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a plurality of conduits extending substantially the length of the sand control screen, each conduit having a plurality of discharge ports in a sidewall section thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a gravel packing assembly further comprises the step of discharging the fluid slurry containing gravel into a gravel packing assembly substantially positioned around the sand control screen to form a first annulus between the gravel packing assembly and the wellbore, the gravel packing assembly comprising an outer tubular and an inner tubular disposed within the outer tubular forming a second annulus therebetween, the second annulus including an axially extending slurry passageway and an axially extending production pathway, the slurry passageway being in fluid isolation from the production pathway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of discharging the second fluid into a gravel packing assembly further comprises discharging the second fluid into the slurry passageway such that the fluid slurry containing gravel exits the slurry passageway through an outlet in the outer tubular, the inner tubular having no openings adjacent the slurry passageway, both the outer and inner tubulars adjacent the production pathway having a plurality of openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising the step of disposing an isolation member within the second annulus to define the slurry passageway and the production pathway and to prevent fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of disposing an isolation member within the second annulus further comprises disposing an isolation member within the second annulus having a pair of substantially parallel, circumferentially spaced apart, axially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars and a pair of substantially parallel, axially spaced apart, circumferentially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fluid slurry containing propping agents and the fluid slurry containing gravel have the same composition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore comprising: 
<claim-text>a sand control screen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cross-over assembly having first and second exit ports, the cross-over assembly having a first position wherein the first exit port is open and the second exit port is closed and a second position wherein the first exit port is closed and the second exit port is open; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gravel packing assembly having an inlet that is in fluid communication with the second exit port, the gravel packing assembly having a plurality of outlets that are located proximate the sand control screen and that extend along the gravel packing assembly substantially the length of the sand control screen. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cross-over assembly further comprises a sleeve having first and second positions, in the first position of the sleeve, the first exit port of the cross-over assembly is open and the second exit port of the cross-over assembly is closed, in the second position of the sleeve, the first exit port of the cross-over assembly is closed and the second exit port of the cross-over assembly is open. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cross-over assembly further comprises first and second valves, the first valve being in an open position and the second valve being in a closed position when the cross-over assembly is in the first position, the first valve being in a closed position and the second valve being in an open position when the cross-over assembly is in the second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gravel packing assembly further comprises a plurality of conduits extending substantially the length of the sand control screen, each conduit including at least one of the outlets in a sidewall section thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gravel packing assembly further comprises an outer tubular and an inner tubular disposed within the outer tubular forming an annulus therebetween, the annulus including an axially extending slurry passageway and an axially extending production pathway, the slurry passageway being in fluid isolation from the production pathway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the portion of the outer tubular adjacent to the slurry passageway includes the outlets, wherein the portion of the inner tubular adjacent the slurry passageway has no openings and wherein both the outer and inner tubulars adjacent the production pathway having a plurality of openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an isolation member disposed within the annulus defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the isolation member further comprises a pair of substantially parallel, circumferentially spaced apart, axially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars and a pair of substantially parallel, axially spaced apart, circumferentially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a wash pipe disposed within the sand control screen to take returns, the wash pipe in fluid communication with a return port of the cross-over assembly when the cross-over assembly is in the second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for sequentially packing an interval of a wellbore having a sand control screen disposed therein, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a packer having a sealing surface positioned within the wellbore; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cross-over assembly partially disposed within the packer, the cross-over assembly having first and second exit ports positioned on one side of the packer and a return port positioned on the other side of the packer, the cross-over assembly having a first position wherein the first exit port is open, the second exit port is closed and the return port is closed and a second position wherein the first exit port is closed, the second exit port is open and the return port is open; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gravel packing assembly having an inlet that is in fluid communication with the second exit port of the cross-over assembly, the gravel packing assembly having a plurality of outlets that are located proximate the sand control screen and that extend along the gravel packing assembly substantially the length of the sand control screen; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wash pipe disposed within the sand control screen to take returns, the wash pipe in fluid communication with the return port when the cross-over assembly is in the second position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cross-over assembly further comprises a sleeve having first and second positions, in the first position of the sleeve, the first exit port is open while the second exit port and the return port are closed, in the second position of the sleeve, the first exit port is closed while the second exit port and the return port are open. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cross-over assembly further comprises first, second and third valves, the first valve is in an open position while the second and third valves are in a closed position when the cross-over assembly is in the first position, the first valve is in a closed position while the second and third valves are in an open position when the cross-over assembly is in the second position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gravel packing assembly further comprises a plurality of conduits extending substantially the length of the sand control screen, each conduit including at least one of the outlets in a sidewall section thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gravel packing assembly further comprises an outer tubular and an inner tubular disposed within the outer tubular forming an annulus therebetween, the annulus including an axially extending slurry passageway and an axially extending production pathway, the slurry passageway being in fluid isolation from the production pathway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the portion of the outer tubular adjacent to the slurry passageway includes the outlets, wherein the portion of the inner tubular adjacent the slurry passageway has no openings and wherein both the outer and inner tubulars adjacent the production pathway having a plurality of openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an isolation member disposed within the annulus defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the isolation member further comprises a pair of substantially parallel, circumferentially spaced apart, axially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars and a pair of substantially parallel, axially spaced apart, circumferentially extending members that radially extend between the outer and inner tubulars defining the slurry passageway and the production pathway and preventing fluid communication therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000702A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
