<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002317A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002317A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002317</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10167397</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-38909</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C011/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>145000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>189060</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>230030</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Ferroelectric memory and method for driving the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hee</given-name>
<middle-name>Bok</middle-name>
<family-name>Kang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Daejeon-shi</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hun</given-name>
<middle-name>Woo</middle-name>
<family-name>Kye</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Duck</given-name>
<middle-name>Ju</middle-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Cheju-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Je</given-name>
<middle-name>Hoon</middle-name>
<family-name>Park</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Geun</given-name>
<middle-name>Il</middle-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyonggi-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hynix Semiconductor Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MORGAN LEWIS &amp; BOCKIUS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1111 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A ferroelectric memory device includes a cell array block having a plurality of sub-cell array blocks regularly arranged in columns and rows, each sub-cell array block includes a plurality of unit cells, a plurality of main bitlines disposed along a first direction corresponding to the sub-cell array blocks in column units, a plurality of sub-bitlines disposed along the first direction in a one-to-one correspondence to the sub-cell array blocks, a plurality of pairs of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines and sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines disposed along a second direction perpendicular to the first direction, each pair corresponding to the sub-cell array block for applying a sub-bitline enable switch signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal, and a plurality of switching control blocks, each corresponding to the sub-cell array block for one of enabling the sub-bitlines selectively in response to the sub-bitline enable switch signal and pulling down the sub-bitlines in response to the sub-bitline pull down signal. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention claims the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. P2001-38909 filed in Korea on Jun. 30, 2001, which is hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a ferroelectric memory, and more particularly, to a ferroelectric memory which can write data on a cell independent from amplification operation of a sense amplifier without restricted by the operation of the sense amplifier; and a method for driving the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Background of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The ferroelectric memory, i.e., a Ferroelectric Random Access Memory (FRAM), having in general a data processing speed similar to a Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM), and being capable of conserving data even if the power is turned off, is paid attention as a next generation memory. The FRAM, a memory having a structure similar to the DRAM, is provided with a capacitor of a ferroelectric material for utilizing a high residual polarization of the ferroelectric material. The residual polarization permits the conservation of a data even after removal of an electric field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a characteristic curve of a hysteresis loop of a general ferroelectric material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, it can be known that a polarization induced by an electric field is, not erased totally, but, a certain amount(&lsquo;d&rsquo; or &lsquo;a&rsquo; state) of which is remained, even if the electric field is removed owing to existence of the residual polarization(or spontaneous polarization). The &lsquo;d&rsquo; and &lsquo;a&rsquo; states are corresponded to &lsquo;1&rsquo; and &lsquo;0&rsquo; respectively in application to a memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A related art non-volatile ferroelectric memory will be explained with reference to the attached drawings. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a unit cell of the related art non-volatile ferroelectric memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the unit cell of the related art non-volatile ferroelectric memory is provided with a bitline B/L formed in one direction, a wordline W/L formed in perpendicular to the bitline, a plateline P/L formed spaced from the wordline in a direction identical to the wordline, a transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a gate connected to the wordline and a drain connected to the bitline, and a ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a first terminal connected to a source of the transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second terminal connected to the plateline P/L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The data input/output operation of the related art ferroelectric memory will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrates a timing diagram of a write mode operation of the related art ferroelectric memory, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> illustrates a timing diagram of a read mode operation of the related art ferroelectric memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In writing, when an external chip enable signal CSBpad transits from &lsquo;high&rsquo; to &lsquo;low&rsquo; and, on the same time, an external write enable signal WEBpad transits from &lsquo;high&rsquo; to &lsquo;low&rsquo;, the write mode is started. When address decoding is started in the write mode, a pulse applied to the wordline transits from &lsquo;low&rsquo; to &lsquo;high&rsquo; to select the cell. Thus, in a period the wordline is held &lsquo;high&rsquo;, the plateline has a &lsquo;high&rsquo; signal applied thereto for one interval and a &lsquo;low&rsquo; signal applied thereto for the other interval in succession. And, in order to write a logical value &lsquo;1&rsquo; or &lsquo;0&rsquo; on the selected cell, a &lsquo;high&rsquo; or &lsquo;low&rsquo; signal synchronized to the write enable signal WEBpad is applied to the bitline. That is, if a &lsquo;high&rsquo; signal is applied to the bitline, and a signal applied to the plateline is &lsquo;low&rsquo; in a period in which a signal applied to the wordline is in a &lsquo;high&rsquo; state, a logical value &lsquo;1&rsquo; is written on the ferroelectric capacitor. If a &lsquo;low&rsquo; signal is applied to the bitline, and a signal applied to the plateline is &lsquo;high&rsquo;, a logical value &lsquo;0&rsquo; is written on the ferroelectric capacitor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Then, the operation for reading the data stored in the cell will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> If the chip enable signal CSBpad is transited from &lsquo;high&rsquo; to &lsquo;low&rsquo; from outside of the cell, all bitlines are equalized to a &lsquo;low&rsquo; voltage by an equalizer signal before the wordline is selected. Then, after the bitlines are disabled, an address is decoded, and the decoded address transits the wordline from &lsquo;low&rsquo; to &lsquo;high&rsquo;, to select the cell. A &lsquo;high&rsquo; signal is applied to the plateline of the selected cell, to break a data corresponding to a logical value &lsquo;1&rsquo; stored in the ferroelectric memory. If a logical value &lsquo;0&rsquo; is in storage in the ferroelectric memory, a data corresponding to the logical value &lsquo;0&rsquo; is not broken. The data not broken and the data broken thus provide values different from each other according to the aforementioned hysteresis loop, so that the sense amplifier senses a logical value &lsquo;1&rsquo; or &lsquo;0&rsquo;. That is, the case of the data broken is a case when the value is changed from &lsquo;d&rsquo; to &lsquo;f&rsquo; in the hysteresis loop in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and the case of the data not broken is a case when the value is changed from &lsquo;a&rsquo; to &lsquo;f&rsquo; in the hysteresis loop in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Therefore, if the sense amplifier is enabled after a certain time period is passed, in the case of the data broken, a logical value &lsquo;1&rsquo; is provided as amplified, and in the case of the data not broken, a logical value &lsquo;0&rsquo; is provided as amplified. After the sense amplifier amplifies data thus, since an original data should be restored, the plateline is disabled from &lsquo;high&rsquo; to &lsquo;low&rsquo; in a state a &lsquo;high&rsquo; signal is applied to the wordline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The following method may be used as one of methods for driving the related art ferroelectric memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A memory cell array is divided into a plurality of sub-cell arrays, and a selection switch signal SBSW is used. In a double pulse operation, a first pulse restores, or rewrites a cell data, a second pulse restores, or rewrites a logical &ldquo;1&rdquo;, i.e., a high data, broken by the first pulse, or to be written newly. In the meantime, an SBPD signal is used for reinforcing a logical &ldquo;0&rdquo;, i.e., a low data. That is, in the related art, after the operation of the sense amplifier is made by using the low data on the bitline, the low data is written again on the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> However, the aforementioned related art ferroelectric memory has the following problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The small design rule and cell size cause many difficulties in fabrication of the cell array and the peripherals, particularly, the use of poly related bitline which has a high resistance makes this problem more severe. High bitline resistance and bitline capacitance, when a ratio of Cb/CS (Cb: bitline capacitance, Cs: cell charge) is great, limits a cell size. In this case, a cell array efficiency is poor, resulting in a larger chip size. Moreover, in writing a low data, because the data is written again after the operation of the sense amplifier in which the low data on the bitline is used is finished, data writing can not be made during the operation of the sense amplifier, that increases a cell operation time period, and a cycle time period. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention is directed to a ferroelectric memory and a method for driving the same that substantially obviates one or more of the problems due to limitations and disadvantages of the related art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a ferroelectric memory and a method for driving the same, which permits to write a data on a cell independent from an amplification operation of a sense amplifier without limited by the operation of the sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Additional features and advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objectives and other advantages of the invention will be realized and attained by the structure particularly pointed out in the written description and claims hereof as well as the appended drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> To achieve these and other advantages and in accordance with the purpose of the present invention, as embodied and broadly described, a ferroelectric memory device includes a cell array block having a plurality of sub-cell array blocks regularly arranged in columns and rows, each sub-cell array block includes a plurality of unit cells, a plurality of main bitlines disposed along a first direction corresponding to the sub-cell array blocks in column units, a plurality of sub-bitlines disposed along the first direction in a one-to-one correspondence to the sub-cell array blocks, a plurality of pairs of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines and sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines disposed along a second direction perpendicular to the first direction, each pair corresponding to the sub-cell array block for applying a sub-bitline enable switch signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal, and a plurality of switching control blocks, each corresponding to the sub-cell array block for one of enabling the sub-bitlines selectively in response to the sub-bitline enable switch signal and pulling down the sub-bitlines in response to the sub-bitline pull down signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In other aspect of the present invention, a ferroelectric memory device includes a cell array block having a plurality of sub-cell array blocks, each with a plurality of unit cells regularly arranged in a column direction, and a row direction, a plurality of main bitlines disposed in a first direction, a plurality of sub-bitlines disposed in the first direction, each corresponding to one of the sub-cell array blocks, a plurality of pairs of split wordlines within each of the sub-cell array blocks disposed along a second direction perpendicular to the first direction, a plurality of sub-bitline pull down application lines and sub-bitline enable switch application lines disposed along the second direction, each corresponding to the sub-cell array block, and a plurality of switching control blocks, each disposed corresponding to one of the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines and one of the sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal, and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, a ferroelectric memory device includes a cell array block having sub-cell array blocks each with a plurality of unit cells arranged in a column direction, and a row direction regularly, a split wordline driver disposed at a center of the sub-cell array blocks divided in column units, a plurality of main bitlines running in one direction, a plurality of sub-bitlines each in correspondence to a sub-cell array block running in a direction the same with the main bitlines, a plurality of pairs of split wordlines in each of the sub-cell array blocks running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines and sub-bitlines, a plurality of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and a plurality of sub-bitline enable switch application lines disposed along a direction the same with the split wordlines each in correspondence to the sub-cell array block, and a plurality of switching control blocks each disposed in correspondence to the sub-bitline pull down application line, and the sub-bitline enable switch application line, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, a ferroelectric memory device includes a cell array block having sub-cell array blocks each with a plurality of unit cells arranged in a column direction, and a row direction regularly, a plurality of main bitlines disposed along one direction, a plurality of sub-bitlines each in correspondence to a sub-cell array block running in a direction the same with the main bitlines, a plurality of pairs of wordlines/platelines in each of the sub-cell array blocks running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines and the sub-bitlines, a plurality of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines running in a direction the same with pairs of the wordlines/platelines each disposed in correspondence to the sub-cell array block, and a plurality of switching control blocks each disposed in correspondence to the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and the sub-bitline enable switch signal application line, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, a method for driving a ferroelectric memory of a split wordline structure for enabling, and pulling down a sub-bitline selected in response to a sub-bitline enable signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal, includes (a) enabling a first split wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and a second split wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, within a continuous enable cycle divided into &lsquo;A&rsquo;, &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, (b) enabling a sub-bitline enable switch signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period at first for applying a cell data value to a bitline through a sub-bitline, disabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods for cutting off signal flows on the sub-bitline and the bitline, and enabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to high again in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods for the second time for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, or to be written newly, and (c) writing a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, by using the sub-bitline pull down signal which is enabled to high only in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, regardless of operation of a sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, A method for driving a ferroelectric memory of a split wordline structure for enabling, and pulling down a sub-bitline selected in response to a sub-bitline enable signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal includes (a) enabling a wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&lsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and a plateline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, within a continuous enable cycle divided into &lsquo;A&rsquo;, &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, (b) enabling a sub-bitline enable switch signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period at first for applying a cell data value to a bitline through a sub-bitline, disabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods for cutting off signal flows on the sub-bitline, and the bitline, and enabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to high again in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods for the second time for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, or to be written newly, and (c) writing a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, by using the sub-bitline pull down signal which is enabled to high only in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, regardless of operation of a sense amplifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory and are intended to provide further explanation of the invention as claimed. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention. In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a characteristic curve of a hysteresis loop of a general ferroelectric material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a unit cell of the related art non-volatile ferroelectric memory; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> illustrates a timing diagram of a write mode operation of the related art ferroelectric memory; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> illustrates a timing diagram of a read mode operation of the related art ferroelectric memory; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary system of a reference cell array block according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary system of an SWL cell in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates another exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates another detailed exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates another exemplary system of an SWL cell in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary operational timing diagram of the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates another exemplary detailed system of a ferroelectric cell array in accordance with the present invention; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates another exemplary operation timing diagram of the ferroelectric cell array in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to the preferred embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a first preferred embodiment of the present invention, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed exemplary system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a first preferred embodiment of the present invention. The present invention provides a core circuit system, and an operation method, for suppressing a chip size increase, securing a stable Cb/Cs ratio, and improving a chip operation speed. The present invention also facilitates a significant reduction of a load on driving a cell capacitor by using an SWL cell, for doubling a number of column arrays. According to this, the present invention reduces an area occupied by the cell driver, and resolves an inconsistency of loading occurred at the wordlines and the platelines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> An entire system of blocks around the cell array of the present invention will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, there are a top array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and a bottom array block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the cell array, and a sense amplifier <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is connected to each of bitlines in the middle of the top, and bottom cell array blocks <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. There is a column switch block <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> at each end of the bitline connected to a data bus io&lt;m&gt;, -----, io&lt;n&gt;. The data buses io&lt;m&gt;, -----, io&lt;n&gt; for the top cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> or the bottom cell array block are connected to a main amplifier (not shown) at one end of the entire cell array block. The top, or bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has a plurality of sub-cell array blocks <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. There is a reference cell array block <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> in correspondence to the top or bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The reference cell array block <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is provided between the top cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and a column switch block <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in correspondence to the top cell array block <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, and the reference cell array block <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is provided between the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and a column switch block <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in correspondence to the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> A detailed system of the top, or bottom cell array block having the plurality of sub-cell array blocks will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the cell array block includes a plurality of main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; running in one direction, a plurality of sub-bitlines SBL each in correspondence to a sub-cell array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> running in a direction the same with the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, a plurality of pairs of split wordlines (SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;n&gt;, SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;n&gt;) in each of the sub-cell array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, and sub-bitlines SBL, SBPD application lines, and SBSW application lines (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;), running in a direction the same with the split wordlines each in correspondence to the sub-cell array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of switching control blocks <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> each in correspondence to the SBPD application line, and the SBSW application line (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;), and each of the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, for switching an SBPD signal, an SBSW signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Each of the switching control blocks <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> includes a first, and a second switching transistors <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected in series, wherein the first switching transistor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBPD application line, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, the second switching transistor <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBSW application line, one side electrode connected to a main bitline, and an output terminal the first and second switching transistors <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected in common thereto is connected to the sub bitline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Each of the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; selectively is connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines SBL in one time of operation. That is, only one of sub-bitline enable switch signals SBSW is enabled for selecting one of the plurality of the sub-bitlines, that permits to reduce a load on the bitline to a level of one sub-bitline load. When a sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD signal is enabled, a level of the sub-bitline is pulled down to Vss. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Systems of a reference cell array block, and a unit cell thereof of the ferroelectric split cell array of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a system of a reference cell array block of the present invention, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a system of an SWL cell in accordance with a first preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The reference cell array block includes a plurality of bitlines BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, BL<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, ----, BLn running in one direction within a unit cell block <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, one reference wordline REF_W/L <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> running perpendicular to the bitlines, a reference plateline REF_P/L <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> running in parallel to the reference wordline REF_W/L, a plurality of reference capacitors FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, FC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, FC<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, ----, FCn connected in parallel each having a first electrode connected to the reference plateline REF_P/L, and a second electrode connected to a storage node SN of the reference cell, a level initializing part <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of an NMOS transistor T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a gate with a reference cell equalizing control signal REF_EQ applied thereto, and one side electrode connected to a ground terminal GND, and the other side electrode connected to the storage node SN, and a switching block having a plurality of NMOS transistors T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, ----, and T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-n, each having one side electrode connected to the bitline, the other side electrode connected to the storage node SN of the reference capacitor, and a gate connected to the reference wordline REF_W/L in common. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The unit cell of the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a first preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The unit cell includes a first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> running in a row direction spaced a fixed distance, a first bitline BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second bitline BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> running in a direction perpendicular to the first, and second split wordlines SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a first transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a gate connected to the first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a drain connected to the first bitline BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a first ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the first transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a second transistor T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having a gate connected to the second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a drain connected to the second bitline BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a second ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the second transistor T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> A ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates a system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed system of a ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention, having sub-cell array blocks each divided into two, and a split wordline driver (SWLD) at a central part thereof, includes a top cell array block <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, a bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of sense amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> each connected to the bitline in the middle of the top, and bottom cell array blocks <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. There is a column switch block <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> connected to the data bus io&lt;m&gt;, ----, io&lt;n&gt; at each end of the bitline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The data buses io&lt;m&gt;, ----, io&lt;n&gt; for the top cell array block <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are connected to the main amplifier (not shown) at one end of entire cell array block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Each of the top, and bottom cell array blocks <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of sub-cell array blocks, wherein the top cell array block <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> includes the split wordline driver (SWLD) <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at a center, and the plurality of the sub-cell array blocks L <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the sub-cell array blocks R <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at left and right of the split wordline driver <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> includes the split wordline driver (SWLD) <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at a center, and the plurality of the sub-cell array blocks L <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the sub-cell array blocks R <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at left and right of the split wordline driver <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> There are reference cell array blocks <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in correspondence to the sub-cell array blocks L <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the sub-cell array blocks R <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>respectively, and reference cell array blocks <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in correspondence to the sub-cell array blocks L <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the sub-cell array blocks R <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>respectively. The reference cell array blocks <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are provided between the top cell array block <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and the column switch blocks <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> corresponding to the top cell array blocks <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, and the reference cell array blocks <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are provided between the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, and the column switch blocks <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> corresponding to the bottom cell array block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. A detailed system of the reference cell array blocks is identical to the system explained in detail in association with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> A detailed system of the cell array block having the plurality of sub-cell array block L, and R will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the cell array block includes a plurality of main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; running in one direction, sub-bitlines SBL formed in correspondence to the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> running in a direction the same with the main bitline BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, pairs of split wordlines (SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&lt;n&gt;, SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;n&gt;) each formed in the sub-cell array <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, and the sub-bitlines, SBPD application lines, and SBSW application lines (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;) formed in correspondence to the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> running in a direction the same with the split wordlines, and a plurality of switching control blocks <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> formed in correspondence to, and between the SBPD application lines, and SBSW application lines (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;), and the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, for switching the SBPD signal, and the SBSW signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Each of the switching control blocks <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> includes first, and second switching transistors <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected in series, wherein the first switching transistor <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBPD application line, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, and the second switching transistor <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBSW application line, and one side electrode connected to the main bitline. There is one output terminal connected to the sub-bitline, to which the first, and second transistors <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are connected in common. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Each of the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; selectively is connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines SBL in one time of operation. That is, only one of sub-bitline enable switch signals SBSW is enabled for selecting one of the plurality of the sub-bitlines, that permits to reduce a load on the bitline to a level of one sub-bitline load. There is the split wordline driver <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> running between the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Unit cell of the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a system of an SWL cell in accordance with a second preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The unit cell includes a first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> running in a row direction spaced a fixed distance, a first bitline BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a second bitline BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> running in a direction perpendicular to the first, and second split wordlines SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a first transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on a left side of the split wordline driver having a gate connected to the first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a drain connected to the first bitline BL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a first ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the first transistor T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a second transistor T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on a right side of the split wordline driver having a gate connected to the second split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a drain connected to the second bitline BL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a second ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the second transistor T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the first split wordline SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The operation of the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the first, or second preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates an operation timing diagram of the ferroelectric split cell array in accordance with the first, or second preferred embodiment of the present invention. The timing operation of reference occurrence will be explained, at first. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> During a prior cycle, a REF_EQ is at high, to leave the reference capacitor in a discharged state. In an &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, for charging the reference capacitor, the REF_PL has a low pulse waveform, and the REF_EQ is still at high. In a &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, for providing a reference level to the bitline BL, the charge stored in the reference ferroelectric capacitor in the &lsquo;A&rsquo; period is discharged, again. To do this, the REF_EQ is disabled to a low pulse, the REF_WL is enabled to a high pulse, and the REF_PL is transited to high. According to this, the reference level is occurred at the bitline BL. The REF_EQ is transited to high again from the &lsquo;C&rsquo; period and thereafter, for resetting the reference level to low again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The operation of the SWL cell array will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> During the prior cycle, which is a period for pre-charging the bitline, the bitline BL, and the sub-bitline are in a state separated from each other as the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline SBL is pre-charged to low as the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD transits to high. The bitline BL is pre-charged to low, separately. In the &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is disabled to low, when an address is decoded. The first split wordline application signal SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is enabled to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and, particularly, generates a voltage of (Vcc&plus;aVtn) higher than external supply voltage in the &lsquo;E&rsquo; period, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; is a value greater than 1.5. The second split wordline application signal SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is enabled to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, disabled to low in rest of the periods, and generates a voltage (Vcc&plus;aVtn) higher than the external supply voltage Vcc in an &lsquo;F&rsquo; period. Therefore, the first split wordline application signal SWL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a single pulse waveform, and the second split wordline application signal SWL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a double pulse waveform. The sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW also has a double pulse waveform. In the &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, the first high pulse is generated, for application of a cell data value to the bitline BL through the sub-bitline SBL, and disabled to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo; , and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, to cut off a signal flow in the sub-bitline SBL, and in the bitline BL. Then, the SBSW signal is enabled to high in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods again, to generate the second pulse (Vcc&plus;aVtn) higher than Vcc, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; has a value greater than 1.5. In the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW, the first pulse is an operation for loading the cell data on the bitline, and the second pulse is a step for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken at the first pulse, or to be written, newly. In &lsquo;E&rsquo; period, a high data is restored, or re-written at the first ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and, in &lsquo;F&rsquo; period, a high data is restored, or re-written at the second ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In order to re-write a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is used for re-writing a low data. That is, the data is written again not after operation of the sense amplifier is finished by using the low data on the bitline, but a low data is written on the cell by using the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD. Therefore, in the data writing of the present invention, since writing of the low data can be made independent from the operation of the sense amplifier, the data writing can be made even if the sense amplifier is in operation, that can reduce a cell operation time period, and a cycle time period by eliminating a time period required for reinforcing the low data after data amplification by the sense amplifier. In more detail, the low data is reinforced by the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD, and only the high data is written by the bitline BL, again. In this instance, in a non-selected sub-cell array block, the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is at high to keep the sub-bitline at low. In the meantime, a sense amplifier enable signal SEN is enabled to high in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, for amplifying a bitline sensing data. The high data amplified thus is restored in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, again. If a column selection signal C/S is enabled to high in &lsquo;D&rsquo; period at a time point the amplification is finished, the amplified bitline data is loaded on a data bus outside of the cell array. On the other hand, in a write mode, since a data on an external data bus forcibly changes the data on the bitline, a new high data is written in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> A system, and a method for operating a ferroelectric cell array in accordance with a third preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a detailed system of a ferroelectric cell array in accordance with a third preferred embodiment of the present invention. A basic cell array system of a ferroelectric cell array in accordance with a third preferred embodiment of the present invention is as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, and a reference cell array block of a ferroelectric cell array in accordance with a third preferred embodiment of the present invention is as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, except that, not the split wordline SWL, but a unit cell using a cell plate line P/L, is employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The ferroelectric cell array in accordance with a third preferred embodiment of the present invention includes a plurality of main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; running in one direction, a plurality of sub-bitlines SBL each in correspondence to a sub-cell array <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> running in a direction the same with the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, a plurality of pairs of wordlines/platelines (W/L&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, P/L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (W/L&lt;n&gt;, P/L&lt;n&gt;) in each of the sub-cell array <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt;, and sub-bitlines SBL, SBPD application lines, and SBSW application lines (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;), running in a direction the same with the pairs of wordlines/platelines (W/L&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, P/L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (W/L&lt;n&gt;, P/L&lt;n&gt;) each in correspondence to the sub-cell array <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of switching control blocks <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> each in correspondence to the SBPD application line, and the SBSW application line (SBPD&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, SBSW&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;), ----, (SBPD&lt;n&gt;, SBSW&lt;n&gt;), and each of the sub-cell arrays <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, for switching an SBPD signal, an SBSW signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Each of the switching control blocks <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> includes a first, and a second switching transistors <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected in series, wherein the first switching transistor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBPD application line, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, the second switching transistor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a gate connected to the SBSW application line, one side electrode connected to a main bitline, and an output terminal the first and second switching transistors <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected in common thereto is connected to the sub bitline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Each of the main bitlines BL&lt;<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&gt;, ----, BL&lt;n&gt; selectively is connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines SBL in one time of operation. That is, only one of sub-bitline enable switch signals SBSW is enabled for selecting one of the plurality of the sub-bitlines, that permits to reduce a load on the bitline to a level of one sub-bitline load. When a sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD signal is enabled, a level of the sub-bitline is pulled down to Vss. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> A system of unit cell is as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The operation of the ferroelectric cell array in accordance with the third preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates an operation timing diagram of the ferroelectric cell array in accordance with the third preferred embodiment of the present invention. The timing operation of reference occurrence will be explained, at first. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> During a prior cycle, a REF_PL, and a REF_EQ are at high, so as to leave the reference capacitor in a discharged state. In an &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, for charging the reference capacitor, the REF_PL has a low pulse waveform, and the REF_EQ is still at high. In a &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, for providing a reference level to the bitline BL, the charge stored in the reference ferroelectric capacitor in the &lsquo;A&rsquo; period is discharged, again. To do this, the REF_EQ is disabled to a low pulse, the REF_WL is enabled to a high pulse, and the REF_PL is transited to high. According to this, the reference level is occurred at the bitline BL. The REF_EQ is transited to high again from the &lsquo;C&rsquo; period and thereafter, for resetting the reference level to low, again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The operation of the SWL cell array will be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> During the prior cycle, which is a period for pre-charging the bitline, the bitline BL, and the sub-bitline are in a state separated from each other as the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline SBL is pre-charged to low as the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD transits to high. The bitline BL is pre-charged to low, separately. In the &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is disabled to low, when an address is decoded. The wordline application signal WL is enabled to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and, particularly, generates a voltage of (Vcc&plus;aVtn) higher than external supply voltage in the &lsquo;E&rsquo; period, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; is a value greater than 1.5. The plateline application signal PL is enabled to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, disabled to low in rest of the periods. Therefore, both the wordline application signal WL, and the plateline application signal PL have a single pulse waveform. The sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW has a double pulse waveform. In the &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, the first high pulse is generated, for application of a cell data value to the bitline BL through the sub-bitline SBL, and disabled to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, to cut off a signal flow in the sub-bitline SBL, and in the bitline BL. Then, the SBSW signal is enabled to high in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods again, to generate the second pulse (Vcc&plus;aVtn) higher than Vcc, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; has a value greater than 1.5. In the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW, the first pulse is an operation for loading the cell data on the bitline, and the second pulse is a step for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken at the first pulse, or to be written, newly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In order to re-write a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is used for re-writing a low data. That is, the data is written again not after operation of the sense amplifier is finished by using the low data on the bitline, but a low data is written on the cell by using the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD. Therefore, in the data writing of the present invention, since writing of the low data can be made independent from the operation of the sense amplifier, the data writing can be made even if the sense amplifier is in operation, that can reduce a cell operation time period, and a cycle time period by eliminating a time period required for reinforcing the low data after data amplification by the sense amplifier. In more detail, the low data is reinforced by the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD, and only the high data is written by the bitline BL, again. As a method for reinforcing the low data, the SBPD signal is set to high in &lsquo;C&lsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, to pull down the sub-bitline to low, forcibly. In this instance, as the WL, and PL signals are in an enabled state to high, the low data is written on the cell by the low level, again. In a non-selected sub-cell array block, the sub-bitline enable switch signal SBSW is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD is at high to keep the sub-bitline at low. In the meantime, a sense amplifier enable signal SEN is enabled to high in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, for amplifying a bitline sensing data. The high data amplified thus is restored in the &lsquo;E&rsquo; period, again. If a column selection signal C/S is enabled to high in &lsquo;D&rsquo; period at a time point the amplification is finished, the amplified bitline data is loaded on a data bus outside of the cell array. On the other hand, in a write mode, since a data on an external data bus forcibly changes the data on the bitline, a new high data is written in &lsquo;E&rsquo; period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> As has been explained, the ferroelectric memory, and the method for driving the same of the present invention have the following advantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The reduction of the bitline resistance and the capacitance made available by the present invention permits efficient fabrication of the cell array, and improvement of device characteristics, irrespective of a design rule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The writing of a low data on a cell by using the sub-bitline pull down signal SBPD permits an independent writing of the low data, irrespective of the operation of the sense amplifier, that implies the data writing is made even during the sense amplifier is in operation, eliminating a time period required for reinforcing the low data continuous to the amplification by the sense amplifier, thereby reducing a cell operation time period, and a cycle time period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the ferroelectric memory, and the method for driving the same of the present invention of the present invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. Thus, it is intended that the present invention cover the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A ferroelectric memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cell array block having a plurality of sub-cell array blocks regularly arranged in columns and rows, each sub-cell array block includes a plurality of unit cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of main bitlines disposed along a first direction corresponding to the sub-cell array blocks in column units; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitlines disposed along the first direction in a one-to-one correspondence to the sub-cell array blocks; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pairs of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines and sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines disposed along a second direction perpendicular to the first direction, each pair corresponding to the sub-cell array block for applying a sub-bitline enable switch signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of switching control blocks, each corresponding to the sub-cell array block for one of enabling the sub-bitlines selectively in response to the sub-bitline enable switch signal and pulling down the sub-bitlines in response to the sub-bitline pull down signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of switching control blocks each include first and second switching transistors interconnected in series, wherein the first switching transistor has a gate connected to the sub-bitline pull down signal application line, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, the second switching transistor has a gate connected to the sub-bitline enable signal application line, and one side electrode connected to one of the main bitlines, and an output terminal the first, and second switching transistors are commonly connected to one of the sub-bitlines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of unit cells each include: 
<claim-text>first and second split wordlines disposed along the second direction and spaced apart by a fixed distance; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second bitlines disposed along the first direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first transistor having a gate connected to the first split wordline and a drain connected to the first bitline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the first transistor and the second split wordline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor having a gate connected to the second split wordline, and a drain connected to the second bitline; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second ferroelectric capacitor connected between a source of the second transistor and the first split wordline. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a split wordline driver disposed between column units and connected to adjacent sub-cell array blocks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of unit cells each include: 
<claim-text>first and second split wordlines disposed along the second direction and spaced apart by a fixed distance; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second bitlines disposed along the first direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first transistor disposed on a first side of the split wordline driver and having a gate connected to the first split wordline, and a drain connected to the first bitline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first ferroelectric capacitor FC<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> connected between a source of the first transistor and the second split wordline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor on a second side of the split wordline driver and having a gate connected to the second split wordline and a drain connected to the second bitline; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second ferroelectric capacitor connected between a source of the second transistor and the first split wordline. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of unit cells each include: 
<claim-text>a bitline disposed along the first direction, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wordline disposed along the second direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plateline disposed along the second direction and spaced apart by a distance from the wordline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transistor having a gate connected to the wordline, and a source connected to the bitline; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ferroelectric capacitor having a first terminal connected to a drain of the transistor and a second terminal connected to the plateline. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cell array block includes: 
<claim-text>a top cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom cell array block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier disposed the top cell array block and the bottom cell array block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of reference cell array blocks, each disposed corresponding to the top cell array block and the bottom cell array block.. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of reference cell array blocks each include: 
<claim-text>a plurality of bitlines disposed along the first direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one reference wordline disposed along the second direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference plateline disposed along the second direction and in parallel to the at least one reference wordline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of reference capacitors connected in parallel, each having a first electrode connected to the reference plateline, and a second electrode connected to a storage node of the reference cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a level initializing portion of an NMOS transistor having a gate with a reference cell equalizing control signal applied thereto, a first side electrode connected to a ground terminal, and a second side electrode connected to the storage node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching block having a plurality of NMOS transistors, each having a first side electrode connected to the bitline, a second side electrode connected to the storage node of the reference capacitor, and a gate connected to the reference wordline. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A ferroelectric memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cell array block having a plurality of sub-cell array blocks, each with a plurality of unit cells regularly arranged in a column direction, and a row direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of main bitlines disposed in a first direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitlines disposed in the first direction, each corresponding to one of the sub-cell array blocks; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pairs of split wordlines within each of the sub-cell array blocks disposed along a second direction perpendicular to the first direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitline pull down application lines and sub-bitline enable switch application lines disposed along the second direction, each corresponding to the sub-cell array block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of switching control blocks, each disposed corresponding to one of the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines and one of the sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal, and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of switching control blocks each include first and second switching transistors interconnected in series, wherein the first switching transistor has a gate connected to one of the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and a first side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, and the second switching transistor has a gate connected to one of the sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines, and a first side electrode connected to one of the main bitlines, and an output terminal commonly connecting the first and second switching transistors to the one of the sub-bitlines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, as only one of the sub-bitline enable switch signals is enabled at one time point, each of the main bitlines are selectively connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines in one time of operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the sub-bitline pull down signal is enabled, a level of the selected sub-bitline is pulled down to Vss. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A ferroelectric memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cell array block having sub-cell array blocks each with a plurality of unit cells arranged in a column direction, and a row direction regularly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a split wordline driver disposed at a center of the sub-cell array blocks divided in column units; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of main bitlines running in one direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitlines each in correspondence to a sub-cell array block running in a direction the same with the main bitlines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pairs of split wordlines in each of the sub-cell array blocks running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines and sub-bitlines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and a plurality of sub-bitline enable switch application lines disposed along a direction the same with the split wordlines each in correspondence to the sub-cell array block; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of switching control blocks each disposed in correspondence to the sub-bitline pull down application line, and the sub-bitline enable switch application line, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the switching control blocks include first and second switching transistors connected in series, wherein the first switching transistor has a gate connected to the sub-bitline pull down signal application line, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, and the second switching transistor has a gate connected to the sub-bitline enable switch signal application line, and one side electrode connected to one of the main bitlines, and an output terminal commonly connected the first and second switching transistors to the sub-bitline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, as only one of the sub-bitline enable switch signals is enabled at one time point, each of the main bitlines are selectively connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines in one time of operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the sub-bitline pull down signal is enabled, a level of the selected sub-bitline is pulled down to Vss. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the split wordline driver is connected to the pairs of split wordlines of adjacent sub-cell array blocks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A ferroelectric memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cell array block having sub-cell array blocks each with a plurality of unit cells arranged in a column direction, and a row direction regularly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of main bitlines disposed along one direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitlines each in correspondence to a sub-cell array block running in a direction the same with the main bitlines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pairs of wordlines/platelines in each of the sub-cell array blocks running in a direction perpendicular both to the main bitlines and the sub-bitlines; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines running in a direction the same with pairs of the wordlines/platelines each disposed in correspondence to the sub-cell array block; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of switching control blocks each disposed in correspondence to the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and the sub-bitline enable switch signal application line, and a space between adjacent sub-cell arrays, for switching a sub-bitline pull down signal and a sub-bitline enable switch signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the switching control blocks include first and second switching transistors connected in series, wherein the first switching transistor has a gate connected to one of the sub-bitline pull down signal application lines, and one side electrode connected to a VSS terminal, and the second switching transistor has a gate connected to one of the sub-bitline enable switch signal application lines, and one side electrode connected to one of the main bitlines, and an output terminal commonly connecting the first and second switching transistors to one of the sub-bitlines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, as only one of the sub-bitline enable switch signals is enabled at one time point, each of the main bitlines are selectively connected to one of the plurality of sub-bitlines in one time of operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the sub-bitline pull down signal is enabled, a level of the selected sub-bitline is pulled down to Vss. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method for driving a ferroelectric memory of a split wordline structure for enabling, and pulling down a sub-bitline selected in response to a sub-bitline enable signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) enabling a first split wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and a second split wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods, within a continuous enable cycle divided into &lsquo;A&rsquo;, &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) enabling a sub-bitline enable switch signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period at first for applying a cell data value to a bitline through a sub-bitline, disabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods for cutting off signal flows on the sub-bitline and the bitline, and enabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to high again in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods for the second time for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, or to be written newly; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) writing a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, by using the sub-bitline pull down signal which is enabled to high only in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, regardless of operation of a sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein data writing in response to the sub-bitline enable signal and the sub-bitline pull down signal is made in unit of a plurality of sub-cell array blocks in the cell array block, and, in a non-selected sub-cell array block, the sub-bitline enable switch signal is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline pull down signal is enabled to high, to keep the sub-bitline at low. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a sense amplifier enable signal for sensing data is enabled to high in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods for amplifying a bitline sensing data, and an amplified high data is stored in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, during a cycle before &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, a REF_EQ is in a high state for leaving a reference capacitor in a discharged state, and, in rest of the enable period, which is a bitline pre-charge period, the sub-bitline enable switch signal is disabled to low, to separate the bitline and the sub-bitline from each other, and the sub-bitline is pre-charged to low as the sub-bitline pull down signal becomes high. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first split wordline application signal generates a voltage Vcc&plus;aVtn, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; denotes a value greater than 1.5 higher than an external supply voltage Vcc in &lsquo;E&rsquo; period, and the second split wordline application signal generates a voltage Vcc&plus;aVtn higher than an external supply voltage Vcc in &lsquo;F&rsquo; period. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sub-bitline enable switch signal generates a voltage Vcc&plus;aVtn, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; denotes a value greater than 1.5 higher than Vcc in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, in an enable cycle in a reference cell block, a REF_PL generates a low pulse waveform, and the REF_EQ is kept to maintain a high state for charging a reference capacitor in &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, for discharging the charge stored in the reference ferroelectric capacitor in &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, the REF_EQ is disenabled to low pulse, a REF_WL is enabled to a high pulse, and the REF_PL is transited to high, for generating a reference level on the bitline BL in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, and the REF_EQ is transited to high in periods after &lsquo;C&rsquo; period, for resetting the reference level to low again. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method for driving a ferroelectric memory of a split wordline structure for enabling, and pulling down a sub-bitline selected in response to a sub-bitline enable signal and a sub-bitline pull down signal, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) enabling a wordline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, and &lsquo;E&rsquo; periods, and a plateline application signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, within a continuous enable cycle divided into &lsquo;A&rsquo;, &lsquo;B&rsquo;, &lsquo;C&rsquo;, &lsquo;D&rsquo;, &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) enabling a sub-bitline enable switch signal to high in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period at first for applying a cell data value to a bitline through a sub-bitline, disabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to low in &lsquo;C&rsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods for cutting off signal flows on the sub-bitline, and the bitline, and enabling the sub-bitline enable switch signal to high again in &lsquo;E&rsquo;, and &lsquo;F&rsquo; periods for the second time for restoring, or re-writing a logical &lsquo;1&rsquo;, i.e., a high data, broken in &lsquo;B&rsquo; period, or to be written newly; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) writing a logical &lsquo;0&rsquo;, i.e., a low data, by using the sub-bitline pull down signal which is enabled to high only in &lsquo;C&lsquo;, and &lsquo;D&rsquo; periods, regardless of operation of a sense amplifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein data writing in response to the sub-bitline enable signal and the sub-bitline pull down signal is made in unit of a plurality of sub-cell array blocks in the cell array block, and, in a non-selected sub-cell array block, the sub-bitline enable switch signal is disabled to low, and the sub-bitline pull down signal is enabled to high, to keep the sub-bitline at low. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, during a cycle before &lsquo;A&rsquo; period, a REF_EQ is in a high state for leaving a reference capacitor in a discharged state, and, in rest of the enable period, which is a bitline pre-charge period, the sub-bitline enable switch signal is disabled to low, to separate the bitline and the sub-bitline from each other, and the sub-bitline is pre-charged to low as the sub-bitline pull down signal becomes high. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wordline application signal and the signal generate voltages Vcc&plus;aVtn, where &lsquo;a&rsquo; denotes a value greater than 1.5 higher than an external supply voltage Vcc in &lsquo;E&rsquo; period.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002317A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
