<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001200A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001200A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001200A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001200A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001200A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001200A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001200A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001200A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001200A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001200A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001200</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896741</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/336</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/76</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/94</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>330000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>332000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>270000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Modified vertical MOSFET and methods of formation thereof</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ramachandra</given-name>
<family-name>Divakaruni</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Somers</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Prakash</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Dev</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Plano</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Rajeev</given-name>
<family-name>Malik</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Pleasantville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Larry</given-name>
<family-name>Nesbit</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Williston</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>International Business Machines Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Armonk</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Philmore H. Colburn II</name-1>
<name-2>Cantor Colburn LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>55 Griffin Road South</address-1>
<city>Bloomfield</city>
<state>CT</state>
<postalcode>06002</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The vertical MOSFET structure used in forming dynamic random access memory comprises a gate stack structure comprising one or more silicon nitride spacers; a vertical gate polysilicon region disposed in an array trench, wherein the vertical gate polysilicon region comprises one or more silicon nitride spacers; a bitline diffusion region; a shallow trench isolation region bordering the array trench; and wherein the gate stack structure is disposed on the vertical gate polysilicon region such that the silicon nitride spacers of the gate stack structure and vertical gate polysilicon region form a borderless contact with both the bitline diffusion region and shallow trench isolation region. The vertical gate polysilicon is isolated from both the bitline diffusion and shallow trench isolation region by the nitride spacer, which provides reduced bitline capacitance and reduced incidence of bitline diffusion to vertical gate shorts. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to processes for the fabrication of integrated circuit devices on semiconductor substrates, and in particular to processes by which self-aligned spacers in vertical gate DRAMs are formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A DRAM (dynamic random access memory) circuit usually includes an array of memory cells interconnected by rows and columns, which are known as wordlines (WLs) and bitlines (BLs), respectively. Reading data from or writing data to memory cells is achieved by activating selected wordlines and bitlines. Typically, a DRAM memory cell comprises a MOSFET (metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor) connected to a capacitor. The transistor includes gate and diffusion regions which are referred to as either drain or source regions, depending on the operation of the transistor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There are different types of MOSFETs. A planar MOSFET is a transistor where a surface of the channel region of the transistor is generally parallel to the primary surface of the substrate. A vertical MOSFET is a transistor where a surface of the channel region of the transistor is generally perpendicular to the primary surface of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Trench capacitors are also frequently used with DRAM cells. A trench capacitor is a three-dimensional structure formed into a silicon substrate. This is normally formed by etching trenches of various dimensions into the silicon substrate. Trenches commonly have N&plus; doped polysilicon as one plate of the capacitor (a storage node). The other plate of the capacitor is formed usually by diffusing N&plus; dopants out from a dopant source into a portion of the substrate surrounding the lower part of the trench. Between these two plates, a dielectric layer is placed which thereby forms the capacitor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To prevent carriers from traveling through the substrate between the adjacent devices, device isolation regions are formed between adjacent semiconductor devices. Generally, device isolation regions take the form of thick oxide regions extending below the surface of the semiconductor substrate. A sharply defined trench is formed in the semiconductor substrate by, for example, anisotropic etching. The trench is filled with oxide back to the surface of the substrate to provide a device isolation region. Trench isolation regions thus formed are called shallow trench isolation (STI) and have the advantages of providing device isolation regions across their entire lateral extent and of providing a more planar structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> DRAM technology beyond the one hundred nanometer technology node requires the use of vertical MOSFETs to overcome the scalability limitations of planar MOSFET DRAM access transistors. Vertical MOSFETs allow the bit densities required for effective size reduction. However, the use of vertical MOSFETs is not yet widespread and several characteristics need to be optimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For example, as a result of increased gate conductor to bitline diffusion overlap area, total bitline capacitance may be larger with vertical MOSFETs than with conventional planar MOSFET structures. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a vertical MOSFET in which the vertical gate conductor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> overlaps the entire depth of the bitline diffusion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Thus, MOSFET structure <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes trench top oxide layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, gate conductor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, gate nitride cap <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, bitline diffusion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, storage node diffusion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and diffusion stud <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The large overlap <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> over the entire depth of the bitline diffusion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> contributes to a larger total bitline capacitance with this vertical MOSFET than with a conventional planar MOSFET. Prior attempts to address this generally require that the depth of the bitline diffusion be minimized. However, minimization of bitline diffusion depth is complicated by the fact that integration requirements may dictate a relatively high thermal budget (i.e., bitline diffusion (BL) needing to be performed relatively early in the process). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An additional drawback of vertical MOSFETs is the occurrence of wordline to bitline diffusion shorts, also referred to as WL-BL shorts. The reason for increased wordline to bitline shorts is because the gate conductor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is connected to the vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in the trench. This is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, where a prior art vertical MOSFET structure is shown with a misalignment between the edge of the gate conductor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the edge of the deep trench. The misalignment causes the occurrence of WL-BL shorts, as indicated at <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. To prevent WL-BL shorts, the formation of spacers inside of the deep trench has been proposed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/757,514 and U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/790,011, both commonly assigned to the assignee. However, the present invention teaches the structure and method to form these spacers after formation of the STI and in a manner that reduces cost as compared to the methods of the previous art. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A method for forming a semiconductor memory cell array structure comprises providing a vertical MOSFET DRAM cell structure having a deposited polysilicon layer planarized to a top surface of a trench top oxide in an array trench of a silicon substrate; forming a shallow trench isolation oxide region along the array trench; etching the polysilicon layer selective to a nitride layer on the silicon substrate to form one or more silicon nitride spacers between a bitline diffusion region and a vertical gate polysilicon region, and between the shallow trench isolation oxide region and vertical gate polysilicon region; and depositing a gate stack structure over the vertical gate polysilicon region and between one or more silicon nitride spacers to form a borderless contact between the gate stack structure and bitline diffusion region, and shallow trench isolation oxide region. This invention is different from the earlier inventions disclosed in both U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/757,514 and U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/790,011, in the fact that the vertical gate polysilicon is not only isolated from the bitline diffusion by the nitride spacer, but also from the isolation oxide by the nitride spacer since the nitride spacer is formed after the shallow trench isolation (STI). This additional feature prevents electrical shorting of the vertical gate polysilicon from the direction of the isolation oxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A vertical MOSFET structure used in forming dynamic random access memory comprises a gate stack structure comprising one or more silicon nitride spacers; a vertical gate polysilicon region disposed in an array trench, wherein the vertical gate polysilicon region comprises one or more silicon nitride spacers; a bitline diffusion region; a shallow trench isolation region bordering the array trench; and wherein the gate stack structure is disposed on the vertical gate polysilicon region such that the silicon nitride spacers of the gate stack structure and vertical gate polysilicon region form a borderless contact with the bitline diffusion region and shallow trench isolation region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The vertical MOSFET formed by this method features reduced vertical gate to top diffusion overlap capacitance (reduced bitline capacitance), and reduced incidence of bitline diffusion to vertical gate shorts (reduced incidence of WL-BL shorts). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The above described and other features are exemplified by the following figures and detailed description.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> illustrate cross-sectional views of prior art embodiments of vertical MOSFET structures; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are cross-sectional views illustrating the process steps for the formation a deep trench spacer in a vertical gate region after the formation of the STI; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a vertical MOSFET structure of the prior art; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a top view of a vertical MOSFET structure manufactured according to the process steps of FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrate the method for manufacturing any type of vertical MOSFET structure for a vertical pass gate DRAM arrays. To eliminate and/or reduce the likelihood of WL-BL shorts occurring in vertical pass gate DRAM arrays, a silicon nitride spacer is added in the vertical gate poly region to provide an insulating layer between the gate conductor stud polysilicon and bitline diffusion. The silicon nitride spacers reduce the overlap capacitance between the array wordline and bitline diffusion junction, and create a borderless contact between the vertical MOSFET and bitline diffusion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring now to a cross-sectional view of a silicon substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> silicon substrate, having undergone deep trench, buried strap, vertical gate and active area processing using one or more known methods, or a combination thereof, comprises a silicon substrate surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> comprising one or more vertical gate regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, a bitline diffusion region <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, an optional oxide collar <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, a layer of array top oxide <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and a layer of silicon nitride (not shown) disposed on the silicon substrate surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The deposited polysilicon can be doped in situ, or the silicon substrate and deposited polysilicon can be doped one or more times using one or more known doping techniques such as diffusion processes, ion implantation processes, combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing doping techniques, and the like. For purposes of illustration, the vertical gate polysilicon regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> forms an N-Field Effect Transistor (N-FET), within a P-type silicon substrate. It is to be noted that the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> may be arrived at by many methods known in the art including, but not limited to, the above-mentioned methods. It is also to be noted that FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> only show the vertical transistor of a more complete structure, which might include a deep trench capacitor connected to the bottom part of the vertical transistor, or a buried bitline (or other known type of conductor), which is connected to the bottom part of the vertical transistor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the vertical gate regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are filled with polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, preferably N&plus; doped polysilicon, and recessed using a poly recess technique known in the art that is selective to the trench top oxide <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and the oxide of the STI region (not shown). The deposited polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is recessed below the silicon surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by preferably about 10 nanometer to about 100 nanometers, more preferably about 50 nanometers below the silicon substrate. N&plus; doped polysilicon can be deposited using an in situ chemical vapor deposition techniques (&ldquo;CVD&rdquo;) such as low pressure CVD (&ldquo;LPCVD&rdquo;), combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing CVD techniques, and the like. In the alternative, intrinsic polysilicon can also be deposited by CVD techniques, and subsequently doped to form N&plus; doped polysilicon within the vertical gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the silicon substrate is further processed using either LPCVD or plasma-enhanced CVD (&ldquo;PECVD&rdquo;) techniques, as well as combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing techniques, and the like, to form a layer of silicon nitride <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> comprising a thickness of preferably about 5 nanometers to about 100 nanometers. The silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is disposed over the trench top oxide layer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, exposed sidewalls of the vertical gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and the vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is then removed from the periphery or support areas (not shown), i.e., non-array regions, by a masking method, and a sacrificial layer of silicon oxide (not shown) is grown over the support areas. It is to be noted that prior to growing the sacrificial support oxide, the array top oxide <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is removed in the support areas by known methods such as wet etching in hydrogen fluoride based chemistries. The support sacrificial oxide is thermally grown from the exposed silicon substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the support regions. The silicon nitride <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the array region protects the vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> from being oxidized. The support implants (not shown) are formed, sacrificial oxide stripped, support gate oxide grown, and a layer of gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is deposited. The resulting array region is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the support polysilicon <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is masked and etched in the array using a resist mask and etch process. The resist is patterned such that the polysilicon <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is exposed in the array region, but is covered in the support regions. This allows for the polysilicon <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to be removed by a chemical downstream etching technique (&ldquo;CDE&rdquo;) that isotropically removes the polysilicon <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> in the array selective to the underlying nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is then etched anisotropically using known methods such as reactive ion etching (&ldquo;RIE&rdquo;) to form silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The resist material is then stripped from the entire silicon wafer surface. In the alternative, after the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is etched forming the spacer, additional spacers may be formed. Once the silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are formed, the gate conductor can be formed according to methods known in the art. The gate conductor fills the space between the spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> in the array trenches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The photoresist material can be stripped away using a stripping method or a combination of stripping methods. When stripping photoresist material from a surface such as silicon, examples of possible resist stripping methods can comprise wet chemical stripping methods (such as phenolic organic strippers, solvent/amine strippers, specialty wet strippers), dry stripping, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring now to an alternative embodiment in FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a layer of polysilicon <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, or preferably N&plus; doped polysilicon <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, comprising a thickness of preferably about 1000 angstroms to about 2000 angstroms, more preferably about 1200 angstroms, is deposited over the silicon substrate illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The deposited polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is then blanket recessed to planarize the deposited polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> with the array top oxide layer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the rest of the gate stack is deposited using methods known in the art. The gate stack structures comprise a gate <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> preferably comprising tungsten, tungsten nitride, tungsten silicide, combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing materials, and the like, and a gate nitride cap <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The gate stack structure is patterned before one or more silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are formed using LPCVD techniques, PECVD techniques, nitridation techniques, combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing techniques, and the like. More particularly, a silicon nitride spacer <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is formed along each sidewall of the gate stack structure. The array top oxide layer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is etched selectively to nitride, i.e., silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, until exposing the silicon substrate surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The resulting silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> contact the silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> which creates an insulating layer between the gate stack structure and bitline diffusion region <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, allowing for the subsequent bitline contact to be borderless to the array vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As referenced earlier, beginning with the silicon substrate illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> gate <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> as described above can be formed between the silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> on the vertical gate polysilicon regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> using known methods such as CVD techniques, to deposit the gate conductor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> conformally, until filling the vertical gate polysilicon regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> between the silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The gate nitride cap <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is then formed using LPCVD techniques, PECVD techniques, nitridation techniques, combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing techniques, and the like, on the gate <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to form one or more gate stack structures. The resulting gate stack structures are then etched, and one or more silicon nitride spacers <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are formed on both sidewalls of the gate stack structures using LPCVD techniques, PECVD techniques, nitridation techniques, combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing techniques, and the like, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Once the gate stack structures are formed and aligned on the silicon substrate surface, the substrate can be further processed to form devices and local interconnect such as forming bitlines, interlevel dielectrics, additional wiring levels, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, after the sacrificial support oxidation and support implants are formed, the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is etched by RIE to form a spacer <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> in the array. During the support gate oxidation, the array vertical gate polysilicon <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is oxidized (not shown) and this oxide is removed by known hydrogen fluoride based wet etch methods before polysilicon <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> or gate conductor <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is deposited. In yet another embodiment, the silicon nitride spacer <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is formed before the silicon nitride layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is deposited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> It is to be noted that top view of the structure presented in this invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is different from the prior art shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the inner spacers <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are only formed between the deep trench <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and active area <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. However, in the present invention the inner spacers <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are formed after shallow trench isolation (STI), thus the spacers <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are formed along the entire surface of the exposed trench <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, and along the edge of the STI oxide region <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to an exemplary embodiment, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for forming a semiconductor memory cell array structure, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a vertical MOSFET DRAM cell structure having a deposited polysilicon layer planarized to a top surface of a trench top oxide in an array trench of a silicon substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a shallow trench isolation oxide region along said array trench; </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching said polysilicon layer selective to a nitride layer on said silicon substrate to form one or more silicon nitride spacers between a bitline diffusion region and a vertical gate polysilicon region, and between said shallow trench isolation oxide region and said vertical gate polysilicon region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate stack structure over said vertical gate polysilicon region and between said one or more silicon nitride spacers to form a borderless contact between said gate stack structure and said bitline diffusion region, and said shallow trench isolation oxide region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said etch further comprises reactive ion etching said nitride layer to form said silicon nitride spacers on one or more sidewalls of said vertical gate polysilicon region, and bordering said bitline diffusion region and said shallow trench isolation oxide region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said deposition further comprises 
<claim-text>depositing a polysilicon layer on said nitride layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>blanket recessing said polysilicon layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate stack and a gate cap nitride to form said gate stack structures between said silicon nitride spacers on said vertical gate polysilicon region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said gate stack structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming one or more silicon nitride spacers on one or more sidewalls of said gate stack structure, wherein said silicon nitride spacers contact said silicon nitride spacers of said vertical gate polysilicon regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching said trench top oxide to expose said silicon substrate and said bitline diffusion region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said deposition further comprises 
<claim-text>depositing a gate stack between said silicon nitride spacers on said vertical gate polysilicon region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate cap nitride on said gate stack to form a gate stack structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming one or more silicon nitride spacers on one or more sidewalls of said gate stack structure, wherein said silicon nitride spacers contact and vertically align with said silicon nitride spacers of said silicon substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing a polysilicon into said vertical gate polysilicon region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising forming a nitride layer comprising a thickness of about five nanometers to about one hundred nanometers on said deposited polysilicon layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said formation further comprises a deposition technique selected from the group consisting of low pressure chemical vapor deposition techniques, plasma-enhanced chemical vapor deposition techniques, and combinations comprising at least one of the foregoing deposition techniques. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method for forming a semiconductor memory cell array structure, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a vertical MOSFET DRAM cell structure having a deposited polysilicon layer planarized to a top surface of a trench top oxide in an array trench of a silicon substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a shallow trench isolation oxide region along said array trench; </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching said polysilicon layer selective to a nitride layer on said silicon substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching said nitride layer to form one or more silicon nitride spacers between a vertical gate polysilicon region and said shallow trench isolation region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a second polysilicon layer on said nitride layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>blanket recessing said second polysilicon layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate stack and a gate cap nitride to form said gate stack structures between said silicon nitride spacers on said vertical gate polysilicon region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning said gate stack structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming one or more silicon nitride spacers on one or more sidewalls of said gate stack structure, wherein said silicon nitride spacers contact said silicon nitride spacers of said vertical gate polysilicon region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching said trench top oxide to expose said silicon substrate and said bitline diffusion region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method for forming a semiconductor memory cell array structure, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a vertical MOSFET DRAM cell structure having a deposited polysilicon layer planarized to a top surface of a trench top oxide in an array trench of a silicon substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a shallow trench isolation oxide region along said array trench; </claim-text>
<claim-text>isotropically removing said polysilicon layer selective to a nitride layer on said silicon substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>anisotropically etching said nitride layer to form one or more silicon nitride spacers bordering a vertical gate polysilicon region of said silicon substrate, and located between said vertical gate polysilicon region and said shallow trench isolation regions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate stack between said silicon nitride spacers on said vertical gate polysilicon region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a gate cap nitride on said gate stack to form a gate stack structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming one or more silicon nitride spacers on one or more sidewalls of said gate stack structure, wherein said silicon nitride spacers contact said silicon nitride spacers of said vertical gate polysilicon region and insulate said gate stack structure from said bitline diffusion region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A vertical MOSFET structure used in forming dynamic random access memory, comprising: 
<claim-text>a gate stack structure comprising one or more silicon nitride spacers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical gate polysilicon region disposed in an array trench, wherein said vertical gate polysilicon region comprises one or more silicon nitride spacers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bitline diffusion region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shallow trench isolation region bordering said array trench; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said gate stack structure is disposed on said vertical gate polysilicon region such that said silicon nitride spacers of said gate stack structure and said vertical gate polysilicon region form a borderless contact with said bitline diffusion region and said shallow trench isolation region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The vertical MOSFET structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an oxide collar formed on a sidewall of said vertical gate polysilicon region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The vertical MOSFET structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said silicon nitride spacers are formed on a sidewall of said gate stack structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The vertical MOSFET structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said silicon nitride spacers are formed on a sidewall of said vertical gate polysilicon region and between said bitline diffusion region and said vertical gate polysilicon region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The vertical MOSFET structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said borderless contact further comprises said silicon nitride spacers of said gate stack structure and said silicon nitride spacers of said vertical gate polysilicon region are vertically aligned. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A vertical MOSFET structure used in forming dynamic random access memory, comprising: 
<claim-text>a gate stack structure comprising one or more silicon nitride spacers disposed on a sidewall of said gate stack structure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical gate polysilicon region comprising one or more silicon nitride spacers disposed on a sidewall, and opposite a bitline diffusion region and a shallow trench isolation region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said gate stack structure is disposed on said vertical gate polysilicon region such that said silicon nitride spacers of said gate stack structure and said vertical gate polysilicon region are in contact and vertically align to form a borderless contact between said gate stack structure and said bitline diffusion region, and between said gate stack structure and said bitline diffusion region.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001200A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001200A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001200A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001200A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001200A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
