<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002124A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002124A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002124</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10203310</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020806</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0002768.0</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000207</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0002769.8</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000207</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02F001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>237000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>515000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical free space signalling system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alan</given-name>
<middle-name>Edward</middle-name>
<family-name>Green</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ickleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Etian</given-name>
<family-name>Morrison</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ickleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Adrian</given-name>
<middle-name>Craig Michael</middle-name>
<family-name>Swinburne</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ickleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>John</middle-name>
<family-name>Morland</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ickleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<family-name>Reynolds</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ickleton</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Fogg Slifer Polglaze</name-1>
<name-2>Leffert &amp; Jay</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO Box 581009</address-1>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55458-1009</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/GB01/00479</doc-number>
<document-date>20010207</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">There is described a signalling device having a plurality of electro-optic elements and a lens system which is operable to receive a plurality of incoming free-space light beams from respective different light sources and direct the received light beams to respective ones of the electro-optic elements. The layout and/or shape of the electro-optic elements in the signalling device is adapted in accordance with a predetermined distribution of light sources. In this way, the number of electro-optic elements can be reduced. In an alternative embodiment, there is provided a signalling device having an electro-optic device, a plurality of lens systems having respective different fields of view, and a plurality of reflecting surfaces. Each reflecting surface is associated with a corresponding one of the plurality of lens systems, and the associated reflecting surface and lens system pairs are arranged so that the electro-optic device is provided in common to the plurality of lens systems. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a signalling system. In particular, this invention relates to a signalling method and apparatus in which data is conveyed by modulating a light beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In recent years, the rapid increase in data transmitted over local area networks (LANs), wide area networks (WANs), the Internet and the like has prompted a large amount of research into increasing data transfer rates by using modulated optical beams to convey information. To date, this research has concentrated on systems in which the optical beams are transmitted along optical fibres. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A problem with using optical fibres is that their installation can be expensive and time consuming. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It has been proposed to use free-space optical beams in communication links between locations within a line-of-sight of each other in order to remove the requirement for optical fibres. International Patent Applications WO 98/35328 and WO 00/48338, the whole contents of which are incorporated herein by reference, describe point-to-multipoint communication systems utilising such free-space optical beams. In particular, WO 98/35328 and WO 00/48338 describe systems in which a plurality of user stations (provided, for example, on respective houses in a street) emit unmodulated light beams which are directed to a local distribution node (provided, for example, on a post in the street). At the local distribution node, each of the incoming light beams is modulated by a respective modulator element of an array of modulator elements, which are individually driveable in accordance with corresponding streams of data, and is reflected back to the user station from which it originated. At the user station, the modulated light beam is detected and the corresponding data stream is regenerated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An aim of the invention is to adapt a signalling device, for example the local distribution node, in view of the environment in which it will be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a first aspect of the invention, there is provided a signalling device having a plurality of modulating elements and a lens system which is operable to receive a plurality of incoming light beams from respective different light sources and direct the received light beams to respective different modulating elements, which modulate the corresponding light beams in accordance with modulation data. The layout and/or shape of the modulating elements in the signalling device is adapted in accordance with a predetermined distribution of light sources. In this way, the number of modulating elements can be reduced which in turn reduces the complexity of the signalling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the aspect ratio of the modulator elements is greater than two for the case where more light sources are expected in a first direction than in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. This enables the number of modulating elements in the second direction to be reduced without significantly affecting coverage in the second direction. More preferably, the aspect ratio of the modulator elements is greater than five, and still more preferably the aspect ratio is greater than ten. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the number of modulators in the second direction is one or two because this allows all the modulator elements to be addressed from their sides, thereby reducing the complexity of fabricating the signalling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a second aspect of the invention, there is provided a signalling device having a plurality of detectors and a lens system which is operable to receive a plurality of incoming modulated light beams from respective different light sources and direct the received light beams onto respective different detectors, which detect the light beams and convert them into corresponding electrical signals, wherein the layout and/or shape of the detectors is adapted in accordance with a predetermined distribution of light sources. In this way, the number of detectors can be reduced which in turn reduces the complexity of the signalling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the aspect ratio of the detectors is greater than two for the case where more light sources are expected in a first direction than a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. This enables the number of detectors in the second direction to be reduced without significantly affecting coverage in the second direction. More preferably, the aspect ratio of the modulator elements is greater than five, and still more preferably the aspect ratio is greater than ten. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the number of detectors in the second direction is one or two because this allows all the detectors to be addressed from their sides, thereby reducing the complexity of fabricating the signalling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a third aspect of the invention, there is provided a signalling device having an electro-optic device, a plurality of lens systems having respective different fields of view, and a plurality of reflecting surfaces. Each reflecting surface is associated with a corresponding one of the plurality of lens systems, and the associated reflecting surface and lens system pairs are arranged so that the electro-optic device is provided in common to the plurality of lens systems. By using said plurality of reflecting surfaces, each lens system can have a longer focal length as the field of view it is required to cover is smaller. Therefore, for a given f/number, the lens systems have larger collection apertures. In this way, a field of view of up to a full 360&deg; can be attained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The electro-optic device may comprise an array of modulator elements. Alternatively, the electro-optic device may comprise an array of light emitting elements. As a further alternative, the electro-optic device may comprise an array of detectors.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Exemplary embodiments of the invention will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a system for distributing data to a plurality of buildings; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram of a local distribution node and a user station which form part of the data distribution system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing a retro-reflector and modem unit which forms part of the local distribution node illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of one modulator of a pixelated modulator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in a first operational mode when no DC bias is applied to electrodes thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of one modulator of the pixelated modulator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in a second operational mode when a bias voltage is applied to the electrodes; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is signal diagram which illustrates the way in which the light incident on a pixel of the modulator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is modulated in dependence upon the bias voltage applied to the pixel electrodes; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a surface of the pixelated modulator forming part of the retro-reflector and modem unit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing a local distribution node of the data distribution system illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> mounted to a wall of a building; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating the mapping of the pixels of the pixelated modulator shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> to corresponding positions on a building; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a system for distributing data to road vehicles; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic block diagram showing the form of a roadside unit and a car terminal for the data distribution system illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing the form of an emitter and detector array of the car terminal illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing the form of a pixelated modulator forming part of the retro-reflector and modem unit in the road terminal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a point-to-multipoint data distribution system in which a local distribution node is surrounded in one plane by user stations; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of components of a local distribution node of the data distribution system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view of the components of the local distribution node shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a first alternative set of components for the local distribution node of the data distribution system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a second alternative set of components for the local distribution node shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view of an alternative set of the components of the local distribution node shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically illustrates a data distribution system which employs a point-to-multipoint signalling system to transmit data to and receive data from a plurality of user stations. As shown, the data distribution system comprises a central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which transmits optical data signals to and receives optical data signals from a plurality of local distribution nodes <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>via respective optical fibres <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> At the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, data streams received from the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are transmitted to respective user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>provided on a building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and data for transmission to the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is received from the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>using free-space optical links <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>i.e. optical links in which light is not guided along an optical fibre path. Similarly, data is transmitted between the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>provided on a building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>using free-space optical links <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j, </italic></highlight>and data is transmitted between the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and local stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>o </italic></highlight>provided on a building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>using free-space optical links <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>o. </italic></highlight>Each of the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to at least one user device (not shown) in the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the user devices include a television set (not shown), which transmits channel information to the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and in response receives corresponding television signals, and a computer system (not shown), which accesses the Internet via the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> emits a low divergence, free-space light beam which is directed at the corresponding local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The emitted light beam is either modulated at the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to convey data from the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to the corresponding local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, or is unmodulated for subsequent modulation and retro-reflection at the corresponding local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to convey data from the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has a plurality of modulating elements (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) which communicate with user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in corresponding parts of the corresponding building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, with the aspect ratio of the modulating elements being adapted for the likely distribution of the users within the corresponding building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In particular, it has been recognised that it is unlikely that there are more than two different users in a single floor of the building, whereas each floor in the building is likely to house different users. Therefore, the number of modulator elements in the direction which corresponds to the horizontal direction on the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> has been reduced to two, with the length of the modulator elements in the direction corresponding to the horizontal direction being greater than the width in the direction corresponding to the vertical direction on the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in order to reduce any loss of coverage of the side of the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> schematically illustrates in more detail the main components of one of the local distribution nodes <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and one of the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the data distribution system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the local distribution node comprises a communications control unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> which (i) receives the optical signals transmitted along the optical fibre <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> conveying data from the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; (ii) regenerates the conveyed data from the received optical signals and generates corresponding drive signals <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> for the modulator elements; and (iii) receives messages <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> transmitted from the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and transmits them to the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as optical signals along the corresponding optical fibre <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. When generating the drive signals <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> from the received data, the communications control unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> encodes the received data with error correction coding and coding to reduce the effects inter-symbol-interference and other kinds of well known sources of interference such as from the sun and other light sources. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> also comprises a retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which is arranged to receive light beams <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which are within its field of view, to modulate the respective light beam in accordance with the appropriate drive signals <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and to reflect the modulated light beams back to the respective user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In the event that an optical beam <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> received from one of the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> carries a message <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, then the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> retrieves the message <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and sends it to the communications control unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> where it is processed and transmitted to the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> also shows the main components of one of the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. As shown, the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> comprises a laser diode <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> which outputs a beam <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of coherent light. In this embodiment, the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are designed so that they can communicate with a local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> within a range of 200 meters with a link availability of 99.9%. To achieve this, the laser diode <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is 50 mW laser diode which outputs a laser beam having a wavelength of 850 nm. The output light beam <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is passed through a collimator <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> which reduces the angle of divergence of the light beam <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The resulting light beam <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is passed through a beam splitter <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> to an optical beam expander <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, which increases the diameter of the light beam for transmitting to the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> located in the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The optical beam expander <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is used because a large diameter light beam has a smaller divergence than the small diameter light beam. Additionally, increasing the diameter of the light beam also has the advantage of spreading the power of the light beam over a larger area, allowing a higher powered laser diode <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to be used while still meeting eye-safety requirements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Using the optical beam expander <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has the further advantage that it both provides a fairly large collecting aperture for the light beam reflected from the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and concentrates the received reflected light beam into a smaller diameter beam. The smaller diameter reflective light beam is then split from the path of the original transmitted light beam by the beam splitter <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and is focussed onto a photodiode <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> by a lens <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The photodiode <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> converts the reflected light beam into an electrical signal which varies in dependence upon the drive signals <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The electrical signal is amplified by an amplifier <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and then filtered by a filter <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The filtered signals are then supplied to a clock recovery and data retrieval unit <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which regenerates the clock and the data from the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> using standard processing techniques. The retrieved data <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is then passed to an interface unit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> which is connected to the user device (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the interface device <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> also receives data from the user device and generates an appropriate message <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for transmittal to the central distribution system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> via the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. This message <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is output to a laser control unit <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> which modulates the light beam <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> output by the laser diode <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in accordance with the message <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, a half-duplex communications link, in which at any one time data is transmitted in only one direction between the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the corresponding local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, is set up in order to avoid interference between signals travelling in opposite directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The structure and function of the components in the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are well known to those skilled in the art and a more detailed description of them shall therefore be omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which is used in this embodiment. As shown, the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> comprises a modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and a telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, which is formed by a lens <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and a stop member <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> having a central aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The stop member <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> and the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> are optically located in the front focal plane <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and the back focal plane <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> respectively. Although for clarity the lens <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is shown as a single lens element, those skilled in the art will appreciate that in practice more than one lens element is likely to be used in the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> with the exact arrangement being a design choice depending on the particular requirements of installation. The size of the aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> is also a design choice, with a large aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> transmitting more of the light from the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> than a small aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> but requiring a more complex and expensive lens <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to focus the light than is required with a small aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. In practice, however, there is generally little benefit in increasing the size of the aperture <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> beyond the point where the transmission loss of the lens system <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> becomes negligible in comparison with atmospheric loss of the free space optical beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> has a field of view which covers 60&deg; in both the horizontal and vertical directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> focusses incident light onto the back focal plane <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> at a position which is related to the angle of incidence of the light. In this way, different angles of incidence within the field of view of the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> are mapped to different positions in the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. Further, the principal rays <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> transmitted through the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> are incident perpendicular to the back focal plane <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and therefore the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> reflects the incident light back along its path of incidence. In this way, the modulator <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> act as the retro-reflector. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that by using the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> can advantageously be formed using conventional planar semiconductor processing techniques because light from the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is incident normal to the planar surface of the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and is therefore reflected back along its path of incidence. Another advantage of using the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is that the efficiency of modulation, i.e. the modulation depth, of existing optical modulators generally depends upon the angle at which the light beam hits the modulator. However, using the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> ensures that the principal rays of the light beams are incident parallel to the optical axis of the modulators regardless of the position of the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> within the field of view of the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and therefore the dependency of the efficiency of modulation upon the position of the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> relative to the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is substantially removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> comprises a two-dimensional array of Quantum Confined Stark Effect (QCSE) devices (which are sometimes also referred to as Self Electro-optic Devices or SEEDs). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the cross-section of one of the QCSE devices <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. As shown, the QCSE device <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> comprises a transparent window <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> through which the light beam <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from the appropriate user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> passes, followed by three layers <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of Gallium Arsenide (GaAs) based material. Layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a p-conductivity type layer, layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is an intrinsic layer having a plurality of quantum wells formed therein, and layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is an n-conductivity type layer. Together, the three layers <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> form a p-i-n diode. As shown, the p-conductivity type layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to an electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and the n-conductivity type layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is connected to a ground terminal <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight>. A reflective layer <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, in this embodiment a Bragg reflector, is provided beneath the n-conductivity type layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and a substrate layer <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> is provided beneath the reflective layer <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In operation, the light beam <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> passes through the window <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> into the gallium arsenide based layers <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The amount of light absorbed by the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> depends upon the DC bias voltage applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. Ideally, when no DC bias is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, the light beam passes through the window <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and is totally absorbed within the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Consequently, when there is no DC Bias voltage applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, no light is reflected back to the corresponding user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, when a DC bias voltage of approximately &minus;5 volts is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the light beam from the corresponding user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> passes through the window <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and the Gallium Arsenide based layers <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the reflecting layer <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> back upon itself along the same path to the corresponding user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Therefore, by changing the bias voltage applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in accordance with the drive signals <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> from the communications control unit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the QCSE modulator <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> amplitude modulates the received light beam and reflects the modulated light beam back to the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In the ideal case, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> zero voltage bias, resulting in no reflected light, is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to transmit a binary 0 and a DC bias voltage of &minus;5 volts is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, resulting in the light from the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> being reflected back from the QCSE device <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, to transmit a binary 1. In practice, however, the QCSE modulator <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> will reflect typically 70% of the light beam when no DC bias is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and 95% of the light beam when &minus;5V DC bias is applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. Therefore, in practice, there will only be a difference of about 25% between the amount of light which is detected at the user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> when a binary 0 is transmitted and when a binary 1 is transmitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The amount of the received light beam absorbed by the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be increased by adding additional quantum wells to increase the depth of the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. However, if the depth of the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is increased, then a higher voltage must be applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in order to produce the required electric field across the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for allowing light to pass through the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. There is, therefore, a trade-off between the absorptivity of the intrinsic layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the voltage applied to the electrode <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> By using the QCSE modulators <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, modulation rates of the individual modulator cells in excess of a Gigabit per second can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the QCSE modulators <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are also used to detect modulated light beams from the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, taking advantage of the fact that each QCSE modulator is p-i-n diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the surface of the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. As shown, the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is a two-dimensional array with sixteen modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> provided in a Y-direction and two modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> provided in an X-direction perpendicular to the Y-direction. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that, by having only two modulators in the X direction, the fabrication of the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is greatly simplified because the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> can be addressed from the sides of the array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each modulator element <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> has a length of approximately 1 mm in the X direction and a width of approximately 100 &mgr;m in the Y direction. As discussed previously, in this embodiment the shape of the modulator element <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> has been selected to match the likely distribution of users within the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In particular, the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is aligned so that the X direction corresponds to the horizontal direction on the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the Y direction corresponds to the vertical direction in the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and less modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> are provided in the X direction than in the Y direction because the users are expected to be predominantly distributed in the Y direction. The length of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> in the X direction is made longer than the width in the Y direction to ensure adequate coverage of the side of the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Due to the non-uniformity in the X and Y directions of the layout of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, a person installing the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> must be able to determine the orientation of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> in order to align the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so that the X direction corresponds to the horizontal direction on the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> mounted to the wall <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> of a building. As shown, the electrical and optical components of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are mounted in a housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> having a window <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, formed on a side <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, through which light beams from the user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can pass to the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is mounted to the wall <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> using a mount (indicated generally by <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>) which includes a plate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> which can be bolted to the wall <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. An arm <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> protrudes perpendicularly from the plate <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> and terminates with an elongate hollow cylinder <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> whose longitudinal axis is vertically aligned. The mount <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> also includes a plate <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> which is bolted to the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and which has an elongate rod <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> mounted parallel with the surface of the plate <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> by supports <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The rod <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> is rotatably mounted within an elongate cylinder <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. An elongate bar <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> with a circular cross-section extends radially from a point halfway along the length of the cylinder <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>, and the end of the bar <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> remote from the cylinder <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> is inserted in the cylinder <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The elongate bar <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> is rotatable within the cylinder <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> to enable rotation of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> about a vertical axis and the elongate rod <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> is rotatable within the cylinder <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> to enable rotation of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> about a horizontal axis. Once the correct alignment of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> is achieved, then the elongate bar <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> can be fixed within the cylinder <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> by tightening a screw <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> and the elongate rod <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> can be fixed within the cylinder <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> by tightening a screw <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the plate <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> is mounted to a side <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> which is adjacent to the side <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> in which the window <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is formed. However, bolt-holes <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are also provided on a side <highlight><bold>137</bold></highlight> which is adjacent both to the side <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and the side <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, so that the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> can be mounted in an orientation which is 90&deg; to that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. A visible marking <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> is formed on the housing <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> in order to indicate the Y direction of the modulator array. Thus, on installation the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can either be arranged with the Y direction substantially vertical (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) or substantially horizontal, depending on the distribution of users within the field of view. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, the telecentric lens <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> maps each direction within its field of view to a respective position on the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> within the field of view of a local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in which the regions of the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> corresponding to each of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> within the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are schematically indicated by the hatched boxes <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As shown, user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are located at various positions by the side of the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> has six floors with each of the top five floors having two windows <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>facing the local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As schematically shown by the hatched areas <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, each window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> has two separate portions which map to respective different modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. Further, the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> corresponding to portions of a window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> also correspond to regions adjacent the sides of the window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, and modulator elements which do not correspond to a portion of a window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> map to other parts of the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the layout of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which form the modulator array has been designed to be especially suited to the building <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. In particular, it has been recognised that each of the windows <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> is likely to correspond to an individual user and that it is unlikely that an individual user will require many different optical links. Further, the shape of the modulator element has been selected to suit the area of a building corresponding to a single user, in particular by increasing the aspect ratio. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the same data will be transmitted to all user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> within the region covered by a single modulator element <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, i.e. all user terminals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> falling within a hatched box <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> will receive the same data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can be placed either in a window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> (see, for example, hatched box <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), by the side of a window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> (see, for example, hatched box <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>), or below a window <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> (see, for example hatched box <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>). If a user does require more than one optical link, then two user stations can be located in or around the appropriate window in positions corresponding to different modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> (see, for example, hatched boxes <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). Further, two user stations <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> can be located in positions corresponding to a single modulator element <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> (see, for example, hatched box <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) in order to provide a backup optical link in case an optical link is interrupted by, for example, a bird or a raindrop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> To summarise, in the first embodiment the layout and shape of the modulator elements <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> forming the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is designed to be especially suited for a particular environment of use, in particular a multi-storey building. A particular advantage of the layout in the first embodiment is that, following the realisation that only two different users are likely to be present on a single floor of a multi-storey building, the modulator elements are arranged in an &ldquo;n-by-2&rdquo; array, having n modulators in a first direction and 2 modulators in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction, which allows each modulator element to be addressed from the side, thereby greatly simplifying the design and fabrication of the modulator array <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In the first embodiment, a data distribution system is described in which data is transmitted between a local distribution node <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a user station <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which are fixed relative to each other. A second embodiment of the invention will now be described in which data is transmitted between a local distribution node and a user station which move relative to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the data distribution system of the second embodiment. As shown, a local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is mounted at the top of a post <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> which is positioned beside a road <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. The field of view of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> encompasses a corresponding distance along the road <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. As shown, cars <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>travelling along the road <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> each have a respective user station <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, hereinafter referred to as car terminals <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>, which optically communicate with the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. As in the first embodiment, the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is operable to receive data from a central distribution system (not shown) and to transmit appropriate data to the car terminals <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> via low divergence, free-space light beams <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is also operable to receive data transmitted from the car terminals <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> and to forward the received data to the central distribution system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> is connected to an input device (not shown), via which a passenger in the car <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> can request information from the central distribution system, and a display (not shown) for displaying the received, requested information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> schematically illustrates in more detail the main components of the-local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and one of the car terminals <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> of the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Components which are the same as corresponding components in the first embodiment have been referenced by the same numerals and will not be described again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, in this embodiment the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> includes an emitter and detector array and lens system <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> comprising a lens system <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight>, an emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> and a detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> comprises a two-dimensional pixelated array with a vertical cavity surface emitting laser (VCSEL) positioned at each pixel. The use of VCSELs is preferred because the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> can then be manufactured from a single semiconductor wafer, without having to cut the wafer. This allows a higher density of lasing elements than would be possible with traditional diode lasers. VCSEL arrays which output light beams having a wavelength in the region of 850 nm within the power range of between 1 mW and 30 mW are available from CSEM SA, Badenerstrasse 569, 8048 Zurich, Switzerland. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each VCSEL in the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> outputs either a modulated light beam conveying a message received from the input device in the car <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> or an unmodulated light beam which is modulated at the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and reflected back to the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. The lens system <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> directs the emitted light beam in a direction within its field of view corresponding to the position of the VCSEL emitting the light beam. As light emitted from each VCSEL is mapped to a different angle or direction within the field of view of the lens system <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight>, by selectively driving the emitter elements in the VCSEL array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, the direction of the emitted light beam within the field of view can be varied. The lens system <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> also directs a received modulated light beam, conveying data from the local distribution node <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, onto the detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight> is a two-dimensional array of photodiodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The electrical signals output by the detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight>, which will vary in dependence upon the data conveyed by the modulated light beam, are amplified by the amplifier <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, filtered by the filter <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, and then supplied to the clock recovery and data retrieval unit <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which regenerates the clock and the original data using standard processing techniques. The retrieved data <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is then input to the interface unit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> which interfaces with the display (not shown) in the car <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows in more detail the emitter and detector array and lens system <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> in the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. As shown, the VCSEL emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> is optically positioned in the back focal plane of a telecentric lens represented by the lens <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> and the stop member <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>. The stop member <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> is optically located in the front focal plane of the telecentric lens. The purpose of employing a telecentric lens is to ensure that the collection efficiency (of light from the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>) of the lens is constant across the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. Therefore, provided all the emitters are the same, the intensity of the light output from the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> will be the same for each emitter. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that with a conventional lens the intensity of the light output from the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> would be greater for light emitted by emitters in the centre of the array than for light emitted by emitters at the edge of the array. The use of a telecentric lens also avoids various cosine fall-off factors which are well known in conventional lenses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each VCSEL emits a linearly-polarised, divergent light beam which is transmitted through a polarisation beam splitter <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> and a quarter-wave plate <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight>, which converts the linearly-polarised light into left-handed circularly polarised light. The light beam is then incident on the telecentric lens which substantially collimates the light beam and directs it in a direction corresponding to the position of the originating VCSEL. The light beam reflected back from the roadside unit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>, which will be formed by right-handed circularly polarised light, is collected by the telecentric lens and directed through the quarter-wave plate <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight>, which converts the right-handed circularly-polarised light into linearly-polarised light whose polarisation is orthogonal to the linearly-polarised light emitted by the VCSELs in the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. The polarisation beam splitter <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> therefore reflects the light from the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> onto the detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight>, which is also optically located in the back focal plane of the telecentric lens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, in this embodiment only one VCSEL in the emitter array <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> is operated at a time. As discussed above, by changing the VCSEL which is operated it is possible to vary the direction of the emitted beam. Further, the light received from the roadside unit <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> will be focussed at a position on the detector array <highlight><bold>227</bold></highlight> which corresponds to the direction of the emitted beam. In this embodiment, the signals from the individual detector elements are monitored, and based on the monitored signals a tracking operation is performed in which the VCSEL element which is driven is changed in order to vary the direction of the emitted light beam to maintain the optical link between the car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> and the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>219</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment is the same as the retro-reflector and modem unit <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment (as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) except for the layout of the modulator elements in the modulator array. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows the surface of the modulator array <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment. As shown, the modulator array <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> is a two-dimensional array with sixteen modulator elements provided in the Y direction and two modulator elements provided in the X direction. As in the first embodiment, by having only two modulator elements in the X direction the fabrication of the modulator array is greatly simplified because the modulator elements can be addressed from the sides of the array. In this embodiment, each modulator element has a length of approximately 1 mm in the Y direction and a width of approximately 100 microns in the X direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is mounted to the post <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> so that the Y direction is substantially vertical and therefore the modulator elements are mapped along the road <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. In particular, the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is designed so that the width of the modulator element corresponds to the width of a lane of the road, while the length of the modulator element corresponds to a distance along the road which is significantly longer than the width of a lane. This has the advantage that a single modulator element <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> is used to communicate with a car terminal <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> for a longer period of time than would be the case if the length of the modulator element was equal to the width of the modulator element. This therefore reduces the complexity of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> because less modulator elements are required and because fewer changeovers between modulator elements are required as the car <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> moves within the field of view of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In the first and second embodiments, the local distribution node was adapted to take account of the environment in which it will be used. In particular, in the first and second embodiments the layout and shape of modulator elements in the modulator array was chosen either to match the distribution of users in a building or to match the expected path to be taken by mobile user stations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The local distribution nodes of the first and second embodiments are able to communicate with user stations within a horizontal field of view of approximately 60&deg;. In some applications a larger field of view is required. However, increasing the field of view while retaining a large collection aperture is problematic because a very low f/number lens is required. A third embodiment will now be described in which the local distribution node has a full 360&deg; horizontal field of view. In particular, in the third embodiment the local distribution node is horizontally surrounded by user stations and therefore a 360&deg; horizontal field of view is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the data distribution system of the third embodiment. As shown, a central distribution system <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> transmits data to and receives data from a local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> via a bundle of optical fibres <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The central distribution system <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> also transmits data to and receives data from other local distribution nodes (not shown) via respective optical fibre bundles <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>. The local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> is located in the centre of twelve user stations <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>l. </italic></highlight>In this embodiment, the local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> is mounted on a post (not shown) in the centre of a square surrounded by buildings (not shown), and the user stations <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> are mounted on the buildings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The components of the user stations <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> are the same as the user stations of the first embodiment and therefore will not be described in detail again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of the key components of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> (with the housing and component mountings removed to improve clarity). The local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> comprises six telecentric lenses, three of which can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> represented as single lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Each of the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> has a horizontal field of view of about 60&deg; and is positioned to cover a respective portion of the horizontal plane so that the six telecentric lenses cover between them a 360&deg; horizontal field of view. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, light from all of the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is reflected onto a single modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> by a pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> which has a hexagonal base and six triangular sides, which are inclined at 45&deg; to the plane of the base. The pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> is positioned so that the apex is adjacent the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> and the base is parallel with the plane of the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>, and the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> are arranged around the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> so that light passing through each telecentric lens <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is directed horizontally onto a respective side of the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> where it is reflected vertically downwards onto the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. The telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> are positioned so that the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> is optically located in the back focal plane of all six telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows a schematic top plan view of the key components of the local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> in which the outline of the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> is shown in phantom lines in order to reveal the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> beneath. As shown, the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>are formed by respective lenses <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and stop members <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>. The telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> collect light within their field of view and direct the collected light as horizontal light beams <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>to the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight>, where the light beams are reflected vertically downwards onto the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> by respective sides of the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> to form corresponding spots <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>on the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. Therefore, as in the first and second embodiments, the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> map incoming light from different directions onto respective different positions on the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>, which modulates the light and reflects the modulated light back in the direction from which the incoming light beam originated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, in this embodiment the modulator array comprises an eight-by-eight array of modulator elements. The user stations <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> are positioned so that when the low-divergence free-space light beams emitted by the user stations are directed onto the local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>, the emitted light beam are directed onto corresponding modulator elements which modulate and reflect the light beam back to the originating user stations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will appreciate that by using six reflectors to reflect light from six telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> onto a single modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>, the fabrication of the local distribution node is simplified because electrical connections only need to be made to a single device. Further, by mounting the six reflectors onto a single body the fabrication of the local distribution node is still further simplified. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">MODIFICATIONS AND FURTHER EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment, each side of a six-sided pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> reflects incoming light beams onto a single integrated modulator array. However, only part of each side actually reflects light during use. Therefore, the portions of the sides which do not reflect light during use do not need to be made reflective. Further, these unused portions could be removed entirely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a first alternative embodiment having a reflector <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> with the form of a six-sided frustum, i.e. a six-sided pyramid with the apex portion, which does not reflect light in use, removed. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> are still positioned so that their back focal planes are optically located in the plane of the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the smaller base portion of the frustum can be glued (or attached in any other way) to the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> because, as can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the modulator elements in the centre of the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> are not required during use. This ensures a robust alignment between the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> and the reflector <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a second alternative embodiment having a reflector <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> with the form of a six-sided frustum in which the tips of the hexagonal base have been sliced off at an angle of 45&deg; to the plane of the base so that each of the reflecting sides is in the form of a hexagon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment, six telecentric lenses, which each have a horizontal field of view of about 60&deg;, are used with a six-sided pyramidal reflector to map a 360&deg; horizontal field of view onto respective positions on the single modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the field of view of each telecentric lens could be increased or reduced and the number of reflecting side surfaces of the pyramidal reflector altered accordingly to maintain a full 360&deg; horizontal field of view. For example, telecentric lenses having a horizontal field of view of 45&deg; could be used with an eight-sided pyramidal body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> In some circumstances, the required horizontal field of view is less than 360&deg; but still more than can be handled by a single telecentric lens. Those skilled in the art will recognise that a reflector can readily be designed for use with two or more telecentric lenses so that a single integrated modulator array can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Although in the third embodiment a 360&deg; field of view was required in a horizontal plane, the local distribution node <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> can be rotated to cover a 360&deg; field of view in any plane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment and the embodiments illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference>, some of the modulator elements of the modulator array <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> are not used, and are therefore redundant, because no light from the telecentric lenses <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is incident on them (as can be seen clearly in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> shows an alternative embodiment in which the frustum-shaped reflector <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is used with a modulator array <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> in which the redundant modulator elements have been removed. In particular, modulator elements have been removed from the corners of the modulator array <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> and the centre of the modulator array <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the modified modulator array <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> could also be used with the pyramidal reflector <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> or the reflector <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment, the modulator elements of the modulator array are rectangular. The shape of modulator elements can be adapted in the manner described in the first and second embodiments to take account of the environment in which the local distribution node will be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> In the first to third embodiments QCSE modulators are used. As those skilled in the art will appreciate, other types of reflectors and modulators could be used. For example, a plane mirror may be used as the reflector and a transmissive modulator (such as liquid crystal) could be provided between the lens and the mirror. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In the first to third embodiments, the QCSE modulators are also used to detect modulated light beams from the user stations. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that separate detecting elements could be used, either integrated with the modulating elements with a detecting element being provided adjacent each modulating element, or a separate detector array being provided with beam splitters being used to direct part of the incoming light transmitted through the telecentric lens onto the detector array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> If separate detecting elements are used, then they can also be shaped in the manner described in the first and second embodiments to take account of the environment in which the local distribution node will be used. Further, in an alternative embodiment, an array of light emitters, for example a VCSEL array, may be provided in the local distribution node which emit modulated light beams to convey data to the user stations, and modulated light beams from the user stations are directed onto corresponding detector elements of a detector array whose layout and shape have been chosen in view the environment in which the local distribution node is being used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> In the first embodiment, a marking was provided on the housing of the local distribution node to indicate the orientation of the modulator array within the housing. Instead of using a marking, the orientation of the modulator array within the housing could be apparent from the shape of the housing, i.e. the housing could be a rectangular box having long edges which correspond to the y-direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> It is possible to determine the orientation of the modulator array, without any indication on the housing, by looking through the window of the telecentric lens to view the modulator array directly. However, this is not preferred because it requires the installer to interpret the appearance of the face of the modulator array correctly and therefore requires the installer to have an increased level of expertise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Rather than customising local distribution nodes for individual locations, a set of local distribution nodes having modulator arrays with respective different arrangements of modulator elements could be provided. An installer would then analyse the environment in which the local distribution node is to be used and select the most appropriate local distribution node from the set of local distribution nodes for installation. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the set of local distribution nodes can therefore be mass produced, thereby reducing fabrication costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Although, as discussed above, telecentric lenses have many advantages both when used with a modulator array and when used with an emitter array, alternative lens systems could be employed. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A signalling device comprising: 
<claim-text>a lens system for collecting light incident on the signalling device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflector for reflecting light collected by the lens system back through the lens system; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a modulator for modulating the light collected by the lens system and/or for modulating the reflected light in accordance with modulation data, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the modulator comprises a plurality of modulating elements, each modulator element extending a first length in a first direction and a second length, which is greater than twice the first length, in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second length is greater than five times the first length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second length is greater than ten times the first length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any preceding claim, wherein each modulating element is rectangular. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any preceding claim, wherein the lens system is a telecentric lens system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any preceding claim, wherein the plurality of modulator elements are arranged in an array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the array is a two-dimensional array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two-dimensional array has a plurality of modulators arranged in a first array direction and two modulators arranged in a second array direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first array direction is parallel to said first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first array direction is parallel to said second direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the array is a one dimensional array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any preceding claim, wherein said modulator and said reflector are formed as a single unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said combined modulator and reflector comprises a quantum confined Stark effect device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A signalling device comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of detectors for converting light into corresponding electrical signals; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lens system for collecting light incident on the signalling device and for directing the incident light to at least one of the plurality of detectors which corresponds to the direction of incidence of the incident light, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each detector extends a first length in a first direction and a second length, which is greater than twice the first length, in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second length is greater than five times the first length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second length is greater than ten times the first length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00014">claims 14</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00016">16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each detector is rectangular. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00014">claims 14</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00017">17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the lens system is a telecentric lens system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00014">claims 14</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00018">18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of detectors are arranged in an array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the array is a two-dimensional array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two-dimensional array has a plurality of detectors arranged in a first array direction and two detectors arranged in a second array direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first array direction is parallel to said first direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first array direction is parallel to said second direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the array is a one dimensional array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any preceding claim, further comprising a housing including indication means indicative of the first and second directions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the indication means comprises a mark on the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the indication means is the shape of the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00025">claims 25</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00027">27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing further comprises mounting means for mounting the signalling device to a structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the mounting means is operable to mount the signalling device in a plurality of different orientations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A signalling device comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of lens systems, each having a respective field of view; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electro-optic device provided in common to said plurality of lens systems; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of reflecting surfaces, each reflecting surface being associated with a corresponding one of the plurality of lens systems and being positioned relative to said associated lens system and said electro-optic device so that light incident on the associated lens system from the respective field of view is directed towards a respective different portion of said electro-optic device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the respective fields of view of the plurality of lens systems encompasses a 360&deg; field of view in a plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, wherein the plurality of reflecting surfaces are formed on a single body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the single body is pyramid-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the single body is frustum-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00030">claims 30</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00034">34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the plurality of lens systems comprises a telecentric lens. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00030">claims 30</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00035">35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electro-optic device comprises an array of light emitting elements, and wherein the plurality of lens systems are operable to direct light from the array of light emitting elements in respective different directions within their combined field of view. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00030">claims 30</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00035">35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electro-optic device comprises an array of detectors, and wherein each lens system is operable to direct light incident from different directions within its field of view towards respective different ones of the array of detectors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00030">claims 30</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00035">35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electro-optic device comprises an array of modulator elements, and wherein each lens system is operable to direct light incident from different directions within its field of view towards respective different ones of the array of modulator elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each modulator element has a reflectivity which is variable in accordance with an applied electrical signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each modulator element comprises a quantum confined Stark effect device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A signalling system comprising a first signalling device and a plurality of second signalling devices, 
<claim-text>wherein the first signalling device comprising a signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or any claim dependent thereon, </claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein each of the plurality of second signalling devices comprises: i) at least one light emitter for emitting a light beam; ii) a lens system for directing the emitted light beam towards the first signalling device and for collecting a modulated light beam received from the first signalling device; and iii) at least one detector for detecting said modulated light beam and for converting the modulated light beam into a corresponding electrical signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A method of installing a signalling system for communicating data between a first signalling device and a plurality of second signalling devices associated with respective users distributed throughout a region of space, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a plurality of signalling devices as claimed in any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00029">29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of signalling devices have different combinations and/or orientations of said first and second lengths; </claim-text>
<claim-text>analysing the environment of said region of space to determine a likely distribution of users; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a signalling device from the plurality of signalling devices to form the first signalling device in accordance with the likely distribution of users determined in the analysing step; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>installing the signalling device selected in the selecting step. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the installing step comprises the steps of identifying the orientation of the first and second directions and mounting the signalling device in accordance with said identified orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said identifying step comprises examining a housing of the signalling device for an indication of the orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said identifying step comprises directly viewing the plurality of modulator elements through the lens system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A signalling system comprising a first signalling device and a plurality of second signalling devices, the plurality of second signalling devices being provide on a building, 
<claim-text>wherein the first signalling device comprising a signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or any claim dependent thereon, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the plurality of second signalling devices comprises: i) at least one light emitter for emitting a light beam; ii) a lens system for directing the emitted light beam towards the first signalling device and for collecting a modulated light beam received from the first signalling device; and iii) at least one detector for detecting said modulated light beam and for converting the modulated light beam into a corresponding electrical signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein said first length and said second length are selected in accordance with a distribution of users within the building. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A signalling system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first direction corresponds to a vertical direction on a side of the building and the second direction corresponds to a horizontal direction on said side of the building. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A signalling system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, wherein the building is a multi-storey building. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A signalling system comprising a first signalling device, a plurality of second signalling devices moveable relative to the first signalling device, and guide means for guiding the relative movement between each second signalling device and the first signalling device to be in a guide direction, 
<claim-text>wherein the first signalling device comprising a signalling device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or any claim dependent thereon, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the plurality of second signalling devices comprises: i) at least one light emitter for emitting a light beam; ii) a lens system for directing the emitted light beam towards the first signalling device and for collecting a modulated light beam received from the first signalling device; and iii) at least one detector for detecting said modulated light beam and for converting the modulated light beam into a corresponding electrical signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein said second direction corresponds to the guide direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A signalling system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the guide means comprises a road, and each of the plurality of second signalling devices is mounted on a road vehicle.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>9</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030002124A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
