<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000335A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000335A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000335A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000335A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000335A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000335A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000335A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000335A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000335</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10203896</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020814</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number> 100 64 770.7</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001222</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G05G001/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>074</class>
<subclass>512000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Device for mounting a pedal lever of a motor vehicle</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Andree</given-name>
<family-name>Burgstaler</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Dielingen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jan</given-name>
<family-name>Dutz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Damme</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Simone</given-name>
<family-name>Patzold</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Cappeln</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>McGlew &amp; Tuttle</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Scarborough Station</address-1>
<city>Scarborough</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10510-0827</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/DE01/04807</doc-number>
<document-date>20011219</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A device is provided for mounting a pedal lever (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of a motor vehicle, which is accommodated in a housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) pivotably around at least one said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). At least one section of a separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is supported via a said support surface (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) against a motor vehicle component (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and brings about the shearing off of the bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) due to the action of an external force caused by an accident due to a relative movement between the separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) and the bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) by applying a shearing force. The separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is accommodated between a surface of the housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and the bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention pertains to a device for mounting a pedal lever for a motor vehicle which is accommodated in a housing pivotably around at least one bearing element. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The increasing requirements imposed on motor vehicles in terms of increasing safety are seen in numerous systems. In pedal fastening means, there is a known risk for accidents in that a deformation of the engine compartment directly or indirectly affects the pedals and these are moved into the leg room of the motor vehicle. The serious injuries to the lower extremities, which can be caused by jamming between the pedals, can be considered to be the risks associated for the driver of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> To avoid these risks of injury, separating mechanisms are known, which utilize the introduction of force from the outside, which is caused by the accident, to drive at least one separating wedge between two cheeks of a housing pivotably accommodating the pedal lever or the pedal levers in order to make possible as a result the release of the bearing bolt carrying the pedal lever. However, these solutions have not ultimately proved successful, because the mounting of such systems is rather complicated and at least the deformation areas must be made of metallic materials. However, it is advantageous in connection with the weight reduction of the assembly units present in the motor vehicle to manufacture the largest possible number of parts from light-weight materials, e.g., plastics. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY AND OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The technical object of the present invention is to provide a device for mounting a pedal lever, which reduces the risk of injury and the degree of severity of the injuries to the driver of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This technical object is accomplished by a device of this type for mounting a pedal lever which is accommodated in a housing pivotably around at least one bearing element. At least one section of a separating wedge is supported via a support surface against a motor vehicle component and brings about the shearing off of the bearing element due to the action of an external force caused by an accident due to a relative movement between the separating wedge and the bearing element by applying a shearing force. This separating wedge is accommodated between a surface of the housing and the bearing element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It can thus be achieved that as a consequence of the action of an external force, which is caused by an accident, a relative movement takes place between the separating wedge and the bearing element, which brings about the shearing off of the bearing element due to the application of a shearing force. This relative movement arises either from the deformation of the motor vehicle component or from the movement of the housing, which in turn originates from a deformation of parts of the motor vehicle. Consequently, the shearing off, i.e., the destruction of the bearing element, is correspondingly brought about deliberately according to the present invention in order to guarantee the necessary protection of the passengers. A bearing bolt or a bearing bush, which mount the pedal lever pivotably, may be used as a bearing element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The device has, on the whole, a very simple design and can be manufactured nearly completely from light-weight materials, such as plastic. As such, there are hardly any limits to shaping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment of the present invention, it is proposed that an abutment for contacting and slidingly movably guiding the separating wedge be provided at the housing. This abutment may have a ramp function, so that the separating wedge can exert its shearing action on the bearing element. At the same time, this abutment makes possible the clearance-free contact of the separating wedge between the abutment and the bearing element during normal operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> To improve the shearing action, it is advantageous to provide the separating wedge with at least one wedge-shaped or arc-shaped active surface on the side facing the bearing element. As a result, it is possible to clearly define the point in time at which the bearing element is completely separated as a function of the path traveled by the separating wedge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A variant of the present invention can, furthermore, be seen in the bearing element traversing two cheeks of the housing located at spaced locations from one another and by the pedal lever being arranged approximately in the middle between the cheeks on the bearing element. A distance is present now between the pedal lever and the respective associated cheek on both sides of the pedal lever, so that the separating wedge, which is provided with two legs in at least this area, is directly in contact with the bearing element, on the one hand, and with the abutment, on the other hand. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> As was mentioned above, the relative movement between the separating wedge and the bearing element can also be achieved by the vehicle component to which the housing is fastened being deformed. It is correspondingly meaningful to fasten the housing at the front wall in the leg area on the driver&apos;s side of the motor vehicle, because the front wall is usually deformed relatively greatly in an accident, and the advantageous effect of the solution according to the present invention is achieved as a result at an early point in time. The motor vehicle component may be correspondingly the cross beam located closest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> To facilitate the shearing off, it is, moreover, appropriate and advantageous to provide the bearing element with at least one predetermined breaking point. Furthermore, the bearing element may be designed as a one-part or two-part bearing bolt. The two-part design has especially advantages in terms of mounting. However, it should be ensured in this case that each of the pin parts is shorn off by the separating wedge during the accident. However, a bearing bush, which can likewise be shorn off by the action of the shearing force, may also be considered to be a bearing element corresponding to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Since the brake pedal of a motor vehicle is connected, e.g., to a brake booster and the latter has a brake rod, the deformation of the front wall in this area may have an especially strong effect, so that there is a risk that the pedal lever is moved into the passenger compartment by an unacceptable large amount before the shearing off of the bearing element. To counteract this situation, it is proposed that a blocking member, which limits the evading movement of the pedal in the direction of the passenger compartment during an accident, be provided at the housing in a solution according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> To fix the separating wedge, which is normally inserted loosely between the cross beam and the pedal mount, a securing means for holding at the housing is, furthermore, provided between the separating wedge and the housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The various features of novelty which characterize the invention are pointed out with particularity in the claims annexed to and forming a part of this disclosure. For a better understanding of the invention, its operating advantages and specific objects attained by its uses, reference is made to the accompanying drawings and descriptive matter in which a preferred embodiment of the invention is illustrated. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional view of a device for mounting a pedal lever; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a device for mounting a pedal lever; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a bearing element for a device for mounting a pedal lever.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings in particular, for mounting a pedal lever <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a motor vehicle, the device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> contains a bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is pivotably accommodated in a housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The housing is fastened at the front wall of the motor vehicle in the leg area of the motor vehicle. A section of a separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, is supported via a support surface <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> against a motor vehicle component <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. This A section of a separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is accommodated between a surface of the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The motor vehicle component <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is a cross beam in this arrangement which is useful for contacting the separating wedge. This is because it is usually deformed only slightly even in serious accidents, so that a reliable, nearly constant support of the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> becomes possible. As is apparent, the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is inserted loosely between the cross beam <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the contact area between the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Complicated mounting can therefore be eliminated. A securing means <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is provided that preferably consists of a soft material, so that the shearing action is not affected when needed. Each securing means <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is present only as a means for protection against loss for the transport of the device at each leg between the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> brings about the shearing off of the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as a consequence of the action of an external force caused by an accident due to a relative movement between the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by applying a shearing force. The separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> comprises in the embodiment being shown a basic body with which two parallel legs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are made in one piece. On the side facing the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, these legs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> have an active surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> each. The active surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> was shaped as an arc-shaped contour in this case. The parallel arrangement of the legs is advantageous, because the shearing force can be applied uniformly on two different areas of the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> under the action of the external force, so that the bearing element can be severed with certainty and reliably when this is necessary. The bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> traverses two cheeks <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The two cheeks <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are arranged at spaced locations from one another. The pedal lever <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is arranged on the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> approximately centrally between these cheeks <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, so that there is a distance <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> between the pedal lever <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the respective associated cheek <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on both sides of the pedal lever <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. These distances <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> form contact areas for the active surfaces <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> at the bearing element <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The distances <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> should not be substantially greater than the width of the legs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. On the side located opposite the active surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is in contact with a housing surface designed as an abutment <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As is apparent from the sectional view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the abutment <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the associated surface of the separating wedge <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are flat surfaces, which permit the sliding movement of the components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> As is apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the bearing element has two predetermined breaking points <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and is designed as a one-part bearing bolt in this case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> To avoid an unacceptably wide movement of the pedal lever into the passenger compartment, a blocking member <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is arranged at the housing <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The blocking member limits the evading movement of the pedal in the direction of the interior space of the vehicle during an accident. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> While specific embodiments of the invention have been shown and described in detail to illustrate the application of the principles of the invention, it will be understood that the invention may be embodied otherwise without departing from such principles. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a said pedal lever (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of a motor vehicle, which is accommodated in a said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) pivotably around at least one said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>at least one section of a said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), which is supported via a said support surface (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) against a said motor vehicle component (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and which brings about the shearing off of the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) due to the action of an external force caused by an accident due to a relative movement between the said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) and the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) by applying a shearing force, is accommodated between a surface of the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>a said abutment (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) is present at the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) for contacting and slidingly movably guiding the said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with one of the above claims, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>the said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) has a said wedge-shaped or arc-shaped active surface (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) on the side facing the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting the pedal lever in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) traverses two said cheeks (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) of the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), which are located at spaced locations from one another, the said pedal lever (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is arranged approximately centrally between the said checks (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) on the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), and there is a said distance (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) between the said pedal lever (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and the said respective associated cheek (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) on both sides of the said pedal lever (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), so that the said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), which is provided with two said legs (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) in at least this area, is in contact with the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), on the one hand, and with the said abutment (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>), on the other hand. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with one of the above claims, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is fastened to the front wall in the leg area of the driver&apos;s side of the motor vehicle, and the said vehicle component (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) is a cross beam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with one of the above claims, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>the said bearing element (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), which has at least one said predetermined breaking point (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>), is a one-part or two-part bearing bolt. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with one of the above claims, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>a said blocking member (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), which limits an evading movement of the pedal in the direction of the interior space of the vehicle, is present at the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Device for mounting a pedal lever in accordance with one of the above claims, 
<claim-text>characterized in that 
<claim-text>the said separating wedge (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) has a said securing means (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) for holding on the said housing (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>).</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000335A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000335A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000335A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000335A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
