<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000515A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000515A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000515A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000515A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000515A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000515A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000515A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000515A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000515</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893327</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A21B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>126</class>
<subclass>02100A</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>126</class>
<subclass>02100R</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Convection oven having multiple airflow patterns</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cole</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Algonquin</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Donald</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fritzsche</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chicago Heights</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Harter</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Port Richey</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ronald</given-name>
<middle-name>Jay</middle-name>
<family-name>Forni</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Littleton</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Malcolm</given-name>
<family-name>Reay</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Drums</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jerry</given-name>
<family-name>Sank</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Palm Harbor</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<family-name>McFadden</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Jones</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Port Richey</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Mark E. Fejer</name-1>
<name-2>Gas Technology Institute</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1700 South Mount Prospect Road</address-1>
<city>Des Plaines</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60018</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A convection oven having multiple airflow patterns within a cooking chamber during a baking cycle. In one embodiment, at least one reversible blower wheel rotatable at varying speeds produces separate airflow states to create multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. In another preferred embodiment, at least one adjustable airflow control surface mounted within the cooking chamber creates multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during the baking cycle. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a convection oven having multiple airflow patterns within a cooking chamber during the baking cycle. The convection oven has at least one blower wheel rotatable at different speeds and/or in different directions for creating multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. Alternatively, at least one mechanically actuated adjustable airflow control surface creates multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional commercial convection ovens have one or more fans which circulate air within an oven cavity. The airflow within the oven cavity is highly turbulent but characterized by a circulation pattern evident in the oven&apos;s cooking performance. A distinct and often undesirable pattern is seen on the cooked food product. In areas of the oven cavity where the airflow is too low, the food product will be raw or uncooked. Conversely, in areas where the airflow is too high, the food product will be burned or overcooked. In such situations, it is desirable to tune the convection oven so that a uniform airflow is obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Many conventional commercial convection ovens are tuned by attempting to produce a single flow pattern having a uniform flow and temperature distribution within the oven cavity. However, accurately tuning conventional convection ovens is difficult, and often a trial and error process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is apparent that there is a need for an easy and effective method for tuning the baking performance of a convection oven wherein multiple airflow patterns are created within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is an object of this invention to provide a convection oven having an easy and effective method for providing multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during the baking cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is another object of this invention to provide a convection oven having at least one blower wheel rotatable at different speeds and/or in different directions for creating multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It is another object of this invention to provide a convection oven having at least one adjustable airflow control surface for creating multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber during a baking cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The above objects and other objects of this invention are accomplished by a convection oven having a cooking chamber with dimensions to accommodate any type, quantity and/or size of food product. An outer enclosure is in communication with the cooking chamber. In one preferred embodiment, at least one reversible blower wheel, preferably at least two reversible blower wheels, are mounted within the outer enclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The reversible blower wheels rotate in the same direction with respect to each other or in different or opposite directions with respect to each other, producing at least four separate airflow states to create different airflow patterns within the cooking chamber. Additional airflow patterns are created by varying the speed at which the reversible blower wheels rotate with respect to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment of this invention, at least one adjustable airflow control surface is mounted within the cooking chamber. The adjustable airflow control surface has, for example a baffle or a fin which is adjustable between a plurality of positions to change the geometry of the cooking chamber. An actuator adjusts the adjustable airflow control surface between a plurality of positions during the baking cycle. As a result, additional airflow states are produced which create multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber. The airflow states can be switched in a predetermined cycle or a random cycle. A uniform baking performance is obtained by averaging the multiple airflow patterns created by periodically switching between the airflow states during the baking cycle. The baking performance of the average state is better than the baking performance of any individual airflow state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment of this invention, a removable inlet baffle is positioned between the cooking chamber and the outer enclosure. Preferably, the inlet baffle has an air return in communication with each reversible blower wheel to allow communication between the cooking chamber and the outer enclosure. The inlet baffle may have a plurality of apertures to allow communication between the cooking chamber and the outer enclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The convection oven has a gas combustion system mounted with respect to the outer enclosure which produces or generates combustion products. The combustion products generated by the gas combustion system move into a heat exchange element. The heat exchange element is mounted within the outer enclosure and with respect to the reversible blower wheels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment according to this invention, separate airflow states are produced by varying the speeds at which the reversible blower wheels rotate with respect to each other and/or changing the direction in which the reversible blower wheels rotate. By varying the respective speed and/or rotational direction of the reversible blower wheels to produce separate airflow states, multiple airflow patterns are created within the cooking chamber. These airflow patterns can be switched or changed periodically during the baking cycle to improve the baking performance of the convection oven. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment according to this invention, the adjustable airflow control surface produces multiple airflow patterns within the cooking chamber by adjusting the adjustable airflow control surface with an actuator to produce different airflow states. Multiple airflow patterns are created during the baking cycle of the convection oven by adjusting the adjustable airflow control surface, improving the baking performance of the convection oven. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a convection oven having two blower wheels, according to one preferred embodiment of this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a convection oven showing two blower wheels mounted adjacent a plurality of heat exchange tubes, according to one preferred embodiment of this invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a partial schematic front view of a convection oven showing the communication between the outer enclosure and the inlet baffle, according to one preferred embodiment of this invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, preferably, but not necessarily, is a commercial convection oven having a combustion system switchable between a direct-fired combustion system and an indirect-combustion system. Convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> comprises a cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has at least one rack for supporting a food product during the baking cycle. Cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can have dimensions to accommodate any type, quantity and/or size of food product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent and in communication with cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is mounted within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has a diameter of about <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> inches. First reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is driven by a reversible motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, reversible motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> has about 0.50 horsepower (&ldquo;hp&rdquo;). It is apparent to those skilled in the art that other means may be used to drive first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to produce the required airflow of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment of this invention, a second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;, preferably, but not necessarily, the same or similar to first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, is mounted within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; can be driven by reversible motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> or can be driven by a second reversible motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>&prime;. In such embodiments wherein first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; are driven by reversible motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, any belt and/or gear arrangement known to those of ordinary skill in the art may be used to allow first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; to rotate at different speeds and/or in different directions with respect to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> First reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotate in the same direction with respect to each other or in different or opposite directions with respect to each other, producing at least four separate airflow states that create different airflow patterns within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The separate airflow states include: (a) first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotating in a clockwise direction and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in a clockwise direction; (b) first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotating in a clockwise direction and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in a counterclockwise direction; (c) first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotating in a counterclockwise direction and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in a counterclockwise direction; and (d) first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotating in a counterclockwise direction and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in a clockwise direction. Additional airflow patterns are created by varying the speed at which first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotate with respect to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Preferably, but not necessarily, the airflow states produce a uniform airflow pattern within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A uniform baking performance is obtained by averaging the multiple airflow patterns created by periodically switching between airflow states during the baking cycle. The baking performance of the average state is better than the baking performance of any individual airflow state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment of this invention, at least one adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is mounted within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>. Adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> comprises, for example a baffle or a fin which is adjustable between a plurality of positions to change the geometry of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An actuator <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> adjusts adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> between a plurality of positions during the baking cycle of convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. By adjusting adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, multiple airflow patterns are created within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be actuated mechanically, electrically or by other actuating means known to those skilled in the art. Further, adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be adjusted to various positions periodically during the cooking cycle in a predetermined sequence of positions or in a random sequence of positions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment of this invention, a removable inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is positionable between cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>. Preferably, inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a first air return <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, in communication with first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and a second air return <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime;, in communication with second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;, to allow communication between cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In another preferred embodiment of this invention, inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a plurality of apertures to allow communication between cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> further comprises a gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> mounted with respect to outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> produces or generates combustion products. The term &ldquo;combustion products&rdquo; as used throughout this specification and in the claims includes, but is not limited to, heat and combustion gas fumes, for example carbon monoxide and nitric acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a gas manifold <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having at least one gas outlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, preferably at least three gas outlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> supplies gas, for example natural gas, to gas manifold <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a burner is attached to each gas outlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. As gas is distributed through gas outlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and into burners <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the gas burns or combusts to generate combustion products. The combustion products move into a heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> connected to each burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is mounted within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and with respect to first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;. Preferably, heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is mounted adjacent first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment of this invention, heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Preferably, each heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has an outer diameter of about 2.0 inches. A baffle <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is positioned within at least a portion of a volume of each heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to assist in conductive and convective heat exchange. At least one heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is preferably connected to each burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As the combustion products move through each heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, heat is transferred from within heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to a volume of outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by conduction through heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Further, first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; produces an airflow across heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to transfer heat from heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the airflow through convection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</cross-reference>, heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are connected to a header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is mounted within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and in communication with gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The combustion products are collected from each heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in a volume of header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and are drawn into an inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> connected to header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A valve (not shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), positioned within inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, is moveable between an open position and a closed position. In the open position, the combustion products drawn into inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are in communication with the ambient air through a vent connected to inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Thus, the combustion products do not enter cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> operates as an indirect-fired combustion system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In the closed position, the combustion products drawn into inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are in communication with cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thus, convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> operates as a direct-fired combustion system. In a direct-fired combustion system, the combustion products directly contact the food product in cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> during the cooking process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; generate an airflow across heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> within outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Heat is transferred from heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the air flowing through outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by conduction and convection. The heated air is forced around inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Air within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is drawn into outer enclosure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> through first air return <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in communication with first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second air return <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; in communication with second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;, creating an airflow pattern within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment according to this invention, separate airflow states are produced by varying the speed at which first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotate with respect to each other and/or by changing the direction in which first reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or second reversible blower wheel <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; rotate. By varying the respective speed and/or rotational direction of blower wheels <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; to produce separate airflow states, multiple airflow patterns are created within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. These airflow patterns are switched or changed periodically during the baking cycle to improve the baking performance of convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Periodically switching between separate airflow states can be accomplished mechanically, electrically or by other means known to those having ordinary skill in the art. Further, periodic switching between separate airflow states can occur in a predetermined or a random manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment according to this invention, adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> produces an airflow pattern within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by changing the geometry of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Actuator <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> adjusts adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> between a plurality of positions during the baking cycle to create multiple airflow patterns within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A second adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is adjustable by actuator <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> in combination with or independent from adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> during the baking cycle. The multiple airflow patterns created during the baking cycle improve the baking performance of convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Further, adjustable airflow control surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be used in combination with first reversible blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and second reversible blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; during the baking cycle of convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to create multiple airflow patterns within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> While in the foregoing specification this invention has been described in relation to certain preferred embodiments, and many details are set forth for purpose of illustration, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that this invention is susceptible to additional embodiments and that certain of the details described in this specification and in the claims can be varied considerably without departing from the basic principles of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A convection oven, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cooking chamber, the cooking chamber having an adjustable airflow control surface, the adjustable airflow control surface creating a first airflow pattern within the cooking chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for adjusting the adjustable airflow control surface to create a second airflow pattern. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a second adjustable airflow control surface within the cooking chamber, the second adjustable airflow control surface adjustable between a plurality of positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a blower plenum in communication with the cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a removable inlet baffle positioned between the cooking chamber and the blower plenum, the inlet baffle having a first air return; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first reversible blower wheel mounted within the blower plenum and mounted with respect to the first air return. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the adjustable airflow control surface is mechanically actuated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the adjustable airflow control surface is electronically actuated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the adjustable airflow control surface is randomly adjustable between a plurality of positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the adjustable airflow control surface is adjustable between a plurality of predetermined positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a heat exchange element mounted within the blower plenum and connected to a gas combustion system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a header connected to the heat exchange element, the header in communication with the gas combustion system; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inducer connected to the header, the inducer having a valve moveable between an open position and a closed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A convection oven, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower plenum in communication with the cooking chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first reversible blower wheel mounted within the blower plenum, the first reversible blower wheel creating multiple airflow patterns during a baking cycle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a second reversible blower wheel mounted within the blower plenum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first reversible blower wheel rotates at a speed different from a speed at which the second reversible blower wheel rotates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first reversible blower wheel rotates in a direction different from a direction in which the second reversible blower wheel rotates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a gas combustion system mounted with respect to the blower plenum, the gas combustion system generating combustion products; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat exchange element mounted within the blower plenum and connected to the gas combustion system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a header connected to the heat exchange element, the header in communication with the gas combustion system; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inducer connected to the header, the inducer having a valve moveable between an open position and a closed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first reversible blower wheel and a second reversible blower wheel are mounted adjacent the heat exchange element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the heat exchange element comprises a plurality of heat exchange tubes, each heat exchange tube of the plurality of heat exchange tubes has a baffle within at least a portion of a volume of the heat exchange tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method for creating multiple airflow patterns within a cooking chamber during a cooking cycle, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>creating a first airflow pattern within a cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>actuating an adjustable airflow control surface to create a second airflow pattern within the cooking chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>switching between the first airflow pattern and the second airflow pattern during a baking cycle.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000515A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000515A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000515A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000515A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
