<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003715A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003715A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003715</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10062717</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020205</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-36969</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/4763</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>637000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>942000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>946000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for forming dual damascene line structure</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Eun</given-name>
<middle-name>Suk</middle-name>
<family-name>Hong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chungcheongbuk-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hynix Semiconductor Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MORGAN LEWIS &amp; BOCKIUS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1111 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of forming a dual damascene line structure suitable for forming a fine pattern is disclosed in the present invention. The method for forming a dual damascene line structure on a substrate includes sequentially depositing an inter-metal dielectric and a first hard mask over the substrate, partially removing the first hard mask to have a positive trench pattern using a first photoresist pattern as a mask, forming a second hard mask having a substantially different etch selectivity from the first hard mask on the partially removed portion of the first hard mask, selectively removing the first hard mask to have a negative via hole pattern using a second photoresist pattern as a mask, partially removing the inter-metal dielectric to have a via hole pattern using the first hard mask as a mask, and forming a trench and a via hole by removing the exposed first hard mask and selectively etching the inter-metal dielectric using the second hard mask. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of Korean Application No. P2001-36969 filed on Jun. 27, 2001, which is hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method for forming a semiconductor device, and more particularly, to a method for forming a dual damascene line structure. Although the present invention is suitable for a wide scope of applications, it is particularly suitable for forming a fine pattern in the semiconductor device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Discussion of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Various methods for forming a via hole and a trench have been introduced in the method for forming a dual damascene line structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A method for forming a via hole after forming a trench and a method for forming a trench after forming a via hole have been suggested as typical methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In such methods, a photoresist pattern is formed on the step portion where a via hole and a trench are formed therein. As a result, the photoresist pattern is often found deformed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A related art method for forming a dual damascene line structure will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating process steps of a related art method for forming a dual damascene line structures. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating another related art method for forming a dual damascene line structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In forming a dual damascene line structure, a via hole may be formed first after forming a trench. Althernatively, a trench may be formed first after forming a via hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, the method for forming a dual damascene line structure includes selectively etching an insulating layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to form a trench, burying a metallic layer inside the trench and planarizing the metallic layer to form a lower metallic line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, a diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is deposited on the lower metallic line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A low dielectric layer is then deposited on the diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to form an inter-metal dielectric IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Then, after depositing a photoresist on the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> having a via hole pattern is formed by exposure and developing processes so that a portion of the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is exposed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In this case, the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed thick enough for forming a deep via hole within the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in a later process. Alternatively, the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is formed to have a higher etch selectivity than that of the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Using the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> as a mask, the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is etched by a plasma dry etching process to form a via hole therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>B, after removing the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, a polymer remaining within the via hole is removed by a cleaning process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, after depositing a photoresist on the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is negatively patterned to expose a portion of the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, thereby forming a photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a trench pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>D, using the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a mask, the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is selectively etched to form a trench. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In this case, a micro-trench shown as portion &lsquo;A&rsquo; is formed inside the trench during the etching process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Additionally, after depositing a metallic material such as tungsten, which is thick enough to completely bury the via hole and the trench, the metallic material is planarized by a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process. Thus, an upper surface of the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is exposed, thereby forming a plug (not shown) and an upper metallic line (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The process of the aforementioned related art method for forming a dual damascene line structure is simple and has an advantage of preventing an increase in a dielectric constant of the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> through the diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. However, the aforementioned method has a disadvantage in that, in order to form a deep via hole, the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> should be thick enough or the IMD <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> should have a higher etch selectivity than that of the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In addition, removing the polymer that remains within the via hole is difficult, and a micro-trench may be formed in forming the trench. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, another related art method of forming a dual damascene line structure includes sequentially depositing a diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a first IMD <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, an etching stop layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a second IMD <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> including a lower metallic line <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> formed within an insulating layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Then, after depositing a photoresist on the second IMD <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, a photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having a trench pattern is formed by exposure and development processes so that a portion of the second IMD <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is exposed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, using the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as a mask, the second IMD <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is etched by a plasma dry etching process exposing a portion of the etching stop layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so as to form a trench. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>C, the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having a trench pattern is removed. A photoresist is once again deposited on the entire surface. Then, the photoresist is patterned by a negative patterning process to expose a portion of the etching stop layer so as to form a photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a via hole pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>D, using the photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a mask, the etching stop layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the first IMD <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and the diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are selectively etched exposing a portion of a lower metallic line so as to form a via hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Then, after depositing a metallic material such as tungsten, which is thick enough to completely bury the via hole and the trench, the metallic material is polished by a CMP process exposing an upper surface of the second IMD <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to form a plug (not shown) and an upper metallic line (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The process of the aforementioned related art method of forming a dual damascene line structure has an advantage of controlling the depth and profile of etching during the trench etching and the via hole etching processes. However, the aforementioned method has a difficulty in controlling the width of the via hole when forming the photoresist pattern for a via hole etching process and an increase in dielectric constant of the IMDs due to the etching stop layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, the two related art methods for forming a dual damascene line structure have the following problems. When etching a via hole and a trench by using a photoresist pattern as a mask for etching an IMD, it is difficult to form a fine pattern due to the thickness of the photoresist pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> This not only results in a difficulty in accurately controlling the size of the trench or the via hole, but also results in a plurality of polymers produced during the etching process of the IMDs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention is directed to a method for a forming dual damascene line structure that substantially obviates one or more of problems due to limitations and disadvantages of the related art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a method for a forming dual damascene line structure capable of forming a fine pattern, by using two(2) metallic hard masks with completely different etching methods to form a via hole and a trench. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Additional features and advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows and in part will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objectives and other advantages of the invention will be realized and attained by the structure particularly pointed out in the written description and claims hereof as well as the appended drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> To achieve these and other advantages and in accordance with the purpose of the present invention, as embodied and broadly described, a method for forming a dual damascene line structure on a substrate includes sequentially depositing an inter-metal dielectric and a first hard mask over the substrate, partially removing the first hard mask to have a positive trench pattern using a first photoresist pattern as a mask, forming a second hard mask having a substantially different etch selectivity from the first hard mask on the partially removed portion of the first hard mask, selectively removing the first hard mask to have a negative via hole pattern using a second photoresist pattern as a mask, partially removing the inter-metal dielectric to have a via hole pattern using the first hard mask as a mask, and forming a trench and a via hole by removing the exposed first hard mask and selectively etching the inter-metal dielectric using the second hard mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory and are intended to provide further explanation of the invention as claimed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this application, illustrate embodiments of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principle of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating process steps of a related art method for forming a dual damascene line structure; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating process steps of another related art method for forming a dual damascene line structure; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating process steps of a method for forming a dual damascene line structure according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to the illustrated embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are cross-sectional views illustrating process steps of a method for forming a dual damascene line structure according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A, a</cross-reference> trench for forming a lower metallic line <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is formed within an insulating layer on a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> by a damascene method. In this embodiment, a metallic material is buried within the trench for forming a lower metallic line to form a lower metallic line <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, silicon nitride having a low dielectric constant is deposited on the lower metallic line <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to form a diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A low IMD material is further deposited on the diffusion barrier layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to form an IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> becomes an insulating layer for the lower metallic line <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and an upper metallic line, which will be formed in a later process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In addition, a metallic material is deposited on the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to form a first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A hard mask has different etch characteristics from an underlying dielectric. Also, the hard mask is more resistant than photoresist to the etching conditions used for the photoresist pattern into the underlying dielectric. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> A material easily etched by a plasma including an activated Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas may be used as the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. For example, one of Ti, TiN, Ta, and TaN may be chosen for the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Additionally, after depositing a photoresist on the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, a first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> having a positive trench pattern is formed by exposure and developing processes so that a portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is exposed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In this case, the first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is formed to have a minimum thickness in order to partially etch the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> formed having a minimum thickness and the flat first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, are advantageous not only in forming a fine pattern but also in accurately forming a critical dimension of the pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Moreover, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, by using the first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> having a positive trench pattern as a mask, a portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is partially removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In this case, the etching process is performed by using a plasma including an activated Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas to partially etch a portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> that is not protected by the first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> By using the aforementioned process, tungsten can be deposited on a first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, one of a Ti or Ta based material. This is because that tungsten, which is used as a material for a second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, cannot be directly formed on the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In addition, because the first photoresist pattern has a positive trench pattern, the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>also has a positive trench pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, after removing the first photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, tungsten is deposited on the entire surface of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and then, planarized by a CMP process exposing the surface of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>so as to form a second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In this case, the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> has a negative metallic line pattern due to a positive patterning of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Therefore, instead of using a damascene reticle, any reticle can be used to form a damascene pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>D, after depositing a photoresist on the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, a second photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a negative via hole pattern is formed on the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by exposure and development processes. A portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is exposed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In this case, the second photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed to have a minimum thickness in order to etch the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Therefore, with the second photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a thin thickness and the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the flat second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> due to a CMP process, a fine pattern is easily formed and a critical dimension of the pattern can be accurately formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>E, by using the second photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>as a mask, the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is selectively etched. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In this case, the etching process uses a plasma including an activated Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas for etching the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>until the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is exposed to form a via hole pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>F, after removing the second photoresist pattern <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, by using the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>having a via hole pattern and the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as masks, an IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is selectively etched to form a via hole pattern within the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In this case, the via hole formed within the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed by an etching process using a plasma including an activted gas of C<highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>&plus;C<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>y</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>&plus;Ar (wherein a, b, x, y, and z are integers), which has a higher etch selectivity than the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the via hole pattern is etched to have good anisotropic characteristic and a minimum change in its cross-section instead of having a bowing shape whereby the cross-section is frequently changed as etching becomes deeper. Also, because the etching process of the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is carried out without using a photoresist, less metallic polymer is produced during the process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>G, using a second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as a mask, the exposed portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In this case, the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is selectively etched by using a plasma activated by a Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas. In the aforementioned etching process, an etch selectivity of tungsten and oxide is extremely low. Therefore, the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are hardly etched and only an exposed portion of the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>H, using the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having via hole pattern is selectively etched to form a via hole and a trench at the same time. The via hole and the trench penetrate the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and reach a lower metallic line <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In this case, the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is etched by using a plasma activated by a C<highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>&plus;C<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>y</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>&plus;Ar gas (wherein a, b, x, y, and z are integers), and through this etching process the second hard mask <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, after removing the first hard mask <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, a metallic material thick enough to completely bury the via hole and the trench is deposited and planarized by a CMP process, so that the upper surface of the IMD <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is exposed, thereby forming a plug (not shown) and an upper metallic line (not shown) therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The aforementioned method for forming a dual damascene line structure according to the present invention has the following advantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> By reducing a thickness of the photoresist for patterning a hard mask and by patterning the photoresist on a completely flat hard mask, a fine pattern is obtained in the present invention. This facilitates the control of the size in the via hole or the trench and enables to achieve an accurate critical dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In addition, the etching process of the IMD is carried out without using a photoresist. Therefore, the amount of polymer produced during the process is significantly reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the method for forming a dual damascene line structure of the present invention without departing from the spirit or scope of the inventions. Thus, it is intended that the present invention covers the modifications and variations of this invention provided they come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for forming a dual damascene line structure on a substrate, comprising: 
<claim-text>sequentially depositing an inter-metal dielectric and a first hard mask over the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>partially removing the first hard mask to have a positive trench pattern using a first photoresist pattern as a mask; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second hard mask having a substantially different etch selectivity from the first hard mask on the partially removed portion of the first hard mask; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively removing the first hard mask to have a negative via hole pattern using a second photoresist pattern as a mask; </claim-text>
<claim-text>partially removing the inter-metal dielectric to have a via hole pattern using the-first hard mask as a mask; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a trench and a via hole by removing the exposed first hard mask and selectively etching the inter-metal dielectric using the second hard mask. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a lower metallic line formed within the inter-metal dielectric. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a diffusion barrier layer on the lower metallic line including the inter-metal dielectric. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inter-metal dielectric is formed of a low inter-metal dielectric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first hard mask is formed of one of Ti, TiN, Ta, and TaN. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second hard mask is formed of tungsten. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second hard mask is formed to have a metallic line having a negative pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first hard mask is etched by using a plasma etching process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plasma includes a Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inter-metal dielectric is etched by using a plasma including an activated C<highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>&plus;C<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>y</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>&plus;Ar gas (wherein a, b, x, y, and z are integers). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first photoresist pattern has a positive trench pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first photoresist pattern has a thickness thin enough to partially etch the first hard mask. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second photoresist pattern has a negative via hole pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second photoresist pattern has a thickness thin enough to etch the first hard mask only. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising planarizing a second hard mask, by using a chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) process after being deposited on the first hard mask. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising removing remaining portions of the first and second hard masks after forming the via hole and the trench. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising depositing a metallic material within the via hole and the trench to form a plug and an upper metallic line.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3D</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003715A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
