<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000941</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10149977</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>99/16108</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991217</filing-date>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H05B003/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>219</class>
<subclass>543000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>219</class>
<subclass>541000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>338</class>
<subclass>322000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>338</class>
<subclass>068000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Device for heating air, fluids and materials, in dry or wet enviornment, powered with low voltage current or alternating or direct very low safe allowable voltage</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jean-Claude</given-name>
<family-name>Couraud</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Fayence</city>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>James C Lydon</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 100</address-1>
<address-2>100 Daingerfield Road</address-2>
<city>Alexandria</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/FR00/03547</doc-number>
<document-date>20001214</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of heating air, fluid or materials in dry or humid conditions, fed by low voltage alternate or continuous electrical current or TBTS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">The invention concerns a method which allows for an increase in temperature of all kinds of surface, flat or otherwise, filled-in or cellular, composed of electrodes covered with a layer of fluid or sticky material which is electrically resistant. The whole device is very thin (about 1 millimeter). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="0">The device as described in the invention is particularly designed to heat premises, swimming pools and pipes which are exposed to frost as well as containers designed to keep food warm. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention concerns a method of electrical heating of air, fluids or materials, designed to cover all surfaces or objects either flat or otherwise, all sizes and shapes, filled-in or cellular, either functioning under very low power for safety purposes (TBTS) or at low power produced by a specially manufactured system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> We already know of the heat-resistant non-metallic material used in radiant electrical heaters invented by a Bulgarian under BG (patent) 15934, which consisted of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Grey or black graphite, at the rate of 100 particles in weight </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A neutral load material at the rate of 0 to 50 particles in weight </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A black-fired varnish at the rate of 75 to 150 particles in weight </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> And coresiline at the rate of 60 to 120 particles in weight </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> This material had the advantage of allowing local heating at low temperature using less energy than the traditional systems but having the disadvantage of using black or grey graphite and black-fired varnish as a binding agent. These heating agents containing grey or black graphite and black-fired varnish require mechanical treatment in order to provide the required electrical factors. Black-fired varnish provides a relatively low mechanical resistance, but it cracks quite rapidly, and once cracked becomes useless. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> We also know about a heat-resistant electrical material for radiant heating, as stipulated in the French Patent demand FR A 2 593 185 deposited on Oct. 30, 1986, consisting of amorphous graphite, vinyl poly-acetate, adulterated alcohol and a diluting agent comprised of coresiline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Whilst having the advantage of presenting very high heat-resistance, this material also has its disadvantages. For instance, the amount of resistance of this graphite paint is important, which only allows for a very feeble intensity of electrical current, for an applied voltage of about 50 volts at the terminals of such a coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Again we know about the demands for French patents FR 2 709 590 dated Sep. 3, 1993, FR 2 709 589 dated Apr. 29, 1994 and the demand for a European patent EP 0 641 845 dated Aug. 26, 1994 deposited by the inventors THUNY and SINIGALIA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Their invention also had certain disadvantages as was obvious from reading the description of the product and its uses, in that a banned substance (i.e. lead) was encased in it, and that also, the presence of PLIOWAY EC-1 rendered it too fluid. If the fluid worked very well on horizontal surfaces, the same could not be said for vertical application on walls for example (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The support which was uniquely lamellate was not really suitable for electrical junction with stretched conductors in the form of adhesives strips which caused multiple electrical arcing, &agr; (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) between the strips and the heated surface which was inevitably destroyed and became useless. On the other hand, connection to the electrical supply presented a real danger as it was carried out by means of overlapping electrical wires and/or the conductors; but especially the device was useless in humid conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Elsewhere, it is possible to find paints which contain a low percentage in weight (generally about 3%) of conductive charge. The incorporation in the said paints of these charges is destined to improve their application and render them electrostatic. The said paints are not electrically conductive, in view of their low charge content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The invention allows us to remedy these disadvantages. It ensures the possibility of connection to the electrical supply by means of two separate electrodes at a fixed or variable distance, the length L covered with a fluid or sticky material having adjustable electrical specific resistance, connected to points P and N.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DEPENDING ON THE PARTICULAR METHOD OF PRODUCTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The &ldquo;phased&rdquo; electrodes are connected to each other like teeth in a comb by a conductor or a conductive bar, to which the &ldquo;neutral&rdquo; electrodes are attached in the same manner between them either with one spatula head or with multiple connections, all the conductors/electrodes being fixed on an insulating base. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It comprises several phased and neutral electrodes in which the phased electrodes which are parallel to each other are connected to a central phased terminal, and to which the neutral electrodes also parallel to each other are connected to a central neutral terminal, the said phased and neutral electrodes being parallel and interspersed alternately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It consists of two parts symmetrical to the base on which it will be applied, the electrodes on each part being arranged in such a manner that the neutral electrodes of one part are symmetrically interspersed with the phased electrodes of the other part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The layer of sticky or fluid material covers the phased and neutral electrodes and the surface between them in such a manner that as soon as the current is switched on, the fluid or sticky material acts as a heating element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The fluid or sticky material enclosed in a binding agent and/or a supple, elastic or flexible substance at the rate of 10 to 90% of its weight in conductive charge consisting of a mixture of two products, one a granular base, the other in strip form, having different electrical specific resistance, and the variable dose of 50/50 to 10/90% according to the expected final specific resistance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The said products are, firstly, a granular mineral base consisting of particles having a nucleus of titanium dioxide or silica, covered with a solid solution consisting of a mixture of metal antimony and tin dioxide, and secondly, a mineral support in strip form having a mica base covered with a double oxide of tin and antimony. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A fluid layer covers all the electrodes and the heating surface and insulates and protects against oxidization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A flame retardant electrical insulation, single or double leaf and/or fluid covers the whole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A fluid electrical conductor or glued or adhesive leaf called the &ldquo;earth&rdquo; covers the whole of the process, and is connected to the earth of the electrical installation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The entire device is sandwiched in a sheath which is entirely waterproof: Initially stuck to the base, then enclosed to form a sheath, either in a fluid or a glued or self-adhesive thermo-stiffened sheet to ensure total proof against humidity, and/or protection against shocks and/or acts as an electrical insulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The invention also applies to the process of manufacture as used in the production of such an electrical heating system for air, fluid or material, destined to cover surfaces or flat or cellular objects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Phased and neutral electrodes are applied to a base which is already covered with an insulating film if it is not electrically insulating, the said electrodes being connected to phased or neutral terminals P and N; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> An adjustable fluid or sticky material having electrical specific resistance is applied to the electrodes and between them; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The fluid or sticky material is left to dry; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A layer of electrical insulating material covers the whole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the invention in accordance with the first method of manufacture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a section of the molecular structure of the mixture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a section of the different components of the device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows two types of network of electrodes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a particular method of manufacture and supply of current to the constituent electrodes after connection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates in perspective a particular method of manufacture of an adaptation of the invention to cover two sides of a support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> With reference to these drawings, the method includes connection to the current by means of two electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) connected to terminals P and N length L, fixed on a base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and spaced having a distance d, forming a heating surface (S). a layer of fluid material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is spread on or between these cylindrical or long electrodes. This fluid or sticky material is enclosed in a binding agent for a surface coating/or a supple, elastic or flexible material of 10 to 90% in weight of resistant charge/electrical conductors consisting of a mix of two different types of base: one granular in order that the particles penetrate the spaces and corners as well as in between, on and under the strips of the other base which is called &ldquo;lamellate&rdquo;. By choosing a different specific resistance between the two products, we can work on the temperature of the surface to be heated (S) by creating a mix having variable proportions of 50/50 to 10/90%. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In the type shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the electrodes in strip form lying parallel are joined by a conductor (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;) as in the teeth of a comb, then spread in spatula form in order to obtain an alternation of phased and neutral electrodes allowing for connection to be carried out in P and N without overlapping the connecting wires and those at one end and/or at both ends of the layout. In this way, we can produce a general heating surface in the form of a band by multiplying the number of electrodes having a regular temperature at all points. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the form shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the electrodes in strip form are connected to each other, either parallel or transversally. This type of multiple overlapping layout placed side by side allows for the heating of large areas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The layer of fluid or sticky material is allowed to dry, then the whole is covered with a layer of fluid (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) to protect against oxidization. This fluid may also be electrically insulating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> On an electrical insulation (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) covered with the layer (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) an electrical conductor (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) formed by a layer of conducting fluid or a conductive leaf creating &ldquo;the earth&rdquo; covers the electrical insulation (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>), and is connected to the earth of the electrical installation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The whole layout is sandwiched between a waterproof layer (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) joined to the waterproof under-coat (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) forming a waterproof sheath. This last may be fluid, thermo-adhesive, thermo-hardening or stuck to materials such as tiles, plastic, glass . . . </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In order to vary the power of the heating, we can act on four different parameters, i.e. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The specific resistance of the fluid or sticky material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The length L of the electrodes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The spread d of the electrodes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The electrical current </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The technical field of the invention is that of the components of the coating, for instance, the paint, varnish, thick coatings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> It may be used in many different fields such as: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In construction for the heating of premises and swimming pools. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In agriculture, in green-houses, for heating soil for cultivation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In the automobile industry, nautical, clothing, textiles, food processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In any case, anybody connected with the trade, reading the above description would be aware of the limitless potential applications of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> We intend to illustrate the invention in its principal form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The electrically resistant fluid material called heating material was made with components which were incorporated as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Binding agent: a varnish consisting of two separate parts which were then incorporated  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="112PT" align="char"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>1st part</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Plioway EC 1</entry>
<entry>6.45</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>White spirit - 1%</entry>
<entry>38.55</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Bentone SD 1</entry>
<entry>0.12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Soya Lecithin</entry>
<entry>0.05</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Subtotal</entry>
<entry>45.17</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>2nd part</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Plioway EC-L</entry>
<entry>7.67</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Dowanol DPnB</entry>
<entry>0.95</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>White Spirit - 1%</entry>
<entry>46</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Bentone SD 1</entry>
<entry>0.15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Soya Lecithin</entry>
<entry>0.06</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total</entry>
<entry>100.00</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Resistant charge </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> 1410 T: sold as SPCI. These are granular particles of titanium dioxide, covered in a solid solution of a mixture of metal antimony and tin dioxide having a specific resistance of 3 ohm/cm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Minatec 31: sold as MERCK. These are strip particles of mica covered in double oxide of tin and antimony having a specific resistance of 4 Kohm (MERCK method) less than 100 ohm/cm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="4"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The product 1410 T is incorporated into the binding agent in the proportion of one volume for 5 volumes of binding agent. It is then allowed to stand for a period of 24 hours. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="4"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Then 4 volumes of the product Minatec 31 is slowly stirred into the substance the evening before use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> With one liter of heating material as described in the above method of manufacture, a surface area of 6m<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>may be heated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The following results were obtained using different criteria: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> On material BA 13 (plasterboard covered with wall-paper)  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Surface</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Voltage</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>Temperature</entry>
<entry>Intensity</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>220 volts</entry>
<entry>&thinsp;12 cms</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&thinsp;62&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>2.01 A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>220 volts</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&thinsp;9 cms</entry>
<entry>more than 100&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>2.02 A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&ensp;45 volts</entry>
<entry>2.8 cms</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&thinsp;65&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>&ensp;0.1 A</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&ensp;12 v continuous</entry>
<entry>0.5 cm</entry>
<entry>50.3&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>0.11 A for an area</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of 8 &times; 2 cm</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&ensp;12 volt intermittent</entry>
<entry>0.5 cm</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&thinsp;54&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>0.08 A for an area</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of 8 &times; 2 cm</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>On fabric</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>220 volts</entry>
<entry>&thinsp;10 cms</entry>
<entry>50.5&deg; C.</entry>
<entry>&ensp;0.1 mA</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> &emsp;Looking back at <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, you will note a diagram of an electrical junction box (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) containing a bi-polar inflow having a phased terminal (P) and a neutral terminal (N). Using this particular method, plurality of phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and neutral (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) is provided in a special manner. As illustrated, the phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are all communally connected to the phased terminal (P). In the same way, the neutral electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are connected to the neutral terminal (N). What is more, all of the electrodes are in this case formed by parallel metallic bars and the neutral and phased electrodes laid-out alternately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In another variation of the invention as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> double device is formed on each side of the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> diagrammatically indicates the special position of the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) without showing the other constitutive elements of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Depending on the method of manufacture, two markedly identical devices are formed on each side of the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). In this instance, the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) take the form of long metal bars connected on each of the two sides. To add to this, the phased electrode on one side is placed opposite the neutral electrode on the other side and vice-versa. The other stages of manufacture of the invention are the same as described previously and are the same on each side of the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The special positions adopted for the phased and neutral electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) have the advantage of enhancing security. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In fact, if inadvertently, the user pierces the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) (for example by means of a nail or screw) this method would immediately result in a power-cut caused by a short-circuit. The user having automatically come into contact with a phased electrode (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The invention also concerns a procedure for the manufacture of the layout as indicated above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The following is a presentation of the essential phases of the manufacturing process. The object of the exercise is to provide a method of heating a base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) for example in the form of a sheet or leaf or any other surface. In order to do this, we place a film of insulating material on the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) if this is an electrical conductor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> We then place phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and neutral (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) on the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) prepared in this manner. In the best method, the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are metallic conductive elements in strip form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Once the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are in position they are covered and so is the area between the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) with a fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> To protect the whole and electrically insulate their environment, they are covered by means of a layer of electrical insulating material (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> This invention is of particular interest in the heating of areas having low voltage or very low voltage but is not limited to these areas.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>REFERENCES</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="91PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1.</entry>
<entry>Base</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2.</entry>
<entry>Sheath</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3.</entry>
<entry>Insulating base</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4.</entry>
<entry>Phased electrode</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4&prime;.</entry>
<entry>&emsp;&emsp;&emsp;Neutral electrode</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5.</entry>
<entry>Fluid or sticky material</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6.</entry>
<entry>Layer</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7.</entry>
<entry>Electrical insulating material</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8.</entry>
<entry>Electrical conductor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9.</entry>
<entry>Fluid</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10.10&prime;</entry>
<entry>&emsp;&emsp;&emsp;Conductor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10.</entry>
<entry>Junction box</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>A.</entry>
<entry>&emsp;&emsp;&emsp;Phase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>N.</entry>
<entry>Neutral</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Method of heating air, fluid and materials, destined to cover surfaces and objects flat or otherwise, all sizes and shapes, filled-in or cellular, characterized by the fact that it comprises connection to electrical current by means of two electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) separated by a fixed or variable distance, length L, covered by a fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) having an adjustable specific resistance (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) connected to terminals P and N. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> characterized by the fact that the electrodes &ldquo;phase&rdquo; (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are connected to each other like teeth in a comb by a conductor (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) or a conductive bar, that the electrodes &ldquo;neutral&rdquo; (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are connected to each other like teeth in a comb by a conductor (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;) or a conductive bar, laid out in spatula form either single or multiple, all of the conductors/electrodes being fixed on the insulating base (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> characterized by the fact that it comprises several phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and neutral (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) and that the phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are connected to the same phased terminal (P) and are parallel, that the neutral electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are connected to the same neutral terminal (N) and are parallel, the said phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the neutral (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are parallel to each other and are positioned alternately. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, characterized by the fact that it consists of two symmetrical parts depending on the thickness of the base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to which it is applied, the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) of each part are organised in such a manner that the neutral electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) on one side are placed in symmetry with the phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) on the other side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">4</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that the layer of fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) covers the phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the neutral (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) as well as the surface (S) between them, in such a manner that when connected to the current, the fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) acts as a heating element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that the fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) incorporated in the binding agent, or/and a supple, elastic, or flexible substance with 10 to 90% weight in conductive charge of a mixture of these two products, one a granular base, the other a base in strip form, to electrical specific resistance, and a variable dosage of 50/50 to 10/90% according to the required final specific resistance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Device as described in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that the said products are, on the one hand, a mineral granular base consisting of particles in which the nucleus is titanium dioxide or silica, covered with a solid solution of a mix of metal antimony and tin dioxide, and on the other hand, a mineral strip form having a base of mica covered in a double oxide of tin and antimony. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">7</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that a layer (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) of fluid electrical insulating product and protection against oxidization covers all of the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) as well as the surface to be heated (S). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">8</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that a flame-proof electrical insulator, (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) either single or double, in leaf form and/or fluid, covers the whole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Device as described in claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">9</dependent-claim-reference> characterized by the fact that an electrical conductor (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) either fluid or in leaf form glued or self-adhesive called the &ldquo;earth&rdquo; covers the whole, and is connected to the earth of the electrical installation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Device as described in any one of the claims from <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> characterized by the fact that the entire mechanism is in sandwich form creating a waterproof sheath; firstly applied to the base, then enclosed in a waterproof fluid or leaf(leaves) glued or self-adhesive or thermo-hardening, which ensures that the device is totally damp-proof, and/or protected against shocks, and/or acts as an electrical insulation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Method of manufacture of a device designed to heat air, fluid and materials, destined to cover surfaces or objects either flat and/or shaped, used for the manufacture of a device which conforms to any one of the claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">11</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized by the fact that: 
<claim-text>phased electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and neutral electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) are stuck to a base (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) previously covered by an insulating film if it is not electrically insulated, the said electrodes being connected to an electrical current by phased and neutral terminals P and N; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) having an adjustable specific resistance, is applied to the electrodes (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime;) and between these; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the fluid or sticky material (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) is allowed to dry. </claim-text>
<claim-text>A layer of electrical insulating material (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) is applied to the whole mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000941A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000941A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000941A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000941A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
