<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001598A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001598A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001598</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10000114</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011030</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01R031/305</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>324</class>
<subclass>751000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and methods for reliable and efficient detection of voltage contrast defects</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302096</doc-number>
<document-date>20010629</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kurt</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Weiner</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gaurav</given-name>
<family-name>Verma</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Atherton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Isabella</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lewis</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>KLA-Tencor Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BEYER WEAVER &amp; THOMAS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 778</address-1>
<city>BERKELEY</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94704-0778</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Disclosed are methods and apparatus for automatically filtering out physical defects from electrical defects that are found during a voltage contrast inspection of a test structure on a semiconductor device. In general terms, the test structure is designed to include a plurality of features that will charge to specific voltage potentials when scanned with an electron beam during a voltage contrast inspection. Images of the scanned features are generated, and the relative brightness level of each feature depends on the corresponding potential on such feature. That is, some features are expected to appear dark, and other features are expected to appear bright. If there is no defect present in the scanned feature, the corresponding image will have the expected number of bright and dark features. However, if there is a defect present, the number of dark and bright features within the generated image will not match expected results. The test structure is also designed so have substantially identical pairs of features. In one implementation, each pair includes a feature that is expected to appear bright and another feature that is expected to appear dark within the generated image. Thus, an image may be generated for each set of features. The generated images are then subtracted from each other to determine whether any defects are present. Alternatively, an image of an inspected set of features may be compared to a reference image constructed from a design database. A subtraction that results in a defect is then analyzed to determine whether it is an electrical defect or a physical defect. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application takes priority under U.S.C. 119(e) of U.S. Provisional Application No.: 60/302,096 filed Jun. 29, 2001 entitled, &ldquo;APPARATUS AND METHODS RELIABLE AND EFFICIENT DETECTION OF VOLTAGE CONTRAST DEFECTS&rdquo; by Kurt H. Weiner, Gaurav Verna, and Isabella T. Lewis, which is incorporated by reference in its entirety for all purposes.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to methods and apparatus for detecting electrical defects in a semiconductor device or test structure having a plurality of features that are specifically designed to produce varying voltage potentials during a voltage contrast inspection. More particularly, it relates to voltage contrast techniques for detecting open and short type defects within the features of the circuit or test structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A voltage contrast inspection of a test structure is accomplished with a scanning electron microscope. The voltage contrast technique operates on the basis that potential differences in the various locations of a sample under examination cause differences in secondary electron emission intensities when the sample is the target of an electron beam. The potential state of the scanned area is acquired as a voltage contrast image such that a low potential portion of, for example, a wiring pattern might be displayed as bright (intensity of the secondary electron emission is high) and a high potential portion might be displayed as dark (lower intensity secondary electron emission). Alternatively, the system may be configured such that a low potential portion might be displayed as dark and a high potential portion might be displayed as bright. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A secondary electron detector is used to measure the intensity of the secondary electron emission that originates from the path swept by the scanning electron beam. Images may then be generated from these electron emissions. A defective portion can be identified from the potential state or appearance of the portion under inspection. The portion under inspection is typically designed to produce a particular potential and resulting brightness level in an image during the voltage contrast test. Hence, when the scanned portion&apos;s potential and resulting image appearance differs significantly from the expected result, the scanned portion is classified a defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Several inventive test structures designed by the present assignee are disclosed in copending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/648,093 (Attorney Docket No. KLA1P016A) by Satya et al., filed Aug. 25, 2000, which application is incorporated herein in its entirety. In one embodiment, a test structure is designed to have alternating high and low potential conductive lines during a voltage contrast inspection. In one inspection application, the low potential lines are at ground potential, while the high potential lines are at a floating potential. However, if a line that is meant to remain floating shorts to an adjacent grounded line, both lines will now produce a low potential during a voltage contrast inspection. If there is an open defect present within a line that is supposedly coupled to ground, this open will cause a portion of the line to be left at a floating potential to thereby produce a high potential during the voltage contrast inspection. Both open and short defects causes two adjacent lines to have a same potential during the voltage inspection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In theory, defects within the above described test structure may be found by comparing images of portions of the test structure that are designed to have identical appearances during voltage contrast inspection. Thus, any difference between two supposedly identical imaged portions can be classified as an electrical defect. However, certain physical defects within the conductive line may introduce &ldquo;nuisance&rdquo; defects into the inspection process. That is, physical defects may be inadvertently counted as electrical defects. In one voltage contrast technique, a first set of imaged adjacent conductive lines are subtracted from a second set of imaged adjacent lines. The imaged sets are selected so that they will be identical if they contain no defects. Thus, if the subtraction operation results in a nonzero value, imaged sets are flagged as having one or more defects. Unfortunately, this subtraction procedure may result in physical defects being flagged, as well as electrical defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The total defect count which results from a voltage contrast inspection on specially designed test chips can run into the thousands for a complete wafer. Manually reviewing and classifying these defects to isolate the electrical defects from the physical defects is very time consuming and tedious. Additionally, manual classification is inherently subject to human errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there is a need for improved apparatus and methods for detecting electrical defects in semiconductor device and test structures without having to manually filter physical defects from the inspection results. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, mechanisms are provided for automatically filtering out physical defects from electrical defects during a voltage contrast inspection of a test structure on a semiconductor device. In general terms, the test structure is designed to include a plurality of features that will charge to specific voltage potentials when scanned with an electron beam during a voltage contrast inspection. Images of the scanned features are generated, and the relative brightness level of each feature depends on the corresponding potential of each feature during the inspection. That is, some features are expected to appear dark, and other features are expected to appear bright. If there is no defect present in the scanned feature, the corresponding image will have the expected number of bright and dark features. However, if there is a defect present, the number of dark and bright features within the generated image will not match expected results. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The test structure may also be designed so have substantially identical pairs of features. In one implementation, each pair includes a feature that is expected to appear bright and another feature that is expected to appear dark within the generated image. Thus, an image may be generated for each set of features. The generated images are then subtracted from each other to determine whether any defects are present. Alternatively, an image of an inspected set of features may be compared to a reference image constructed from a design database. A subtraction that results in a defect is then analyzed to determine whether it is an electrical defect or a physical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the aspect ratio of each scanned feature is known. If the defect has substantially the same aspect ratio as the known aspect ratio, it is determined to be an electrical defect. Otherwise, it is determined to be a physical defect. Other mechanisms are described for locating the found electrical defect and filtering out the location of physical defects during this process. Additionally, mechanisms are described for calibrating the inspection process based on a test structure having a plurality of known defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a method of detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device is disclosed. Each of the features is designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam. A first and second image of a first and second set of feature portions, respectively, are provided. The first and second images are generated as a result of scanning an electron beam over the first and second set of feature portions, and the first set of feature portions are designed to be substantially identical to the second set of feature portions when there is no defect present. The first image is subtracted from a second image to generate a difference image. When the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions, it is determined whether the defect is an electrical defect or a physical defect. In one implementation, this determination is accomplished by determining that the defect indicates an electrical defect when the defect has about a same aspect ratio as a one of the scanned feature portions. When the defect has a different aspect ratio than a one of the scanned feature portions, it is determined that the defect indicates a physical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In a specific implementation, the features include a plurality of conductive lines, and the conductive lines are designed to include a plurality of lines at a grounded potential interleaved and are arranged parallel with a plurality of lines at a floating potential. An electrical defect is found when two adjacent conductive lines have a same potential when scanned with the electron beam. In another aspect, the scanned feature portions are a plurality of end stub portions of the conductive lines, and each end stub portion has a substantially same aspect ratio. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In a further implementation, it is determined that the electrical defect is a short when the when the defect has a first brightness value. It is determined that the electrical defect is an open when the differ when the defect has a second brightness value. In one aspect, the first brightness value is higher than the second brightness value. In yet another embodiment, when an electrical defect is found, the electron beam is then scanned along the defective feature perpendicular to the first scan to form a plurality of images of portions of the defective feature not scanned in the first scan and one or more features adjacent to the defective feature. A first image of the defective feature is subtracted from a second image of the defective feature to obtain a difference image. The defective feature is designed to have a first portion having a bright appearance and a second portion having a dark appearance when there is an open defect present within the defective feature. When the difference image has a significantly sized second defect that represents a difference between the first and second image of the defective feature, it is then determined whether the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect or a physical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In a preferred implementation, determining whether the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect or a physical defect is accomplished by determining that the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect and that the electrical defect is an open when the second defect would be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image. It is determined that the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect and that the electrical defect is a short defect when the second defect would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the second defect touches two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image. It is determined that the second defect represents a location of a physical defect when the second defect would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the second defect does not touch two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, the invention pertains to a computer program product for detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device. Each of the features is designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam, the computer program product includes at least one computer readable medium and computer program instructions stored within the at least one computer readable product configured to cause the inspection system to perform one or more of the above described methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, the invention pertains to an inspection system for detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device. Each of the features is designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam. The system includes a beam generator for generating an electron beam, a detector for detecting electrons, and a controller arranged to cause the beam generator to scan an electron beam over a first and a second set of feature portions. The first set is designed be substantially identical to the second set of feature portions when there is no defect present. The controller is further arranged to generate a first image of the first set of feature portions and a second image of the second set of feature portions from electrons detected by the detector emitted from the scanned feature portions in response to the scanned electron beam. The controller is also configured to subtract the first image from the second image to generate a difference image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> When the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect has about a same aspect ratio as a one of the scanned feature portions, the controller is further configured to determine that the defect indicates an electrical defect within the scanned features. When the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect has a different aspect ratio than a one of the scanned feature portions, the controller is further configured to determine that the defect indicates a physical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> These and other features and advantages of the present invention will be presented in more detail in the following specification of the invention and the accompanying figures which illustrate by way of example the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic top view representation of a test structure on which the techniques of the present invention may be implemented in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic representation of a cell subtraction procedure, wherein one of the cells contains an electrical defect, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates subtraction process for cells, wherein one of the cells contains a physical defect, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic illustration of a subtraction procedure implemented on a cell containing a partially imaged stub in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> illustrates a technique for determining the location of an open defect within two or more electrically defective test features in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> illustrates a subtraction process for determining the location of an open type electrical defect within two or more electrically defective test features while filtering out the locations of any physical defect in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> illustrates a subtraction process for determining the location of a short type electrical defect within two or more electrically defective test features while filtering out the locations of any physical defect in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating a calibration procedure in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic representation of a system in which the techniques of the present invention may be implemented. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF SPECIFIC EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to a specific embodiment of the invention. An example of this embodiment is illustrated in the accompanying drawings. While the invention will be described in conjunction with this specific embodiment, it will be understood that it is not intended to limit the invention to one embodiment. On the contrary, it is intended to cover alternatives, modifications, and equivalents as may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. The present invention may be practiced without some or all of these specific details. In other instances, well known process operations have not been described in detail in order not to unnecessarily obscure the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The detection techniques of the present invention may be applied to any type of structure having features that respond to a voltage contrast inspection in a known way when defects are not present within the test structure. The test structure include features that will have particular voltage potentials when scanned with an electron beam. Some of the features may retain a low potential, while other features charge up to a higher potential. When an image is generated from electrons emitted from the scanned features, the image will also depend on the features&apos; particular potentials achieved or retained during the electron beam scan. For example, a features having a low potential may result in a bright feature, while a feature with a high potential may result in a dark feature within the image. Alternatively, low potential features may appear dark, and high potential features appear bright. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Since the test structure is designed to result in a particular image, one may determine whether there is a defect in a portion of the test structure by comparing the imaged &ldquo;target&rdquo; portion to a reference image having no defects. The reference image may be an identical portion of the test structure or may be generated from a design database (e.g., that was used to fabricate the test structure). Significant differences between the target and the reference images may be classified as defects. The present invention includes mechanisms for analyzing these defects to determine whether they are electrical or physical defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic top view representation of a test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> on which the techniques of the present invention may be implemented in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is referred to as a comb-like structure. As shown, the test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of grounded conductive lines and a plurality of floating conductive line <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Voltage contrast images of a top portion of the conductive lines <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are generated as an electron beam moves in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Each image is referred herein to as a &ldquo;cell.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the image cells correspond to feature portions that are designed to result in substantially identical images when no defects are present. In one embodiment, an image cell is generated for a top portion of each pair of grounded and floating lines. However, other portions of the features (e.g., a middle portion of the conductive lines) may be scanned. As shown, when the conductive lines are scanned in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, cell <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is first obtained and then cell <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is obtained. Since the test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is expected to have alternating lines of grounded and floating potential, each image cell is expected to contain a bright line and a dark line. For example, the grounded lines <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> will appear bright, while the floating lines <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> will appear dark. Of course, the inspection tool may be set up so that the grounded lines <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> appear dark and the floating lines <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> appear bright. The intensity value of the conductive lines as the electron beam scans across them may also be graphed as shown in intensity graph <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. When there are no defects, the intensity values are expected to include alternating high and low intensity values. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> However, the test structure may contain electrical defects, as well as physical defects. As shown, there is an electrical short <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>between line <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight>This short <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>causes both lines <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>to appear bright. Another type of electrical defect that may occur in the test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is an open. As shown, there is an open defect <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in line <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i. </italic></highlight>An open defect causes a portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of line <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>to have a floating potential. Accordingly, the floating portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> will appear dark, while the portion of the line that remains coupled to ground (<highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>) will have a bright appearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In sum, when two lines are shorted together, both lines will appear bright when scanned in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In contrast, when a supposedly grounded line contains an open, the top portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of such line has the same dark appearance as its neighboring floating conductive lines when scanned in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when the electron beam moves in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, a defect may be found when a particular cell is subtracted from another cell. For example, cell <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be subtracted from cell <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>If the particular cell does not have a defect, this subtraction will ideally produce zero results. In contrast, when the particular cell has a defect, this subtraction will produce a significant difference that is then classified as a defect. Electron beam tool parameter settings determine the percentage difference between the two cells that will be classified as a defect. The parameter settings may be experimentally determined and adjusted, for example, according to techniques described below with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrated a cell subtraction procedure, wherein one of the cells contains an electrical defect, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As shown, cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>contains a pair of conductive line portions <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with different brightness levels (e.g., cell <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is bright and cell <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is dark). Cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>contains two conductive line portions <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>having the same brightness level (e.g., they both appear dark). Since each cell is expected to have conductive line portions with different brightness levels, a cell that has conductive lines with the same brightness level is expected to represent a defective feature. As shown, cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is defect free, while cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>contains defective conductive line <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>If the above described comb type test structure <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is being imaged, conductive line <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>probably contains an open. If there was an electrical short present, both lines within the cell would appear bright in this implementation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An electrical defect may be found by subtracting two cells. Cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>contains a representation of a result from subtracting cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>The result of this subtraction is defect <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Defect <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is substantially the same size as a scanned feature portion. Defect <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> has width <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and height <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, which are substantially equal to feature width <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and height <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. This similarity may be used to distinguish electrical defects from physical defects, as explained further below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a subtraction procedure using two cells, wherein one of the cells contains a physical defect <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As shown, cell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>includes bright line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and dark line <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Cell A also includes a physical defect <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. Cell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>contains bright line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and dark line <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Since each cell contains both a dark line and a bright line, the corresponding features of such cells do not contain electrical defects. However, the above described subtraction method may result in a defect being found. As illustrated, the results of such subtraction process are represented in cell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>where cell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is subtracted from cell <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>As shown, this subtraction process results in defect <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The present invention includes techniques for filtering out physical defects (e.g., <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) from electrical defects. The physical defects may take any form, such as bumps along the edge of the line, indentations along the edge of the line, or holes within the center of the line. Electrical defects may be distinguished from physical defects since the aspect ratio of an electrical defect will tend to have about the same aspect ratio as a corresponding scanned feature portion. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the aspect ratio for feature portion <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(the scanned top portion is herein referred to as a &ldquo;stub&rdquo;) has length <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and width <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, which are substantially the same as the aspect ratio of electrical defect <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> having length <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and width <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. In one particular design process, each stub has a length of five &mgr;m and a width of 0.13 &mgr;m. In contrast, a physical defect will have a significantly different aspect ratio than a scanned feature portion (e.g., stub). As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, physical defect <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> has an aspect ratio with a length <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and a width <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> which vary significantly from the width and length of a scanned stub (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). Accordingly, when the defect has an aspect ratio that is substantially the same as a scanned feature portion&apos;s aspect ratio, the defect is classified as an electrical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Even when the stubs are not properly imaged, the techniques of the present invention may provide effective mechanisms for filtering out physical defects from electrical defects. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic illustration of a subtraction procedure implemented on cells containing a partially imaged stub in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As shown, cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>contains a partially imaged stub <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>However, this partially imaged stub <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has an intensity value that contrasts with the adjacent stub <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Accordingly, this cell does not contain a defect. Cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>includes two dark stubs <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Since stubs <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are both dark, cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is associated with an electrical defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>represents subtraction of cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>As shown, the aspect ratio for defect <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> may be determined by drawing a boundary <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> around the resulting defects <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>This boundary <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> has a length <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> and a width <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight>. This length <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> and width <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> of defect <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> is substantially equivalent to the aspect ratio of one of the stubs as shown in cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>having length <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and width <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. The resulting defect will have the same aspect ratio when cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is subtracted from cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>as compared to subtracting cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrates defect <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> having dark spots <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>resulting from such alternative subtraction process. As shown, this defect <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> has the same aspect ratio having length <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> and width <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> as the defect <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> in cell <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>Thus, both defects <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> are classified as electrical defects since their aspect ratios are substantially the same as the aspect ratio of a scanned stub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, when it is determined that a conductive line contains an electrical defect by scanning in direction <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, the actual defect (e.g., short or open) may be located by scanning in direction <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. While searching for an electrical defect, a physical defect may also be found. Preferably, the location of physical defects are filtered out from the location of an electrical defect. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> illustrates a technique for determining the location of an open type defect in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. As the electron beam scans down the defective conductive line (as illustrated by direction <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), cell images are generated for portions of the defective conductive line, as well as portions of adjacent conductive lines. Any suitable number of lines may be imaged during this scan. For simplicity, only two lines are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Cells <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate contiguous portions of two conductive lines <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight>. In cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the first conductive line <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> contains a dark portion <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the second conductive line <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight> contains a dark portion <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>In cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the first conductive line includes a dark line portion <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which is contiguous to the dark portion <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>In cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the second conductive line includes a dark line portion <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the electrical open <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>and a bright line portion <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>illustrates the results from subtracting cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Preferably contiguous cells are subtracted from each other. However, non-contiguous cells may also be subtracted from each other. The subtraction produces dark portion <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and bright portion <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>It is determined that the defect is an electrical defect when there is a transition <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>between dark and bright intensity within the resulting defects <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The transition <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>location may be determined to be the defect location. Alternatively, the defect portion <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that is positioned above the intensity transition <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>may be determined to be the defect location. This location of defect <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>corresponds more accurately to the actual electrical defect location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> illustrates a subtraction process for determining the location of an open type electrical defect within two or more electrically defective test features while filtering out the locations of any physical defect in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Portions of two dark lines <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> are present in cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>However, cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>also contains physical defect <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>. A physical defect may be encountered as the electron beam scans down the defective line before reaching the actual electrical defect. In this case, since the electrical defect is an open defect, both lines <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> appear dark. In other imaging implementations, both lines may appear bright for an open type defect before reaching the open defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>illustrates the subtraction of cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>As shown, the subtraction results in defect <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>. However in this case, there is no transition in intensity adjacent to the defect <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> (as when the actual electrical open defect is found). Thus, it is determined that this defect <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> is a physical defect, as opposed to an electrical defect. Alternatively, since the position of the actual electrical defect is expected to be within area <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> or area <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>, if the defect is not within these areas <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> it may be classified as a physical defect. If the difference cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>was overlaid with the non-defective cell <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>these areas correspond to the conductive line portions <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. However, this alternative technique may not work for other types of defects such as indentations or holes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Another type of electrical defect is a short. Such a defect is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as defect <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>In one short defect example, as the electron beam scans down a defective line and its adjacent lines to find a short&apos;s location, the defective line and the adjacent lines are expected to have a same intensity value. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>C, cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>contains bright lines <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. Cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>also includes a physical defect <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> and a short defect <highlight><bold>557</bold></highlight>. Cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>illustrates the results from subtracting cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>This subtraction results in physical defect <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight> and short defect <highlight><bold>559</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Any suitable technique may be utilized to distinguish the electrical defect <highlight><bold>559</bold></highlight> from the physical defect <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight>. Initially, the areas of the conductive lines may be determined. As shown, cell <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>includes area <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and area <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. In one technique, the defect image <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>may be overlaid with the image <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which contains no defects to determine conductive line areas <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> in the defect image <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>A short type defect would be expected to touch both areas <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, since defect <highlight><bold>559</bold></highlight> touches area <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and area <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>, it is determined to be an electrical defect. In contrast, if the defect merely touches one of the areas, the defect is determined to be a physical defect. Since defect <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight> merely touches area <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> and not area <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>, it is determined to be a physical defect. Alternatively, it may determined whether the defect has a substantially same width as the spacing between each scanned feature (e.g., <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight>). If the defect width is substantially the same, it is classified as an electrical short defect. If the defect width is not substantially the same, it is classified as a physical defect. If a particular defect is classified as an electrical defect, its location is determined to be the location for the short defect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Mechanisms for calibrating the inspection tool may also be implemented. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating a calibration procedure in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Initially, a test structure having a plurality of known defects is provided in operation <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. For example, the test structure is a comb type structure that includes a plurality of known opens and short defects. Additionally, the test structure may include a number of known physical defects. Operating parameters for the inspection system (e.g., scanning electron microscope) are then selected in operation <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. Operating parameters include, but are not limited to, landing energy (for the electron beam), extraction energy, acceleration voltage, sensitivity, threshold, etc. The operating parameters may also include the specific algorithms used to filter out physical defects from electrical defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The test structure is then scanned for defects using the selected operating parameters in operation <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>. It is then determined whether the defect capture rate is acceptable in operation <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>. For example, it may determined whether all or a significant portion (greater than 95%) of the known electrical defects have been captured. Additionally, it may be determined whether the physical defects were filtered out of the defect captures. If the capture rate is acceptable, the procedure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> ends. If the defect capture rate is not acceptable, the selected operating parameters are then adjusted in operation <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>. For example, the settings of the scanning electron microscope that affect defect detection sensitivity are adjusted. Additionally, the techniques for distinguishing between electrical and physical defects may be modified if the electrical defects are not being properly distinguished from the physical defects. The test structure continues to be scanned for defects and the selected operating parameters adjusted until the defect capture rate is within acceptable limits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> These known defects may also be used for in-situ monitoring of the performance of the inspection. For every wafer that is scanned, statistics are automatically maintained regarding the capture rate of the known defects. These statistics provide the ability to monitor the performance of the tool for every inspection. If the performance of the inspection degrades, this can be determined in real time and the operator can be alerted. The operator can then re-optimize the electron microscope parameters to obtain acceptable capture rates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic representation of a scanning electron microscope (SEM) system in which the techniques of the present invention may be implemented. The detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is provided for illustrative purposes. One skilled in the art would understand that variations to the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> fall within the scope of the present invention. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows the operation of a particle beam with a continuously moving stage. However, the test structures and product structures and many of the inspection techniques described herein are also useful in the context of other testing devices, including particle beams operated in step and repeat mode. As an alternative to moving the stage with respect to the beam, the beam may be moved by deflecting the field of view with an electromagnetic lens. Alternatively, the beam column to be moved with respect to the stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Sample <highlight><bold>1057</bold></highlight> can be secured automatically beneath a particle beam <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight>. The particle beam <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> can be a particle beam such as an electron beam. The sample handler <highlight><bold>1034</bold></highlight> can be configured to automatically orient the sample on stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight>. The stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight> can be configured to have six degrees of freedom including movement and rotation along the x-axis, y-axis, and z-axis. In a preferred embodiment, the stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight> is aligned relative to the particle beam <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> so that the x-directional motion of the stage is corresponds to an axis that is perpendicular to a longitudinal axis of inspected conductive lines. Fine alignment of the sample can be achieved automatically or with the assistance of a system operator. The position and movement of stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight> during the analysis of sample <highlight><bold>1057</bold></highlight> can be controlled by stage servo <highlight><bold>1026</bold></highlight> and interferometers <highlight><bold>1028</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> While the stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight> is moving in the x-direction, the inducer <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> can be repeatedly deflected back and forth in the y direction. According to various embodiments, the inducer <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> is moving back and forth at approximately 100 kHz. According to a preferred embodiment, the stage <highlight><bold>1024</bold></highlight> is grounded to thereby ground the substrate and any structure tied to the substrate (e.g., source and drains) to allow voltage contrast between the floating and grounded structures as the result of scanning the targeted features. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> A detector <highlight><bold>1032</bold></highlight> can also be aligned alongside the particle beam <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> to allow further defect detection capabilities. The detector <highlight><bold>1032</bold></highlight> as well as other elements can be controlled using a controller <highlight><bold>1050</bold></highlight>. Controller <highlight><bold>1050</bold></highlight> may include a variety of processors, storage elements, and input and output devices. The controller may be configured to implement the defect detection and location and calibration techniques of the present invention. The controller may also be configured to correlate the coordinates of the electron beam with respect to the sample with coordinates on the sample to thereby determine, for example, a location of a determined electrical defect. In one embodiment, the controller is a computer system having a processor and one or more memory devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Regardless of the controller&apos;s configuration, it may employ one or more memories or memory modules configured to store data, program instructions for the general-purpose inspection operations and/or the inventive techniques described herein. The program instructions may control the operation of an operating system and/or one or more applications, for example. The memory or memories may also be configured to store images of scanned samples, reference images, defect classification and position data, as well as values for particular operating parameters of the inspection system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Because such information and program instructions may be employed to implement the systems/methods described herein, the present invention relates to machine readable media that include program instructions, state information, etc. for performing various operations described herein. Examples of machine-readable media include, but are not limited to, magnetic media such as hard disks, floppy disks, and magnetic tape; optical media such as CD-ROM disks; magneto-optical media such as floptical disks; and hardware devices that are specially configured to store and perform program instructions, such as read-only memory devices (ROM) and random access memory (RAM). The invention may also be embodied in a carrier wave travelling over an appropriate medium such as airwaves, optical lines, electric lines, etc. Examples of program instructions include both machine code, such as produced by a compiler, and files containing higher level code that may be executed by the computer using an interpreter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail for purposes of clarity of understanding, it will be apparent that certain changes and modifications may be practiced within the scope of the appended claims. Therefore, the described embodiments should be taken as illustrative and not restrictive, and the invention should not be limited to the details given herein but should be defined by the following claims and their full scope of equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device, each of the features being designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a first and second image of a first and second set of feature portions, respectively, generated as a result of scanning an electron beam over the first and second set of feature portions, wherein the first set of feature portions are designed to be substantially identical to the second set of feature portions when there is no defect present; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the first image from a second image to generate a difference image; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions, determining whether the defect is an electrical defect or a physical defect. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein determining whether the defect is an electrical or physical defect is accomplished by: 
<claim-text>determining that the defect indicates an electrical defect when the defect has about a same aspect ratio as a one of the scanned feature portions, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the difference feature indicates a physical defect when the defect has a different aspect ratio than a one of the scanned feature portions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the features include a plurality of conductive lines and the conductive lines are designed to include a plurality of lines at a grounded potential interleaved and are arranged parallel with a plurality of lines at a floating potential. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an electrical defect is found when two adjacent conductive lines have a same potential when scanned with the electron beam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the scanned feature portions are a plurality of end stub portions of the conductive lines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each end stub portion has a substantially same aspect ratio. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>determining that the electrical defect is a short when the defect has a first brightness value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the electrical defect is an open when the defect has a second brightness value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first brightness value is higher than the second brightness value. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>when an electrical defect is found, scanning the electron beam along the defective feature perpendicular to the first scan to form a plurality of images of portions of the defective feature not scanned in the first scan and one or more features adjacent to the defective feature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting a first image of the defective feature from a second image of the defective feature to obtain a difference image, wherein the defective feature is designed to have a first portion having a bright appearance and a second portion having a dark appearance when there is an open defect present within the defective feature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image of the defective feature has a significantly sized second defect that represents a difference between the first and second image of the defective feature, determining whether the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect or a physical defect. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein determining whether the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect or a physical defect is accomplished by: 
<claim-text>determining that the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect and that the electrical defect is an open when the second defect would be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the second defect represents a location of the electrical defect and that the electrical defect is a short defect when the second defect would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the second defect touches two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the second defect represents a location of a physical defect when the second defect would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the second defect does not touch two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the physical defect is selected from a group consisting of a bump in a feature edge, an uneven feature edge, an indentation in a feature edge, and a hole within an interior of the feature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An inspection system for detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device, each of the features being designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>beam generator for generating an electron beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector for detecting electrons; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller arranged to: 
<claim-text>cause the beam generator to scan an electron beam over a first and a second set of feature portions, wherein the first set is designed be substantially identical to the second set of feature portions when there is no defect present; </claim-text>
<claim-text>generate a first image of the first set of feature portions and a second image of the second set of feature portions from electrons detected by the detector emitted from the scanned feature portions in response to the scanned electron beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtract the first image from the second image to generate a difference image; </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect feature that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect feature has about a same aspect ratio as a one of the scanned feature portions, determine that the defect feature indicates an electrical defect within the scanned features; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect feature that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect feature has a different aspect ratio than a one of the scanned feature portions, determine that the difference feature indicates a physical defect. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the features include a plurality of conductive lines, wherein the conductive lines are designed to include a plurality of lines at a grounded potential interleaved and arranged parallel with a plurality of lines at a floating potential. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an electrical defect is found when two adjacent conductive lines have a same potential when scanned with the electron beam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the scanned feature portions are a plurality of end stub portions of the conductive lines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each end stub portion has a substantially same aspect ratio. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, the controller further arranged to: 
<claim-text>determine that the electrical defect is a short when the difference potential is a first value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determine that the electrical defect is a short when the difference potential is a second value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, the controller further arranged to: 
<claim-text>when an electrical defect is found, cause the electron beam to scan along the defective feature perpendicular to the first scan to form a plurality of images of portions of the defective feature not scanned in the first scan and one or more features adjacent to the defective feature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtract a first image of the defective feature from a second image of the defective feature to obtain a difference image, wherein the defective feature is designed to have a first portion having a bright appearance and a second portion having a dark appearance when there is an open defect present within the defective feature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect feature that represents a difference between the first and second image of the defective feature and the defect feature would be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image, determine that the defect feature is an open; </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect feature that represents a difference between the first and second image of the defective feature and the defect feature would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the defect feature touches two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image, determine that the defect feature is a short defect; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect feature that represents a difference between the first and second image of the defective feature and the defect feature would not be adjacent to a dark and bright portion of the defective feature and the defect feature does not touch two adjacent features if the difference image were overlaid with the first or second image, determine that the defect feature is a physical defect </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An inspection system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the physical defect is selected from a group consisting of a bump in a feature edge, an uneven feature edge, an indentation in a feature edge, and a hole within an interior of the feature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A computer program product for detecting defects in a plurality of features on a semiconductor device, each of the features being designed to have a particular potential when scanned with an electron beam, the computer program product comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one computer readable medium; 
<claim-text>computer program instructions stored within the at least one computer readable product configured to cause the inspection system to: </claim-text>
<claim-text>provide a first and second image of a first and second set of feature portions, respectively, generated as a result of scanning an electron beam over the first and second set of feature portions, wherein the first set of feature portions are designed be substantially identical to the second set of feature portions when there is no defect present; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtract the first image from a second image to generate a difference image; </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect has about a same aspect ratio as a one of the scanned feature portions, determine that the defect indicates an electrical defect within the scanned features; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>when the difference image has a significantly sized defect that represents a difference between the first set of feature portions and the second set of feature portions and the defect has a different aspect ratio than a one of the scanned feature portions, determine that the defect indicates a physical defect.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001598A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
