<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004491A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004491A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004491</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09892342</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61M031/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>604</class>
<subclass>502000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>604</class>
<subclass>059000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>604</class>
<subclass>187000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Medicinal implant and device and method for loading and delivering implants containing drugs and cells</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kevor</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Tenhuisen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Clinton</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Joel</given-name>
<family-name>Rosenblatt</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Watchung</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<family-name>McAllen</family-name>
<name-suffix>III</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Point Pleasant</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Ethicon, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Ralph W. Selitto, Jr.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 1477</address-1>
<city>Edison</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>08818-1477</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system for injecting controlled release medicinal implants has a syringe-like injector body with a lumen and plunger. A needle is attached to the injector body and receives therein an injectable implant with an internal hollow. The implant is retained in the needle by friction, which is overcome by the plunger upon dispensing. As the plunger moves from the retracted position to the deployed position, it forces a medicament previously loaded into the injector body into the implant hollow and then pushes the implant out of the needle into the creature into which the needle has been inserted. The implant may contain a filler to absorb flowable medicaments to aid in their retention within the implant. As in known implants, the medicament is released gradually depending upon the dissolution rate of the implant body which is formed from a biodegradable material. Because the medicament is loaded into the implant at the time of injection, issues concerning the reaction of the medicament with the implant material during preparation and storage are eliminated. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a device for inserting or implanting a solid or semi-solid drug or cell delivery implant subcutaneously, interstitially or intramuscularly. More particularly, the invention relates to a device for loading a solution, suspension, a flowable phase or a solid into a delivery implant at the time of use followed by implantation of the implant under the surface of the skin or within the muscle of a human or animal. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Implantation of medical devices is a widely accepted medical procedure to deliver medicaments, such as pharmaceutical agents and bioactive compounds, for treatment of disease in humans and other species. Many types of medicaments have been delivered as implants, including hormones for reproductive control, vaccines, and antibiotics. In more recent technologies, the implantable composition has contained the medicament in a biologically compatible adsorbing polymer matrix. However, these compositions are prepared prior to use and suffer from the inherent problems presented by processing a polymer with a medicament. These difficulties include the use of complex processing techniques to avoid degrading the active agent in the medicament and concerns about the shelf-life of the polymer/medicament composition after processing and compatibility/reactivity between the medicament and the polymer. For example, an aqueous based medicament will degrade a biodegradeable polymer implant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> While the prior art is replete with various medicament implants, e.g., in pelletized form, as well as, various apparatus for loading and introducing such implants into the body of a living creature, it does not adequately address the above stated concerns by providing a simple medicinal implant loading and injecting mechanism that maximally preserves the medicament from degradation during the processing/formation of the implant, (which may, e.g., involve high temperatures, such as during injection molding, exposure to radiation during curing and/or sterilization) nor from degradation due to chemical reaction with the material of the implant during processing and/or storage prior to use. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The problems and disadvantages associated with the conventional techniques and devices utilized to prepare and inject medicinal implants are overcome by the present invention which includes a system for implanting medicinal implants into the body of a living creature. The system has an injector body with a first lumen therein and a plunger slideable within the first lumen between a retracted position and a deployed position. A needle having a second lumen therein is coupled to the injector body with the second lumen communicating with the first lumen. An injectable implant having an internal hollow is positionable within at least one of the first and second lumens with the hollow communicating with the first lumen. A medicament is at least partially storable within the first lumen when the plunger is in the retracted position. The internal hollow of the injectable implant receives at least a portion of the medicament when the plunger is moved from the retracted position to the deployed position. The plunger pushes the injectable implant through the second lumen and out of the needle when the plunger assumes the deployed position.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a device for introducing medicinal implants into the body of a human or an animal in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the current invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a portion of the device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> prior to loading an active agent into a delivery implant held in a needle portion thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the device of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at an intermediate stage during the loading of active agent into the delivery implant; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a segment of the device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional schematic view of the device of FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as the delivery implant is being administered under the skin of a living subject.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an insertion device that loads a precise and accurate amount of an active agent into a hollow delivery implant at the time of subcutaneous or intramuscular insertion. By loading the delivery implant at the time of insertion, reaction between the medicament and the implant during implant manufacture and storage is avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the present invention is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, having barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Both barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are cannulated to allow passage of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> coaxially therethrough. On the distal, or front, end of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Both hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> have bores therein to allow passage of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be attached to barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by one of several common means. For example, hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may have a female thread on the interior surface of its proximal, or rear, end that is matched to a male thread on the exterior distal surface of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may also be glued (epoxied) or press fit onto barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is attached to the distal end of hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may be attached to hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> by one of several common means. For example, cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may have a female thread on the interior surface of its proximal end, which is matched to a male thread on the exterior distal surface of hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the alternative, the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be attached to the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via a Luertype fitting, a fitting which is well known in the art. (LUER-LOK) is a registered trademark of Becton, Dickinson and Company, of Franklin Lakes, New Jersey. More specifically, one of the mating ends of the Luer-type fitting can be machined, molded or epoxied onto the proximal end of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The mating Leur-type fitting can be machined, molded or epoxied onto the end of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, replacing hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. As yet another alternative, the entire barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be molded as one piece, eliminating the need for attachment of a separate hub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extends from the proximal end of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and partially through the cannulation (lumen) <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is provided at its proximal end with flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to receive manual pressure. Flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may be attached to plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by one of several common means. For example, flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may have a blind hole with a female thread that is matched to a male thread on the proximal end of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may also be press fit, soldered, or epoxied onto plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The plunger tip <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) may have a plastic piston on it to better seal against the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In addition, the distal end of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may be beveled or rounded to ensure a smooth transition from the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the cannulation (lumen) <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Suitable materials from which the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> members may be formed include glasses, noncorrodible metals, noncorrodible synthetic resins such as plastics, and the like. These materials may be used alone or in combination. If the members are of glasses, noncorrodible metals, or sterilizable noncorrodible synthetic resins, they may be used repeatedly by performing sterilization. Preferably, barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed from glass or plastic, needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are formed from noncorrodible metals, and hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> members are formed from plastic or metals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are cross-sectional views of the distal portion of implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the distal portion of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> located in the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In the distal portion of the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is located the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to be loaded into hollow delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by the means discussed herein. The cross-sectional dimensions, e.g., the diameter, of the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is matched to that of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> so that the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may push the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> through the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> without the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> leaking between the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This is particularly applicable to active agents <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in liquid, gel or paste forms. The cross-sectional shape of the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be hexagonal, octagonal, eliptical or any other shape, with a circular cross-sectional shape being preferred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is located at the distal end of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and passes through both hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is located in the proximal portion of the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The diameter of the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is matched to that of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> such that the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may push the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> through the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> without the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> leaking between the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The outer diameter of delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is matched to the diameter of the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to form a friction fit such that delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> does not inadvertently slide out of the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> prior to being purposely forced out by plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and to insure that the active agent does not leak between delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has a hollow bore <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> with an inner diameter that is sufficiently less than the diameter of the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, such that the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> bears upon the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and does not enter the hollow bore <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> while the implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is being forced out of the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are located on the proximal end of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Both are cannulated to allow coaxial placement over the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is press fit over the outer diameter of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The outer diameter of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is also closely matched to the diameter of the cannulation of gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> such that the gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> presses forcefully against the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to establish a seal, as well as to strengthen the mechanical retention of the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> when the cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is tightened on to the hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Suitable materials from which the collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may be formed include glasses, noncorrodible metals, noncorrodible synthetic resins such as plastics, soft metal, and the like. These materials may be used alone or in combination. If collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is of glass, noncorrodible metal, or sterilizable noncorrodible synthetic resin, it may be used repeatedly by performing sterilization. The collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may also be disposed of as expendable after one use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Suitable materials from which the gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be formed include those such as, for example, noncorrodible synthetic resins such as plastics, and the like. Synthetic resins are used because gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> needs to deform when attaching needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. If gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is of sterilizable noncorrodible synthetic resin, it may be used repeatedly by performing sterilization. The gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may also be disposed of as expendable after one use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferably, collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is formed from noncorrodible metal, such as <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> stainless steel, and gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is formed from a noncorrodible synthetic resin such as poly(tetrafluoro ethylene), sold under the tradename TEFLON by E. I. duPont (Wilmington, Del.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> To attach needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the proximal end of the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> assembly is first placed in the hub cannula <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Next, the distal end of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is passed through the through hole of cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> until cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> comes into contact with the distal end of collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Then, cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is attached to the distal end of hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> by means such as those discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> show the loading of active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is urged through the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by application of a force on flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> (See <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is driven into the proximal end of delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> by plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in this embodiment is a tubular structure that is open at both distal (input) and proximal (vent) ends. This configuration permits active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to pass from the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Any gas trapped within the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be vented from the proximal end. The active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be of a variety of compositions and may be a solid, liquid, gel, paste, suspension or combination of the foregoing. In FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is depicted in the form of a solid, slender rod. A solid active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> was selected to facilitate the illustration of the invention, but as noted, the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> can exhibit any selected phase. The volume of active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be more than, less than, or equal to the volume of the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the volume of active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is matched to the volume of the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> so that active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> fills the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> when the distal end of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> reaches the distal end of the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, loaded with active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, being administered under the skin <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of a patient. Plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is forced into the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by application of a force on flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, loaded with active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, is forced out of the distal end of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is fully administered when the distal end of plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> reaches the distal end of needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> While it is possible to begin displacement of the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> prior to the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> penetrating the skin <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, it is preferred that the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> penetrates the skin <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the patient prior to the loading of active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. That is, prior to plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> being forced into the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by application of a force on flange <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In this manner, the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of this invention allows for a simple, one-step process for loading the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> at the time the implant is being inserted into the patient. After inserting the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> into the patient, the health professional administering the delivery implant forces the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In one step, the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is loaded into the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is administered to the patient. By loading the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> at the time of insertion, issues of processing and shelf-life of preloaded delivery implants are avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one method of loading the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> prior to use, the hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is first attached to the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by means described above. The plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is inserted into the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> until the distal end of the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> reaches the distal end of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is filled with the appropriate amount of active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> by moving the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> proximally, which, in the case of a flowable active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, such as a liquid or gel, will draw the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> retreats in a proximal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another method, the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is partially inserted into the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> metered into the cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> through the distal end, of the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, e.g., through the hub cannula <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. If the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is flowable, then the hub cannula <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> may be plugged with rubber or resin to eliminate evaporation or leakage during storage. Prior to injection of the implant, the hub cannula <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> plug <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> (shown diagrammatically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> by dotted lines) may be removed or pierced. The hub cannula <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> plug or seal <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> may be in the form of a rupturable membrane that ruptures under the pressure exerted on the plunger <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by the user of the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In separate process steps, the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> portion of the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be prepared for assembly to the hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as follows. The needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with press fit collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is passed through the bore in the cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and the gasket <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is placed on the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> abutting the collar <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is then inserted into the cannulation <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, thus completing preparation for the assembly of needle portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to the hub <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> If the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is sealed in cannulation <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by a plug <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> or membrane occluding hub cannulation <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, then the barrel <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and needle <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be assembled prior to packaging and sterilization. Alternatively, the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be stored separately from the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and introduced into the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, i.e., by the methods outlined above, just prior to injection of the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> If different means of sterilization are required for the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the active agent, then it is preferred that each of these <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> components be packaged and sterilized separately. In this manner, degradation of the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> due to exposure to, e.g., radiation used to sterilize the device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, can be avoided. The separate portions of the device may then be assembled as described above at the time of use by the medical professional. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As mentioned earlier, if a prior art delivery implant is made from a biodegradable polymer, there are inherent problems presented by combining the biodegradable polymer with a medicament containing an active agent. These include having to use complex processing techniques so as not to harm the active agent, being concerned with the shelf-life of the polymer/active agent composition after processing and compatibility issues between the active agent and the polymer such as if the medicament is aqueous based, and the polymer degrades when exposed to water. In accordance with the present invention, by loading the delivery implant at the time of insertion, issues of undesirable processing and shelf-life reactions are avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A variety of biodegradable polymers can be used to make the delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the present invention. Examples of suitable biocompatible, biodegradable polymers include polymers selected from the group consisting of aliphatic polyesters, poly(amino acids), copoly(ether-esters), polyalkylenes oxalates, polyamides, tyrosine derived polycarbonates, poly(iminocarbonates), polyorthoesters, polyoxaesters, polyamidoesters, polyoxaesters containing amine groups, poly(anhydrides), polyphosphazenes, biomolecules (i.e., biopolymers such as collagen, elastin, bioabsorbable starches, etc.) and blends thereof. For the purpose of this invention aliphatic polyesters include, but are not limited to, homopolymers and copolymers of lactide (which includes lactic acid, D-,L- and meso lactide), glycolide (including glycolic acid), &egr;-caprolactone, p-dioxanone (1,4-dioxan-2-one), trimethylene carbonate (1,3-dioxan-2-one), alkyl derivatives of trimethylene carbonate, &dgr;-valerolactone, &bgr;-butyrolactone, &egr;-decalactone, hydroxybutyrate, hydroxyvalerate, 1,4-dioxepan-2-one (including its dimer 1,5,8,12-tetraoxacyclotetradecane-7,14-dione), 1,5-dioxepan-2-one, 6,6-dimethyl-1,4-dioxan-2-one 2,5-diketomorpholine, pivalolactone, &ggr;-diethylpropiolactone, ethylene carbonate, ethylene oxalate, 3-methyl-1,4-dioxane-2,5-dione, 3,3-diethyl-1,4-dioxan-2,5-dione, 6,8-dioxabicycloctane-7-one and polymer blends thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> used in the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention may be of a pharmacological and/or cellular nature. The variety of different pharmacological agents that can be used in conjunction with the present invention is vast. In general, pharmacological agents which may be administered via this invention include, without limitation: antiinfectives such as antibiotics and antiviral agents; chemotherapeutic agents (i.e. anticancer agents); anti-rejection agents; analgesics and analgesic combinations; anti-inflammatory agents; hormones such as steroids; antigens, including but not limited to cytokines, attachment factors, genes, peptides, proteins, nucleotides, carbohydrates or even cells or cell fragments; growth factors, including bone morphogenic proteins (i.e. BMP&apos;s 1-7), bone morphogenic-like proteins (i.e. GFD-5, GFD-7 and GFD-8), epidermal growth factor (EGF), fibroblast growth factor (i.e. FGF 1-9), platelet derived growth factor (PDGF), insulin like growth factor (IGF-I and IGF-II), transforming growth factors (i.e. TGF-&bgr;, I-III), vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF); and other naturally derived or genetically engineered proteins, polysaccharides, glycoproteins, or lipoproteins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The pharmacological agent may be present as a liquid, or formulated in a solution, suspension, or gel containing the component(s), or any other appropriate physical form. Typically, but optionally, additives, such as diluents, carriers, excipients, stabilizers or the like may be included in the formulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The amount of pharmacological agent will depend on the particular medical condition being treated, and will vary depending on the release profile desired and the amount of drug employed. Prolonged delivery (over, say 1 to 5,000 hours, preferably 2 to 800 hours) of effective amounts (say, 0.0001 mg/kg/hour to 10 mg/kg/hour) of the agent are desired. This dosage form can be administered as is necessary depending on the subject being treated, the severity of the affliction, the judgment of the prescribing physician, and the like. Following this or similar procedures, those skilled in the art will be able to prepare a variety of formulations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Active agents of the present invention may also be cellular by nature. Cells which can be loaded into the delivery implant of the current invention include, but are not limited to, bone marrow cells, stromal cells, stem cells, embryonic stem cells, chondrocytes, osteoblasts, osteocytes, osteoclasts, fibroblasts, pluripotent cells, chondrocyte progenitors, endothelial cells, macrophages, leukocytes, adipocytes, monocytes, plasma cells, mast cells, umbilical cord cells, mesenchymal stem cells, epithelial cells, myoblasts, islet of langerhorn, and precursor cells derived from adipose tissue. The cells can be loaded into the delivery implant of the present invention for a short period of time, e.g. less than one day, just prior to implantation, or cultured for longer a period, e.g. greater than one day, to allow for cell proliferation and matrix synthesis within the delivery implant prior to implantation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Cells typically have at their surface, receptor molecules which are responsive to a cognate ligand (e.g., a stimulator). A stimulator is a ligand which when in contact with its cognate receptor induce the cell possessing the receptor to produce a specific biological action. For example, in response to a stimulator (or ligand) a cell may produce significant levels of secondary messengers, like Ca<highlight><superscript>&plus;2</superscript></highlight>, which then will have subsequent effects upon cellular processes such as the phosphorylation of proteins, such as (keeping with our example) protein kinase C. In some instances, once a cell is stimulated with the proper stimulator, the cell secretes a cellular messenger usually in the form of a protein (including glycoproteins, proteoglycans, and lipoproteins). This cellular messenger can be an antibody (e.g., secreted from plasma cells), a hormone, (e.g., a paracrine, autocrine, or exocrine hormone), or a cytokine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The following examples are illustrative of the principles and practice of this invention. Numerous additional embodiments within the scope and spirit of the invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 (a prototypical implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> A 10 &mgr;l glass syringe (part&num; 701 RN, Hamilton Company, Reno, Nev.) with a removable needle was purchased. A thin-walled, 18&deg; pointed, 20 gauge needle, 1.125-inches long was also purchased (Popper and Sons, Inc., New Hyde Park, N.Y.). Collars and gaskets were machined using 316 stainless steel and poly(tetrafluoro ethylene) (sold under the tradename TEFLON by E. I. duPont, Wilmington, Del.), respectively. The dimensions of both were 0.105-inch height&times;0.125-inch diameter). Through the center of each collar and gasket was drilled a 0.0355-inch diameter hole. The collar was press-fit onto the 20 gauge needle, with the distal end of the collar 0.2-inch from the proximal end of the needle. The TEFLON gasket was then press-fit onto the proximal end of the needle and seated snugly against the proximal end of the collar. A 0.042-inch diameter hole was drilled in the center of the threaded, knurled cap. The distal end of the needle was placed first through the proximal end of the hole in the cap and pulled through until the distal end of the press-fit collar was seated on the inside of the cap. A 316 stainless steel plunger 4.188 inches in length was centerless ground to a diameter of 0.0185&plusmn;0.0002-inch. To one end of this plunger was press-fit a stainless steel flange for the thumb. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 (a prototypical delivery implant) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Tubing was melt extruded from an elastomeric copolymer of &egr;-caprolactone (CAP) and glycolide (GLY) having a mole ratio of &egr;-caprolactone to glycolide of about 35/65 (35/65 CAP/GLY, Ethicon, Inc., Somerville, N.J.). The inherent viscosity (IV) of the 35/65 CAP/GLY was about 1.3 deciliters per gram (dL/g), as measured in a 0.1 g/dL solution of hexafluoroisopropanol (HFIP) at 25&deg; C. The tubing had an outer diameter of approximately 0.0256 inches and an inner diameter of approximately 0.0177 inches. Pieces of this tubing 1-inch in length were cut with a razor blade. The inside of each piece of tubing was filled with about 2 mg of fibers composed of 90/10 copolymers of poly(glycolic acid) with poly(lactic acid) (PGANPLA), sold under the tradename VICRYL (Ethicon, Inc., Somerville, N.J.). As this example teaches, the present invention comprehends a delivery implant <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the hollow <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of which is partially filled with filler <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> (shown diagrammatically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) such as fillers, fibers or a foam into which the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> infiltrates. Such fillers can be advantageous with respect to holding and metering out liquid active agents <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to assist in controlled release of the active agent <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 (illustrating the operation of the implant insertion device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A solution was made containing &tilde;0.1% Nigrosin dye (Aldrich Chemicals, Milwaukee, Wis., part &num; 19,828-5) in deionized water. Approximately 2.5 &mgr;l of this die solution was drawn into the syringe barrel through a 30 gauge needle. The 30 gauge needle was then removed from the syringe barrel. A fiber-filled 1-inch long piece of tubing from Example 2 was placed into the proximal end of a 20 gauge needle from Example 1. The needle assembly was attached to the syringe barrel. The plunger was depressed until the fiber filled tube was expelled out the end of the needle. Upon inspection the tube was filled with the dyed liquid. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for implanting medicinal implants into the body of a living creature, comprising: 
<claim-text>an injector body with a first lumen therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plunger slideable within said first lumen between a retracted position and a deployed position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a needle having a second lumen therein, said needle coupled to said injector body with said second lumen communicating with said first lumen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an injectable implant having an internal hollow and positionable within at least one of said first lumen and said second lumen, said hollow communicating with said first lumen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a medicament, storable at least partially within said first lumen when said plunger is in said retracted position, said internal hollow of said injectable implant receiving at least a portion of said medicament when said plunger is moved from said retracted position to said deployed position, said plunger pushing said injectable implant through said second lumen and out of said needle when said plunger assumes said deployed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said implant is biodegradable and provides a selected rate of release of said medicament into the body of the creature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injectable implant is formed from a material selected from the group consisting of biodegradable polymers, biopolymers, bioabsorbable starches and blends thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the phase of said medicament is selected from the group consisting of solid, liquid, gel, suspensions and paste. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said medicament has an active agent component selected from the group consisting of antibiotics, antiviral agents, anticancer agents, anti-rejection agents, analgesics, anti-inflammatory agents, hormones, antigens, cyotkines, attachment factors, genes, peptides, proteins, nucleotides, carbohydrates, cells, cell fragments, growth factors, polysaccharides, glycoproteins and lipoproteins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injectable implant has an input opening to admit said medicament and a vent to discharge gas displaced by said medicament. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injectable implant is substantially tubular in shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injectable implant has cross-sectional dimensions approximating the cross-sectional dimensions of said first lumen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a filler disposed within said internal hollow of said injectable implant, said medicament diffusable into said filler. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said filler is a biodegradable fiber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injectable implant has a friction fit relationship relative to at least one of said first lumen and said second lumen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a seal disposed in a distal end of said first lumen, said seal retaining said medicament within said first lumen when said plunger is in said retracted position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said seal is a removable plug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said seal is a rupturable membrane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said needle is removably coupled to said injector body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said injector body includes an elongated cylindrical barrel with a threaded nipple at a distal end thereof, said needle having a peripheral collar disposed proximate a first end thereof and further comprising a needle retention cap having a threaded bore terminating in a bridging cap member with a needle bore therein for accommodating said needle therethrough, said threaded bore being threadedly receivable on said threaded nipple, said bridging cap member abutting said peripheral collar for urging said needle toward said threaded nipple when said needle retention cap is threadedly received thereon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said nipple has a needle aperture therethrough communicating with said first lumen, said needle aperture slideably receiving said first end of said needle, and further comprising a gasket slideable over said needle proximate said first end, said gasket being captured between said collar and said nipple when said needle retention cap is received on said nipple. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said needle is removably coupled to said injection body by a Leur-type connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method for introducing a medicament into the body of a living creature, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>(A) providing an injector having a first lumen therein, a plunger slideable within the first lumen between a retracted position and a deployed position and a needle with a second lumen disposed at one end of the injector for penetrating the body of the creature; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(B) providing an injectable implant with an internal hollow therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(C) charging the first lumen with a medicament; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(D) inserting the injectable implant into the second lumen; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(E) penetrating the body of the creature with the needle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(F) moving the plunger from the retracted position to the deployed position, the plunger moving the medicament into the hollow of the injectable implant as it moves from the retracted position towards an intermediate position contacting the injectable implant and pushing the injectable implant out of the needle and into the body of the creature as the plunger moves to the deployed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of assembling the needle to the injector just prior to moving the plunger in said step (F) </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of sterilizing the injector and the injectable implant separately from the medicament and prior to moving the medicament into the hollow of the injectable implant in said step (F). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of sealing the medicament in the first lumen after charging the first lumen with medicament in said step (C) and overcoming the sealing of the medicament in the first lumen prior to said step of moving the medicament into the hollow of the injectable implant in said step (F). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the medicament has approximately the same volume as said hollow. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the medicament includes living cells and further comprising the step of waiting to move the plunger after the plunger has reached the intermediate position in order to allow the cells to interact with the injectable implant prior to penetrating the body with the needle and prior to injecting the injectable implant into the body of the creature.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004491A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
