<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003906A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003906A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003906</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09884637</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010619</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04Q007/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>424000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>063000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Methods and systems for reducing interference across coverage cells</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephanie</given-name>
<family-name>Demers</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Edison</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Zablocky</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Shrewsbury</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shimon</given-name>
<family-name>Moshavi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bet Shemesh</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Orville R. Cockings, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>Telcordia Technologies, Inc.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>445 South Street, Room 1G112R</address-1>
<city>Morristown</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>07960</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Methods and systems are provided for reducing interference across coverage cells using base stations interconnected by a packet network. A wireless device monitors the channel signal strength of its serving cell and its neighboring cell. The serving cell collects measurements from the wireless devices within its cell and informs its neighboring cell when one of the wireless device may be causing significant interference to the neighboring cell. The neighboring cell collects this information and executes a multi-user detection and cancellation algorithm on a subset of these interfering wireless devices. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The application of Paul Proctor and Paul Zablocky entitled, &ldquo;Methods and Systems for Adjusting Sectors Across Coverage Cells,&rdquo; filed concurrently with the present application, contains subject matter related to the subject of the present application, and is hereby incorporated in its entirety by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to reducing interference in a wireless communication system, and more particularly, to methods and systems for reducing interference by canceling interfering radio signals transmitted from wireless devices in neighboring cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As wireless communications become more widely used, the demand for wireless resources, such as the available electromagnetic bandwidth, has become increasingly inadequate. One radio communication technique known as Code Division Multiple Access (&ldquo;CDMA&rdquo;) has been introduced to alleviate some of these problems by allowing simultaneous transmission of multiple signals over a shared portion of the electromagnetic spectrum. This is accomplished by using a spread spectrum technique to assign a unique code to data and modulating the result onto a radio frequency carrier signal. A receiver then detects the radio signal and recovers the data by demodulating the radio signal using that unique spreading code. As a result of the spread spectrum technique, the receiver is able to generate a gain in the power of the detected signal with respect to noise and other signals. Accordingly, signals from a number of transmitters may be contemporaneously transmitted using different spreading codes over the same bandwidth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Theoretically, if the unique spreading codes were perfectly orthogonal, bandwidth capacity would only be limited by the processing power available at the receiver and the length of the codes. In reality, however, it is unfeasible to design these unique codes to be perfectly orthogonal given the random time offset between signals. Accordingly, interference between contemporaneous signals called multiple access interference (&ldquo;MAI&rdquo;) results and impacts the capacity and performance of conventional CDMA systems. Although the MAI caused by a single signal is usually small, the amount of MAI becomes substantial as the number of signals increase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In addition, the amount of MAI can be further exacerbated by high data rate communications. In some CDMA systems, a high data rate communication can be divided into multiple data channels, which prevents too low a spreading factor. In such a situation, each data channel uses a different code and consequently each high data rate communication uses multiple codes. Accordingly, high data rate communications can create artificial hot spots, i.e. one high data rate communication is equivalent to several lower data rate communications all bundled together. For this reason, the MAI impact of a high data rate communication can be more significant than the MAI impact of a lower data rate communication. Similarly, signals originating near the edge of a coverage cell can also exacerbate MAI due to the increased power needed to transmit those signals from the edge of the coverage cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Several methods have been used in conventional CDMA detectors to mitigate the effect of MAI. For example, power control has been used to mitigate the near-far effect problem such that all signals, irrespective of distance, arrive at the base station with the minimum power required. The minimum power required for high data rate signals, however, may still be sufficiently great to drown out or severely interfere with other signals. Moreover, limiting the transmit power will generally result in an unwanted consequence of smaller cell sizes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another attempt to reduce MAI in wireless communication systems involves subtracting interfering signals from the received signal. Two well-known subtractive interference cancellation detectors are the successive interference cancellation (&ldquo;SIC&rdquo;) detector and parallel interference cancellation (&ldquo;PIC&rdquo;) detector. The SIC detector takes a serial approach to canceling interference. Each stage of this detector makes a bit decision, regenerates, and cancels out one additional signal from the received signal, so that the remaining signals detect less MAI in the next stage. In contrast to the SIC detector, the PIC detector estimates and subtracts out all of the MAI for each signal in parallel. Further information on SIC and PIC detectors may be found in Multi-User Detection for DS-CDMA Communications, S. Moshavi, IEEE Communications Magazine, October 1996, Vol 34, No. 10., herein incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Prior art cancellation techniques, however, suffer from at least two disadvantages. First, only the signals that are known to the receiving cell are capable of being subtracted. This is because the receiver needs the desired signal&apos;s unique code to demodulate and subtract it from the total received signal. In conventional CDMA systems, those signals are limited to signals from wireless devices within the cell and signals from wireless devices undergoing soft-handoff. Accordingly, interfering signals that are not in soft-handoff or originating within the serving cell are neglected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In addition, prior art cancellation techniques fail to determine which signal(s) should be subtracted to improve signal reconstruction of the remaining signal(s). Making such a determination is valuable since the processing power required to demodulate and subtract interfering signals is usually limited. The prior art also fails to subtract strategic signals, such as high data rate signals, to significantly reduce MAI. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, methods and systems are provided to overcome the above and other problems of the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Methods and systems consistent with the present invention, as embodied and broadly described herein, reduce interference in a wireless communication system. In one embodiment of the present invention, a first wireless device, being served by a first cell, performs measurements and transmits the measurements to the first cell. Upon receiving the measurements, the first cell determines whether the first wireless device may be causing interference at a second cell and then transmits interference information to a second cell if it is determined that the first wireless device is causing interference at the second cell. Upon receiving the interference information from the first cell, the second cell demodulates and cancels the first wireless device based on the interference information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, interference between wireless devices is canceled within a plurality of cells serving the wireless devices. The signal strengths of the cells are monitored by the wireless devices and information from the wireless devices is collected at the serving cells. Based on that information, it is determined that one or more of the wireless devices causes interference in one or more of the cells neighboring the serving cells that serve the one or more interfering wireless device. The information about the interference is then transmitted to the neighboring cells to cancel the interference, if the neighboring cells so choose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory only and are not restrictive of the invention, as claimed. Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objects and advantages of the invention will be realized and attained by means of the elements and combinations particularly pointed out in the appended claims. The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate several embodiments of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a wireless system, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of a base station, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a wireless system, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates two exemplary base stations in a wireless communications system operating in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> illustrate a system process diagram for reducing interference across coverage cells in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> illustrates a flow chart of the steps performed for canceling interference across cells in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> illustrates a flow chart of the steps performed for canceling interference across cells in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9C</cross-reference> illustrates a flow chart of the steps performed for canceling interference across cells in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed toward systems and methods for sharing information between base stations to reduce interference within a wireless communication coverage cell. By sharing information between base stations, interfering communication signals may be detected and demodulated to cancel the interfering communications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art appreciate that only a small portion of neighboring-cell communications need to be canceled to obtain significant reduction of MAI. More particularly, by carefully selecting the highest MAI-producing communications, significant reduction in neighboring-cell interference can be made while keeping the processing power requirement to its minimum. By canceling the worst neighboring-cell&apos;s interfering communications, performance gains such as increased capacity, better reliability, wider coverage, higher data rates, and improved power utilization, may be achieved. In addition, reducing the interference impact of high data rate communications will allow service providers to offer uniform coverage throughout the cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to the preferred embodiments of the invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of a wireless system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention. As illustrated, one or more base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are connected to a network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, which may include, for example, the Internet or any other type of network. The base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be directly connected to network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> or may be connected to network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> through subnetworks (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As illustrated, each base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is connected to an antenna <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> through which communication is established with wireless devices. Like present cellular systems, each base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> communicates with wireless devices located in a particular cell where each cell covers a specific geographical area. The wireless devices (not shown) used to communicate in cellular wireless system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may include, for example, a standard wireless phone, a third generation cellular device, or any other type of wireless device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In cellular wireless system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the intelligence that in the prior system resided in the base transceiver systems (&ldquo;BTS&rdquo;), base station controllers (&ldquo;BSC&rdquo;), and mobile switching centers (&ldquo;MSC&rdquo;) may be distributed amongst the base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> For example, each base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may operate autonomously and include intelligence for exchanging information with other base stations for the purposes of adjusting the coverage areas for the base stations, handing off wireless devices from one base station to another, and, when the base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is plugged into the network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, automatically locating other base stations and configuring itself. Further, each base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be configured using software programmable on a MultiPC platform. That is, the base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may not need specific hardware, but rather, all of the base station&apos;s functionality may be performed in software using general purpose processors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Because there is no central MSC or BSC, the wireless system can be grown simply by adding base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to the wireless system. As such, this solution may be used for both very small and very large configurations. Also, the base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may use advanced signal processing, such as space time adaptive processing (&ldquo;STAP&rdquo;), multi-user detection (&ldquo;MUD&rdquo;), and multi-user detection across cells (&ldquo;MUDAC&rdquo;). Further, the base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may use sectored antennas that adapt their direction dynamically to improve network performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may also use standard internet protocols for communicating over the network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. For example, the base stations may use Mobile IP, DHCP, VPN, etc. to communicate with each other. Also, the base stations may use standard air interfaces, such as, IS-<highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, cdma<highlight><bold>2000</bold></highlight>, UWC-<highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, W-CDMA, UMTS-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>GPP-W-CDMA, etc. Further, because standard air interfaces may be used, no changes to existing cellular phones or networks are necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of a base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention. As shown, the base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a network interface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a processor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, a memory <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, a storage device <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, an antenna interface <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and a bus <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. The network interface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is preferably an Ethernet type interface that the base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> uses to connect to the network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The processor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be any type of processor for performing computer type operations. The memory <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be any type of memory, such as a Random Access Memory (&ldquo;RAM&rdquo;). The storage device <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be any type of storage device, such as, a hard drive, a CD-ROM, etc. The antenna interface <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> connects the base station to an antenna for communicating with wireless devices. The antenna interface <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may include a radio transmitting and receiving device (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, each base station may be a plug and play type device. For example, when a base station <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> connects to a network such as network <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, it automatically identifies any other base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also connected to the network. Then, the base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> communicate with one another to automatically determine the coverage area for the new base station and the existing base stations in the network. Then, the base stations may communicate amongst themselves to accomplish various functions, such as handing off wireless devices from one base station to another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a wireless system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the invention. As illustrated, base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected to network <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a network <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> through gateway <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Network <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may include a Dynamic Host Control Protocol (&ldquo;DHCP&rdquo;) server <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight> and a Domain Name Server (&ldquo;DNS&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>372</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Base stations <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to a network <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which connects to network <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> through gateway <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A carrier database <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, which connects to network <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, stores information regarding the base stations in a carrier&apos;s network. For example, the carrier database <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> may store the IP address for each of the base stations in the carrier&apos;s network. A carrier refers to a company providing wireless services. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Networks <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may include any type of network, such as, an Ethernet, a Fiber Distributed Date Interface (&ldquo;FDDI&rdquo;) network, etc. Network <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> may also include any type of network, such as the Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The central database of wireless networks (&ldquo;CDWN&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> stores information regarding the network addresses (e.g. IP addresses) for the carrier databases <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. For example, there may be multiple carriers providing wireless services, such as Bell Atlantic, Sprint, etc. In such an embodiment, the CDWN <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> may store the network address of the carrier database <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> for each carrier. Thus, if a base station needs to locate a carrier database <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> of a particular carrier, it can access the CDWN <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> to obtain the network address for the carrier database <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> With the above preface on the illustrative operating environment, the remaining FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, which illustrate aspects of the preferred embodiments of the present invention, will be described next. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates two exemplary base stations <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> connected by a network <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> in a wireless communications system operating in accordance with methods and systems consistent with the present invention. While the two exemplary base stations <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> are shown to be interconnected via packet network <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>, any network with sufficiently high data speed and sufficiently low delay could be used to connect the base stations. As described above, in one embodiment of the present invention, the packet network <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> may include the global computer network commonly referred to as the &ldquo;Internet.&rdquo; The packet network <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> may use protocols well known to those skilled in the art, such as Mobile IP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Base stations <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> are also shown serving a plurality of wireless devices, <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, . . . , </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, . . . , </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>n</italic></highlight>, respectively. Wireless devices typically have a limited range and communicate within respective coverage cells of a wireless communication system. Within such a system, a handoff occurs when a wireless device moves out of range of its existing base station contact within a given cell. Instead of allowing the call connection signal to deteriorate to noise level, the call connection is transferred or handed-over to another cell to maintain the communication with the roving wireless device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The coverage areas of base stations <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> are shown as hexagonal cells <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight>, which serve to indicate an approximate boundary within which radio communications can be effected with their respective wireless devices <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight>. Data is communicated between wireless devices operating within its radio coverage area and their respective base stations by transmitting and receiving radio signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the wireless devices communicate with their respective base stations via antennas in accordance with Wide-Band Code Division Multiple Access (&ldquo;W-CDMA&rdquo;). A detailed explanation of how data is communicated using W-CDMA is provided in the 3GPP standards:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Physical Layer:</entry>
<entry>3GPP TS 25-200 Series (Release 1999)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>UE-UTRAN radio interface:</entry>
<entry>3GPP TS 25-300 Series (Release 1999)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>UTRAN lu, lur, lub interfaces:</entry>
<entry>3GPP TS 25-400 series (Release 1999)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entireties. While several embodiments of the present invention will be generally described in the context of a W-CDMA wireless communication system, other communication schemes or techniques, such as spread spectrum CDMA, may be used instead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Each base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> includes an antenna array comprising at least one antenna capable of receiving a plurality of communications from a plurality of wireless devices. Because each wireless device is individually located within a cell, a plurality of transmission paths exists between the antennas and the wireless devices. Each transmission path, in turn, has a corresponding path delay and signal strength relative to its receiving antenna. For example, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>shown located near the outer edge of coverage cell <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight>, has a longer transmission path and typically a higher transmit-power level than wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>which is located closer to base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. As described in the background section, wireless devices transmitting at increased power levels can cause significant interference. This is because the increased power, while necessary for the wireless device to effectively transmit to its serving base station, may be so strong that the signal also effectively reaches a neighboring base station, thereby causing interference. Assuming the neighboring base station is not demodulating the interfering signal, i.e., undergoing soft-handoff, the neighboring base station has no way of canceling the interference. In this embodiment, such interference, as well as interference caused by any other wireless devices, such as high data-rate devices, is reduced by exchanging information about the wireless devices between base stations. The exchanged information may then be used to demodulate and cancel interfering signals across cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Canceling the signals of interfering devices, such as high transmit-power and high data-rate devices, not only reduces interference but also reduces the necessary transmit-power and increases the capacity available in the neighboring cell. In addition, it allows high data-rate devices, which may previously have been restricted to a small region around the base station, to have broader access within their serving cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 through 8</cross-reference>, a system process diagram for reducing interference across coverage cells will be described in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is shown within coverage cell <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> served by base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. Wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is also shown transmitting at a power level sufficient to cause interference at neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. For example, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be transmitting at a high data-rate or located near the edge of its coverage cell. With respect to a particular wireless device, the term &ldquo;neighboring cell&rdquo; or &ldquo;neighboring base station&rdquo; as used herein means any base station that does not currently serve that wireless device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment, wireless devices, such as wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>perform downlink channel measurements on both their serving base stations and their neighboring base stations. For example, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may perform signal strength measurements on each of its neighboring base stations. In another embodiment of the invention, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may perform signal-to-noise ratio measurements on each neighboring base station or a combination of both signal strength and signal-to-noise ratio measurements on each neighboring base station. The methods and systems for taking signal strength measurements are well known to anyone skilled in the art of wireless technology. Likewise, the methods of making signal-to-noise ratio measurements are well known to anyone skilled in the art of CDMA wireless technology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the results of these measurements are communicated to the serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> by data messages sent from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. In accordance with one embodiment, wireless devices may transmit measurement messages when requested by their serving base station. In another embodiment, the serving base station may specify transmission of measurement information based on particular measurement reporting criteria. For example, the measurement reporting criteria may specify periodic reporting, event triggered reporting&mdash;such as when a neighboring base station signal strength measurement exceeds a predetermined threshold, or a combination of both periodic and event triggered reporting. Wireless devices may perform intra-frequency and/or inter-frequency measurements depending on the frequency of the neighboring cells as compared to the serving cell. For example, if all neighboring cells were at the same frequency as the serving cell, a wireless device would only perform intra-frequency measurements. Four event-triggered measurements, events <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>as well as one periodic internal measurement report, UE transmit power, are initially defined directly from 3GPP W-CDMA standards so as to provide simple integration with the W-CDMA system. For events <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>the wireless device reports pilot measurements when the pilot becomes stronger than an absolute threshold. Event <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is for intra-frequency measurements and event <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>is for inter-frequency measurements. For events <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the wireless device repeats its transmit power measurements when the wireless device power becomes larger or smaller than an absolute threshold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> On receipt of the measurement information, base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> evaluates the information to determine whether wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be causing interference at a neighboring base station, such as base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. For example, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be considered potentially interfering to a particular neighboring base station when its measurement of the base station&apos;s signal exceeds a predetermined threshold, which may depend, among other things, on the wireless device data rate and location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, upon determining wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be causing interference at neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> transmits an interference report to base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> via network <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>. The interference report may include the following information for wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a: </italic></highlight>1) measurement information of the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>&apos;s signal strength, 2) transmit power, 3) unique scrambling code, and 4) radio link configuration. Base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may also send separately to base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, the sequence of symbols or bits of the wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>causing interference at neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. This may be done when the base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> knows that the wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may cause interference to base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> but the signal from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> will be too weak to be successfully demodulated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, upon receiving information about a potentially interfering signal from base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>, base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may then further evaluate the information before canceling the interfering signal based on the wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>interference impact, loading in base stations <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (e.g., the number of available carriers), desired capacity at base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>processing burden, and processing power availability at base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The measurement information is then used to determine if base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> will demodulate and cancel the interfering signal from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>using a multi-user detection (&ldquo;MUD&rdquo;) algorithm. The MUD algorithm will be discussed in further detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9C</cross-reference> below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9A, 9B</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>C illustrate an exemplary method for canceling a communication from a single wireless device, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. While the method describes a simple example involving only one wireless device, its serving base station, and its neighboring base station, this exemplary method is applicable to any number of wireless devices, base stations, and sectors per cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A, a</cross-reference> wireless device, such as wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, first performs downlink channel measurements on its serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> and neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>902</bold></highlight>). The neighboring base station information is available in a neighbor list broadcasted by the wireless communication network and made available to wireless devices through their respective serving base stations. After performing its measurements, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>transmits the measurement information to its serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>904</bold></highlight>). As described above, the serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may use measurement control messages to specify transmission of measurement information based on particular measurement reporting criteria. For example, the measurement reporting criteria may specify periodic reporting, event triggered reporting, or a combination of both periodic and event triggered reporting. Alternatively, measurement information may be transmitted only upon request. Accordingly, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may request measurements from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In that case, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>performs measurements on neighboring base stations and transmits the information to serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Upon receiving measurements from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> assesses the potential interference caused by wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> by determining whether the signal strength measurement of base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> exceeds a predetermined strength threshold (Step <highlight><bold>908</bold></highlight>). Alternatively, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> assesses the potential interference caused by wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> based on a combination comprising both neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>&apos;s signal strength measurement as well as wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&apos;s data rate and location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> This threshold may vary in time, per data rate, and per base station. For example, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may determine that during a certain busy period, cancellation of interfering signals is not feasible due to the unavailability of processing power. Consequently, during such times serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> need not send measurement information to neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> need not be sent. To offer maximum flexibility and reserve resources, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may periodically send a strength threshold setting and report status to base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. The report status can take one of two values: no report or report based on a specified reporting period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> If the signal strength measurement is determined not to exceed the strength threshold or the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> requested no report status, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> awaits the next measurement report from wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(Step <highlight><bold>906</bold></highlight>). If, however, the signal strength measurement exceeds the predetermined threshold and the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> requested reports based on a specified reporting period, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> transmits, via the network connection <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>, an interference report to neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>910</bold></highlight>), which is then received by neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>912</bold></highlight>). The interference report comprises following information for wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a: </italic></highlight>1) measurement information of the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>&apos;s signal strength, 2) transmit power, 3) unique code, and 4) radio link configuration. Base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may also send separately to base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> the sequence of symbols or bits of the interfering wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to facilitate demodulation and cancellation of wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>B, upon receiving an interference report, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> determines an approximate interference impact of wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and inserts it into a Wireless Device (&ldquo;WD&rdquo;) list (Step <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight>). The interference impact may be measured through interference level measurement or approximated through interference impact that may be calculated based on the path loss between the interfering wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and the wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>transmit power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> then ranks the order of the WD list based on the approximate interference impact and/or the measured interference level (Step <highlight><bold>922</bold></highlight>). The WD list may already be populated with other wireless devices from cells adjacent to neighboring cell <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Indeed, the WD list may already include wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from a previous interference report. In that case, wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is merely updated based on its new interference impact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The WD list is further parsed and condensed into a Multi-User Detection (&ldquo;MUD&rdquo;) list based on the ordered WD list, loading in base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and its neighboring base stations (e.g., the number of available carriers), desired capacity at base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, individual wireless devices&apos; processing burden, and the processing power available at base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>924</bold></highlight>). For example, if base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is operating near full capacity, the MUD list will be more limited than if base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is operating at partial capacity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Every M frames (Step <highlight><bold>925</bold></highlight>), neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> demodulates, determines bit and channel estimates, and measures and stores interference levels for all wireless devices in the MUD list (Step <highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight>). A W-CDMA frame is 10 ms and M frames is normally set to a value no smaller than the transmission time interval over which a data block was coded and interleaved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Other base stations may assist in demodulating and determining bit and channel estimates where one or more base stations are overloaded. Furthermore, base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may also assist base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> in determining bit or symbol estimates of wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>when the interfering signal of wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is too weak for successful demodulation by base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> by providing the actual sequence of bits or symbols from interfering wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Whether other base stations assist depends on the ability of the target base station to demodulate the communication with or without this additional information and the load and delay on the IP network. This decision may also depend on the performance gain resulting from sending these bits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Every N frames (Step <highlight><bold>928</bold></highlight>), neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> measures and stores the interference levels of each wireless device in the WD list that were not demodulated previously in step <highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>929</bold></highlight>). In addition, based on the bit and channel estimates obtained at step <highlight><bold>926</bold></highlight>, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> performs the MUD algorithm (Step <highlight><bold>930</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> A major drawback of conventional MUD algorithms is the extensive processing power required to implement multi-user detection. For example, at each stage of the PIC MUD algorithm, K users are demodulated and bit and channel estimates are obtained for each of the K users. Then, each of the K bit estimates is scaled by the channel estimate and respread. All but one input signal at each of the outputs is then summed and subtracted from the total received signal to get a cleaner signal of each of the K users. The cleaner signals are finally fed back into the next stage of the conventional MUD algorithm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9C</cross-reference> shows a flow diagram of a MUD algorithm, in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention. The MUD algorithm of an embodiment of the present invention reduces the processing power usage required by conventional algorithms in several ways. First, only the wireless devices included in the MUD list are demodulated. And as described above, the MUD list can shrink or grow depending on processing power availability. For example, processing power may be further reduced by using a modified PIC MUD algorithm. Instead of demodulating and reconstructing every user in the MUD LIST at every stage of the multi-user detection algorithm, a goodness metric such as error on cyclic redundancy check (&ldquo;CRC&rdquo;) may be used to estimate and cancel users only once or to minimize how many times users are cancelled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>C, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> determines whether any of the bit estimates meet a goodness metric (Step <highlight><bold>940</bold></highlight>). The goodness metric is used in the MUD algorithm to determine if the bit estimates of the interfering wireless devices should be reconstructed and canceled definitively from the total received signal or re-estimated in the next stage of the MUD algorithm. The goodness metric is also used to reduce the processing complexity involved in having to regenerate signals from all wireless devices at every stage of the algorithm. The goodness metric may be based on coding path differences and/or a CRC check, if decoding is performed before the MUD algorithm. Signals from wireless devices with no failure on a CRC would be cancelled directly and not regenerated for the next stage of the MUD algorithm thus reducing processing complexity of the algorithm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> If any of the bit estimates meet the goodness metric, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> regenerates estimates for those wireless devices corresponding to the bit estimates (Step <highlight><bold>942</bold></highlight>). Other base stations may also assist in regenerating estimates. In other words, serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may send the symbol sequence of the interfering wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>directly to its neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> when that serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> detects that the neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> would not be able to demodulate this wireless device <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In some instances, the delay needed to receive these symbols may not be worth the increase in performance, and therefore, the serving base station <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> may decide not to send these symbol estimates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Once the estimates are regenerated and/or received, they are then subtracted from the signal received by neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>944</bold></highlight>). Neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> then determines whether any additional wireless device signals remain to be subtracted (Step <highlight><bold>946</bold></highlight>). If so, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> determines whether the maximum number of stages in the MUD algorithm has been reached (Step <highlight><bold>948</bold></highlight>). The maximum number of stages depends on the availability of processing power as well as the performance gain. An extra stage may be added to the multi-user detector if the performance gain obtained from the new stage is significant. If the maximum number of stages have not been reached, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may attempt to demodulate the wireless devices that did not meet the goodness metric in step <highlight><bold>940</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>950</bold></highlight>). If, on the other hand, the maximum number of stages is reached, neighboring base station <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> returns to step <highlight><bold>922</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> While it has been illustrated and described what is at present considered to be the preferred embodiments and methods of the present invention, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made, and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the true scope of the invention. Therefore it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiments and methods disclosed herein, but the invention includes all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for reducing interference in a wireless communication system, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>receiving, at a first cell, measurement information from a first wireless device served by the first cell while the first wireless device is at the first cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the first wireless device causes interference at a second cell, serving wireless devices other than the first wireless device, based on the measurement information; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sending to the second cell information about the interference; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the interference information at the second cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a signal based on the interference information; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the signal at the second cell to reduce the interference. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of receiving measurement information is responsive to a measurement request from the first cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of receiving measurement information comprises the step of receiving measurement information that includes signal strength measurements on the first and second base stations and the transmit power of the first wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of receiving measurement information comprises the step of receiving measurement information that includes signal-to-noise ratio measurements on the first and second base stations and the transmit power of the first wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the location of the first wireless device is measured based on strength and interference impact of a channel signal from the second cell and received by the first wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the steps of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> is repeated for a second wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the subtracting step comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>determining an approximate interference impact of the first and second wireless devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ranking the first and second wireless devices based on their respective approximate interference impact; </claim-text>
<claim-text>creating a list of wireless devices based on the interference impact of the first and second wireless devices; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the signals of the wireless devices on the list. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the subtracting step comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>determining a measured interference level of the first and second wireless devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ranking the first and second wireless devices based on their respective measured interference level; </claim-text>
<claim-text>creating a list of wireless devices based on the measured interference level of the first and second wireless devices; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>subtracting the signals of the wireless devices on the list. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of creating a list of wireless devices is further based on processing burden of the first and second wireless devices, loading in the first and second cells, desired capacity at the second cell, and processing power availability at the second cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the subtracting step comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>demodulating signals of the wireless devices on the list; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a bit estimate and a channel estimate for the demodulated signals of the wireless devices on the list; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the signals of the wireless devices on the list meet a goodness metric. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein only the signals of the wireless devices on the list meeting the goodness metric are subtracted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of determining a bit estimate is performed at the first cell when the signal is undetectable by the second cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of determining a bit estimate is performed at the first cell and the bit estimate is transmitted from the first cell to the second cell when the signal is undetectable by the second cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the goodness metric includes a CRC error check. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the goodness metric includes a coding path difference. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method for reducing interference in a wireless communication system, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>receiving a signal from a first wireless device served by a first cell while the first wireless device is at the first cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that the signal interferes with at least one other wireless device at a second cell serving wireless devices other than the first wireless device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>sending information about the first wireless device to the second cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>reducing the interference caused by the signal at the second cell based on the transmitted information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sending step further comprises sending the information to the second cell through a packet network. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of determining that the signal interferes comprises the step of receiving, at the first cell, measurement information from the first wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A system for reducing interference between wireless devices, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of wireless devices including a first wireless device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of cells including a first cell and a second cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a packet network; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first cell receives measurement information from the first wireless device, determines that the first wireless device causes interference at the second cell, and transmits information about the interference to the second cell through the packet network; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second cell receives the interference information from the first cell, and cancels the interference caused by the first wireless device based on the interference information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of creating a list of wireless devices based on interference impact of the plurality of wireless devices, loading at the first and second cells, desired capacity at the second cell, processing burden of the plurality of wireless devices, and processing power availability at the second cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of only demodulating the wireless devices on the list. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method for canceling interference between wireless devices, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a plurality of cells that serve a plurality of wireless devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring signal strengths of the cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting, at the serving cells, information about the plurality of wireless devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining that one or more of the wireless devices causes interference in one or more of the serving cells neighboring another one of the serving cells that serve the one or more wireless devices; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting information about the interference to the neighboring serving cells to cancel the interference.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003906A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
