<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002042</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10151992</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020521</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>101 24 773.7</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010521</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01J004/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>356</class>
<subclass>365000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Polarization detector and method for fabricating the polarization detector</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Werner</given-name>
<family-name>Spath</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Holzkirchen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ulrich</given-name>
<family-name>Steegmuller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Regensburg</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LERNER AND GREENBERG, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2>PATENT ATTORNEYS AND ATTORNEYS AT LAW</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Post Office Box 2480</address-1>
<city>Hollywood</city>
<state>FL</state>
<postalcode>33022-2480</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A polarization detector is described which contains a beam splitter, which disperses an incident light beam into partial beam paths. The partial beams pass though &lgr;/4 wafers and a cholesterol layer and impinge upon detectors. The polarization direction of the incident light beam can be measured by the polarization detector with the aid of the signal level of the detectors. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Field of the Invention </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a device for detecting a change in a polarization direction of linearly polarized light, with a beam splitter, with which the incident linearly polarized light can be dispersed into partial beams, and with filters and detectors that are disposed behind the beam splitter in the partial beam paths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a method for fabricating a device serving for detecting the polarization direction of linearly polarized light, whereby detectors are formed on a substrate, and beam splitters and filters are disposed in front of the detectors in the beam path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Devices of this kind are primarily utilized for reading magneto-optical storage media. In magneto-optical storage media, the stored information is read by analyzing the polarization of the light that is reflected by the storage medium, because the light reflected by the storage medium is rotated &plusmn;5 degrees depending on the magnetization of the storage medium as a result of the Kerr effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> For the purpose of detecting the polarization direction, there is a beam splitter in the optical path of the reflected light, which splits the incident light into two partial beams. Furthermore, discrete polarizers are disposed in the optical path of the partial beams, behind which photodiodes are disposed. Given a change of polarization direction, the signal of the photodiodes changes in characteristic fashion, so that the change of polarization direction can be deduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A disadvantage of the known devices is their large space requirement. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is accordingly an object of the invention to provide a polarization detector and a method for fabricating the polarization detector that overcome the above-mentioned disadvantages of the prior art devices and methods of this general type, which detects the polarization direction of linearly polarized light and which can be integrated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> With the foregoing and other objects in view there is provided, in accordance with the invention, a device for detecting a change of a polarization direction of linearly polarized light. The device contains a beam splitter for splitting incident linearly polarized light into partial beams, and filters and detectors disposed downstream of the beam splitter in a path of the partial beams. The filters each have a first layer of a bi-refringent material for converting the incident linearly polarized light into elliptically polarized light, and a second layer of a cholesterol-phase material disposed behind the first layer in an incident direction. The filters differ with respect to a dependency of a transmission on the polarization direction of the incident linearly polarized light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The object is inventively achieved in that the filters in the optical path of the partial beams respectively contain a first layer of a bi-refringent material, which converts the linearly polarized light into elliptically polarized light, and a second layer of a material in the cholesterol phase, which is disposed behind the first layer in the direction of incidence. The filters differ with respect to the dependency of the transmission on the polarization direction of the incident light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an added feature to the invention, the beam splitter is formed by a diffraction element or a hologram. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an additional feature of the invention, the first layer contains cross-linkable polymers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further feature of the invention, the first layer of each of the filters contains a &lgr;/4 wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another feature of the invention, the incident linearly polarized light is dispersed into two partial beams by the beam splitter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further added feature of the invention, the two partial beams have an opposite helicity after passing through the &lgr;/4 wafer of a respective one of the filters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> It is also the object of the invention to propose a method for fabricating the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The object is also inventively achieved in that material for the layer in the cholesterol phase is deposited on a transparent carrier, and the carrier is attached to the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A characteristic of materials in the cholesterol phase is that they reflect light with the same helicity and pass light with the opposite helicity. If the linearly polarized light is converted into elliptically polarized light by the layer of bi-refringent material, the transmission through the layer of cholesterol-phase material depends on the alignment of the polarization vector of the incident linearly polarized light. In particular, a change of the direction of polarization is detected by way of a corresponding change of the signal level at the detectors. The inventive device thus represents a working polarization detector that is capable of detecting deviations in the polarization direction of linearly polarized light on the order of magnitude of 0.5 degrees. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The particular advantage of this is that the polarization detector according to the invention can also be built with microelectronic dimensions. In particular, the layer of cholesterol-phase material can be deposited with the aid of techniques, which are known from the semiconductor industry, for depositing photosensitive resist onto a carrier. The carrier is a transparent carrier that is placed onto the actual substrate with the photodetector. It is also possible to deposit the layer of cholesterol-phase material directly onto the substrate. The contacts formed on the substrate can then be exposed by removing the layer of cholesterol-phase material. Processes that are known in the semiconductor industry can then be applied to the fabrication of the inventive polarization detector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> With the foregoing and other objects in view there is further provided, in accordance with the invention, a method for fabricating a device for detecting a polarization direction of linearly polarized light. The method includes providing a substrate, forming detectors on the substrate, forming filters by depositing a cholesterol phase on a transparent carrier, attaching the carrier to the substrate, and disposing the filters and a beam splitter in front of the detectors in a direction of an optical path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an added mode of the invention, there are the steps of forming contact points in the substrate, and constructing weak points in the transparent carrier in regions that are positioned over the contact points of the substrate in a finished device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another mode of the invention, there is the step of removing the weak points from the transparent carrier after the transparent carrier is placed on the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In accordance with further mode of the invention, there is the step of dividing the substrate for forming individual components, after the weak points are removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> With the foregoing and other objects in view there is additionally provided, in accordance with the invention, a method for fabricating a device for detecting a polarization direction of linearly polarized light. The method includes providing a substrate, constructing detectors on the substrate, depositing a material of a cholesterol-phase layer on the substrate, and disposing filters and a beam splitter in a direction of an optical path in front of the detectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a concomitant mode of the invention, there is the step of covering the cholesterol-phase layer with a transparent carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Other features which are considered as characteristic for the invention are set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Although the invention is illustrated and described herein as embodied in a polarization detector and a method for fabricating the polarization detector, it is nevertheless not intended to be limited to the details shown, since various modifications and structural changes may be made therein without departing from the spirit of the invention and within the scope and range of equivalents of the claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The construction and method of operation of the invention, however, together with additional objects and advantages thereof will be best understood from the following description of specific embodiments when read in connection with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic, side-elevational view of a photodetector according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top, plan view of the photodetector; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are sectional views showing successive steps of a method for fabricating the polarization detector.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the figures of the drawing in detail and first, particularly, to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> thereof, there is shown an incident light beam <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> dispersed into partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by a beam splitter <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The beam splitter <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be a diffraction element or hologram. The partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> respectively strike &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, which convert the partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> into elliptically polarized light (circularly polarized light being the specific instance of elliptically polarized light considered in this example). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The elliptically polarized light in the partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> impinges upon a layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of a cholesterol-phase material. If the helicity of the incident circular light matches the helicity of the layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the incident light is reflected. On the other hand, if the helicity of incident circularly polarized light is the opposite of that of the layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the incident light is transmitted. The cholesterol-phase material is generally an optically single-axis negative and optically active material. Various cholestene derivatives have this property. The materials are known to the person skilled in the art and do not constitute subject matter of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Lastly, the partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> impinge upon detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. With the aid of the change of signal level of the detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, it is possible to detect the change of polarization direction of the linearly polarized incident light beam <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of the polarization detector represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are respectively aligned in such a way that an optical main axes of the materials utilized for the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> stand at a right angle to one another and at an angle of approximately 45&deg; to a polarization direction <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the linearly polarized incident light. In this case, the incident linearly polarized light is respectively converted by the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> into circularly polarized light with a different helicity. Of the two partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the partial beam whose helicity matches the helicity of the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is reflected at the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and the partial beam whose helicity is aligned anti-parallel, and not parallel, to the helicity of the cholesterol layer is transmitted by the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, one of the two detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is charged with light, while little light, if any, impinges upon the other of the two detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Note that the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may also be replaced by bi-refringent layers of a cross-linkable polymer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> If the polarization direction of the incident light beam <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> no longer assumes an angle of 45&deg; to the optical main axes <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the light in the partial beams <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is respectively converted into elliptically polarized light, which is only partly reflected or transmitted at the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the signal levels at the detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> also change. The detector <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> that was previously highly charged with light now receives less light, whereas the detector <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> that previously received little or no light now receives more light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The polarization detector represented in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> represents a differentially working sensitive polarization detector, with which it is also possible to detect changes of less than 0.5&deg; of the polarization direction of the incident light beam <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The polarization detector represented in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> has the additional advantage that it can be fabricated in an integrated construction with the aid of processes that are known in the semiconductor industry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The fabrication of an exemplifying embodiment of the polarization detector will now be described in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> According to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> transparent carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is fabricated, for instance a glass carrier, in whose bottom <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> recesses <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are incorporated. The recesses <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be constructed in the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by sandblasting, for example. Material for the cholesterol phase is then spun onto a top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (spin coating) and cured with UV light. Next, the &lgr;/4 wafers are deposited onto the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The &lgr;/4 wafers can also be replaced by a bi-refringent layer of cross-linkable polymers. The bi-refringent layer can also be constructed by a spin coating technique followed by treatment with polarized light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are formed separately in a substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Contacts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which serve for driving the detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, are also constructed on a top surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Next, the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is attached onto the substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in such a way that the recesses <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are situated over the contacts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Weak points <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are thus realized above the contacts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by the recesses <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. This produces the cross-section represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The weak points <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, which are situated above the recesses <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, are then sawed out. The contacts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on the substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> are thereby exposed. Next, the substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is divided in order to separate the individual polarization detectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> With this technique, the individual components of the polarization detector are precisely mounted in relation to one another. Besides this, the detectors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are protected from damage with the aid of the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In a modified exemplifying embodiment, the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are constructed directly on the substrate <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The covered contacts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> can be exposed again by a special wet-chemical etching technique or dry etching technique subsequent to the deposition of the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The advantages of this modification are the low assembly costs and the fact that the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be forgone. It can also be advantageous not to omit the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, because then the cholesterol layer <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> will be protected by the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In this case, the &lgr;/4 wafers <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are expediently disposed on the carrier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A device for detecting a change of a polarization direction of linearly polarized light, comprising: 
<claim-text>a beam splitter for splitting incident linearly polarized light into partial beams; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>filters and detectors disposed downstream of said beam splitter in a path of the partial beams, said filters each having a first layer of a bi-refringent material for converting the incident linearly polarized light into elliptically polarized light, and a second layer of a cholesterol-phase material disposed behind said first layer in an incident direction, said filters differ with respect to a dependency of a transmission on the polarization direction of the incident linearly polarized light. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said beam splitter is formed by a diffraction element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first layer contains cross-linkable polymers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first layer of each of said filters contains a &lgr;/4 wafer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the incident linearly polarized light is dispersed into two partial beams by said beam splitter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two partial beams have an opposite helicity after passing through said &lgr;/4 wafer of a respective one of said filters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said beam splitter is formed by a hologram. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method for fabricating a device for detecting a polarization direction of linearly polarized light, which comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming detectors on the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming filters by depositing a cholesterol phase on a transparent carrier; </claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching the carrier to the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the filters and a beam splitter in front of the detectors in a direction of an optical path. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises: 
<claim-text>forming contact points in the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>constructing weak points in the transparent carrier in regions that are positioned over the contact points of the substrate in a finished device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises removing the weak points from the transparent carrier after the transparent carrier is placed on the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises dividing the substrate for forming individual components, after the weak points are removed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for fabricating a device for detecting a polarization direction of linearly polarized light, which comprises the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>constructing detectors on the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a material of a cholesterol-phase layer on the substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing filters and a beam splitter in a direction of an optical path in front of the detectors. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, which comprises covering the cholesterol-phase layer with a transparent carrier.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002042A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002042A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002042A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002042A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
