<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002817A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002817A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002817</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180315</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-197175</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/36</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>078000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Optical connector and optical connector ferrule to be used therein</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tadashi</given-name>
<family-name>Yamaguchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kurobe-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tetsuya</given-name>
<family-name>Katsumi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kurobe-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mamoru</given-name>
<family-name>Ishida</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sendai-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hitoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Ofune</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Uozu-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>YKK Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow,</name-1>
<name-2>Garrett &amp; Dunner, L.L.P.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1300 I Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3315</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical connector comprises a mount having an accommodating portion and an optical connector ferrule. The mount and the outer surface of the optical connector ferrule to be brought into contact therewith are made of the same kind of material, thereby securing the good weldability therebetween. In one embodiment, both the mount and the ferrule are made of an amorphous alloy. In another embodiment, the mount is made of a metal, for example stainless steel, and the ferrule comprises a body made of an amorphous alloy and a surface part covering the outer surface of the body is made of the same kind of material as the mount, i.e. a metal such as stainless steel. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to optical connectors for connecting and/or fixing optical fiber ends or optical fiber cable ends to be used in optical communications and optical connector ferrules to be used therein, particularly optical connector ferrules having a metal tube incorporated therein as an integral part thereof (hereinafter referred to occasionally as &ldquo;optical connector ferrule of the metal tube built-in type&rdquo;). The term &ldquo;ferrule&rdquo; used herein collectively refers to a capillary-shaped ferrule (also called &ldquo;capillary&rdquo;) and a ferrule having a flange part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> When an optical connector ferrule is connected to a semiconductor laser module to be used as a light source for an optical communication device and the like, a mount for attachment to a module is commonly used. Now, the relation between the ferrule and the mount is explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates one example of a conventional butterfly type LD module. An optical unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> assembled in advance is placed and fixed in a butterfly package <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> denotes a group of package electrode terminals of the butterfly type which connect a driving power source to a laser diode (LD) <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the optical unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and are adapted to be connected to electrode terminals of an optical system for monitoring the driving state. Two groups of electrode terminals <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are attached to both sidewalls of the package body as opposed to each other. A ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> into which a leading end of an optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is fitted is connected to the butterfly package <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> via a mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for attachment to a module. Laser beams emitted from the laser diode <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are collected by aspherical lenses <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and introduced into the optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> embedded in the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at the leading end thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Heretofore, the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been generally manufactured from ceramics such as zirconia and preliminarily press-fitted into the tube-shaped mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> made of stainless steel. This mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is attached to the butterfly package <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> by laser welding. In the diagram the welding positions are indicated by the reference sign &ldquo;X&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Parts for optical connectors are required to have high dimensional accuracy in order to prevent the loss of light. The conventional method for the production of an optical connector ferrule (capillary) comprises the steps of first molding a ceramic powder containing a binder by injection molding, extrusion molding or the like thereby forming a ferrule blank, sintering the resultant blank, and finishing the blank into a desired dimension by subjecting it to machining such as abrasive finishing of the outside diameter, abrasive finishing of the inside diameter, and polishing of the leading end into the spherical convex surface (PC polishing). Since the inside diameter of a small hole of the ferrule for the insertion of an optical fiber is very small (for instance, the diameter of the small hole of the capillary of the SC type is 0.126 mm), the wire lapping finishing is commonly used for the finishing of the inside diameter thereof. Accordingly, the process of production is lengthy and requires expensive apparatuses such as an inside diameter finishing machine and an outside diameter finishing machine, and the cost of production is inevitably large. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the problems mentioned above, the assignee of this application has already proposed to manufacture the ferrules from an amorphous alloy (Japanese Patent Application, KOKAI (Early Publication) No. 10-186176). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The use of amorphous alloy has such advantages that the ferrules satisfying the dimensional accuracy and the surface quality required of optical connector ferrules can be manufactured by a metal mold casting method with high mass productivity and in a single process and further that such machining steps as outside diameter finishing and inside diameter finishing of the ferrule can be diminished markedly. However, the weldability of an amorphous alloy to a metal such as stainless steel commonly used as a material of the mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> mentioned above is poor and thus the ferrule made of an amorphous alloy cannot be joined to the mount with sufficient strength. Therefore, it poses a problem that the ferrule made of an amorphous alloy can be used as a part of module only with difficulty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is, therefore, an object of the present invention to improve the joining properties or weldability of the ferrule made of an amorphous alloy and having excellent properties and advantages as mentioned above to a mount for attachment to a module and enable the ferrule to be used as a part of the module. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide an optical connector ferrule having excellent optical properties, which ferrule can be joined or welded to a mount even when the mount made of a metal such as stainless steel is used and can be used as a part of the module. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> To accomplish the objects mentioned above, a first aspect of the present invention provides an optical connector. A first embodiment thereof is directed to an optical connector comprising a mount having an accommodating portion or space and an optical connector ferrule attached to the mount, wherein the mount and at least the outer surface of the optical connector ferrule are made of the same kind of material and the ferrule is integrally joined to the mount. This embodiment includes the case that both the mount and the optical connector ferrule mentioned above are made of an amorphous alloy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the present invention is directed to an optical connector comprising a mount having an accommodating portion or space and an optical connector ferrule attached to the mount, wherein the optical connector ferrule comprises a body and a surface part covering the outer surface of the body, and the mount and the surface part mentioned above are made of the same kind of material and are integrally joined to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention provides an optical connector ferrule which can be advantageously used in this embodiment. The optical connector ferrule is characterized by comprising a body made of an amorphous alloy having at least a glass transition region and a surface part of an existing metal material covering the outer surface of the body.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Other objects, features, and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following description taken together with the drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross-sectional view schematically illustrating a conventional butterfly type LD module; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross-sectional view schematically illustrating one embodiment of the joining state between a ferrule of the metal tube built-in type of an optical connector according to the present invention and a mount for attachment to a module; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross-sectional view schematically illustrating another embodiment of the joining state between a ferrule of the metal tube built-in type of an optical connector according to the present invention and a mount for attachment to a module; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference> illustrate one embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type according to the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> depicting a schematic cross-sectional view and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> depicting a schematic side view thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating another embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating still another embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating yet another embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating one embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube/center tube built-in type according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating one embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube/optical fiber built-in type according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view schematically illustrating one embodiment of the ferrule of the metal tube/central tube/optical fiber built-in type according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross-sectional view schematically illustrating one embodiment of an apparatus for the production of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The fundamental characteristic feature of the present invention, for the purpose of improving the joining properties or weldability of a ferrule made of an amorphous alloy having excellent properties and advantages as mentioned above to a mount for attachment to a module and enabling the ferrule to be used as a part of a module, resides in the fact that the mount and the outer surface of the optical connector ferrule to be brought into contact therewith are made of the same kind of material, thereby securing the good weldability. The embodiments of this feature include an embodiment wherein both the mount and the ferrule mentioned above are made of an amorphous alloy and an embodiment wherein the mount is manufactured from a metal, for example stainless steel (SUS) as in the conventional manner, and the ferrule comprises a body made of an amorphous alloy and a surface part covering the outer surface of the body and made of the same kind of material as the mount, i.e. a metal such as stainless steel. In either embodiments, it is possible to securely fix the ferrule made of substantially an amorphous alloy to the mount by welding because the joining properties or weldability between the amorphous alloys or between the metal materials are excellent. Incidentally, the same kind of material (amorphous alloy-amorphous alloy or metal-metal) satisfies the requirement for the weldability and there is no need to be the totally same material. Needless to say, any metals other than stainless steel may be used as a metal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type of the present invention can not only be applied to the optical connectors for connecting the optical fibers by abutting the end faces of the ferrules to each other, but also be used as the parts of LD modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Since the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type of the present invention have a body portion made of an amorphous alloy, they exhibit excellent durability, high positional accuracy of an optical fiber fitted therein, and low connector insertion loss. Furthermore, the present invention allows the optical connector ferrules having good concentricity of the inside diameter and the outside diameter thereof to be mass-produced with high efficiency by a simple process. Moreover, the present invention obviates such machining steps as inside diameter finishing of the ferrule, thereby considerably lowering the number of machining steps and, therefore, enables to lower the cost of production of the ferrules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Now, the present invention will be described more concretely below with reference to the attached drawings which illustrate some embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates schematically one embodiment of the joining state between a mount for attachment to a module and a ferrule of the metal tube built-in type. The mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>comprises a body member <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for accommodating and fixing a lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a flange member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, both the body member and the flange member being made of stainless steel. On the other hand, the ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> into which a leading end of an optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is securely fitted is made of an amorphous alloy and integrally joined into a tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> made of a metal (stainless steel). Accordingly, the body of the ferrule is made of an amorphous alloy and a surface part covering the outer surface of the body is formed from a stainless steel tube. This ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the metal tube built-in type is fitted into the stainless steel flange member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and fixedly secured thereto at predetermined positions of the metal (stainless steel) tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by welding. Likewise, the stainless steel flange member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is welded to the body member <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The reference sign &ldquo;X&rdquo; denotes the welding positions. The mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the metal tube built-in type in the integrally joined state as mentioned above is fixed to a butterfly package of an LD module as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a modified embodiment of the aforementioned embodiment. In this embodiment, lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is attached to one end portion of a mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as in the case of the above embodiment, the mount has a pipe-like shape containing a recessed part <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for welding at its central portion and the material thereof is stainless steel except the lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Similar to the embodiment mentioned above, the ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> into which the leading end of the optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is securely fitted is made of an amorphous alloy and integrally joined into the tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> made of a metal (stainless steel). This ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the metal tube built-in type is fitted into the mount <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>made of stainless steel and fixedly secured thereto at predetermined positions of the metal (stainless steel) tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Although the aforementioned embodiments use a stainless steel tube longer than the ferrule, the present invention is not limited to such embodiments. A metal tube having the length substantially equal to that of the ferrule (capillary) may be used instead. Some embodiments of such ferrules of the metal tube built-in type are described below with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of the amorphous alloy ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> casted integrally in the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has an elongated through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for the insertion of an optical fiber (or a basic thread of an optical fiber coated with a plastic thin film) along the axis thereof. Such ferrules of the metal tube built-in type can be easily manufactured by placing a metal tube in a cavity of a mold as mentioned hereinafter and casting an amorphous alloy therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a capillary part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a flange part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>integrally formed therewith from an amorphous alloy, the capillary part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being casted integrally in the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrate other embodiments of the ferrule having a capillary part and a flange part as separate components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is composed of the capillary part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of which outer surface is covered with a metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and which has formed along the axis thereof a through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a small diameter intended for the insertion of an optical fiber and the flange part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which has formed along the axis thereof a through-hole <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of a large diameter for the insertion of a sheathed optical fiber (the optical fiber coated with a sheath). The capillary part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is fixed into a leading end recessed part <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the flange part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by virtue of tight fit or adhesion. The through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the small diameter in the capillary part and the through-hole <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the large diameter in the flange part are joined through the medium of a tapered hole part <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> has the structure similar to that of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, except that the through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a small diameter intended for the insertion of an optical fiber and the through-hole <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of a large diameter for the insertion of a sheathed optical fiber are continuously formed in the capillary part la along the axis thereof so as to be joined through the medium of the tapered hole part <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In either embodiments mentioned above, the flange part <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be made of a metal such as stainless steel or an amorphous alloy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> further illustrate other embodiments of the ferrule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the outer surface of the ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is covered with a metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> having the through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a small diameter intended for the insertion of an optical fiber is integrally fixed in the inside peripheral part of the ferrule along the axis thereof </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is identical with the embodiment mentioned above in that the outer surface of the ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is covered with the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, but differs therefrom in that an optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is integrally fixed in the through-hole of the inside peripheral part of the ferrule along the axis thereof </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the outer surface of the ferrule (capillary) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is covered with the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> having the through-hole <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a small diameter intended for the insertion of an optical fiber is integrally fixed in the inside peripheral part of the ferrule along the axis thereof, and further the optical fiber <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is integrally fixed in the through-hole of the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> along the axis thereof. Although in this embodiment the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> does not extend throughout the entire length of the ferrule <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, it may be embedded in the ferrule throughout the entire length thereof as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. As the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> mentioned above, a ceramic tube may be used besides a metal tube. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The ferrules mentioned above can be easily manufactured by placing the metal tube in a cavity of a mold along the inside peripheral wall thereof or further placing the center tube and/or the optical fiber along the axis of the cavity and casting an amorphous alloy therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> An example of the method for the production of the ferrule is-described below with reference to the diagram. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates the schematic construction of one mode of embodying an apparatus and method for the production of the ferrule of the metal tube built-in type or the ferrule of the metal tube/center tube built-in type containing the center tube in the central portion thereof according to the present invention. In the diagram, reference numeral <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> denotes a metal mold provided with a molding cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> adapted to define the outside dimension of the optical connector ferrule. The mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is a split mold which is separable, for example, composed of an upper mold and a lower mold as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. A sprue (through-hole) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> communicating with the cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is formed in a lower portion of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> While the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be made of such metallic material as copper, copper alloy, cemented carbide or superalloy, it is preferred to be made of such material as copper or copper alloy which has a large thermal capacity and high thermal conductivity for the purpose of heightening the cooling rate of the molten alloy injected into the cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The mold may have disposed therein such a flow channel as allow flow of a cooling medium like cooling water or cooling gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> An injection sleeve (melting vessel) <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is provided with a cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a plunger <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> slidably disposed in the sleeve. The injection sleeve <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is disposed directly below the sprue <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in such a manner as to be reciprocated vertically. The plunger <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is vertically moved by means of a hydraulic cylinder (or pneumatic cylinder) not shown in the diagram. The upper part of the cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> forms a raw material accommodating part <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> in combination with the upper face of the plunger <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A high frequency induction coil <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> as a heat source is disposed so as to encircle the raw material accommodating part <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. As the heat source, any arbitrary means such as one resorting to the phenomenon of resistance heating may be adopted besides the high-frequency induction heating. The material of the cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and that of the plunger <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are preferred to be such heat-resistant material as ceramics or metallic materials coated with a heat-resistant film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, for the purpose of preventing the molten alloy from forming an oxide film, it is preferred to dispose the apparatus in its entirety in a vacuum or an atmosphere of an inert gas such as Ar gas or establish a stream of an inert gas at least between the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the raw material accommodating part <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the injection sleeve <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The production of the ferrule of the metal tube and/or center tube built-in type according to the present invention is effected by first setting the injection sleeve <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in a state separated downwardly from the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, placing the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> along the inside peripheral wall thereof or further placing the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in position so as to extend vertically along the axis thereof, and then charging the empty space inside the raw material accommodating part <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> with the raw material &ldquo;A&rdquo; capable of forming an amorphous alloy. The alloying raw material &ldquo;A&rdquo; to be used may be in any of the arbitrary forms such as rods, pellets, and minute particles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the injection sleeve <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is elevated until the upper end thereof abuts against the periphery of the sprue <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the high frequency induction coil <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is excited to heat the alloying raw material &ldquo;A&rdquo; rapidly. After the fusion of the alloying raw material &ldquo;A&rdquo; has been confirmed by detecting the temperature of the molten alloy, the high frequency induction coil <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is demagnetized. Then, the hydraulic cylinder is actuated to effect rapid elevation of the plunger <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and injection of the molten alloy through the sprue <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The injected molten alloy is introduced into the molding cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and compressed and rapidly solidified therein. In this case, the cooling rate exceeding 10<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>K/s can be obtained by suitably setting such factors as injection temperature and injection speed, for example. Thereafter, the injection sleeve <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is lowered and the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is separated to allow extraction of the cast product. The product is obtained by severing runner parts from the cast product and, as occasion demands, effecting the finishing process such as end portion finishing and PC polishing (polishing to the spherical convex surface). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In such a method, the ferrule is strongly fixed in the metal tube <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the outside surface portion and/or the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in the central portion integrally without causing any gap therebetween because the amorphous alloy scarcely causes solidification shrinkage after casting, and the ferrule (capillary) of the metal tube built-in type as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> through <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> or the ferrule (capillary) further incorporating the center tube integrally therein as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is obtained. Incidentally, in the case of the ferrule (capillary) shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the shape and the size of the through-holes <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are defined by the outside dimension of a core pin set in the cavity. Further, when the injection molding is carried out by using an optical fiber instead of the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and placing it in the cavity <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the mold <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> so as to extend vertically along the axis thereof, the ferrule of the optical fiber built-in type as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is obtained. Moreover, when the injection molding is carried out by placing an optical fiber in the center tube <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> so as to extend along the axis thereof, the ferrule of the optical fiber built-in type as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, for example, is obtained. In this case, when the optical fiber is set in the mold so as to have one end thereof continuously extended outward from the mold, the ferrule of the optical fiber built-in type having the optical fiber that continuously extends from one end of the ferrule is obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Since the outer peripheral surface of the metal tube or the inner peripheral surface of the center tube to be used in the above method is smooth and the amorphous alloy allows manufacture of a cast product of smooth surface faithfully reproducing the contour of the cavity of the mold, the ferrule having good concentricity of the inside diameter and the outside diameter can be obtained. Further, since this method obviates such machining steps as inside diameter finishing and outside diameter finishing of the ferrule, the number of machining steps can be considerably lowered. Accordingly, the method of the present invention allows the ferrule (capillary) having a metal tube incorporated therein as an integral part thereof or further having a center tube and/or an optical fiber incorporated therein as an integral part thereof, which ferrule is excellent in the roundness of the diameter of the through-hole and the cylindricity thereof and satisfies a predetermined shape, dimensional accuracy, and surface quality, to be mass-produced with high efficiency by a simple process and, therefore, enables to lower the cost of production of the ferrule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, in the production of the ferrule of the center tube built-in type, there is no need to use a core pin as in the conventional method because the center tube also functions as a core pin. However, it is also possible to use a core pin for the purpose of reinforcing the center tube in strength during the injection molding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As the material for the center tube, various ceramics such as quartz glass, amorphous oxides, crystalline oxides, and nitrides like Si<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>may be used besides various metals such as stainless steel. In the case of ceramics, amorphous oxides (oxide glass) and oxide materials exhibiting smoothness equivalent to that of the amorphous oxide may be advantageously used. Since the quartz glass permits easy machining into a tube with high dimensional accuracy and has a coefficient of linear thermal expansion substantially equal to that of an optical fiber, it is suitable as the material for the center tube to be embedded in the ferrule into which the optical fiber is fitted. That is to say, the optical connector ferrule having excellent resistance to environment can be obtained without incurring such problems that an end face of the optical fiber protrudes from the end face of the ferrule or the optical fiber separates from the ferrule due to the deterioration of an adhesive caused by the heat cycle in the use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As a material for the body of the ferrule, it is freferable that an amorphous alloy should be used, as mentioned above. An amorphous alloy possesses highly accurate castability and machinability and, therefore, allows manufacture of a product of smooth surface faithfully reproducing the contour of the cavity of the mold by the metal mold casting method or molding method. Accordingly, the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type which satisfy dimensional prescription, dimensional accuracy, and surface quality can be manufactured by a single process with high mass productivity insofar as the metal mold to be used is suitably prepared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Although the amorphous alloy does not need to be limited to any particular substance but may be any of the alloys insofar as they have at least a glass transition region, the amorphous alloy having a composition represented by either one of the following general formulas (1) to (6) may be advantageously used.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> wherein M<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents either or both of the two elements, Zr and Hf; M<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ni, Cu, Fe, Co, Mn, Nb, Ti, V, Cr, Zn, Al, and Ga; Ln represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Yb, and Mm (mish metal: aggregate of rare earth elements); M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Be, B, C, N, and O; M<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ta, W, and Mo; M<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Au, Pt, Pd, and Ag; and a, b, c, d, e, and f represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 25&lE;a&lE;85, 15&lE;b&lE;75, 0&lE;c&lE;30, 0&lE;d&lE;30, 0&lE;e&lE;15, and 0&lE;f&lE;15. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The above amorphous alloy includes those represented by the following general formulas (1-a) to (1-p).</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-a)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> This amorphous alloy has large negative enthalpy of mixing and good producibility of the amorphous structure due to the coexistence of the M<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>element and Zr or Hf.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-b)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The addition of a rare earth element to the alloy represented by the above general formula (1-a), as in this amorphous alloy, enhances the thermal stability of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-c)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-d)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The filling of gaps in the amorphous structure with the M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>element having a small atomic radius (Be, B, C, N, or O), as in these amorphous alloys, makes the structure stable and enhances the producibility of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-e)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-f)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-g)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-h)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The addition of a high melting metal, M<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>(Ta, W, or Mo) to the above alloys, as in these amorphous alloys, enhances the heat resistance and corrosion resistance without affecting the producibility of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-i)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-j)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-k)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-l)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-m)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-n)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-o)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(1-p)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> These amorphous alloys containing a noble metal, M<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>(Au, Pt, Pd, or Ag) will not be brittle even if the crystallization occurs.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Al<highlight><subscript>100-g-h-i</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>g</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>h</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> wherein Ln represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Yb, and Mm; M<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, Ta, and W; M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Be, B, C, N, and O; and g, h, and i represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 30&lE;g&lE;90, 0&lE;h&lE;55, and 0&lE;i&lE;10. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The above amorphous alloy includes those represented by the following general formulas (2-a) and (2-b).</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Al<highlight><subscript>100-g-h-i</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>g</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>h</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2-a)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> This amorphous alloy has large negative enthalpy of mixing and good producibility of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Al<highlight><subscript>100-g-h-i</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>g</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>h</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2-b)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> This amorphous alloy has a stable structure and enhanced producibility of the amorphous structure due to the filling of gaps in the amorphous structure with the M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>element having a small atomic radius (Be, B, C, N, or O).</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-p</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(3)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; and p represents an atomic percentage falling in the range of 5&lE;p&lE;60. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> This amorphous alloy has large negative enthalpy of mixing and good producibility of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-r</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>8</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>r</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(4)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; M<highlight><superscript>8 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Al, Si, and Ca; and q and r represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 1&lE;q&lE;35 and 1&lE;r&lE;25. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The filling of gaps in the amorphous structure of the alloy of the above general formula (3) with the M<highlight><superscript>8 </superscript></highlight>element having a small atomic radius (Al, Si, or Ca), as in this amorphous alloy, makes the structure stable and enhances the producibility of the amorphous structure.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-s</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>9</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(5)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-r-s</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>8</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>r</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>9</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(6)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; M<highlight><superscript>8 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Al, Si, and Ca; M<highlight><superscript>9 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, and Mm; and q, r, and s represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 1&lE;q&lE;35, 1&lE;r&lE;25, and 3&lE;s&lE;25. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The addition of a rare earth element to the alloy of the general formula (3) or (4) mentioned above, as in these amorphous alloys, enhances the thermal stability of the amorphous structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Among other amorphous alloys mentioned above, the Zr-TM-Al and Hf-TM-Al (TM: transition metal) amorphous alloys having very wide differences between the glass transition temperature (Tg) and the crystallization temperature (Tx) exhibit high strength and high corrosion resistance, possess wide supercooled liquid ranges (glass transition ranges), &Dgr;Tx&equals;Tx&minus;Tg, of not less than 30 K, and extremely wide supercooled liquid ranges of not less than 60 K in the case of the Zr-TM-Al amorphous alloys. The Zr<highlight><subscript>60</subscript></highlight>Al<highlight><subscript>15</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>2.5</subscript></highlight>Ni<highlight><subscript>7.5</subscript></highlight>Cu<highlight><subscript>15 </subscript></highlight>alloy (Tg: 652K, Tx: 768K), for example, has such an extremely wide &Dgr;Tx as 116 K. In the above temperature ranges, these amorphous alloys manifest very satisfactory workability owing to viscous flow even at such low stress not more than some tens MPa. They are characterized by being produced easily and very stably as evinced by the fact that they are enabled to furnish an amorphous bulk material even by a casting method using a cooling rate of the order of some tens K/s. After a further study in search of uses for these alloys, it has been ascertained that by the metal mold casting from a melt, these alloys produce amorphous materials and permit very faithful reproduction of the shape and size of a molding cavity of a metal mold and, with the physical properties of the alloys as a contributory factor, befit the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> While certain specific embodiments of the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type have been described hereinbefore, the present invention is not limited to these embodiments. As mentioned above, the body of the ferrule is made of an amorphous alloy. When the mount for attachment to a module is also made of an amorphous alloy, the weldability between the ferrule and the mount can be secured even if the outer surface of the ferrule body is not covered with a metal tube. Accordingly, the present invention includes such an embodiment. As a matter of course, in this embodiment the ferrule may also be in the form of the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type as mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the ferrules of the metal tube built-in type and/or the center tube built-in type and/or the optical fiber built-in type mentioned above can be applied not only to the butterfly type LD module as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> but also to other LD modules and to the optical connectors for connecting the optical fibers by abutting the end faces of the ferrules to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The described embodiments are therefore to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, the scope of the invention being indicated by the appended claims rather than by the foregoing description and all changes which come within the meaning and the range of equivalency of the claims are, therefore, intended to be embraced therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The disclosure in Japanese Patent Application No. 2001-197175 of Jun. 28, 2001 is incorporated here by reference. This Japanese Patent Application describes the invention described hereinabove and claimed in the claims appended hereinbelow and provides the basis for a claim of priority for the instant invention under 35 U.S.C. 119. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An optical connector comprising a mount having an accommodating portion and an optical connector ferrule attached to the mount, wherein said mount and at least an outer surface of said optical connector ferrule are made of the same kind of material and said ferrule is integrally joined to said mount. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The optical connector according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein both said mount and said optical connector ferrule are made of an amorphous alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An optical connector comprising a mount having an accommodating portion and an optical connector ferrule attached to the mount, wherein said optical connector ferrule comprises a body and a surface part covering an outer surface of said body, and said mount and said surface part are made of the same kind of material and are integrally joined to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The optical connector according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein both said mount and said surface part of the optical connector ferrule are made of a metal and said body of the optical connector ferrule is made of an amorphous alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An optical connector ferrule, comprising a body made of an amorphous alloy having at least a glass transition region and a surface part of a metal material covering an outer surface of said body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an optical fiber incorporated therein as an integral part thereof along the axis of said ferrule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said optical fiber extends in the interior of said optical connector ferrule from one end to the other end of said ferrule and further continuously extends outward from one end of said optical connector ferrule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a center tube incorporated therein as an integral part thereof along the axis of said ferrule. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said center tube is made of a metal or ceramics. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a body made of an amorphous alloy having at least a glass transition region, a metal tube covering an outer surface of said body as an integral part thereof, a center tube embedded in said body in the longitudinal direction thereof, and an optical fiber integrally fixed in said center tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The optical connector ferrule according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said body is made of a substantially amorphous alloy having a composition represented by either one of the following general formulas (1) to (6) and containing an amorphous phase in a volumetric ratio of at least 50%:</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>M<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>a</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>b</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>e</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight>f&emsp;&emsp;(1)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein M<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents either or both of the two elements, Zr and Hf; M<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ni, Cu, Fe, Co, Mn, Nb, Ti, V, Cr, Zn, Al, and Ga; Ln represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Yb, and Mm (mish metal: aggregate of rare earth elements); M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Be, B, C, N, and O; M<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>M represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ta, W, and Mo; M<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Au, Pt, Pd, and Ag; and a, b, c, d, e, and f represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 25&lE;a&lE;85, 15&lE;b&lE;75, 0&lE;c&lE;30, 0&lE;d&lE;30, 0&lE;e&lE;15, and 0&lE;f&lE;15,</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Al<highlight><subscript>100-g-h-i</subscript></highlight>Ln<highlight><subscript>g</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>h</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein Ln represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Yb, and Mm; M<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zr, Nb, Mo, Hf, Ta, and W; M<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Be, B, C, N, and O; and g, h, and i represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 30&lE;g&lE;90, 0&lE;h&lE;55, and 0&lE;i&lE;10,</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-p</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(3)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; and p represents an atomic percentage falling in the range of 5&lE;p&lE;60,</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-r</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>8</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>r</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(4)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; M<highlight><superscript>8 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Al, Si, and Ca; and q and r represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 1&lE;q&lE;35 and 1&lE;r&lE;25,</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-s</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>9</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(5)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; M<highlight><superscript>9 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, and Mm; and q and s represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 1&lE;q&lE;35 and 3&lE;s&lE;25, and</claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Mg<highlight><subscript>100-q-r-s</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>7</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>q</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>8</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>r</subscript></highlight>M<highlight><superscript>9</superscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(6)</in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein M<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Cu, Ni, Sn, and Zn; M<highlight><superscript>8 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Al, Si, and Ca; M<highlight><superscript>9 </superscript></highlight>represents at least one element selected from the group consisting of Y, La, Ce, Nd, Sm, and Mm; and q, r, and s represent such atomic percentages as respectively satisfy 1&lE;q&lE;35, 1&lE;r&lE;25, and 3&lE;s&lE;25.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002817A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
