<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000170A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000170A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000170</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894269</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E04C005/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>052</class>
<subclass>677000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>052</class>
<subclass>684000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>052</class>
<subclass>686000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>052</class>
<subclass>689000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Concrete reinforcing bar support</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Felix</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Sorkin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Stafford</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>John S. Egbert</name-1>
<name-2>Harrison &amp; Egbert</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>7th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>412 Main Street</address-2>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77002</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A concrete reinforcing bar support including a base, a support structure extending upwardly from the base, a first clamping member affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above a top surface of the support structure, a second clamping member affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above a top surface of the support structure, and a third clamping member affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above the top surface of the support structure. The second clamping member has an interior surface generally facing the interior surfaces of the first and third clamping members. The first clamping member is separated by a space from the third clamping member. Ribs extend inwardly from the interior surfaces of each of the clamping members so as to compressively contact a reinforcing bar placed interior of the clamping members. The support structure has a generally H-shaped cross-section in a plane parallel to said base. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to devices for use in connection with construction. More particularly, the present invention relates to reinforcing bar chair apparatus for use in reinforced concrete construction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In reinforced concrete construction applications, such as highways, floors, or walls of buildings, spacer devices, commonly referred to as chairs, are required for supporting and maintaining reinforcing rods or bars which are positioned in the area where concrete is to be poured. These reinforcing rods are sometimes referred to as &ldquo;rebars&rdquo;. Depending on such parameters, such as the total surface area and the thickness of the end product of concrete, reinforcement is mandated in varying degrees by building codes. One such method of reinforcement involves a steel mesh, while in major concrete construction, such as highways and high-rise buildings, reinforcing rods of various diameters, typically one-half inch or more, are required. In addition, on such jobs, the reinforcing bars may be positioned in spaced layers due to the thickness of the floor. In some installations, a first layer of rebar is provided, with the reinforcing rods or rebars in spaced parallel relationship, and generally parallel to the surface on which the concrete is to be poured. A second layer of rebar is then added, with the orientation of the second layer perpendicular to the first layer, thus forming a grid or lattice work. After the reinforcing bars or lattice work is prepared, the concrete is then poured over this grid or framework, which is ultimately embedded within the highway floor or wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For a concrete floor on a prepared surface, spacers or chairs are utilized for providing the vertical separation of the rebar grid from the surface on which the concrete is to be poured. The prepared surface may be a wood, plywood, or foam structure or a compacted surface, the latter of which my be provided with a layer of compacted sand, with a plastic sheet covering thereon providing a moisture barrier. Spacers or chairs are then positioned on the prepared surface for supporting the rebars in a plane generally parallel to the prepared surface. Typically, with modem building codes, a spacer is needed for every linear foot of the rebar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With rebar spacers or chairs, one common problem is occasioned by the number of different sizes required to be maintained by a supplier to accommodate different thicknesses of poured concrete, such as two-inch, three-inch, four-inch, etc. and many intermediate fractional sizes. Another common problem with rebar spacers has been encountered in the method of securing the rebar to the chair or spacer, with twisted wire being the most common method. This particular problem is more acute when mutually perpendicular layers of rebar are coupled to the same chairs or spacers. With wire connections, a first strip of wire secures the first layer and a second strip of wire secures the perpendicular layer of rebar. With any metal or wire within the reinforcing bar grid work, there is a problem with rusting or decomposing of the wire or metal components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the past, various patents have issued relating to these chair supports for reinforcing rods. In particular, the present inventor is the owner of U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,555,693 and 5,791,095 for such chairs. Each of these chairs has a receiving area with a horizontal section and a generally parabolic section extending transverse to the horizontal section. A plurality of separate legs extends downwardly from the receiving area. Each of the legs has a foot extending horizontally outwardly therefrom. The receiving area and the plurality of legs are integrally formed together of a polymeric material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 3,788,025, issued on Jan. 29, 1974 to S.D. Holmes, describes a chair for supporting in right angular relation two reinforcing rods used in construction. The chair has a lower arched base part and an upper rod supporting part integral with the base. The base is an arched support with means for providing lateral, longitudinal, vertical support and strength. The rod supporting part comprises two spaced apart arms, the lower parts of which form a saddle for receiving one reinforcing rod and the upper part for each of which is formed by two separate spaced upstanding inwardly concave arms, the upper ends of which are spaced to provide an opening through which a second reinforcing rod, arranged at a right angle to the first rod, may be introduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 3,673,753, issued on Jul. 4, 1972 to G. C. Anderson, teaches a concrete reinforcing bar support in which a base supports an upright pedestal. A lower clamping portion is supported by the pedestal which has a first rod-receiving open passageway therethrough. Resilient detents extend from the lower clamping portion to retain a reinforcing rod disposed through the first passageway. An upper clamping portion is provided which includes a pair of hook members extending from the lower clamping portion. Each of the hook members has a mouth opening in the same direction to define a second rod-receiving passageway which is normally disposed to the first passageway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 4,835,933 issued on Jun. 6, 1989 to F. P Yung, describes a spacer assembly which includes a spacer with a body having a base portion with a generally centrally disposed support post portion. One end of the support post portion is formed as a planar surface with a centrally located generally concave saddle portion configured for receiving a reinforcing bar. The planar surface is provided with apertures therethrough on both sides of the saddle. A clamp member is provided for simultaneously securing mutually perpendicular rebars to the chair. The clamp member is a generally U-shaped lower portion, with the depending arms thereof in spaced generally parallel relationship for engaging a first bar within the saddle. A generally identical pair of hook arms extends upwardly from the bight portion. The hook arms are oriented for engaging a second rebar in an orientation perpendicular to the first rebar engaged within the saddle portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,893,892, issued on Apr. 13, 1999 to Hardy, Jr. et al, teaches an apparatus for fixating and elevating an interconnected rebar lattice having individual longitudinal and transverse rebar intersections. The apparatus includes a holding portion having an open-ended recess with two opposing walls being generally U-shaped. The recess has longitudinal access and is sized and shaped to receive a longitudinal rod. An arc-shaped portion extends laterally outwardly from each opposing wall and perpendicular to the longitudinal access of the recess. The arc-shaped portion includes a recess and an opposing wall with each wall including a snap-type lock. A locking member has a generally arc-type portion and includes a snap-type lock for attaching to the arc-type portion and engaging with the snap-type lock of the arc-type portion. A leg portion extends downwardly from the holding portion and is integrally attached to a base. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows one type of prior art concrete reinforcing bar support that is commonly used. Bar support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> extending upwardly from the base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a first clamping member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> affixed to the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and extending upwardly thereabove, a second clamping member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above the top surface of the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and a third clamping member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above the top surface of the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As can be seen, the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has a generally T-shaped cross-section of the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Particularly, the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> includes a panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extending vertically upwardly from the base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a first angled gusset <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extending upwardly on one side of the panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and connected, at a top end thereof, to the second clamping member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Gusset <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is connected centrally to the panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. A pair of gussets <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are formed on the opposite side of the panel <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and extend upwardly so as to connect, at their upper ends, to clamping members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, respectively. The first clamping member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes a detent <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes a detent <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The third clamping member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> includes a detent <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has an interior surface generally facing the interior surfaces of the first and third clamping members. The interior surfaces of the first, second and third clamping members are suitable for receiving a reinforcing bar therebetween. The base <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the support structure <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the first clamping member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the second clamping member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are integrally formed together of a polymeric material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, with this device, each of the clamping members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a configuration which is suitable for receiving only a single diameter of rebar therein. There is no technique whereby the clamping members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can automatically adjust to the various sizes of rebar. Also, when there is a deflection of the rebar, the rebar can easily push through from the clamping members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and past the detents <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. This prior art bar support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has no way of suitably locking the rebar in the area between the clamping members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and for preventing the release of the rebar from therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the prior art bar support <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> also has a generally unstable support structure. Since the support structure is of a generally T-shaped cross-section, the support structure can deflect under the load of a rebar. Additionally, the T-shaped cross-section of the support structure can tip over when certain forces are applied to the top surface of the support structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the present invention to provide a bar support which is corrosion-proof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a bar support that is adaptable to receive various diameters of rebar therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a bar support that can be placed on various flat surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a bar support that can be easily snap-fitted onto and locked around a reinforcing bar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a bar support which allows a free flow of concrete therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> It is a further object of the present invention to provide a bar support with a load-resistant stable support structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> It is a further object of the present invention to provide a reinforcing bar support which is easy to use, easy to manufacture and relatively inexpensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from a reading of the attached specification and appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The present invention is a concrete reinforcing bar support comprising a base, a support structure extending upwardly from the base, a first clamping member affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above the top surface, and a second clamping member affixed to the support structure and extending upwardly above the top surface. Each of the first and second clamping members has an interior surface suitable for receiving a reinforcing bar there-between. The interior surface of the first clamping member faces the interior surface of the second clamping member. The base, the support structure and the first and second clamping members are integrally formed together of a polymeric material. A third clamping member is affixed to the support structure and extends upwardly above the top surface. The third clamping member has an interior surface generally facing the interior surface of the second clamping member. The third clamping member is separated by a space from the first clamping member. The second clamping member is positioned in a plane of the space between the first and third clamping members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Each of the clamping members has a detent formed therein. The detent has an angled surface extending upwardly and outwardly therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Each of the clamping members has a plurality of ribs extending inwardly from the interior surface thereof. Each of the ribs is parallel to and spaced from an adjacent rib. The lower rib of the plurality of ribs extends inwardly from the interior surface a greater distance than that of an upper rib of the plurality of ribs. Each of the plurality of ribs is flexible. Each of the plurality of ribs extends in a horizontal plane. When the reinforcing bar is placed between the clamping members, the plurality of ribs will flex in such a manner so as to secure the rebar in a desired position between the clamping members regardless of the diameter of the rebar. The plurality of ribs lock the rebar in the area between the clamping members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The first clamping member, the second clamping member and the third clamping member have identical configurations. The second clamping member faces in an opposite direction to that of the first and third clamping members. Each of the clamping members are resilient members. The innermost edge of the interior surface of the first clamping member is spaced from an innermost edge of the interior surface of the second clamping member by less than a diameter of the reinforcing bar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, the base is a flat generally rectangular surface. The support structure comprises a first truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from one side of the base, a second truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from another side of the base, and a panel extending vertically upwardly from the base between the first and second truncated pyramidal walls. The panel has a plurality of apertures formed therein so as to allow a free flow of concrete therethrough. The support structure is particularly configured to withstand heavy loads and to resist tipping over.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF SEVERAL VIEW OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a prior art bar support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an upper perspective view of a simplified view form the bar support of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the simplified form of the present invention when receiving a rebar therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an upper perspective view of a preferred embodiment of the bar support in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an end view of the preferred embodiment of the bar support of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic illustration of the manner of receiving rebars of different diameters within the interior surfaces of the clamping members of the bar support of the preferred embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, there is shown at <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> the simplified form of the bar support in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. The simplified form of the bar support <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shows a superior support structure which withstands heavy loads and which is resistive of tipping. Bar support <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extending upwardly from the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> so as to define a top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> opposite to the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the present invention, each of the first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are affixed to the support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and extend upwardly above the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> have respective interior surfaces <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> which generally face the interior surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each of the clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> have identical configurations. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> faces in a different direction than the clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is spaced by a distance from the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> on one side of the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is positioned within a plane of the space between the first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the second clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> on an opposite side of the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, a second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are integrally formed together of a polymeric material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has a generally curved interior surface <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of a size suitable for receiving a side of a reinforcing bar therein. Similarly, the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has its interior surface <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of a suitable curvature for receiving the same side of the reinforcing bar therein. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also has a curved interior surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for compressively engaging an opposite side of a rebar. The reinforcing bar is positioned above the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and within the interior areas of the clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has a detent <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> formed adjacent an upper end thereof. Detent <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has an angled surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extending upwardly and outwardly therefrom. Similarly, the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has a detent <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> formed adjacent an upper end thereof. Another angled surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> extends from detent <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> upwardly and outwardly therefrom. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also has a detent <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> formed thereon with an upwardly and outwardly angled surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extending from the detent <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The upwardly and outwardly angled surfaces <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> serve to &ldquo;funnel&rdquo; the rebar into the interior areas of the respective clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> so that the rebar will reside in a proper position along the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The detents <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are spaced from the detent <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by less than the diameter of the rebar. As such, after the rebar is placed into the interior areas, this close spacing will prevent the rebar from easily sliding outwardly therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is of a generally square or rectangular configuration. The base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a flat bottom surface <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and a generally flat top surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes a first truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> extending upwardly and inwardly from side <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> also includes a second truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> extending upwardly and inwardly from an opposite side <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A panel <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> extends upwardly form the top surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> between the first truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and the second truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The upper ends of the walls <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the panel <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> define the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The tapering and angled relationship of the walls <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provides superior load-resistive characteristics to that of the prior art of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The load-bearing superiority is achieved by virtue of the H-shaped cross-section of the support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the present invention as compared to the T-shaped cross-section of the prior art of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The wide area of the base in combination with the inwardly angled walls <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> keeps the bar support <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from being easily tipped over. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is positioned into the interior areas between the first clamping member <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> will reside on the top surface <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the support structure <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will support the reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> at a desired distance above the underlined surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> has a diameter which is greater than the distance between the detent <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the second clamping member <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the detents <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the respective clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. As such, the resilient clamping members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will compressively contact and retain the reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the preferred embodiment <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The preferred embodiment <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> has a similar configuration of the simplified embodiment <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In particular, the bar support <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, a support structure <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, a top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, a first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, a second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and a third clamping member <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> will face the first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the third clamping member <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> has an interior surface <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> with a plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extending inwardly therefrom. Each of the ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extends in a horizontal plane and is generally in parallel relationship to each other. The second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> also has a plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> extending inwardly from the interior surface <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The third clamping member <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> also has a plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> extending inwardly from the interior surface <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are particularly configured within the concept of the present invention to retain various diameters of rebars therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is a generally flat planar surface positioned on the top of the support structure <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The support structure <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> includes a first truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> extending upwardly from one side of the base <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> extending upwardly from an opposite side of the base <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and a central panel <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> extending upwardly from the top surface of the base <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> between the walls <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. The panel <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> has a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> formed therein for the purpose of weight reduction and also for the purpose of allowing concrete flow therethrough. The panel <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, within the concept of the present invention, will not present a barrier to full concrete flow within the structure and will allow the concrete to flow freely therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Each of the clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> has an exterior support rib <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, respectively. These exterior support ribs <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> add structural integrity to the respective clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Each of the clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> includes a detent of a similar form to that shown in connection with the previous embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, an end view of the bar support <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is particularly illustrated. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the configuration of the first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is particularly illustrated. The bar support <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> includes the base <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> with the truncated pyramidal wall <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> extending upwardly therefrom. The top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is defined by the top of the support structure <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> extends outwardly from the top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in a generally curved configuration. Supporting rib <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> wraps around the exterior of the lower portion of the clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so as to provide structural support therefore. Another exterior support rib <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is formed along the upper exterior of the clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so as to provide support to the upper portion of the clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and to the outwardly angled surface <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> extending from detent <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The second clamping member also has a support rib <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> extending along an exterior surface thereof. Another support rib <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is formed on the upper exterior surface of the second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> adjacent to the upwardly and outwardly angled surface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> extending from detent <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> A plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extend inwardly from the interior surface <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Another plurality of ribs <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> extends inwardly from the interior surface <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the lowermost rib <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> extends inwardly for a greater distance from the interior surface <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> than does the uppermost rib <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. Any intermediate ribs will have inwardly extending length between that of the lowermost rib <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and the uppermost rib <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. The ribs <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> have a similar configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In normal practice, the reinforcing bar will be placed between the upwardly and outwardly angled surfaces <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> so as to deform the clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> outwardly and to enter the area above the top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and between the inner surfaces <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of respective clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. If the rebar has a large diameter, then the ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> will simply and easily push downwardly in generally compressive contact with the exterior surface of the reinforcing bar. On the other hand, if the reinforcing bar is of a relatively small diameter, it will push through the ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> so as to be retained below the ribs against the top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The uppermost ribs will go into generally locking engagement against the exterior surface of the reinforcing bar. As a result, the rebar will not deflect outwardly of the clamping members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates, diagrammatically, how the various diameters of rebar can be secured within the interior area between the clamping members <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Ribs <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the first clamping member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> are urged downwardly and inwardly by the outer diameter of rebar <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. However, the uppermost rib <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> will slightly contact the upper exterior surface of the reinforcing bar <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. The ribs associated with the second clamping member <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> will behave in a similar manner. The arrangement of the respective ribs <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> will create a &ldquo;centering effect&rdquo; causing the rebar to reside properly upon the top surface <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The use of the ribs prevents a misalignment of the bar support relative to the longitudinal axis of the reinforcing bar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Since the bar support of the present invention is integrally formed of a polymeric material, the bar support can be mass produced in a generally inexpensive manner by injection molding processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The foregoing disclosure and description of the invention is illustrative and explanatory thereof. Various changes in the details of the illustrated construction can be made within the scope of the appended claims without departing from the true spirit of the invention. The present invention should only be limited by the following claims and their legal equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A concrete reinforcing bar support comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support structure extending upwardly from said base, said support structure having a top surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said first clamping member having an interior surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said second clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said first clamping member, said interior surface of said first and second clamping members being suitable for receiving a reinforcing bar therebetween, said base and said support structure and said first and second clamping members being integrally formed together of a polymeric material, each of said first and second clamping members having a plurality of ribs extending inwardly from said interior surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a third clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said third clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said second clamping member, said third clamping member being separated by a space from said first clamping member, said third clamping member having a plurality of ribs extending inwardly from said interior surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, said second clamping member positioned in a plane of said space between said first and third clamping members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said first clamping member, second clamping member and said third clamping member having a detent formed thereon, said detent having an angled surface extending upwardly and outwardly therefrom. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said plurality of ribs being parallel to and spaced from an adjacent rib. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, a lower rib of said plurality of ribs extending inwardly from said interior surface a greater distance than a distance that an upper rib of said plurality of ribs extends inwardly form said interior surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said plurality of ribs being flexible. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said plurality of ribs extending in a horizontal plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said first and second clamping members having an identical configuration facing in opposite directions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said first and second clamping members being resilient members, an innermost edge of said interior surface of said first clamping member being spaced from an innermost edge of said interior of said surface of said second clamping member by less than a diameter of the reinforcing bar. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said base being a flat surface, said support structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a first truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from one side of said base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from another side of said base; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel extending upwardly from said base between said first and second truncated pyramidal walls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The bar support of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, said panel having a plurality of holes formed therein so as to allow a free flow of concrete therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a reinforcing bar having a length dimension and a diameter dimension; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support structure extending upwardly from said base, said support structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a first truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from one side of said base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second truncated pyramidal wall extending upwardly and inwardly from another side of said base; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a panel extending upwardly from said base between said first and second truncated pyramidal wall; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said first clamping member having an interior surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said second clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said first clamping member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said third clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said second clamping member, said second clamping member positioned between said first clamping member and said third clamping member along said length dimension of said reinforcing bar, said first and third clamping members resiliently compressively contacting one side of said reinforcing bar, said second clamping member resiliently compressively contacting another side of said reinforcing bar. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, said second clamping member having an identical configuration of each of said first and third clamping members, said second clamping member facing in a direction opposite to that of said first and third clamping members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, said support structure having a generally H-shaped cross-section in a plane parallel to said base. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, said panel having a plurality of holes formed therein so as to allow a free flow of concrete therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, each of said clamping members having a plurality of ribs extending inwardly from the respective interior surfaces thereof, each of said plurality of ribs contacting an exterior surface of said reinforcing bar. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, a lower rib of said plurality of ribs extending inwardly of said interior surface a greater distance than an upper rib of said plurality of ribs extends inwardly from said interior surface, each of said plurality of ribs being flexible. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, said base and said support structure and said clamping members being integrally formed together of a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A concrete reinforcing bar support comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support structure extending upwardly from said base, said support structure having a top surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said first clamping member having an interior surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said second clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said first clamping member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third clamping member affixed to said support structure and extending upwardly above said top surface, said third clamping member having an interior surface generally facing said interior surface of said second clamping member, said third clamping member being separated by a space from said first clamping member, each of said first clamping member and said second clamping member and said third clamping member having a plurality of ribs extending inwardly from the respective interior surfaces thereof, each of said plurality of ribs being parallel to and spaced from an adjacent rib.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000170A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
