<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003696A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003696A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003696A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003696A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003696A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003696A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003696</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896124</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/36</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C30B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>485000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>507000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>935000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for tuning a plurality of processing chambers</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Avgerinos</given-name>
<family-name>Gelatos</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Redwood City</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Joel</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Huston</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lawrence</given-name>
<middle-name>Chung-Lai</middle-name>
<family-name>Lei</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Milipitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Vicky</given-name>
<middle-name>Uyen</middle-name>
<family-name>Nguyen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yin</given-name>
<family-name>Lin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Fong</given-name>
<family-name>Chang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Los Gatos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>APPLIED MATERIALS, INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2881 SCOTT BLVD. M/S 2061</address-1>
<city>SANTA CLARA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95050</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Generally, a substrate processing apparatus is provided. In one aspect of the invention, a substrate processing apparatus is provided. In one embodiment, the substrate processing apparatus includes one or more chamber bodies coupled to a gas distribution system. The chamber bodies define at least a first processing region and a second processing region within the chamber bodies. The gas distribution system includes a first, a second and a third gas supply circuit. The first gas supply circuit is teed between the first and second processing regions and is adapted to supply a first processing gas thereto. The second gas supply circuit is coupled to the first processing region and adapted to supply a second process gas thereto. The third gas supply circuit is coupled to the second processing region and is adapted to supply a third process gas thereto. Alternatively, the processing regions may be disposed in a single chamber body. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the invention relate to a method and apparatus for performing chemical vapor deposition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Background of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Chemical vapor deposition, or CVD, is a well-known and practiced technique for the deposition of material on a substrate such as a semiconductor wafer. A CVD chamber is typically defined by electrically grounded walls and a lid. A pedestal for supporting the substrate is disposed within the chamber. A showerhead is disposed beneath the lid and above the pedestal. Coupled to the chamber is a gas panel and optionally an RF power source. The gas panel is coupled to the showerhead and provides process and other gases to the chamber. The process gases and the substrate are pre-heated to a temperature that facilitates thermal decomposition of the gases and substrate film formation. In plasma enhanced systems, the showerhead is coupled to an RF source. When used, the RF source drives the showerhead, igniting and sustaining a process gas plasma that enhances the deposition process for plasma-enhanced CVD (PECVD). Deposition occurs when the process gas or gases injected into the chamber react to form a layer of material on the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One particular type of CVD processing system comprises a chamber having an internal wall that bifurcates the chamber into two separate processing regions. Generally, the process gases are supplied to the process regions via a single gas panel. This configuration has generally provided robust processing performance and enhanced throughput over conventional CVD chamber designs. Occasionally, under certain process conditions, the substrates processed in each processing region may not yield matching deposition results. As substrate to substrate deposition uniformity is highly desirable, the ability to tune the deposition results between the process regions is highly desirable. Therefore, a need exists in the art for a method and apparatus for tuning a CVD process in twin chamber designs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a substrate processing apparatus is provided which includes one or more chamber bodies coupled to a gas distribution system. The chamber bodies define at least a first processing region and a second processing region therein. The gas distribution system includes a first, a second and a third gas supply circuit. The first gas supply circuit is coupled between the first and second processing regions and is adapted to supply a first processing gas thereto. The second gas supply circuit is coupled to the first processing region and adapted to supply a second process gas thereto. The third gas supply circuit is coupled to the second processing region and is adapted to supply a third process gas thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the substrate processing apparatus includes a chamber body coupled to a gas distribution circuit. The chamber body includes a top, a bottom and sidewalls. At least one interior wall is coupled between the top and bottom and defines at least a first processing region and a second processing region within the chamber body. The gas distribution system includes a first, a second and a third gas supply circuit. The first gas supply circuit is coupled between the first processing region and the second processing region. The first gas supply has a flow controller adapted to selectively supply a first process gas or another process gas to the first and second processing regions. The second gas supply circuit is coupled to the first processing region and has a second flow controller adapted to supply a second process gas to the first processing region at a first rate. The third gas supply circuit is coupled to the second processing region and has a third flow controller adapted to supply a third process gas to the second processing region at a second rate. The first and second rates are independently controlled to tune deposition results between the first and second processing region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the invention, a method for processing a plurality of substrates is provided. In one embodiment, the method includes flowing a first process gas to a first process region and a second process region through a common conduit coupled therebetween, flowing a second process gas to the first process region at a first rate, and flowing a third process gas to the second process region at a second rate, wherein the first rate and the second rate are independently controlled to tune processing results between the first process region and the second process region.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> So that the manner in which the above-recited features, advantages and objects of the present invention are attained can be understood in detail, a more particular description of the invention, briefly summarized above, may be had by reference to the embodiments thereof which are illustrated in the appended drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is to be noted, however, that the appended drawings illustrate only typical embodiments of this invention and are therefore not to be considered limiting of its scope, for the invention may admit to other equally effective embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts a substrate processing system having a gas distribution system coupled to multiple processing regions; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts one embodiment of a gas distribution system.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> To facilitate understanding, identical reference numerals have been used, wherever possible, to designate identical elements that are common to the figures. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts a substrate processing system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that includes a gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> coupled to a chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> having two or more substrate processing regions. Although the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is described as a chemical vapor deposition (CVD) system, the invention has utility with other processing chamber such as physical vapor deposition (PVD) systems, etch systems and other processing systems having multiple processing regions defined within a chamber body. In addition, aspects of the invention have utility with single wafer processing system (as described below) and batch-type processing systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> generally comprises a top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, a bottom <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and sidewalls <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. At least one interior wall <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> is disposed between the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and bottom <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and defines at least a first processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a second processing region <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Although the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are depicted as integral to a single chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (and other processing regions) may alternatively be disposed in a plurality of individual chambers or a single chamber with dividing walls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Each processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> generally includes a pedestal <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> disposed therein which is typically coupled to the chamber bottom <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> or the sidewalls <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The pedestal <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> generally supports a substrate <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> during processing. The pedestal <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may retain the substrate by a variety of methods including the use of an electrostatic chuck, vacuum clamps, mechanical clamps, gravity or other holding methods generally used to retain a substrate during processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Exhaust ports <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> typically couple the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to a vacuum pump <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Typically, the exhaust ports <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> are disposed in the bottom <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, but may be located in other portions of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A throttle valve (not shown) is generally disposed between the pump <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and each exhaust port <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> and is utilized to regulate pressure in the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Optionally, each exhaust port <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> may be coupled to a dedicated pump. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is generally coupled to the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> above the pedestal <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> generally includes a plurality of holes formed in a center portion of the showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that uniformly distribute process and other gases to the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Gas boxes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B are generally disposed in the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and fluidly couple each processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, respectively, to the gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The gas boxes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B generally mix the process and/or other gases delivered from the gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and injects the mixed (or partially mixed) gases into an area defined between the showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The mixed gases then flow through the showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> into the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. A gas box that may be adapted to benefit from the invention is described in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/609,994, filed Jul. 5, 2000 by Shmurun et al., which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A cleaning plasma generator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> may also be coupled to the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> through the gas boxes <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B. In one embodiment, the cleaning plasma generator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> provides a cleaning agent such as atomic fluorine which removes unwanted deposition and other contaminants from the chamber components. One such generator is available from Azte Corporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Optionally, a RF power source <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be coupled to the showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The RF power source <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> drives the showerhead <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, igniting and sustaining a plasma of the mixed process gas(es) and/or other gases within the respective processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Plasma enhanced processing enables processing within the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to operate at lower temperatures, provides additional process flexibility and provides a capability for the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to be used for varied types of deposition processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> generally includes at least a first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, a second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and a third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. The first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> generally couples one or more gas sources to a main supply line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> providing at least a first process gas. The main supply line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is coupled by a tee <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to a first chamber branch line <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and a second chamber branch line <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The first chamber branch line <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> is fluidly coupled to the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A while the second chamber branch line <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is fluidly coupled to the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B. The branch lines <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> may be at least partially routed through the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> or walls <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to thermally condition the gases before mixing and delivery into the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is generally coupled to the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A and provides a second process gas thereto. The third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is generally coupled to the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B and provides a third process gas thereto. Typically, although not limited thereto, the second and third process gases are the same whether from independent or common sources. As with the branch lines <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, at least a portion of the circuits <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> may be at least partially routed through the top <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> or walls <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the chamber body <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to thermally condition the gases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a flow diagram of one embodiment of the gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> generally couples at least a first process gas to the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> via the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, and couples other process gases to the process regions via gas supply circuits coupled between a single gas source and each processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> on individual circuits, i.e., the second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and the third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> depicted in the illustrated gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Other circuits may be utilized in systems having additional chambers and/or process gases. Additionally, as the individual circuits allow independent flow control to the individual processing regions, the individual circuit may share one or more gas sources as long as individual flow control is provided by each circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The gas distribution system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> generally supplies a first process gas regulated by a first control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> from a first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>, a second process gas regulated by a second control system <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> from a second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a third process gas regulated by a third control system <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> from a third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, and an optional fourth process gas regulated by a fourth control system <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> from a fourth process gas source <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. The first process gas is generally supplied to the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> with a first carrier gas. The first carrier gas is supplied from a first carrier gas source <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> and regulated by a fifth control system <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. The second process gas is generally supplied to the processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with a second carrier gas. The second carrier gas is supplied from a second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and regulated by a sixth control system <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The third process gas is generally supplied to the processing region <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> with a third carrier gas. The third carrier gas is supplied from a third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and regulated by a seventh control system <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. The optional fourth process gas is generally supplied to the processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with a fourth carrier gas. The fourth carrier gas is supplied from an fourth gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and regulated by an eighth control system <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A and the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B. The main delivery line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> generally is coupled to the first process gas source <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. The first process gas source <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> may be configured to supply any number of process gases dependent upon the desired process to be performed within the processing region. In one embodiment, the first process gas is titanium tetrachloride (TiCl<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The first flow control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> is fluidly coupled to the main delivery line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to control the flow and flow rate and of the first process gas from the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the first flow control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> generally includes a first flow control system valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>, an injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>, a first flow control system controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>, and a first flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> is generally a shut-off valve of the type typically utilized in cryogenic applications and disposed in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> between the tee <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> is generally interlocked with other valves of the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such that inadvertent flow from the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight> may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> is coupled between the first flow control system valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> and the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. The injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> generally allows a first carrier gas to be combined with the first process gas prior to the first valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>. One injector valve which may be utilized is available from HoribaSTEC Corporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The first flow control system controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> generally controls the flow rate of the first process gas through the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and is coupled between the injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. The first flow controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> may be an orifice, mass flow controller, needle valve, proportional valve or other flow regulating device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The first flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> regulates the pressure of the first process gas exiting the first gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. The regulator <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> is typically coupled between the controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> and the first process gas source <highlight><bold>288</bold></highlight>. Such regulators are generally available from Veriflo Corporation, located in Richmond, Calif. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Generally, the first process gas is introduced into the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> with a carrier gas. In the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> first carrier gas, such as helium, flowing from the first carrier gas source <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> is coupled to the first flow control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> at the injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. Generally, the flow and flow rate of the first carrier gas is regulated by the fifth flow control system <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The fifth flow control system <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> typically comprises a fifth flow control system controller <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight>, a fifth flow control system filter <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> and a fifth flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and the filter <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. The fifth flow control system filter <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> is generally a sub-micron filter utilized to minimize particulates entrained in the first process gas and is coupled between the controller <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> and the regulator <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. Such filters are generally available from Pall Corporation, East Hills, N.Y. The fifth system regulator <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the filter <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> and the first carrier gas source <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>278</bold></highlight> and regulator <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the controller and regulator of the first flow control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight> is selectively coupled to the first flow control circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> at a tee <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> which directs a purge gas to a tee <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight> disposed between the valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> and the tee <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> or to a tee <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> disposed in the first control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> between the controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> and the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>. A plurality of purge shut-off valves <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> control the distribution of the purge gas (typically nitrogen) provided by the purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight>. Generally, the purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight> is selectively coupled to the main delivery line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> by the purge shut-off valve <highlight><bold>249</bold></highlight> disposed between the tee <highlight><bold>293</bold></highlight> and tee <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight>. The purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight> is selectively coupled to the first control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> by the purge shut-off valve <highlight><bold>292</bold></highlight> disposed between the tee <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> and tee <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight>. The purge shut-off valve <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> isolates purge gas within the first control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> from the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Generally, the flow of the purge gas is controlled by a purge gas regulator <highlight><bold>247</bold></highlight> disposed between the purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight> and the tee <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight>. A check valve <highlight><bold>296</bold></highlight> disposed between the tee <highlight><bold>294</bold></highlight> and the purge gas regulator <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight> generally prevents flow towards the purge gas source <highlight><bold>298</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The first carrier gas combined with the first process gas at the injector valve <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> and is then introduced into the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, an optional fourth process gas, for example, chlorine utilized for chamber cleaning, may alternatively be provided at a tee <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> disposed in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> between the tees <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight>. Generally, the flow and flow rate of the fourth process gas is regulated by the fourth flow control system <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The fourth flow control system <highlight><bold>209</bold></highlight> generally includes a fourth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>, a fourth flow control system controller <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>, a fourth flow control system filter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, a fourth flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and a fourth flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>239</bold></highlight>. Generally, the valve <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> is coupled between the tee <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> and the controller <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is coupled between the controller <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> and the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight>. The regulator <highlight><bold>239</bold></highlight> is coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and the fourth gas supply <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The fourth flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> generally provides a controller (not shown) coupled to the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with pressure information utilized to control the flow of the fourth process gas. Such sensors are generally available from MKS Instruments, located in Andover, Mass. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The fourth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>, controller <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> and regulator <highlight><bold>239</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the valve, controller and regulator of the first flow control system <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is generally similar to the filter <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The fourth process gas is generally delivered to the process regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> in the presence of a fourth carrier gas such as nitrogen. The flow of the fourth carrier gas is generally controlled by the eighth flow control system <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> which is coupled to the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> at a tee <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> disposed between the valve <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and the tee <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The eighth flow control system <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> generally includes an eighth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, an eighth flow control system controller <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>, an eighth flow control system filter <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, an eighth flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and an eighth flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is generally a shut-off valve similar to the valve <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> and is disposed in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> between the tee <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> and the fourth carrier gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is generally interlocked with other valves of the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such that inadvertent flow from the fourth carrier gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The controller <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> generally controls the flow rate from the fourth carrier gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and is coupled between the valve <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> and the filter <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. The flow controller <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is generally similar to the flow controller <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> is generally a sub-micron filter similar to the filter <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> is coupled between the flow controller <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> and the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The pressure sensor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> generally provides a controller (not shown) coupled to the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with pressure information utilized to control the flow of the fourth carrier gas. The pressure sensor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is typically coupled between the filter <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and the regulator <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The regulator <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> regulates the pressure of the fourth carrier gas exiting the fourth carrier gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. The fifth regulator <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> is typically coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and the fourth carrier gas source <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> provides the second process gas from the second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A. A second control system <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> is coupled between the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A and the second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to control the flow of the second process gas. The second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may be configured to supply any number of process gases dependent upon the desired process to be performed within the processing region. In one embodiment, the second process gas is ammonia (NH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the second flow control system <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> generally includes a second flow control system valve <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, a second flow control system controller <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, a second flow control system filter <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a second flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and a second flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. Generally, the valve <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is similar to the valve <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight> and is coupled between the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A and the second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is coupled between the valve <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the filter <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>. The pressure sensor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the filter <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and the second process gas source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The second flow control system controller <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, filter <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, pressure sensor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> and pressure regulator <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the controller, filter, pressure sensor and pressure regulators utilized in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Generally, the second process gas is introduced into the processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with a carrier gas. In the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> second carrier gas flowing from the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is coupled to the second flow control system <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> at a tee <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Generally, the flow and flow rate of the second carrier gas is regulated by a sixth flow control system <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The sixth flow control system <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> typically comprises a sixth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, a sixth flow control system controller <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, a sixth flow control system filter <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, a sixth flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and a sixth flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is disposed in the third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> between the tee <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The sixth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is generally interlocked with other valves of the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such that inadvertent flow from the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The sixth flow control system controller <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> controls the flow rate from the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and is coupled between the valve <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> is coupled between the controller <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the second carrier gas source <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The sixth flow control system valve <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, the controller <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, the filter <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the regulator <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the controller, filter, pressure sensor and pressure regulators utilized in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> provides the third process gas from the third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B. The third control system <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is coupled between the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B and the third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to control the flow of the third process gas. The third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> may be configured to supply any number of process gases dependent upon the desired process to be performed within the processing region. In one embodiment, the third process gas is ammonia (NH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the third flow control system <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> generally includes a third flow control system valve <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, a third flow control system controller <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, a third flow control system filter <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, a third flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and a third flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. Generally, the valve <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> is coupled between the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B and the third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. The controller <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> is coupled between the valve <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> and the filter <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. The pressure sensor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is coupled between the regulator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> and the filter <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>. The regulator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and the third process gas source <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. The third flow control system valve <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, controller <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, filter <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight>, pressure sensor <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and pressure regulator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the valve, controller, filter, pressure sensor and pressure regulators utilized in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Generally, the third process gas is introduced into the processing region <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> with a carrier gas. In the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> third carrier gas flowing from the third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> is coupled to the third flow control system <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> at a tee <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. Generally, the flow and flow rate of the third carrier gas is regulated by a seventh flow control system <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The seventh flow control system <highlight><bold>207</bold></highlight> typically comprises a seventh flow control system valve <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, a seventh flow control system controller <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>, a seventh flow control system filter <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, a seventh flow control system pressure sensor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and a seventh flow control system regulator <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> is disposed in the third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> between the tee <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and the third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>. The valve <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> is generally interlocked with other valves of the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> such that inadvertent flow from the third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The seventh flow control system controller <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> generally controls the flow rate from the third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> and is coupled between the valve <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> and flow controller <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> is coupled between the controller <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight> is generally coupled between the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and the third carrier gas source <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>. The seventh flow control system valve <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, the controller <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>, the filter <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight>, the pressure sensor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and the regulator <highlight><bold>237</bold></highlight> are generally similar to the controller, filter, pressure sensor and pressure regulators utilized in the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, in one mode of operation, the first gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> provides about 5 to about 120 sccm of the first process gas (e.g., titanium tetrachloride) through the main supply line <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> which is split at the tee <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to each gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B of the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> provides about 50 to about 500 sccm of the second process gas (e.g., ammonia) to the first gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>A of the processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Simultaneously, the third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> provides about 50 to about 500 sccm of the second process gas (e.g., ammonia) to the second gas box <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>B of the processing region <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The process gases combine and thermally decompose to deposit titanium nitride on the substrate&apos;s surface. Depending on the relative deposition results between the processing regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, at least one of the flow rates of the gases flowing the second gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and the third gas supply circuit <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may be adjusted to tune the results so that the substrates processed within the regions <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> yield substantially identical results. As such, the flows of the second and third process gases may be identical or different depending upon the process characteristics of each processing region <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the flow circuits coupled thereto. One skilled in the art will recognize that the tuning of multiple process regions may be practiced utilizing deferent deposition or etch processes, different process gases, common gas sources, different processing region configurations and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> While the foregoing is directed to the preferred embodiment of the present invention, other and further embodiments of the invention may be devised without departing from the basic scope thereof. The scope of the invention is determined by the claims which follow. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A substrate processing apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>one or more chamber bodies defining at least a first processing region and a second processing region therein; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas distribution system coupled to the processing regions, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first gas supply circuit coupled between the first processing region and the second processing region and adapted to supply a first process gas thereto; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gas supply circuit coupled to first processing region and adapted to supply a second process gas thereto; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third gas supply circuit coupled to second processing region and adapted to supply a third process gas thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second process gas and the third process gas comprises identical process gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a flow rate of the second process gas is independently controllable relative to the third process gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a flow rate of the second process gas is substantially equal to the third process gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a flow rate of the second process gas is regulated relative to a flow rate of the third process gas to tune deposition results in the first and second processing regions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gas circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first chamber branch coupled to the first processing region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second chamber branch circuit coupled to the second processing region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tee connecting the first chamber branch and the second chamber branch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow control system coupled to the tee. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow control system further comprises: 
<claim-text>a regulator coupled to a first process gas source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow controller coupled to the regulator. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow control system further comprises: 
<claim-text>a pressure transducer adapted to sense pressure between the regulator and the flow controller; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed between the regulator and the flow controller. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gas circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first shut off valve disposed between the first processing region and the flow control system; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure sensor disposed between the first shut off valve and the first processing region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow controller further comprises: 
<claim-text>an orifice, a mass flow controller, a needle valve or a proportional valve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gas supply circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first process gas delivery branch having the first process gas source fluidly coupled a first carrier gas source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gas delivery branch having a fourth process gas source fluidly coupled a second carrier gas source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a least one valve coupled to the first gas delivery branch and/or second gas delivery branch for selectively coupling either the first process gas source or the second process gas source to the first and second processing regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas comprises titanium tetrachloride and the fourth process gas comprises chlorine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas comprises titanium tetrachloride and/or chlorine, the second process gas comprises ammonia and the third process gas source comprises ammonia. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the one or more chamber bodies comprise a single chamber body having a top, bottom and sidewalls, at least one interior wall is coupled between the top and bottom, the interior wall separating the first processing from the second processing region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A substrate processing apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a chamber body having a top, bottom and sidewalls, at least one interior wall coupled between the top and bottom and defining at least a first processing region and a second processing region within the chamber body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas distribution system coupled to the chamber body, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first gas supply circuit coupled between the first processing region and the second processing region, the first gas supply circuit having at least a first flow controller adapted to selectively supply a first process gas and a fourth process gas to the first and second processing region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gas supply circuit coupled to first processing region and having a second flow controller adapted to supply a second process gas to the first processing region at a first rate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third gas supply circuit coupled to second processing region and having a third flow controller adapted to supply a third process gas to the second processing region at a second rate controlled independently from the first rate to tune deposition results between the first and the second processing region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second process gas and the third process gas comprises identical process gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gas circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first branch circuit coupled to the first processing region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second branch circuit coupled to the second processing region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tee connecting the first branch circuit and the second branch circuit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flow control system having the flow controller disposed therein fluidly coupled to the tee. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow control system further comprises: 
<claim-text>a regulator coupled between a first process gas source and the first flow controller; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure transducer adapted to sense pressure between the regulator and the first flow controller; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed between the regulator and the first flow controller. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the flow controller further comprises: 
<claim-text>an orifice, a mass flow controller, a needle valve or a proportional valve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gas supply circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a first process gas delivery branch having the first process gas source fluidly coupled a first carrier gas source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gas delivery branch having a fourth process gas source fluidly coupled a second carrier gas source; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a least one valve coupled to the first gas delivery branch and/or second gas delivery branch for selectively coupling either the first process gas source or the second process gas source to the first and second processing regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas comprises titanium tetrachloride and the fourth process gas comprises chlorine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas comprises titanium tetrachloride and/or chlorine, the second process gas comprises ammonia and the third process gas source comprises ammonia. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second flow rates are equal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A substrate processing apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a chamber body having a top, bottom and sidewalls, at least one interior wall coupled between the top and bottom and defining at least a first processing region and a second processing region within the chamber body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas distribution system coupled to the chamber body, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first gas supply circuit having a tee fluidly coupling the first processing region and the second processing region, a main delivery line having a first process gas delivery branch and a second gas delivery branch selectively coupled to the tee, the first gas delivery branch having a first process gas source and the second gas delivery branch having a second process gas source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gas supply circuit coupled to the first processing region and having a first flow controller adapted to supply a third process gas to the first processing region at a first rate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third gas supply circuit coupled to the second processing region and having a second flow controller adapted to supply a fourth process gas comprising the identical process gas as the third process gas to the second processing region at a second rate controlled independently from the first rate to tune deposition results between the first and second processing regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second gas supply circuit further comprises: 
<claim-text>a regulator coupled between a third process gas source and the first flow controller; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure transducer adapted to sense pressure between the regulator and the first flow controller; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed between the regulator and the third flow controller; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the third gas supply circuit further comprises. 
<claim-text>a regulator coupled between a fourth process gas source and the second flow controller; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure transducer adapted to sense pressure between the regulator and the second flow controller; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter disposed between the regulator and the second flow controller. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second flow controller further comprises: 
<claim-text>an orifice, a mass flow controller, a needle valve or a proportional valve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas comprises titanium tetrachloride, the second process gas comprises chlorine, the third process gas comprises ammonia and the fourth process gas source comprises ammonia. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A method for processing a plurality of substrates, comprising: 
<claim-text>flowing a first process gas to a first process region and a second process region through a common conduit coupled therebetween; </claim-text>
<claim-text>flowing a second process gas to the first process region at a first rate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>flowing a third process gas to the second process region at a second rate, wherein the first rate and the second rate are independently controlled to tune processing results between the first process region and the second process region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A method for processing a plurality of substrates, comprising: 
<claim-text>flowing a first process gas to a first chemical vapor deposition region and a second chemical vapor deposition region through a common conduit coupled therebetween; </claim-text>
<claim-text>flowing a second process gas to the first chemical vapor deposition region at a first rate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>flowing a third process gas that is the same as the second process gas to the second chemical vapor deposition region at a second rate, wherein the first rate and the second rate are independently controlled to tune deposition results between the first process region and the second process region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second rate is different than the first rate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising forming a plasma in the first chemical vapor deposition region from a mixture of the first process gas and the second process gas. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first process gas is TiCl<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>, and the second and third process gases are NH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003696A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003696A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003696A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
