<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002551A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002551A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002551</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896603</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01S003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>372</class>
<subclass>038020</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Laser diode driver</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Youngwoo</given-name>
<family-name>Kwon</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chino Hills</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jinho</given-name>
<family-name>Jeong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>BROADBAND TRANSPORT TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KOPPEL &amp; JACOBS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 107</address-1>
<address-2>555 St. Charles Drive</address-2>
<city>Thousand Oaks</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>91360</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A laser diode driver circuit uses transconductance amplifying devices, preferably FETs, in a balanced input configuration. First and second amplifying devices are arranged to receive respective inverting and non-inverting input signals on their respective control terminals (gates). The amplifying devices are arranged to drive a laser diode connected between the current output terminals (source terminals) of said first and second amplifying devices. In one embodiment, a first node connects a source terminal of a first amplifier FET, a first terminal of the laser diode, and a drain terminal of a biasing FET. In another embodiment, in addition to the circuitry of the first embodiment a second node connects the second amplifier FET, a drain of a second biasing FET, and a second terminal of the laser diode. Preferably, the first and (optionally) the second biasing FETs bias the circuit&apos;s outputs with an offset, relative to one another, of substantially the turn-on threshold of the laser diode. The invention provides fast transitions with low power consumption. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to electro-optics and optical communications generally and more specifically to electronic driver circuits for modulated laser diodes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Fiber optic communication systems such as the &ldquo;Synchronous Optical Network&rdquo; (SONET) commonly employ electro-optic transponders which translate signals from electrical to optical (and vice-versa). A typical fiber optic communication system might include a fiber transmission medium with multiple nodes at each of which a transponder launches and receives optical data and provides a data interface to electronic systems. To provide the appropriate optical/electronic data interface, transponders commonly include both an optical transmitter and an optical receiver in the same package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Currently, the semiconductor laser diode is the most prevalent device used in transponders in the transmitter section to directly convert electronic signals into pulses of light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A suitable electronic driver circuit is required to modulate or switch a laser diode in a transponder circuit. Such a laser diode driver should preferably have fast rise and fall times and low power dissipation. In addition, the driver should provide clean switching of the laser diode: no distortion or spurious content should be introduced into the optical signal (for example, from power supply line fluctuation). Furthermore, a laser diode driver circuit should preferably be relatively simple, economical, and operable from readily available power supply levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A typical prior laser-diode driver circuit is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. A differential pair of transistors Q<highlight><subscript>diff1 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>diff2 </subscript></highlight>is driven by a differential drive input (<highlight><subscript>&plus;</subscript></highlight>Vin and &minus;Vin). The differential pair is biased by a current source I<highlight><subscript>source </subscript></highlight>in the common &ldquo;tail&rdquo; of the emitter circuit, in the well known differential amplifier configuration. Typically the current source includes at least two transistors in a &ldquo;current mirror&rdquo; or similar configuration. The laser diode is connected in the collector circuit of one of the transistors (Q<highlight><subscript>diff2 </subscript></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Typically such driver circuits are supplied in an open collector configuration, so that the laser diode LD is required to be connected via a pin out <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as shown. Optionally, a current limiting resistor R<highlight><subscript>limit </subscript></highlight>can be interposed between the supply voltage VCC and the laser diode LD. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Although the prior circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is adequate for many applications, it consumes power at an undesirably high rate, in part because of the large number of transistors (including multiple transistors included in the tail current source) . The typical driver circuit can be viewed as a switched current source with fairly high output impedance. Since laser diode impedance levels are relatively low (less than 10 ohms, typically), a high mismatch between the driver and load impedance levels exists. In order to reduce ringing and waveform distortion problems associated with the mismatch, a matching resistor is placed off-chip in series with the laser diode to provide a better matched load to the driver. The matched load, of course, comes at the price of useless dissipation of power. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In view of the above problems, the present invention is a simple, economical laser diode driver circuit which provides fast switching times while maintaining a clean optical output, notwithstanding substantial power supply fluctuations. A key improvement provided by the present invention is the ability to drive low impedance loads directly without the need for external matching resistors which can greatly increase the power dissipation in transponder systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The circuit of the invention includes an amplifier having inverting and non-inverting inputs and inverted and non-inverted outputs arranged to drive a laser diode connected between the inverted and the non-inverted outputs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The driver circuit uses transconductance amplifying devices, preferably FETs, in a balanced input configuration. First and second amplifying devices are arranged to receive respective inverting and non-inverting input signals on their respective control terminals (gates). The amplifying devices are arranged to drive a laser diode connected between the current output terminals (source terminals) of said first and second amplifying devices. In one embodiment, a first node connects a source terminal of a first amplifier FET, a first terminal of the laser diode, and a drain terminal of a biasing FET. In another embodiment, in addition to the circuitry of the first embodiment a second node connects the second amplifier FET, a drain of a second biasing FET, and a second terminal of the laser diode. Preferably, the first and (optionally) the second biasing FETs bias the circuit&apos;s outputs with an offset, relative to one another, of substantially the turn-on threshold of the laser diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> These and other features and advantages of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description of preferred embodiments, taken together with the accompanying drawings, in which:</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a prior art laser diode driver circuit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block level schematic of a laser diode circuit in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a component level schematic diagram of one embodiment in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a graph of voltage versus time, showing typical voltage inputs Vin<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and Vin<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, representative of a balanced 5 Gigahertz square wave input; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows the time variation of the current through the laser diode of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, in response to the input shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, for a variety of supply voltages; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>shows the response of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> when excited by the input of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, under the condition of an induced supply voltage (V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&prime;) fluctuation of 0.2 V. (peak-to-peak); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>shows the corresponding response of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> under the condition of an increased supply voltage (V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&prime;) fluctuation of 0.4 V. (peak-to-peak); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>shows the superimposition of the waveforms of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, to allow convenient comparison; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a graph of the frequency response of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with amplitude graphed on a linear scale and frequency on a logarithmic scale; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an alternate embodiment of a driver circuit in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a multistage laser diode driver circuit which incorporates an output stage in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is an accumulated response &ldquo;eye diagram&rdquo; which graphs output current (in amperes) as a function of time (in picoseconds) for the simulated circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> when driven by a pseudorandom binary excitation at a 10 Gigabit per second rate, where 0.2 nanohenries of bond lead inductance have been assumed associated with the each bond lead of the laser diode; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. is another &ldquo;eye diagram&rdquo; obtained under circumstances analogous to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, with the single difference that no bond lead inductance has been assumed.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the laser diode driver amplifier <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has inverting and non-inverting inputs (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) and inverted and non-inverted outputs (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>), arranged to receive a laser diode LD connected between the differential outputs <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The amplifier <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is preferably biased to create an offset voltage between the output branches, to set the operating point of the laser diode LD at a predetermined voltage: for example, it can be maintained at the turn on threshold (for switching applications) or it could alternatively be biased slightly on, in a more linear part of the laser diode&apos;s response curve (for applications which demand more linear response). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The economical circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> embodies a laser diode driver in accordance with the invention. Differential input signals V<highlight><subscript>in1 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>in2 </subscript></highlight>are coupled to respective gates of FETs Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, which are arranged in two parallel branches. Bias FET Q<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>provides a bias current which is shared (unequally) by the FETs Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. The driven laser diode LD is connected between the branches: i.e., with its anode connected to the source of Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>(a first output terminal <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) and its cathode connected to the source of Q<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(a second output terminal <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) as shown. Thus, the circuit in its simple form includes a differential source follower amplifier, having inverting and non-inverting inputs, inverted and non-inverted outputs (<highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>), and a load (laser diode) connected between the inverted and non-inverted outputs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Bias to FETs Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is set by the gate bias voltages of each FET as well as the bias voltage V<highlight><subscript>gg1 </subscript></highlight>applied to the gate of Q<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. Preferably, the bias point is set so that the laser diode is &ldquo;half-biased&rdquo; near its turn-on threshold&mdash;for example, at approximately 1 volt (forward bias) with no input signals applied to V<highlight><subscript>in1 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>in2 </subscript></highlight>. This allows the circuit to drive the laser diode with a small input signal and achieve high efficiency and fast switching times. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The circuit operates as follows. When V<highlight><subscript>in</subscript></highlight>&equals;V<highlight><subscript>in1</subscript></highlight>&minus;V<highlight><subscript>in2 </subscript></highlight>is high, the diode is switched on and current flows through Q<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, LD and Q<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. When V<highlight><subscript>in </subscript></highlight>is reduced (near zero or negative voltage), the current through Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>is switched off and instead diverted to the right hand branch of the circuit through Q<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The inductances L<highlight><subscript>ss1 </subscript></highlight>and L<highlight><subscript>ss2 </subscript></highlight>represent stray inductance associated with the laser diode LD and its circuit pathways. It is advantageous to provide a compensating circuit, preferably a series Resistor-Capacitor circuit to cancel the effects of the stray inductances at the anticipated frequency of operation. Typically (but not necessarily) the laser diode LD will not be integrated on the same chip with the driver circuit, but will instead be separately packaged. In such an arrangement, it has been found that the stray inductances L<highlight><subscript>ss1 </subscript></highlight>and L<highlight><subscript>ss2 </subscript></highlight>are typically on the order of <highlight><subscript>0.2 </subscript></highlight>nanohenries. The compensating resistance and capacitance should be chosen to compensate appropriately. For example, for operation at <highlight><subscript>10 </subscript></highlight>Ghz, the compensating resistance and capacitances (R<highlight><subscript>c1</subscript></highlight>, R<highlight><subscript>c2</subscript></highlight>, C<highlight><subscript>C1 </subscript></highlight>and C<highlight><subscript>c2</subscript></highlight>) can be chosen suitably to introduce a 3 decibel attenuation frequency is placed at approximately 11.5 Gigahertz, to reduce ringing. In practice, values of <highlight><subscript>&mdash;</subscript></highlight>5 ohms and 1 picofarad for each resistance R and capacitance have been found to produce desirably clean switching waveforms at a switching frequency of 10 Ghz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The network of R<highlight><subscript>s1</subscript></highlight>, R<highlight><subscript>s2</subscript></highlight>, L<highlight><subscript>s1 </subscript></highlight>L<highlight><subscript>s2 </subscript></highlight>and C<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>has been introduced to simulate characteristics of a real, imperfect voltage source. For simulation purposes, a square wave fluctuation V<highlight><subscript>fluc7 </subscript></highlight>has also been added, representing a small square wave fluctuation on top of a DC voltage supply. The supply fluctuations V<highlight><subscript>fluc7 </subscript></highlight>typically arise due to coupling with other circuits on or nearby the chip with the circuit in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. There may also be independent fluctuations in the supply voltage itself in a typical application. For purposes of simulation (the results of which are discussed below in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>) the following values were assumed: R<highlight><subscript>s1</subscript></highlight>&equals;0.5 Ohm, R<highlight><subscript>s2</subscript></highlight>&equals;2.0 Ohm, L<highlight><subscript>s1&equals;0.2 </subscript></highlight>nH, L<highlight><subscript>s2</subscript></highlight>&equals;10 nH, and C<highlight><subscript>s1</subscript></highlight>&equals;20 nF. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows typical drive input pulses as might be applied to V<highlight><subscript>in1 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>in2</subscript></highlight>. V<highlight><subscript>in1 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>in2 </subscript></highlight>preferably have a DC offset of approximately 0.9 V DC for the off state (of the laser diode). The output current I<highlight><subscript>LD </subscript></highlight>through the laser diode is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, for several values of supply voltage V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>. Curve <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> represents the response with V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&equals;3.5 V, curve <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> the response for V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&equals;3.0 V, curve <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> for V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&equals;2.5 V, and curve <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> represents the response for V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&equals;2.0 V. For purposes of this analysis, inherent supply inductance L<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>and supply resistance R<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>are assumed to be 10,000 nanohenrys and 0.001 Ohm, respectively. These values were chosen to represent realistic assumptions, but actual power supplies will have varying characteristics which will affect performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> provides excellent rejection of supply voltage fluctuations. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>shows a typical case in which voltage V<highlight><subscript>dd</subscript></highlight>&prime; fluctuates by 0.2 V peak-to-peak from a typical average value. Nevertheless, the voltage across the laser diode LD is not greatly affected by the V<highlight><subscript>dd </subscript></highlight>fluctuation. Waveforms for the respective voltages v<highlight><subscript>d1 </subscript></highlight>and v<highlight><subscript>d2 </subscript></highlight>at the anode and cathode of the laser diode LD are shown. The voltage across the laser diode LD follows the input waveform, without significant effect from the supply fluctuation, as demonstrated by the figure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>shows the corresponding response for an increased (induced) power supply voltage fluctuation of 0.4 V. peak-to-peak. Voltages Vd1 and Vd2 show little deviation from the previous figure. The insensitivity to supply fluctuation is further emphasized by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, which simply superimposed the two previous figures. No difference in the responses Vd1 and Vd2 is visible (the waveforms superimpose completely). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In a typical application, laser diode current swings in the range of 80-100 milliamps are obtained without appreciable sensitivity to supply voltage fluctuations, even at very fast switching speeds (up to 10 Ghz). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The frequency response of a driver circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Flat frequency response is displayed from 100 KHz to 10 GHz, with less than 3 db reduction in response even at frequencies as high as 100 GHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The circuit of the invention can most suitably be fabricated with Psuedomorphic High Electron Mobility Transistors (PHEMT) for all the FETs. GaAs is a suitable material for the PHEMTs, and provides fast switching with low supply voltages, thus keeping power consumption low. Low power consumption is also facilitated by the reduced number of transistors as compared to prior art circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> An alternate embodiment of the invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The alternate embodiment includes the same essential circuit as the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, with an additional FET Q<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>connected between the source of Q1 and ground. The additional FET Q<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>sinks some current from the source of Q<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, in an amount which is determined by the bias voltage (V<highlight><subscript>gg2</subscript></highlight>). This additional FET provides more flexibility in setting the bias point of the laser diode LD, but at the expense of some additional power consumption. Thus, the alternate embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> would be most appropriate in an application in which the laser diode must be biased at a precisely determined turn-on voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> It is desirable in either of the above described embodiments that the current bias be provided by a simple single transistor (in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) or dual transistor (in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). More complex current source bias circuits such as a current mirror should preferably be avoided in order to reduce power consumption and heat generation by the driver circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a multistage laser diode driver circuit which incorporates a driver circuit in accordance with one embodiment of the invention (the embodiment discussed above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> could also be modified to use a driver in accordance with the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The circuit is well adapted for driving a laser diode LD at frequencies in the neighborhood of 10 Gigahertz from a supply voltage Vdd of 3.3 Volts. Balanced inputs IN&plus; and IN&minus; are amplified by differential amplifier stage <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, level shifted by level shifting stage <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and further amplified by a second differential amplifier stage <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The amplified and level shifted signal is coupled to a load bias control circuit <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, which offsets the &plus; and &minus; drive signals with respect to one another. The offset is adjustable by the voltages at V<highlight><subscript>bias1 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>bias2</subscript></highlight>, and is preferably set to produce driver output at or near the turn on threshold for the laser diode LD, for zero input signal. The driver stage <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is essentially the circuit discussed above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Note that the stray inductance L<highlight><subscript>bond </subscript></highlight>is the inductance associated with bond and other wire pathways connecting the (typically external) laser diode LD. The components shown in block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are typically external to (not monolithically fabricated with) the driver circuit (<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Typical simulated time domain output responses of the circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(&ldquo;eye diagrams&rdquo;) . The outputs show overlaid responses of the circuit when driven by a pseudorandom binary excitation at a 10 Gigabit per second rate. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>assumes that the bond inductance in the laser diode branch (external laser diode) is equivalent to two inductors (in series), each with a value of 0.2 nanohenries. Output current in amperes is shown by curves <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> (phase shifted by one half period). Both rising and falling waveforms are shown superimposed in order to illustrate and emphasize the symmetry of the response. Excellent balance, low overshoot and fast rise time (approximately 30 picoseconds) are apparent. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows the corresponding outputs where the bond inductance has been assumed to be 0.0 nanohenries. Very slight peak overshoot is seen in curves <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. In both figures, compensating capacitance C<highlight><subscript>out </subscript></highlight>is assumed to be 1 picofarad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> While several illustrative embodiments of the invention have been shown and described, numerous variations and alternate embodiments will occur to those skilled in the art. Differing amounts of additional voltage gain, for example from a common source gain stage, can be incorporated to drive input FETs Q<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and Q<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>from whatever input voltage levels are available. Bipolar transistors could be partially or completely substituted for the FETs. Transistors and supplies of complementary polarity could be employed to produce an equivalent circuit. Obviously, Vdd could be fixed at a nominal zero or ground potential, and the circuit ground could be biased at a negative potential such as &minus;3.3 volts with respect to Vdd. Such variations and alternate embodiments are contemplated, and can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A laser diode driver circuit, comprising: 
<claim-text>an amplifier having inverting and non-inverting inputs and inverted and non-inverted outputs; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a laser diode, connected between said inverting and said non-inverting outputs so that said laser diode is driven by the difference between the respective voltages at said inverted and said non-inverted outputs. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a biasing circuit, connected to said amplifier, arranged to offset said inverted and non-inverted outputs at a predetermined offset voltage with respect to one another. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The laser diode driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said amplifier comprises: 
<claim-text>A first branch of said driver circuit, comprising a first amplifier transistor in series with a first biasing transistor, with the source of said first amplifier transistor connected to the drain of said first biasing transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second branch of said driver circuit, connected in parallel with said first branch, said second branch comprising a second amplifier transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said inverting and non-inverting inputs connected to the respective gates of said first and second amplifier transistors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said inverted and non-inverted outputs connected to said sources of said first and second amplifier transistors, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said amplifier transistors are pseudomorphic high electron mobility transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said biasing transistor is a pseudomorphic high electron mobility transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said biasing transistor together with the gate bias control of the first and second amplifying transistor biases said outputs with an offset, relative to one another, of substantially 1.0 volt, to bias a laser diode substantially at its turn-on threshold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The driver circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one compensating capacitor coupled to a terminal of said laser diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A circuit for electrically modulating the drive to a laser diode, suitable for operation in switching mode at frequencies in the Gigahertz region, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor, having a gate control terminal, a source terminal and a drain terminal, said first transistor arranged to receive on its control terminal a first input; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor, having a gate control terminal, a source terminal and a drain terminal, said second transistor arranged to receive on its control terminal a second input; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first biasing transistor, having a gate control terminal, a source terminal and a drain terminal, having its drain terminal connected to said source terminal of said second transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second output terminals, said first output terminal connected to said source terminal of said first transistor, and said second output terminal connected to said source terminal of said second transistor, for driving a laser diode coupled between said output terminals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a laser diode coupled between said output terminals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second biasing transistor having a control terminal, a source terminal and a drain terminal, having its drain terminal connected to said source terminal of said first transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first, second transistor and said first biasing transistor are the only active devices which carries the drive current which also flows through said laser diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first and second transistors are pseudomorphic high electron mobility transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said biasing transistor is also a pseudomorphic high electron mobility transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first biasing transistor biases said output terminals with an offset, relative to one another, of substantially 1.0 volt, to bias a laser diode substantially at its turn-on threshold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one compensating capacitor, coupled to an output terminal, to compensate for inductance in the circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002551A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
