<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001254A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001254A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001254A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001254A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001254A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001254A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001254A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001254A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001254A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001254A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001254</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893307</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L023/488</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>691000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>791000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>778000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>697000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>439</class>
<subclass>075000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>830000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>840000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>842000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electronic assembly with separate power and signal connections</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>Daniel</middle-name>
<family-name>Jackson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Beaverton</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Terrance</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Dishongh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Damion</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Searls</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SCHWEGMAN, LUNDBERG, WOESSNER &amp; KLUTH, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2938</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A electronic assembly is disclosed and claimed. The electronic assembly includes a first substrate and a second substrate. A plurality of power connections are coupled between the first substrate and the second substrate and a multiplicity of signal connections separate from the plurality of power connections are also coupled between the first substrate and the second substrate. Each of the plurality of power connections have a substantially different size and shape compared to each of the multiplicity of signal connections. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to electronic circuits, assemblies and the like, and more particularly to an electronic assembly with separate power and signal connectors or connections. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In electrically connecting a semiconductor chip, socket or other electronic device to a printed circuit board or the like, two types of electrical connections typically need to be made. One type of connection or group of connections is to deliver power to the semiconductor chip or electronic device and the other type of connection or group of connections is to provide transmission of signals or data between the chip or device and other components on the printed circuit board or elsewhere. Power delivery is a relatively low frequency problem that relies on the bulk property of the conductive material to deliver sufficient current to the chip, device or die or to be able to carry at least the amount of current required or expected to be provided to the chip or device without being damaged or overheated and causing damage to other components. Signal integrity is a relatively high frequency problem that relies on smooth or seamless interfaces or transitions at points or nodes where conductors are joined or soldered together. As chips and other devices are required to perform more functions or operations in shorter periods of time, power requirements and signal requirements for semiconductor chips are continually increasing. The higher power requirements are solved by adding more conductors or power pins that take up more area on the chip and board and result in difficulty in delivering clean power to the devices. Additionally, the increased signal requirements call for additional connections that compete with the increased number of power connections for area on the chip and board. Further, the close proximity of the power and signaling connections can result in electromagnetic interference in delivering error free signaling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One arrangement for making power connections and signal connections between a printed circuit board and a chip or device or a socket into which the chip or device are mounted involves using solder balls or a ball grid array (BGA) or similar arrangement for both power and signal connections or delivery. Another arrangement for making power and signal connections utilizes a multiplicity of pins attached to the socket or device that are inserted into holes or recesses formed in the circuit board for both power and signal connections. Because the current carrying requirements are much larger for a connection providing power compared to the current carrying requirement for a connection carrying data signals, and because all of the pins or solder balls in both arrangements above are the same size and therefore have the same current carrying capacity, a multiplicity of balls or pins are required to be used in the aggregate to satisfy the power delivery requirements of high performance chips. Hundreds of balls or pins are usually needed to provide the power and ground connections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The pin contact for a signal connection also may not be as good or reliable as a re-flowed solder ball connection. Smooth or seamless interfaces are more reliable in providing the delivery of clean signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, for the reasons stated above, and for other reasons that will become apparent upon reading and understanding the present specification, there is a need for an electronic assembly for making power and signal connections between two substrates or between a semiconductor chip, socket or other device and a circuit board or the like that separates the power and signal connections, utilizes the appropriate type of connection and size and shape connection for the function being performed, makes efficient use of available area for making power and signal connections by minimizing the area on the chip or die and on the circuit board needed for making power and signal connections, and may be made efficiently with compatible manufacturing techniques or processes to form both the power and signal connections. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D illustrate a sequence of steps in making an electronic assembly in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block schematic diagram illustrating the different devices and sequence used in making the electronic assembly in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an example of a cross-section of a pin to make a power connection in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an example of a press fit connection between a pin and a hole formed in a substrate in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart of a method of making the electronic assembly of the present invention in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings which form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and structural changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Referring initially to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> which illustrates a first step in a process of making an electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention, a first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is provided. The first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may be a printed circuit board or the like. A plurality of holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or openings are formed in the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> at selected locations. A multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or a conductive layer of material may be formed on the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> in a predetermined conductive pattern. Referring also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, which is a block schematic diagram of a group of devices that may be used to make the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention, the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may be formed by a screen printing device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> using known methods. For example, a stencil (not shown) may be placed on a top surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Openings formed in the stencil define the predetermined pattern. Conductive material, such as solder or the like, may then be applied to exposed portions of the top surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> by spraying, roller or chemical vapor deposition to form the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or the conductive pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B, a</cross-reference> second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is disposed adjacent to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may be a socket to hold a semiconductor chip or may be the chip itself or another electronic device. The second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> attached to one surface <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> at selected locations. In accordance with the present invention, each of the plurality of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are received by a corresponding one of the plurality of holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> formed in the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. A multiplicity of solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> or the like are disposed between the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be supported in place at predetermined positions on the surface <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by an adhesive <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> or similar material during a placement operation when the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is placed adjacent to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> by a pick and place machine or part placement machine <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Each of the multiplicity of solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will substantially, closely align with a corresponding one of the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> formed on the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Each of the multiplicity of solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will self-align with the corresponding one of the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> during a re-flow operation as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may also include conductive contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to which the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will become electrically connected. The conductive contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may be a multiplicity of conductive pads formed in a distinctive pattern. The conductive contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> may also be formed by a screen printing process or the like. The second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may be provided with the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> already formed or attached thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> illustrates the results after performing a solder re-flow operation on the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. After placement of the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> adjacent to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is placed in a solder re-flow oven <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. During the solder re-flow operation, the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is heated under controlled conditions at predetermined temperatures for predetermined periods of time to cause at least each of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to melt or flow and integrally form an electrical contact or signal connection <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> with each of the corresponding conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> on the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the corresponding conductive contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> on the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Each of the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> define a connection for the transmission of signals between the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Each of the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> formed by the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and conductive contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is substantially smooth or seamless across the boundaries or interfaces between the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and contacts <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> for clean transmission of signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> fit into the holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> with a predetermined tolerance AT that forms a ring gap <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> between the pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and an interior wall of the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The ring gap <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> permits the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to move relative to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> so that each of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> can self-align with each of the corresponding conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> during the solder re-flow operation. The surface tension of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> when in a liquid state causes them to be pulled into alignment with the conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> such that the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> will be in alignment when the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> cool and resolidify. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> illustrates the results of a wave soldering operation applied to the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to electrically connect the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to the holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and thereby provide power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> between the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> to the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The wave soldering operation is performed by passing the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through a wave solder machine <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In the wave solder machine <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a bottom surface <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is skimmed over the surface of molten solder (not shown). The molten solder wicks up into the holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by capillary action to form a bond or connection between the interior wall of the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to provide the electrical power connection <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> between the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. During the wave solder operation the top surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> does not become appreciably heated and the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> or signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> will not melt, re-flow or be altered. Accordingly, the re-flow operation to form the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the wave solder operation to form the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are compatible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment of the present invention, solder deposits <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference>) maybe formed on the surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> around the holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> prior to the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> being positioned next to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> with each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> inserted into its corresponding hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The solder deposits <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be formed at the same time as the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or in a subsequent operation. During the re-flow operation, the solder deposits <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> will melt and flow into the gaps <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> defined by the predetermined tolerance &Dgr;T between each pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The solder deposits <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> will resolidify after the reflow operation to electrically connect each pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to its hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the wave solder machine <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) would not be needed and the duration of the process would be reduced by eliminating the wave soldering operation because the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> would be formed during the same re-flow operation that the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are melted to form the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. This process of depositing the solder deposits <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and re-flowing to connect to the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> during the solder re-flow operation may be referred to as the pin-in-paste option. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the present invention, the power connection <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> between the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be formed by a press fit connection. For example, each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has a cross-section that can be deformed when inserted into the corresponding hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Either the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are made large enough or the holes are formed such that there is no predetermined tolerance &Dgr;T or ring gap <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> between the pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the interior of the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The deformed pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is retained in the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by a friction fit and makes electrical contact with the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. One example of a deformable cross-section for each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is a substantially I-beam shaped cross section <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The I-beam shaped cross-section in then deformed when the pin <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is press fit into the hole <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> will have a selected size, diameter or cross-section to be able to carry a predetermined amount of current and there will be a predetermined number of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> needed to carry the total maximum current expected to be carried by the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> between the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The amount of current each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> will be capable of carrying will be a function of the cross-sectional area and the bulk material properties of each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> will also have a selected shape so as to minimize the area occupied by the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> on the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In the one embodiment discussed above, the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> have a substantially I-beam shape. In another embodiment the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be cylindrically shaped and in yet another embodiment, the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be formed by morphing multiple solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> which are fused to electrical contacts similar to the conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to form the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> between the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be any selected size and shape that satisfies the power or current carrying needs and is compatible with design constraints or circuit layout constraints. Because of the different functions and current loads on the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> compared to the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, each of the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> will have a substantially different size and shape compared to the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The relative size of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> compared to the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is shown to be large in the drawings for purposes of explaining the invention; however, in actuality the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> forming the signal connections <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> will be much smaller than the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> forming the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> that will be required to carry much higher current loads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The selected locations of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is preferably proximate to an edge <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, chip or die. The large size or cross-section of each of the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also provides support in absorbing mechanical stresses associated with any thermal mismatches between the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> or circuit board and the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> or chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart of a method for making the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in accordance with at least one embodiment of the present invention. In step <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, a first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is provided with a plurality of holes or openings <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> formed therein and in step <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, a second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> with a plurality of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> formed thereon at selected locations is provided. A multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are formed on at least one of the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in a predetermined pattern in step <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>, a multiplicity of solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are adhered to one of the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> or the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in predetermined positions. The solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be attached by a glue or adhesive <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to hold them in the predetermined positions during manufacturing of the electronic assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. If the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is a chip or socket to support a chip, the second substrate may be provided with the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> already attached. In step <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is disposed relative to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> with each of the plurality of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> being received by a corresponding one of the plurality of holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and each of the multiplicity of solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> being disposed between the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>, a re-flow operation is conducted to re-flow each of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to make a electrical contact or connection <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> for transmitting signals between the first and second substrates <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Each of the solder balls <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will self-align with a corresponding one of the multiplicity of conductive pads <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as described above. In step <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> each of the plurality of pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is electrically connected to the corresponding one of the plurality of holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by one of a solder re-flow process, press-fitting or a wave soldering process, as described above. If the press-fit option or embodiment is being used, the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> will be press-fit into the respective holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> when the second substrate <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is disposed relative to the first substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> in step <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. If the re-flow process or pin-in-paste option or embodiment is being used, then the pins <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are soldered to the respective holes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> during the solder re-flow process in step <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> to form the power connections <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that any arrangement which is calculated to achieve the same purpose may be substituted for the specific embodiment shown. This application is intended to cover any adaptations or variations of the present invention. Therefore, it is intended that this invention be limited only by the claims and the equivalents thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electronic assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of power connections coupled between the first substrate and the second substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplicity of signal connections separate from the plurality of power connections coupled between the first substrate and the second substrate, wherein each of the plurality of power connections have a substantially different size and shape compared to each of the multiplicity of signal connections. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the plurality of power connections are formed by a different process than each of the multiplicity of signal connections. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the plurality of power connections are formed by one of press fitting, wave soldering or re-flow soldering a plurality of pins, and each of the multiplicity of signal connections are formed by re-flowing a multiplicity of solder balls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the plurality of power connections comprises a pin and each pin has a selected size and shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the first and second substrates has a plurality of holes formed therein to receive the pins and each pin includes a cross-section adapted to be press fit into each of the plurality of holes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plurality of holes formed in at least one of the first and the second substrates and wherein each of the power connections comprises a pin, each pin being received into a corresponding one of the plurality of holes and wherein each of the pins is electrically connected to its corresponding hole by one of wave soldering or re-flow soldering. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the signal connections comprises a solder ball. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the plurality of power connections is a pin and wherein at least one of the first and second substrates has a plurality of holes formed therein to receive each of the pins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins fits into each of the plurality of holes with a predetermined tolerance for self-alignment of each of the solder balls with a conductive pattern formed on at least one of the first and second substrates during a re-flow process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one of the first and second substrates is a printed circuit board and the other one of the first and second substrates is one of a socket or a semiconductor chip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A electronic assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first substrate including a plurality of holes formed therein at selected locations; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplicity of conductive pads formed on the first substrate in a predetermined pattern; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second substrate disposed adjacent to the first substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of pins coupled to the second substrate and extending into each of the plurality of holes of the first substrate to make electrical contact between the second substrate and the first substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplicity of solder balls disposed between the first substrate and the second substrate and in contact with the plurality of conductive pads. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the plurality of pins are adapted to provide a power connection between the first and second substrates and the multiplicity of solder balls are adapted to provide transmission of signals between the first and second substrates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins has a selected size and shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins has a cross-section adapted to be press fit into each of the plurality of holes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins has a substantially I-beam shaped cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins has a selected size to carry a predetermined amount of current and the plurality of pins includes a predetermined number of pins to carry at least a total maximum expected current. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins fits into a corresponding one of the plurality of holes with a predetermined tolerance for self-alignment of each of the solder balls with a corresponding one of the multiplicity of conductive pads during a solder re-flow process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins are formed by morphing a plurality of solder balls together. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins is electrically connected to a corresponding one of the holes by one of a wave soldering process or a re-flow soldering process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The electronic assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the selected locations for each of the plurality of pins are proximate to a peripheral edge of the second substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method of forming an electronic assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a first substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a plurality of power connections between the first and second substrates; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a multiplicity of signal connections separate from the plurality of power connections between the first and second substrates, wherein each of the multiplicity of signal connections have a substantially different size and shape compared to each of the plurality of power connections. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the plurality of power connections comprises: 
<claim-text>inserting each of a plurality of pins attached to the second substrate into a corresponding hole formed in the first substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>making an electrical connection between each of the pins and the corresponding hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein making the electrical connection between each of the pins and the corresponding hole comprises one of press fitting each pin into the corresponding hole, wave soldering each pin to the corresponding hole or soldering each pin into the corresponding hole during a solder re-flow process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins are inserted into each of the corresponding plurality of holes with a predetermined tolerance for self-alignment of each of the multiplicity of signal connections with a predetermined conductor pattern formed on at least one of the first and second substrates when forming the multiplicity of signal connections. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the plurality of power connections comprises providing a plurality of pins, each of the pins having a selected size to carry a predetermined amount of current and the plurality of pins includes a predetermined number of pins to carry at least a total maximum expected current. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein forming the multiplicity of signal connections, comprises: 
<claim-text>disposing a multiplicity of solder balls between the first and second substrates; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>re-flowing each of the multiplicity of solder balls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A method of forming an electronic assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a first substrate with a plurality of holes formed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second substrate with a plurality of pin formed thereon at selected locations; </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering a multiplicity of solder balls to one of the first and second substrates in predetermined positions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the second substrate relative to the first substrate with each of the plurality of pins being received by a corresponding one of the plurality of holes; </claim-text>
<claim-text>re-flowing each of the multiplicity of solder balls to make electrical contact between the first and second substrates; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>electrically connecting each of the plurality of pins to the corresponding one of the plurality of holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein electrically connecting each of the plurality of pins to the corresponding plurality of holes comprises one of press fitting each pin onto the corresponding one of the plurality holes, wave soldering each pin to the corresponding one of the plurality of holes, or soldering each pin to the corresponding one of the plurality of holes during a solder re-flow process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the pins fits into the corresponding hole with a predetermined tolerance for self-alignment of each of the plurality of solder balls with a corresponding one of a multiplicity of conductive pads formed on at least one of the first or second substrates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>coupling each of the plurality of pins to the corresponding one of the plurality of holes to provide a power connection between the first and second substrates; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling each of the multiplicity of solder balls to the first and second substrates to provide transmission of signals between each of the first and second substrates.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1B</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001254A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001254A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001254A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001254A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001254A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
