<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004474A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004474A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004474</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10189361</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61M001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>604</class>
<subclass>317000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Sample collection system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301807</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Daniel</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Barker</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Suffolk</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>GEORGE F. HELFRICH</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>162 SHASTA DR.</address-1>
<city>NEWPORT NEWS</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>23608</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A system for collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample includes a sample intake positioned in a chosen location within a body of liquid. A first conduit section transfers a sample, which has been withdrawn from the body of liquid, from the sample intake to the pump. A second conduit section transfers the sample from the pump to a receptacle for collecting the sample. The second conduit section is connected to the receptacle by means providing for an air and watertight seal for the receptacle, which is coupled with means providing for the escape of air from the receptacle during collection of the sample therein. The means providing for an air and watertight seal for the receptacle is a specially designed transfer cap. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/301,807, filed Jul. 2, 2001 for &ldquo;Sample Collection System.&rdquo;</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to sample collection for chemical analysis. It relates particularly to a sample collection system which provides a representative sample and which avoids contamination of the sample during collection, preparation and storage for subsequent analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The universally accepted maxim that a chain is no stronger than its weakest link has particular application to the procedures of chemical analysis. That is to say, all of the intricate work in conducting a qualitative and quantitative analysis will be of little value if the sample presented for this analysis is not representative of the mass from which it was obtained, and/or if such a sample was contaminated during collection, preparation, and storage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With particular regard to the analysis of liquids, especially aqueous media such as lakes, ponds, reservoirs, rivers, and effluent streams, the analytical results obtained are often crucial. Indeed, the quality of analytical data obtained for regulatory purposes, such as derivation of site specific water quality standards, establishing wastewater permit discharge limitations, reasonable potential determinations, and in determining the compliance status of dischargers, must meet very high standards because of the legal significance of this data. In recent studies, it has been clearly demonstrated that the quality of trace metal data may be compromised because of contamination of samples during collection, preparation, and storage. Therefore, the use of clean techniques for sampling as well as analysis is critical to obtaining representative and accurate data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Although numerous improved sampling techniques and systems have been developed over the years, today&apos;s exacting technical and legal standards required even better sampling systems for the provision of truly representative samples wherein significant contamination is eliminated. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is accordingly a primary object of the present invention to provide a sample collection system which affords the obtainment and storage of precisely representative samples, especially of liquids, which are essentially free of contamination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> This object is achieved, and disadvantages of related art systems are obviated by the present invention, which in essence is a closed loop sample collection system. That is to say, a sample is withdrawn, i.e., from a body of a liquid, and transferred to a collection receptacle with minimal exposure to the atmosphere and minimal exposure to solid or liquid contaminants. To ensure that the sample is representative of the mass from which it is taken, i.e., from the body of liquid, the present invention provides for the obtainment of flow-proportioned or time-weighted composite samples, as well as for grab samples and duplicate samples. The simultaneous collection of a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated field blank is also provided by the sample collection system of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention, including its primary object and attending benefits, reference should be made to the Detailed Description of the Invention, which is set forth below. This detailed description should be read together with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic depicting a system for collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample, according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic depicting a system for simultaneously collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated field blank, according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic depicting a system for simultaneously collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated duplicate sample, according the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic depicting a system for collecting a grab sample, according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic depicting a system for collecting a grab field blank, according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring now the drawings, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically depicts a system <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample, according to the present invention. System <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes a sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which is advantageously a hollow rod or tube, which may be outfitted with a strainer, depending upon the particular liquid environment into which the sample intake is placed. For example, it may be desirable to strain or keep out large particulates, which may interfere with sample collection. The sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&mdash;as well as the conduits, receptacles, caps, tubes, and the like which are also components of the system of the present invention and which are discussed in detail hereinafter&mdash;is fabricated from a material which is inert to the liquid medium being sampled. Commonly employed for this purpose are polymeric materials such as polyethylene, polypropylene, polytetrafluoroethylene, derivatives of polytetrafluoroethylene, acetal, phenolic, and nylon. Sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is positioned in a chosen location within body of liquid <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by means of sample intake holder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which is advantageously a pole or a bracket to which sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is attached, and which keeps sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> securely positioned in the chosen location therefor. System <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> also includes a conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, which communicates with pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, which communicates with pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Conduit sections <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> respectively are also fabricated from a material which is inert to the liquid medium being sampled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> serves to withdraw a sample from body of liquid <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> through conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and to impel the sample through conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is advantageously an ISCO&reg; 3710 controller, which is programmed to withdraw time-weighted or flow-proportioned composite samples of varying pre-calibrated aliquot volumes. Accordingly, sample amounts are determined by a chosen and pre-set time interval and aliquot volume, or they are determined from measurements made by a flow measuring device such as a flowmeter, which is located in the body of liquid (e.g., a moving final effluent stream) and which communicates electronically with the pump. The pump is usually powered in one of three ways: a Ni&mdash;Cd battery, a Ni&mdash;Cd battery with AC backup, or a 12V battery and battery cable. A junction box is employed in association with the pump to provide the electronic connection between the pump and external flow signals from the flow measuring device, thereby providing flow-proportioned composite sampling when appropriate. The pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is also capable of providing a grab sample, as discussed in more detail hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> serves as a collection container for the sample. It is also fabricated from a material which is inert to the liquid being sampled. The sample enters receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> from conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which provides an air and watertight seal for receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. That is to say, there is no leakage of air or water through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which is an integral part of the instant closed loop sample collection system. A vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is provided in transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which is an integral part of the instant closed loop sample collection system. A vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is provided in transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to provide for the escape of air from receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> during collection of the sample therein. Vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be coupled with a filter if desired. Pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is provided for manipulating the sample, e.g., for removing a portion of the sample for analysis, without removing transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is a tube made of inert material which passes through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and extends to the bottom of receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The sample is accordingly collected by the sample collection system of the present invention and manipulated, as appropriate, without any significant contamination internally or from the outside atmosphere during collection and manipulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which is advantageously a screw cap, has a roof <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of sufficient thickness to provide a positive and permanent connection for conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and for vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, as well as for pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. That is to say, the inert fitting connections to transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> at <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> respectively are precise&mdash;i.e., allowing no leakage&mdash;and durable&mdash;i.e., not deteriorating with the passage of time. Without a sufficient thickness of roof <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, some leakage will take place, especially with the passage of time. A sufficient thickness for roof <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is determined empirically, and is dependent upon the size and configuration of transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the material from which it is fabricated among other variables. Roof thicknesses of standard screw caps have been generally determined to be insufficient to provide the positive and permanent connections required for the sample collection system according to the present invention. Therefore transfer caps <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are specially fabricated so that the roofs <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> thereof have been augmented to provide the necessary additional thickness. Without such a thickness augmentation, leakage around the connections will take place, especially with the passage of time. As an example of a preferred embodiment, a roof thickness of from about {fraction (5/8)} inches to {fraction (7/8)} inches has been found sufficient when the transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fabricated from high molecular weight polyethylene. The transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is fabricated from a rigid, non-metallic material, especially a polymeric material, preferably by machining or injection molding. The polymeric material is desirably a member selected from the group consisting of polytetrafluoroethylene, derivatives of polytetrafluoroethylene, acetal, phenolic, polypropylene, nylon, and polyethylene, with high molecular weight polyethylene being especially preferred for many applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, depicted therein is a system for simultaneously collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated field blank, according to the present invention. Sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is positioned in a chosen location within body of liquid <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by means of sample intake holder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> communicates with pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> communicates with pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> which is outfitted with vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. &lsqb;Sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, sample intake holder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, first conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, second conduit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, as referred to hereat and in additional embodiments presented hereinbelow, are as disclosed in detail hereinabove.&rsqb; It has been found advantageous, and even required in some instances, to maintain the collected sample at a given temperature. Under these circumstances the instant invention includes means <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> communicating with receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for maintaining the collected sample at a chosen temperature. Such means includes a common cooler which has been filled with small plastic bags containing ice. Use of such a cooler maintains the sample at a temperature of 4&deg; C. or below. The present embodiment of the sample collection system according to the present invention also includes a vessel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> for holding analyte-free water <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and means <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> for connecting conduit section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to pump <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, whereby an analyte-free water specimen is simultaneously withdrawn from vessel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to pump <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> through an air and watertight seal for vessel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, which is provided by transfer cap <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Transfer cap <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is outfitted with a vent <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, which is optionally coupled with a filter. Pump <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> withdraws a specimen of analyte-free water through conduit section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and impels the analyte-free water specimen through conduit section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and impels the analyte-free water specimen through conduit section <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to receptacle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, which provides an air and watertight seal for receptacle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and is coupled with vent <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, which provides for the escape of air from vessel <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> during collection of the analyte-free water specimen therein. Pickup tube <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> allows for manipulation of the specimen of analyte-free water which has been collected in receptacle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> without removing transfer cap <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and means <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> communicates with receptacle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> for maintaining the collected specimen of analyte-free water at a chosen temperature. In this embodiment the following groupings of elements are equivalent in construction and function: sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and means <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>; pumps <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>; receptacles <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>; means <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>; transfer caps <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>; vents <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>; and pickup tubes <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The specimen of analyte-free water which has been collected hereby is referred to as a field blank, as it is collected at the sampling site simultaneously with, and in identical fashion to the collection of the sample of the body of liquid. Field blanks are the most comprehensive of all blanks because they are collected as actual samples, and they are treated as actual samples inclusive of all site conditions, handling, preservation, transport, and analysis. In order to ensure an identical withdrawal of the actual sample and the field blank from their respective sources, a junction box communicates with pumps <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and sends signals thereto ensuring their identical activation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, depicted therein is a system for collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample, and an associated field duplicate sample. In this embodiment a sample is withdrawn by sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which is positioned by sample intake holder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and passed through conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, whence it is impelled through conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which is outfitted with vent <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and pickup tube <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> communicates with means <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for maintaining the sample collected in receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> at a chosen temperature. Simultaneously therewith, a duplicate sample is withdrawn by sample intake <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is positioned by sample intake holder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and passed through conduit section <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to pump <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, whence it is impelled through conduit section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, which is outfitted with vent <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and pickup tube <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Receptacle <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> communicates with means <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for maintaining the duplicate sample collected in receptacle <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> at a chosen temperature. A junction box communicates with pumps <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and sends signals thereto ensuring their identical activation. In this embodiment the following pairs of elements are identical in construction and function: sample intakes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>; pumps <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>; receptacles <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>; transfer caps <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>; vents <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>; pickup tubes <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>; and means <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In the preceding embodiments, details have been presented concerning the obtainment of: a composite sample, a composite sample and an associated field blank, and a composite sample and an associated field duplicate sample. That is to say, the samples, blanks, and duplicates have been time-weighted or flow-proportioned composites, as described hereinabove. As understood by the skilled artisan, the sample collection system of the present invention is also applicable to the obtainment of grab samples and field blanks, i.e., those samples and field blanks which are obtained by instantaneous withdrawal of a sample from a body of liquid and instantaneous withdrawal of a specimen of analyte-free water from a vessel containing the same. Such grab samples and grab field blanks provide in effect a snapshot picture of exactly what is present at a particular point in time in the liquid medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> depict sample collection systems according to the present invention for the obtainment of a grab sample and a grab field blank respectively. Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> sample from body of liquid <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is instantaneously withdrawn by pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from sample intake <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> through conduit section <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, whence it is impelled by pump <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> through conduit section <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>A. Transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>A is identical to transfer cap <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the embodiments specified hereinabove, except that no vent is provided for the escape of air from receptacle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and no pickup tube is provided for manipulation of the sample collected. Such a vent and pickup tube have been found to be unnecessary in this application, because of the relatively small amount of sample obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> specimen of analyte-free water from the analyte-free water <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> contained in vessel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is instantaneously withdrawn by means of pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> from sample intake <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> in vessel to through transfer cap <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, having vent <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> located therein, and thence through conduit section <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Pump <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> then impels the specimen of analyte-free water through conduit section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> into receptacle <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> through transfer cap <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The following pairs of elements from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> are identical in construction: sample intakes <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>; pumps <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>; conduit sections <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>; receptacles <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>; and transfer caps <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Vessel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is identical to vessel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; and transfer cap <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> with its associated vent <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is identical to transfer cap <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with its associated vent <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The sample collection system of the present invention has found special application in the evaluation of the final effluent metals levels during normal operating conditions of various industrial plants. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been described in detail with respect to certain preferred embodiments thereof. It is understood that variations and modifications in this detail may be made without any departure from the spirit and scope of the present invention, as defined in the hereto-appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A system for collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample, which system comprises: 
<claim-text>(a) A sample intake; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) Means for positioning the sample intake in a chosen location within a body of liquid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) A first conduit section for transferring a sample, which has been withdrawn from the body of liquid, from the sample intake to a pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) A second conduit section for transferring the sample from the pump to a receptacle for collecting the sample; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) Means for connecting the second conduit section to the receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the receptacle, coupled with means for providing for the escape of air from the receptacle during collection of the sample therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, which additionally comprises means communicating with the receptacle for maintaining the sample at a chosen temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A system for simultaneously collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated field blank, which system comprises: 
<claim-text>(a) A sample intake; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) Means for positioning the sample intake in a chosen location within a body of liquid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) A first conduit section for transferring a sample, which has been withdrawn from the body of liquid, from the sample intake to a first pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) A second conduit section for transferring the sample from the first pump to a first receptacle for collecting the sample; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) Means for connecting the second conduit section to the first receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the first receptacle, coupled with means for providing for escape of air from the first receptacle during collection of the sample therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) A vessel for holding analyte-free water; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) Mean for connecting a third conduit section to the vessel for holding analyte-free water to allow an analyte-free water specimen to be withdrawn from the vessel to a second pump through an air and watertight seal for the vessel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) A fourth conduit section for transferring the analyte-free water specimen from the second pump to a second receptacle for collecting the analyte-free water specimen; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) Means for connecting the fourth conduit section to the second receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the second receptacle, coupled with means for providing for the escape of air from the second receptacle during collection of the analyte-free water specimen therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, which additionally comprises means communicating with the first receptacle for maintaining the sample at a chosen temperature, and means communicating with the second receptacle for maintaining the analyte-free water specimen at a chosen temperature. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A system for simultaneously collecting a representative, non-contaminated sample and an associated duplicate sample, which system comprises: 
<claim-text>(a) A first sample intake; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) Means for positioning the first sample intake in a first chosen location within a body of liquid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) A first conduit section for transferring a first sample, which has been withdrawn from the body of liquid, from the first sample intake to a first pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) A second conduit section for transferring the first sample from the first pump to a first receptacle for collecting the first sample; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) Means for connecting the second conduit section to the first receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the first receptacle, coupled with means for providing for the escape of air from the first receptacle during collection of the first sample therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) A second sample intake; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) Means for positioning the second sample intake in a second chosen location within a body of liquid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) A third conduit section for transferring a second sample, which has been withdrawn from the body of liquid, from the second sample intake to a second pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) A forth conduit section for transferring the second sample from the second pump to a second receptacle for collecting the second sample; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(j) Means for connecting the fourth conduit section to the second receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the second receptacle, coupled with means for providing for the escape of air from the second receptacle during collection of the sample therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein element (e) is a transfer cap fabricated to provide an air and watertight seal for the receptacle and possessing a roof having a thickness which is sufficient to provide a permanent and positive connection for the second conduit and for the means providing for the escape of air from the receptacle during collection of the sample therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated from a rigid, non-metallic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rigid, non-metallic material is a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymeric material is a member selected from the group consisting of polytetrafluoroethylene, derivatives of polytetrafluoroethylene, acetal, phenolic, polypropylene, polyethylene, and nylon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymeric material is high molecular weight polyethylene. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated by machining or injection molding. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for connecting the second conduit section to the first receptacle to provide an air and watertight seal for the first receptacle is a transfer cap; and wherein the means for connecting the third conduit section to the vessel for holding analyte-free water is a transfer cap; and wherein the means for connecting the fourth conduit section to the second receptacle is a transfer cap; the transfer cap in each case being fabricated to provide an air and watertight seal for the first receptacle, the vessel for holding analyte-free water, and the second receptacle, respectively; the transfer cap in each case possessing a roof having a thickness which is sufficient to provide a permanent and positive connection for the second conduit section, and for the fourth conduit section, respectively, as well as for the means providing for the escape, intake, and escape of air during collection, withdrawal, and collection, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated from a rigid, non-metallic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rigid, non-metallic material is a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymeric material is a member selected from the group consisting of polytetrafluoroethylene, derivatives of polytetrafluoroethylene, acetal, phenolic, pholpropylene, polyethylene, and nylon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymeric material is high molecular weight polyethylene. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated by machining or injection molding. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for connecting the second conduit section to the first receptacle is a transfer cap, and the means for connecting the fourth conduit section to the second receptacle is a transfer cap, the transfer cap in each case being fabricated to provide an air and watertight seal for the first receptacle and the second receptacle, respectively; the transfer cap in each case possessing a roof having a thickness which is sufficient to provide a permanent and positive connection for the second conduit section and the fourth conduit section, respectively, as well as for the means providing for the escape of air from the first receptacle and the second receptacle, respectively, during collection of the first and second sample respectively therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated from a rigid, non-metallic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rigid, non-metallic material is a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymeric material is a member selected from the group consisting of polytetrafluoroethylene, derivatives of polytetrafluoroethylene, acetal, phenolic, pholpropylene, polyethylene, and nylon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polymerical material is high molecular weight polyethylene. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the transfer cap is fabricated by machining or injection molding. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sample is a flow-proportioned or time-weighted composite sample. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sample is a grab sample.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004474A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
