<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002000A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002000A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002000</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186585</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-201230</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02F001/1343</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>349</class>
<subclass>141000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>In-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device and method of fabricating the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Makoto</given-name>
<family-name>Watanabe</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>NEC CORPORATION</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Norman P. Soloway</name-1>
<name-2>HAYES SOLOWAY P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>130 W. Cushing Street</address-1>
<city>Tucson</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<postalcode>85701</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device includes (a) a first film composed of inorganic material, (b) a second film composed of organic material, both of the first and second films being to be formed below an electrode as underlying films, (c) a first vernier formed on the first film for measuring a width of the electrode, and (d) a second vernier formed on the second film for measuring a width of the electrode. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a liquid crystal display device and a method of fabricating the same, and more particularly to an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device and a method of fabricating the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A method of fabricating a liquid crystal display device usually includes a step in which patterns have to be overlapped each other without misregistration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For instance, a gate electrode, a source electrode and a drain electrode all to be formed on a thin film transistor (TFT) substrate are usually formed in a multi-layered pattern. In such a multi-layered pattern, misregistration in overlapping a lower layer pattern of which a gate electrode is comprised and an upper layer pattern of which source and drain electrodes are comprised each other has to be quite small. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Similarly, when a plurality of patterns is to be formed in a common layer, misregistration in a boundary at which adjacent patterns are contiguous to each other has to be quite small. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In addition, a difference between an actual dimension of a pattern having been actually formed in a photolithography step and a dimension defined by a mask, that is, a designed dimension has to be equal to or smaller than a threshold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Since it is almost impossible to accurately measure the above-mentioned misregistration and difference in dimensions after a liquid crystal display device has been fabricated, a vernier is frequently used for indirectly measuring the misregistration and difference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> For instance, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. 6-75243 has suggested a liquid crystal display device including a vernier pattern for measuring the above-mentioned misregistration and difference in a display area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A liquid crystal display device may be grouped into a first type in which molecular axes of aligned liquid crystal molecules are rotated in a plane perpendicular to a substrate to display a certain image, and a second type in which molecular axes of aligned liquid crystal molecules are rotated in a plane parallel with a substrate to display a certain image. Herein, a direction of axes of aligned liquid crystal molecules is called a director. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A typical one in the first type is a twisted nematic (TN) mode liquid crystal display device, and the second type is called an in-plane switching (IPS) mode liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Since a viewer looks only at a direction in which minor axes of liquid crystal molecules extend, even if he/she moves his/her eye point, in an IPS mode liquid crystal display device, how liquid crystal molecules stand is not dependent on a viewing angle, and accordingly, an IPS liquid crystal display device can present a wider viewing angle to a viewer than a TN mode liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Hence, an IPS mode liquid crystal display device has been more popular these days than a TN mode liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In an in-plane switching (IPS) mode liquid crystal display device, it is necessary to accurately control a width of a line of which an electrode is comprised. If such a line had a width much different from a designed width, a liquid crystal display device would have deteriorated uniformity in a brightness in a display area, or a liquid crystal display device could not have an electric field having an optimal intensity, resulting in deterioration in a brightness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> For instance, in a TN mode liquid crystal display device, a line of which an electrode is comprised is required to have a width controlled at an accuracy in the range of &plusmn;1.5 to 2.0 micrometers, whereas, in an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device, a line of which an electrode is comprised is required to have a width controlled at an accuracy in the range of &plusmn;0.2 to 0.3 micrometers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> An underlying film to be formed below an electrode in a liquid crystal display device is usually composed of inorganic or organic material. As mentioned above, a line of which an electrode is comprised in an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device is required to have an accurately controlled width. An organic film usually discharges gas when etched. An etching rate of an electrode formed on an organic film is greater than an etching rate of an electrode formed on an inorganic film. Accordingly, it is more difficult to control a line width of an electrode formed on an organic film than to control a line width of an electrode formed on an inorganic film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. 8-106100 (A) has suggested a method of fabricating a liquid crystal display device including two transparent substrates, and a liquid crystal layer sandwiched between the transparent substrates. In the suggested method, a transparent electrode and a scale are formed on at least one of upper and lower surfaces of the transparent substrates, and then, the transparent substrate are adhered to each other through sealing material coated at a periphery of the transparent substrates. When necessary, a line width of the sealing material is measured by means of the scale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. 9-258265 (A) has suggested a liquid crystal display device including two electrically insulating substrates, and a liquid crystal layer sandwiched between the electrically insulating substrates. One of the electrically insulating substrates are formed a plurality of switching devices arranged in matrix, first and second wirings electrically connected to the switching devices, an interlayer insulating film covering the first and second wirings therewith and having an upper surface and an inclining surface, and first and second electrodes one of which is electrically connected to the switching devices, for applying an electric field to the liquid crystal layer. The first and second electrodes cover the upper and inclining surfaces of the interlayer insulating film to thereby apply the electric field to the liquid crystal layer in parallel with the electrically insulating substrates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> ITO etching shift characteristics on an organic insulating film is discussed by Y. Kataoka et al. in ISSN 1083-1312/00/2001, pp. 123-126. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> However, the above-mentioned problem remains unsolved in those Publications. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In view of the above-mentioned problems in the conventional in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device, it is an object of the present invention to provide an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device including an inorganic film and an organic film as underlying films to be formed below an electrode which device is capable of accurately controlling a line width of an electrode formed on those inorganic and organic films. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> It is also an object of the present invention to provide a method of fabricating such an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the present invention, there is provided an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device including (a) a first film composed of inorganic material, (b) a second film composed of organic material, both of the first and second films being to be formed below an electrode as underlying films, (c) a first vernier formed on the first film for measuring a width of the electrode, and (d) a second vernier formed on the second film for measuring a width of the electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device in accordance with the present invention includes the first and second verniers formed on the first and second films, respectively. Hence, it is possible to measure a line width of an electrode formed on the first film and a line width of an electrode formed on the second film independently of each other, and thus, it is possible to control a line width of the electrodes. This ensures enhancement in a fabrication yield of an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The first vernier may be designed to have a centerline extending in the same direction as a direction in which a centerline of the second vernier extends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> For instance, each of the first and second verniers may be comprised of a metal film including (c1) a plurality of first metal linear regions extending in a first direction and arranged in a second direction perpendicular to the first direction such that the first metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another, (c2) a plurality of second metal linear regions extending in the first direction and arranged in the second direction such that the second metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another, (c3) a plurality of first slits extending in the first direction and arranged in the second direction such that the first slits are contiguous to the first metal linear regions, and (c4) a plurality of second slits extending in the first direction and arranged in the second direction such that the second slits are contiguous to the second metal linear regions. A first metal linear region located at an end has a first width equal to a width of the electrode to be measured, and a first metal linear region located remoter from the end has a width equally smaller than the first width. A second metal linear region located at the end has the first width, and a second metal linear region located remoter from the end has a width equally greater than the first width. The first and second slits commonly have the first width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The metal film may be composed of indium tin oxide (ITO). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The electrode may be composed of electrically conductive transparent material such as indium tin oxide (ITO). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> There is further provided an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device including (a) a first film composed of organic material, and formed below an electrode in a display area as an underlying film, (b) a second film composed of inorganic material, and formed below an electrode in a terminal area extending around the display area, (c) a first vernier formed on the first film for measuring a width of the electrode, and (d) a second vernier formed on the second film for measuring a width of the electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device in accordance with the present invention includes the first vernier formed on the first film in a display area and the second vernier formed on the second film in a terminal area. Hence, it is possible to measure a line width of an electrode formed on the first film and a line width of an electrode formed on the second film independently of each other, and thus, it is possible to control a line width of the electrodes. This ensures enhancement in a fabrication yield of an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of fabricating an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device, including the steps of (a) forming a first film composed of inorganic material, on a substrate, (b) forming a second film on the first film in a display area of the liquid crystal display device, the second film being composed of organic material, (c) fabricating a first vernier on the first film in a terminal area extending around the display area, for measuring a width of an electrode, (d) fabricating a second vernier on the second film for measuring a width of the electrode, and (e) forming the electrode on the first and second films. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the method of fabricating an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device, in accordance with the present invention, the first vernier is formed on the first film in a display area and the second vernier is foxed on the second film in a terminal area. Hence, it is possible to measure a line width of an electrode formed on the first film and a line width of an electrode formed on the second film independently of each other, and thus, it is possible to control a line width of the electrodes. This ensures enhancement in a fabrication yield of an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The first and second verniers may be formed in separate steps, or may be formed in a common step. Specifically, the above-mentioned steps (c) and (d) may be carried out separately or concurrently. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that the second vernier is fabricated in the step (d) such that it has a centerline extending in the same direction as a direction in which a centerline of the first vernier extends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and advantageous features of the present invention will be made apparent from the following description made with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which like reference characters designate the same or similar parts throughout the drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of a unit pixel in an in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display,device in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line II-II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram of the unit pixel illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a partial cross-sectional view of a boundary between a display area and a terminal area in the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a positional relation between a display area and a terminal area in the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view illustrating an example of a vernier used in the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>,</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments in accordance with the present invention will be explained hereinbelow with reference to drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> illustrate an in-plane switching mode active matrix type liquid crystal display device in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of a unit pixel of the liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along the line II-II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram of the unit pixel illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is comprised of an active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, an opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and a liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> sandwiched between the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes an electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, a black matrix layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> formed on a first surface of the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> as a light-shielding film, a color layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> formed on the first surface of the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> such that the color layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> partially overlaps the black matrix layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, a transparent overcoating layer <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> covering the black matrix layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the color layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> therewith, an alignment film <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> formed covering the transparent overcoating layer <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, an electrically conductive layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> formed on a second surface of the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and a polarizer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed on the electrically conductive layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The color layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is comprised of resin films containing red (R), green (G) and blue (B) pigments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The electrically conductive transparent layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> prevents electric charges caused by contact of a liquid crystal display panel with other materials, from exerting electrical influence on the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The active matrix substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes an electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a first metal layer formed on the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and defining a scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and a gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>(see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) therein, a first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> formed on the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an island-shaped amorphous silicon film formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a second metal layer defining a data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and a source electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a drain electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a thin film transistor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> therein, a first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>formed on the first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>a common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> both formed as transparent electrodes on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and a polarizer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> formed on a lower surface of the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The first and second films <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>constitute a second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The active matrix substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> further includes a pixel auxiliary electrode <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> together with the data lines <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, The data lines <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the pixel auxiliary electrode <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are comprised of the second metal layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In the specification, an &ldquo;upper&rdquo; layer means a layer located closer to the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a &ldquo;lower&rdquo; layer means a layer located remoter from the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in both the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> include alignment films <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, respectively, both making contact with the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the alignment films <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are rubbed such that the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is homogeneously aligned in a direction inclined from a direction in which the common electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> extend, by an angle in the range of 10 to 30 degrees, and then, adhered to the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, respectively, such that they face each other. The above-mentioned angle is called initial alignment orientation of liquid crystal molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Though not illustrated, spacers are sandwiched between the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to ensure a thickness of the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a seal <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) is formed around the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> between the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for avoiding leakage of liquid crystal molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The polarizer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a polarization axis extending perpendicularly to the liquid crystal initial alignment direction, and the polarizer <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a polarization axis extending in parallel to the liquid crystal initial alignment direction. The polarization axes extend perpendicularly to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes data lines <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to which data signals are transmitted, common electrode lines <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to which a reference voltage is applied, a common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to which the reference voltage is applied, a pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> associated with pixels in which images are to be displayed, a scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to which a scanning signal is applied, and a thin film transistor (TFT) <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The thin film transistor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>(see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), a drain electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a source electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The thin film transistor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed in the vicinity of an intersection of the scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and the data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in association with a pixel. The gate electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is electrically connected to the scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is electrically connected to the data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and the source electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is electrically connected to the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Both the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are designed to have a comb-teeth shape, and the comb-teeth in the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> extend in parallel with the data lines <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The comb-teeth of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the comb-teeth of the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are arranged to be in mesh with each other, and further, spaced away from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> formed as a transparent electrode is electrically connected to the common electrode line <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>through a first contact hole <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the common electrode lines <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are both comprised of the first metal layer, and extend in parallel with the scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A common electrode voltage is applied to the common electrode lines <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at their ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> formed as a transparent electrode is electrically connected to the pixel auxiliary electrode <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprised of the second metal layer and integrally formed with the source electrode <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the thin film transistor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, through a second contact hole <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment, an electric field is generated in parallel with the electrically insulating transparent substrates <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> between the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> in a pixel which is selected by a scanning signal transmitted through the scanning line <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and into which a data signal transmitted through the data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is written. The alignment direction of liquid crystal molecules are rotated in a plane parallel with the electrically insulating transparent substrates <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in accordance with the electric field to thereby display a certain image. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> rectangular column surrounded by the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is called a column. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment, both of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are composed of indium tin oxide (ITO), a transparent material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is comprised of an inorganic film composed of inorganic material. The first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is comprised of an inorganic film composed of inorganic material, and the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is comprised of an organic film composed of organic material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> An organic film has a smaller dielectric constant than that of an inorganic film. Hence, the second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> having such a multi-layered structure could have a reduced dielectric constant in comparison with having a single-layered structure of an inorganic film. As a result, parasitic capacity between wirings can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> When the second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is designed to have a multi-layered structure including the first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be composed of silicon nitride SiNx, and the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be composed of photosensitive acrylic resin or photosensitive polyimide resin, for instance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>b may be comprised of a single organic layer, in which case, the second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may be composed of benzocyclobutene (BCB), organic polysilazane, or siloxane, for instance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a partial cross-sectional view of a boundary between a display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> extending around the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, in the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a positional relation between the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the layers constituting the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, such as the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the second interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, are formed only in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In contrast, the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> covers the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> composed of organic material and formed on the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and an electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> composed of ITO and formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment is designed to include first verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> formed on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at four corners in the rectangular display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and second verniers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> at four corners in the rectangular terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are arranged such that centerlines <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) of them extend in the same direction. In the first embodiment, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are arranged such that they have centerlines extending in parallel with one of sides of the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The first verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are used for measuring a line width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> both formed on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the second verniers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are used for measuring a line width of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be identical in shape to each other, or may be different in shape from each other. The in-plane switching mode liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment is designed to include the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> identical in shape to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of an example of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is comprised of a metal film having a particular pattern. For instance, each of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be comprised of an ITO film. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, solid areas indicate areas in which a metal film remains, and hollow areas indicate areas in which a metal film is eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> has a left half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>L and a right half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>R A centerline <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> extends in a length-wise direction of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> along a boundary between the left half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>L and the right half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R, a plurality of second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L, a plurality of first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R, and a plurality of second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L. The first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R and the first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R are formed in the right half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>R, and the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L and the second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L are formed in the left half <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R extend in a horizontal direction, and are arranged in a vertical direction such that the first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R are equally spaced away from one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R extend in a horizontal direction, and are arranged in a vertical direction such that the first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R are contiguous to the first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R located at an uppermost end is designed to have a first width equal to a width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to be measured, and a first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R located remoter from the uppermost end is designed to have an equally decreasing width relative to the first width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R are designed to have a width equal to the first width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R have a common length. In contrast, the first slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>R are designed to have an increasing length every five first slits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L extend in a horizontal direction, and are arranged in a vertical direction such that the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L are equally spaced away from one another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L extend in a horizontal direction, and are arranged in a vertical direction such that the second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L are contiguous to the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> A second metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L located at an uppermost end is designed to have the first width equal to a width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to be measured, and a second metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L located remoter from the uppermost end is designed to have an equally increasing width relative to the first width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L are designed to have a width equal to the first width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L have a common length. In contrast, the second slits <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>L are designed to have an increasing length every five first slits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Scales &ldquo;0&rdquo; to &ldquo;&minus;3&rdquo; and &ldquo;0&rdquo; to &ldquo;&plus;3&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> indicate a line width of the first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R and the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L. Scale &ldquo;0&rdquo; indicates that a line width of the first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R and the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L is equal to a line width of a mask For instance, scale &ldquo;&minus;3&rdquo; indicates that a line width of the first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R associated therewith is thicker than a line width of a mask by 3 micrometers, and scale &ldquo;&plus;3&rdquo; indicates that a line width of the second metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L associated therewith is thinner than a line width of a mask by 3 micrometers </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In measuring a line width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> through the use of the first vernier <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, a first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R having a line width equal to a line width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is first found out among a plurality of the first metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R. In accordance with a location of the thus found-out first metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>R in a vertical direction, a gap between an actual line width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and a designed line width or a line width of a mask of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> can be measured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> In measuring a line width of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> through the use of the second vernier <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, a second metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L having a line width equal to a line width of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is first found out among a plurality of the second metal linear regions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L. In accordance with a location of the thus found-out second metal linear region <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>L in a vertical direction, a gap between an actual line width of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a designed line width or a line width of a mask of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be measured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment is fabricated in the same process as a conventional process of fabricating the same, except the following steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> First, the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is formed on the electrically insulating transparent substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Then, the data line <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the pixel auxiliary electrode <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the first film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> only in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Then, the first verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are formed on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the second verniers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be formed in separate steps, or may be formed in a common step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> After the formation of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are formed on the second film <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and then, the alignment film <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is formed covering the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> therewith. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Then, the active device substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the opposing substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are adhered to each other with the liquid crystal layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> being sandwiched therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Thus, the in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment is completed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> In the in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment, the first verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are formed on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the display area <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the second verniers <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the terminal area <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. Hence, it is possible to measure a line width of the common electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the pixel electrode <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> formed on the second film <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a line width of the electrically conductive transparent film <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> formed on the first interlayer insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, independently of each other through the use of the first and second verniers <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the first embodiment makes it possible to control a line width of the electrodes and film, and ensures enhancement in a fabrication yield of the in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described in connection with certain preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the subject matter encompassed by way of the present invention is not to be limited to those specific embodiments. On the contrary, it is intended for the subject matter of the invention to include all alternatives, modifications and equivalents as can be included within the spirit and scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> The entire disclosure of Japanese Patent Application No. 2001-201230 filed on Jul. 2, 2001 including specification, claims, drawings and summary is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device including: 
<claim-text>(a) a first film composed of inorganic material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a second film composed of organic material, both of said first and second films being to be formed below an electrode as underlying films; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a first vernier formed on said first film for measuring a width of said electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a second vernier formed on said second film for measuring a width of said electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first vernier has a centerline extending in the same direction as a direction in which a centerline of said second vernier extends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said first and second verniers is comprised of a metal film including: 
<claim-text>(c1) a plurality of first metal linear regions extending in a first direction and arranged in a second direction perpendicular to said first direction such that said first metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c2) a plurality of second metal linear regions extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said second metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c3) a plurality of first slits extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said first slits are contiguous to said first metal linear regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c4) a plurality of second slits extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said second slits are contiguous to said second metal linear regions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first metal linear region located at an end has a first width equal to a width of said electrode to be measured, and a first metal linear region located remoter from said end has a width equally smaller than said first width, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second metal linear region located at said end has said first width, and a second metal linear region located remoter from said end has a width equally greater than said first width, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second slits commonly have said first width. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said metal film is composed of indium tin oxide (ITO). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrode is composed of indium tin oxide (ITO). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device including: 
<claim-text>(a) a first film composed of organic material, and formed below an electrode in a display area as an underlying film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a second film composed of inorganic material, and formed below an electrode in a terminal area extending around said display area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a first vernier formed on said first film for measuring a width of said electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a second vernier formed on said second film for measuring a width of said electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first vernier has a centerline extending in the same direction as a direction in which a centerline of said second vernier extends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said first and second verniers is comprised of a metal film including: 
<claim-text>(c1) a plurality of first metal linear regions extending in a first direction and arranged in a second direction perpendicular to said first direction such that said first metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c2) a plurality of second metal linear regions extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said second metal linear regions are equally spaced away from one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c3) a plurality of first slits extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said first slits are contiguous to said first metal linear regions; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c4) a plurality of second slits extending in said first direction and arranged in said second direction such that said second slits are contiguous to said second metal linear regions, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first metal linear region located at an end has a first width equal to a width of said electrode to be measured, and a first metal linear region located remoter from said end has a width equally smaller than said first width, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second metal linear region located at said end has said first width, and a second metal linear region located remoter from said end has a width equally greater than said first width, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second slits commonly have said first width. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said metal film is composed of indium tin oxide (ITO). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrode is composed of indium tin oxide (ITO). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of fabricating an in-plane switching type liquid crystal display device, including the steps of; 
<claim-text>(a) forming a first film composed of inorganic material, on a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) forming a second film on said first film in a display area of said liquid crystal display device, said second film being composed of organic material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) fabricating a first vernier on said first film in a terminal area extending around said display area, for measuring a width of an electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) fabricating a second vernier on said second film for measuring a width of said electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) forming said electrode on said first and second films. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said steps (c) and (d) are concurrently carried out. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second vernier is fabricated in said step (d) such that it has a centerline extending in the same direction as a direction in which a centerline of said first vernier extends.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002000A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
