<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000044A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000044A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000044</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10197137</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020717</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E05D001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>016</class>
<subclass>221000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Flag clamping device for automobile antenna</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10197137</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020717</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>29132238</doc-number>
<document-date>20001106</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>D448702</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hawkins</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Monroe</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DOUGHERTY &amp; CLEMENTS</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>TWO FAIRVIEW CENTER</address-1>
<address-2>6230 FAIRVIEW ROAD, SUITE 400</address-2>
<city>CHARLOTTE</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>28210</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is directed to a garment clamping device for automobile antennas upon which a flag or banner may be secured and displayed. The clamping device comprises two generally rectangular shaped halves which are joined together by a hinge strap mechanism. Each half has at least one aperture and at least one corresponding mounting stud for clamping the two halves around an automobile antenna. Further, each half has at least one barb and at least one corresponding aperture located on the other half for holding and supporting a display flag after the apparatus is clamped around the antenna. Extending from one half is a cap for securing the apparatus atop the antenna. In operation, the device is positioned around an antenna and the mounting stud, barbs and respective apertures are engaged. Once engaged, the hinge straps form a cavity wherein the antenna is displaced. The cap of the device is positioned so that it rests upon the antenna ball located atop the antenna thereby keeping the clamp in a visibly appealing position. In certain embodiments, additional support is provided by a tape strip or other adhesive. In certain other embodiments, an attachment means for attaching the device to a bicycle or motor bike is provided. The attachment means comprises an elongated shaft and a second clamping device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This is a Continuation-In-Part Application of co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 29/132,238 filed Nov. 6, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an apparatus for supporting flags and banners on automobile antennas, and more particularly pertains to an apparatus which supports and removably displays flags or banners at the top of automobile antennas. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Often it is desirable for an individual to display a symbol or word(s) from an automobile. These displays take many forms and are used for many purposes, including but not limited too advertising athletic teams, professional organizations, political groups, etc. Some individuals place bumper stickers on their automobiles, others place flags or banners on their car and some prefer to place signs on the sides or hood of the car. Each of the currently known methods and devices have certain disadvantages. By way of example, bumper stickers and signs can damage the surface of the car, thus reducing its resale value. Moreover, bumper stickers are typically low and poorly located. Thus, the desired display is not effective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> By way of another example, most flags or banners are difficult to attach to a car without interfering with the operation of the same. The present art relating to the use of flags on automobiles focuses on three types of attachment systems. First, the use of an attachment system which affixes the flag to a window on the car is employed by most people. This system has several drawbacks. One such drawback is that the device requires the window to remain in the raised position. Another drawback is that the device usually must be wedged between the window and the door frame or jamb. This prevents the door or window from being tightly closed. Thus, in the case of rain, water may seep into the vehicle. Still another drawback is that the presence of the flag in the window creates a blind spot resulting in a hazardous condition during operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another type of attachment system is one which attaches a flag to a bumper or hood of an automobile. These systems are typically permanent and, in the case of removable systems, the flag may slide or move from its original position on the automobile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Finally, an attachment system whereby a flag is affixed to a car antenna may be used. With respect these types of attachment system, the prior art generally teaches of three types. The first type uses cuts of a plastic extruded material which uses kinetic energy to form a recurve in the plastic which grips around an antenna. This recurve material would have a small flag stapled through the plastic. Because of the enlarged graduation of the older telescoping antennas the extrusion recurve would not allow the flag to slide down the antenna. However, the invention and major usage of the single non-telescoping antenna causes this item to fail after continued usage by allowing it to fall to the bottom of the antenna. Moreover, continued usage of this system causes wear on the inside of the recurve and the staples holding the flag in place which leads to failure of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A second type of system is the cloth sewn style. In this system, a long sock like configuration is sewn together with the flag at the end. The sock portion of the flag is pulled down over the antenna leaving the flag at the top of the antenna. The sock portion generally traverses the entire length of the antenna. A disadvantage of this system is that the device is not aesthetically pleasing to the eye. Moreover, nothing is provided to prevent the device from sliding off the antenna as the automobile gains speed. The majority of these types of systems can only practically be used for promotional car sales on vehicles which are stationary and not in the operational mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A third type of system comprises Velcro&reg; strips which have flags sewn thereon. The antenna of the automobile and the flag is sandwiched between the opposing hook and yarn strips of the Velcro&reg; to hold the flag in place. A disadvantage of this type of system is that the flag material frays and becomes entangled in the Velcro&reg;, thereby causing an unsightly ball of cloth with extreme wind resistance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> While the above described known devices may fulfill their respective, particular objectives and requirements, the aforementioned references do not describe an apparatus for supporting and removably displaying flags on automobile antennas which will maintain its position on the antenna while providing the capability of 360&deg; rotation. Therefore, it can be appreciated by those skilled in the art that there exists a continuing need for new and improved apparatus for supporting flags on automobile antennas which can be used for removably positioning flags on antennas of automobiles. Further, it can be appreciated that a need exists which also provides the capability of 360&deg; rotation of the displayed flag above the antenna as directed by the wind. In this regard, the apparatus for supporting flags on automobile antennas according to the present invention substantially departs from the conventional concepts and designs of the prior art, and in doing so provides an apparatus primarily developed for the purpose of removably positioning flags on antennas of automobiles which have a greater life cycle and which provide the capability of 360&deg; rotation while maintaining its position on the top of the antenna. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Generally, the present invention is directed to a garment clamping device (hereinafter referred to as &ldquo;antenna clamp&rdquo;) which is used with automobile antennas. The antenna clamp is used to display a flag or banner from the top of the antenna. The clamp is configured so that the flag is always displayed at the top portion of the antenna, thus providing maximum visibility. The antenna clamp generally comprises two generally elongated rectangular-shaped substantially identical halves which may or may not be joined together in a closed position around the antenna. In a preferred embodiment, the antenna clamp is provided with a connection means wherein a first half of the antenna clamp is provided with at least one projecting stud and the second half is provided with a corresponding mating aperture adapted for snap engagement with the stud. Moreover, the antenna clamp is provided with a garment securing means wherein a second half of the antenna clamp is provided with at least one barb and the first half is provided with a corresponding aperture for receiving the barb. The barbs of the antenna clamp are used to secure a flag or banner in place while the clamp is in the closed position. The studs and corresponding apertures are used to maintain the clamp in a snap together closed position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Intermediate and connecting the halves is a flexible hinge strap mechanism. The hinge mechanism is configured to allow manipulation of the clamp into a closed position thereby forming a generally circular cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In addition, a small cap is provided which projects from the top of the antenna clamp in order to keep the clamp from sliding down the antenna. In operation, a flag material is placed on the barbs, the antenna is positioned into the recurve of the hinge, the clamp is closed around an antenna and secured into position. In the closed position, the cavity diameter of the hinge strap is dimensioned to be larger than the diameter of the antenna so as to encircle the antenna while allowing 360&deg; of rotation of the clamp as so directed by the wind. Further, the cavity diameter is dimensioned to be smaller than the diameter of an antenna ball or knob located at the distal end of the antenna, thereby preventing the clamp from sliding off the top of the antenna. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The principal object of the present invention is to provide an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle which does not introduce safety hazards and which prominently displays the flag in a high visible position when the automobile is parked or driven. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A still further object of this invention is to provide an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle which is easily removed and replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on an antenna which maintains its position at the top of the antenna while providing rotational capabilities about the antenna. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> These together with other objects of the invention, along with various features of novelty which characterize the invention, are pointed out with particularity in the claims annexed to and forming a part of the disclosure. For better understanding of the invention, its operating advantages and the specific objects attained by its uses, reference should be had to the accompanying drawings and descriptive matter which there is illustrated preferred embodiments of this invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A full and enabling disclosure of the present invention, including the best mode thereof, to one of ordinary skill in the art, is set forth more particularly in the remainder of the specification, including reference to the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a preferred embodiment of the antenna clamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front view of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a fragmentary view illustrating the connection means in the open position of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a fragmentary view illustrating the connection means in the closed position of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a top view of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in the closed position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the invented antenna clamp shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in the closed position around an automobile antenna. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspecitve view of an alternative embodiment of the present invention in the closed position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the drawings are merely illustrative of the invention and are not meant to limit the claims. Various modifications and additions may be made to the apparatus by those skilled in the art, without departing from the spirit and scope of this invention, which is therefore understood to be limited only by the scope of the appended claims. Further, the same reference numerals refer to the same parts throughout the various Figures. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As required, detailed embodiments of the present invention are disclosed herein. However, it is to be understood by one of ordinary skill in the art that the present discussion is a description of exemplary embodiments only and is not intended as limiting the broader aspects of the present invention, which broader aspects are embodied in the exemplary construction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The present invention is preferably unitary in construction and is useful with any plastic or other elastomeric material or any combination thereof. By unitary, it is meant that the present invention is formed as one continuous apparatus as opposed to separate parts which are joined to form one apparatus. Suitable plastics are recycled plastics, injection molded plastics, reinforced plastics or the like generally comprised of polyethylene, polypropylene, and polyvinylchloride. Further, the described configuration can be in different sizes and shapes to correspond to different designs and characteristics of automobile antennas, flags and other tubular members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing disadvantages inherent in the known types of devices for supporting flags or antennas now present in the prior art, the present invention provides an improved apparatus for supporting flags on-automobile antennas. As such, the general purpose of the present invention, which will be described subsequently in greater detail, is to provide a new and improved apparatus for supporting flags on automobile antennas which has all the advantages of the prior art and none of the disadvantages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the drawings, a preferred embodiment of the present invention is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the shown antenna flag clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is generally comprised of a first half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a second half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The two halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are substantially similar in configuration and generally comprise an elongate rectangular member having opposing inner and outer sides <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. Each half also has opposing first and second ends, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. The sides <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are dimensioned so as to have a greater length than the ends <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The inner sides <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are joined together by a hinge strap mechanism <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> displaced intermediate therein. The outer sides <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the respective halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>have rounded edges <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> located at the corners. By using the hinge strap <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, preferably integrally formed with the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>will always be aligned for proper connection as explained herein. Preferably, the disclosed antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is approximately 4.5&Prime; long and 1.7&Prime; wide in construction. Further, the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> preferably measure 0.5 inches in width, 6 inches in length, and 0.05 inches in thickness. The connecting hinge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is most effective with a thickness of approximately 0.02&Prime; for these dimensions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> A connection means is provided for connecting the halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>together and maintaining them in the closed position. The connection means generally has at least one cylindrically shaped projecting member, or stud <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, mounted on the first half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A corresponding and mating first aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is located in the second half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for snap engagement thereto. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, the stud <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is optionally provided with a snap ring <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> located substantially at the outward projecting end for snap engagement with the corresponding first aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Also, the corresponding aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is configured so that its receiving side <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is tapered to permit slideable engagement with the stud <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Finally, the exit side of the aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is optionally provided with a snap rim <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In operation, the first half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is manipulated so that the stud <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is aligned and matingly engaged with the aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for a secure fit, thereby keeping the device in a closed position (See, FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>). The optional snap ring <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and snap rim <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> add extra security to the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> when it is in the closed position as the snap ring <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> overlaps the snap rim <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> after the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been manipulated into the closed position. The use of the above connection means provides the ability to close and open the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as described without affecting the structural integrity of the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art, that the cylindrically shaped studs <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can take on various other shapes and configurations, provided they will mate with an aperture of like configuration in a male/female connecting relationship. Moreover, it will be appreciated that the projecting stud <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can be on the second half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with the aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> located on the opposing half. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The hinge strap mechanism <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> used in the present invention is sometimes known as a living hinge. The hinge strap <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is flexible in construction and connects the two halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. When the apparatus is positioned closed a cavity <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is defined whereby an automobile antenna can be placed therein. The diameter of the cavity <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is configured so that an antenna ball, located at the top of the antenna cannot pass therethrough. Further, it is configured so that the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may freely rotate about the antenna shaft as so directed by the wind or other force. Once the apparatus is in the closed position, the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can readily rotated about the antenna in response to the movement of the air flow. Rotation can be in either the clockwise or counter-clockwise direction up to 360&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Also provided, is a garment securing means generally comprised of at least one barb <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> located on the second half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with a corresponding second aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> located on the opposing half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The barbs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are used to securely retain a flag or garment material which is placed thereon. Upon snapping the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> together the barbs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and second aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are perfectly aligned so that the barbs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are centered in the second aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of each opposing half and barely protrude through the opposing half. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> There is an arm extension <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> protruding from the top of the second half <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This extension <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has affixed to it a small cap <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which is flat on the underside. The cap <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is designed to rest atop the antenna ball while the remainder of the clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is rotatably attached below the antenna ball. This configuration both prevents the clamp from inadvertently sliding off the antenna and from sliding down the antenna to a visibly less desirable position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In operation, a garment is placed upon one half of the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and an automobile antenna is placed in the hinge recurve area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with the antenna ball protruding and centered in the space between the end of the hinge/strap <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the underside of the cap <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The two halves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are snapped together by the connection means, the antenna is captured inside the diameter closed hinge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a garment or flag cloth is captured by the piercing barbs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which protrude through the cloth and into the second aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the securing means. The preferred dimensions stated above and the above described configuration of the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are both aesthetically pleasing to the eye and provides a safe manner of displaying the garment on the automobile. By having the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> located at the top of the antenna, no visual obstructions are created on the automobile which would constitute a safety hazard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> An alternative embodiment of the present invention allows for the antenna clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be attached to an elongated shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a zip clamp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> located at its distal end. The zip clamp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> generally has a C-shaped configuration wherein a first distal end is provided with a toothed strip extending therefrom and a second distal end is provided with an opening for receiving the toothed strip. The zip clamp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> can be attached to the front handle bar of a bicycle or like vehicle by stretching open the zip clamp <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and positioning over and around the bar. Thereafter, the toothed strip is passed through the opening of the second distal end and tightened closed. The elongated shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is made of flexible plastic material which can easily collapse if impacted. The use of the flexible shaft prevents sharp protruding edges from being exposed to a user thereby providing a greater safety factor. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE ACHIEVEMENT OF THE OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing, it is readily apparent that I have invented an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Further, it is apparent that I have invented an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle which does not introduce safety hazards and which prominently displays the flag in a high visible position when the automobile is parked or driven. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Still further, it is apparent that I have invented an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on the antenna of an automobile or other transportation vehicle which is easily removed and replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Still further, it is apparent that I have invented an improved apparatus for supporting a flag or banner on an antenna which maintains its position at the top of the antenna while providing rotational capabilities of the antenna clamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the foregoing description and specific embodiments are merely illustrative of the best mode of the invention and the principles thereof, and that various modifications and additions may be made to the apparatus by those skilled in the art, without departing from the spirit and scope of this invention, which is therefore understood to be limited only by the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A garment clamping device for automobile antennas comprising: 
<claim-text>a first half having a generally rectangular configuration; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second half having a substantially similar configuration as the first half; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hinge intermediate the first and second halves, wherein the hinge is flexible and may be manipulated into a closed position thereby defining a generally circular cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an antenna connection means for securing the clamping device in the closed position around the automobile antenna; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a garment securing means for securing the garment to the clamping device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connection means is comprised of at least one projecting stud located on either the first or second half and at least one first aperture located in a corresponding position on the opposing half. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the securing means comprises a barb for piercing the garment on the half opposing the projecting stud and a second aperture on the half with the projecting stud, said second aperture being located and adapted in a coresponding position for matingly receiving said barb. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a cap extending from the first half. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said barbs comprise a conical shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said projecting stud comprises a cylindrical shape and has a snap ring located at its distal end for added security after snap engagement with the first aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first aperture for receiving said projecting stud comprises a tapered entry point and elevated rim portion at its exit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said device is unitary in construction and manufactured by injection molding an elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the elastomeric material is slected from a group consisting of polypropylene, polyethylene, polyvinyl chloride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A garment clamping device for use with an automobile antenna comprising: 
<claim-text>a first generally rectangular half, said first half comprising at least one projecting stud and at least one aperture; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second half having substantially similar shape to the first half, said second half comprising at least one barb located in a corresponding position to the aperture and at least one hole located in a corresponding position to the projecting stud; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hinge mechanism connected intermediate the first and second halves; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap extending from the top of the second half; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shaft extending from the bottom of the second half; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a zip clamp affixed to the distal end of the shaft for attachment to a tubular device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second halves are configured for receiving a garment, being manipulated around said antenna and secured in a closed position by snap engagement of the projecting stud and the hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A garment clamping device for use with an automobile antenna comprising: 
<claim-text>a body having a first and second half; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible hinge strap connected intermediate the first and second halves; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap extending from the second half of the body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection means for securing the first and second halves together; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the garment is placed on one of the first and second halves and the body is closed around the antenna and held in place by the connection means so that the garment is retained in a fixed position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in the closed position the body of the clamping device is located immediately beneath an enlargement at an upper end of the antenna for minimizing the chance of inadvertently lifting off the shaft of the antenna and the cap is located atop enlargement to prohibit the clamping device from sliding down the shaft of the antenna. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the connection means comprises: 
<claim-text>at least one projecting stud extending from either the first or second half; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one mating aperture in a corresponding position to the projecting stud located on the half opposing the projecting stud for snap engagement; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one barb located on either half; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one corresponding aperture for receiving the barb located on the opposing half. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the barbs have a conical shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the projecting stud is cylindrical and further comprises a snap ring located at its distal end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the device is further provided with an adhesive material placed along the length of the first half for added support of the garment being retained. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the device is of a unitary construction and comprised of an elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the elastomeric material is selected from a group consisting of polypropylene, polyethylene, or polyvinyl cloride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the device is manufactured by injection molding. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The garment clamping device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein aperture for receiving the projecting stud is tapered at the entrance and is provided with a rim at its exit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000044A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
