<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000513</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09892841</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A21B001/28</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>126</class>
<subclass>02100A</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Switchable combustion system for a convection oven</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Cole</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Algonquin</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Donald</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fritzsche</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chicago Heights</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Harter</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Port Richey</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ronald</given-name>
<middle-name>Jay</middle-name>
<family-name>Forni</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Littleton</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Malcolm</given-name>
<family-name>Reay</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Drums</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jerry</given-name>
<family-name>Sank</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Palm Harbor</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<family-name>McFadden</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Jones</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>New Port Richey</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Pauley Peterson Kinne &amp; Fejer</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 365</address-1>
<address-2>2800 W. Higgins Road</address-2>
<city>Hoffman Estates</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60195</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A convection oven having a gas combustion system that is switchable between a direct-fired combustion system and an indirect-fired combustion system by a damper moveable between a closed position and an open position. In one preferred embodiment, a separate heat exchange element supplies combustion products to the convection oven. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a convection oven having a switchable combustion system permitting the convection oven to operate as a direct-fired combustion system and an indirect-fired combustion system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional convection ovens are heated by either a direct-fired combustion system or an indirect-fired combustion system. Direct-fired combustion systems circulate combustion products within the cooking space and in direct contact with the food being cooked. These direct-fired combustion systems are a key contributor to the &ldquo;pinking&rdquo; of meat, particularly poultry, common in direct-fired convection ovens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Researchers have concluded that nitrogen dioxide present in the muscle tissue of the meat product combines readily with combustion gas fumes. As a result, the cooked meat product has a bright red color on the surface which may extend one-eighth to one-fourth of an inch inward. This result is greater if the meat is uncovered during the cooking process and/or cooked in a poorly ventilated oven. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In indirect-fired combustion systems, the combustion products do not circulate within the cooking space. In an indirect-fired gas oven, heat generated during the combustion process is exchanged with air in the cooking space by means of a heat exchange device. Because the combustion products never directly contact the food, indirect-fired gas ovens create an environment more suitable for the introduction of steam into the cooking space. However, these ovens are not as efficient as the direct-fired gas ovens, having a slow heat-up time and slow recovery capability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is apparent that there is a need for a commercial convection oven having a switchable combustion system permitting the oven to function as a directfired combustion system and an indirect-fired combustion system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is an object of this invention to provide a convection oven having a switchable combustion system permitting the convection oven to operate as a direct-fired combustion system, having rapid heat-up and recovery capabilities, or an indirect-fired combustion system, creating an environment more suitable for the introduction of steam and/or suitable for cooking without concerns with interactions between the combustion products and the food being cooked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The above object and further objects of this invention are accomplished with a convection oven having a duct positioned adjacent a cooking chamber and extending into the cooking chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The duct is connected to a gas combustion system having at least one burner connected to a gas supply or fuel source. The convection oven according to different embodiments of this invention may be heated by a gas combustion system having an induced draft, a forced draft and/or a natural draft system, with or without a convection fan. As the gas supplied to the burner combusts, combustion products are generated. A damper is further connected with respect to the duct. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of this invention, when the damper connected to the duct is in the closed position, the convection oven is preferably heated by a direct-fired combustion system. The combustion products generated by the gas combustion system are drawn through the duct by a convection blower mounted within the cooking chamber. As the combustion products are drawn into the cooking chamber, the combustion products circulate through the cooking chamber and make direct contact with the food being cooked. After circulating through the cooking chamber, the combustion products exit the cooking chamber through a vent and into ambient air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> When the damper is in the open position, the convection oven is heated by an indirect-fired combustion system. As the combustion products generated by the gas combustion system travel through the duct, heat is transferred from within the duct into the cooking chamber through a heat exchanger. The combustion products exit the duct through a flue connected to the duct and are prevented from being drawn into the cooking chamber by the damper. As heat exchange occurs, the convection blower circulates the heated air within the cooking chamber. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, after circulating through the cooking chamber, the circulated heated air can be reused, with any excess heated air exiting the cooking chamber through the vent. In the indirect-fired combustion system, the combustion products do not directly contact the food being cooked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment of this invention, a separate heat exchange element is provided. A blower plenum is positioned adjacent the cooking chamber. An inlet baffle is positioned between the blower plenum and the cooking chamber. Preferably, the inlet baffle has a plurality of apertures. The blower plenum is in communication with the cooking chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A gas combustion system is mounted within the blower plenum having a gas manifold connected at a first end to the gas supply and at a second end to at least one gas outlet. A burner is connected to each gas outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A heat exchange element mounted within the blower plenum, for example a heat exchange tube, is connected to each burner and extends into a header. The header is in communication with the gas supply so that the combustion products produced in the gas combustion system travel through the heat exchange element and are collected within a volume of the header. An inducer having a valve that is moveable between an open position, wherein the convection oven operates as an indirect-fired combustion system, and a closed position, wherein the convection oven operates as a direct-fired combustion system is connected to the header. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> At least one convection impeller is mounted within the blower plenum and adjacent the heat exchange element. As the convection impeller generates airflow across the heat exchange tubes, heat is transferred from the heat exchange tubes to the air flowing across the heat exchange tubes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The heated air is forced into the cooking chamber by the convection impeller and circulates within the cooking chamber. Apertures in the inlet baffle allow circulated air within the cooking chamber to be drawn into the blower plenum by at least one convection impeller which recirculates the drawn air across the heat exchange element.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The drawings show different features of a convection oven having a combustion system switchable between a direct-fired combustion system and an indirect-fired combustion system, according to preferred embodiments of this invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a schematic view of a convection oven having a direct-fired combustion system, according to one preferred embodiment of this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a schematic view of a convection oven having an indirect-fired combustion system, according to one preferred embodiment of this invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective side view of a convection oven having a combustion system switchable between a direct-fired combustion system and an indirect-fired combustion system with a separate heat exchange element. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> comprises a cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be of any suitable dimensions to accommodate food prepared to be cooked. A duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is positioned adjacent cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and preferably extends along at least a portion of a wall of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, at least a portion of a floor of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and/or at least a portion of a ceiling of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has a first end portion connected to an output end portion of a gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a second end portion which extends into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is mounted with respect to cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. According to different embodiments of this invention, gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may comprise an induced draft system, a forced draft system or a natural draft system. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises at least one burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> connected to a gas supply or fuel source <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, for example a natural gas supply. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> supplies gas, preferably natural gas, to burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The gas burns or combusts within burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to produce or generate combustion products. The term &ldquo;combustion products&rdquo; as used throughout this specification and in the claims includes, but is not limited to, heat and combustion gas fumes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment of this invention, a convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is mounted within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and in communication with duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In another preferred embodiment of this invention, convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be mounted within duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Preferably, but not necessarily, convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is rotated by a motor. Any conventional motor or other means known to those skilled in the art may be used to rotate convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A flue <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and is in communication with ambient air outside convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is connected to duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is moveable between a closed position, wherein damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> prevents passage of air through duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> into flue <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and an open position, wherein damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> prevents passage of air through duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> may be actuated electronically, mechanically or in any other manner of actuation known to those having ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, when damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the closed position, convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is heated by a direct-fired combustion system. Gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> supplies gas to burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> where the gas combusts to generate combustion products. With damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the closed position, the combustion products generated by gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are drawn through duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. As the combustion products travel through duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, heat may be transferred from within duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via a heat exchanger <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, e.g. through the adjacent wall of duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, through the floor of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or through the ceiling of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As the combustion products are drawn into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the combustion products circulate through cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and make direct contact with the food being cooked. After circulating through cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the combustion products exit cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through a vent <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and into ambient air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, when damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the open position, convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is heated by an indirect-fired combustion system. As the combustion products generated by gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> travel through duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, heat is transferred from within duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through heat exchanger <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, heat exchanger <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is at least a portion of the inner wall of duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, at least a portion of the floor of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and/or at least a portion of the ceiling of cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. With damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the open position, the combustion products exit duct <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through flue <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and are prevented by damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from flowing into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As the heat exchange occurs through heat exchanger <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> circulates the heated air within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. After circulating through cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the circulated heated air can be reused or recirculated through cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, with any excess heated air exiting cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through vent <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In the indirect-fired combustion system, the combustion products do not directly contact the food being cooked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is fail safe because in any position it will not permit the build up of combustion products. With damper <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> moveable between an open position and a closed position, a flue path will always be available either through flue <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or vent <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment of this invention as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> separate heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is provided. A blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is preferably positioned adjacent and in communication with cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. An inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is positioned between blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to one preferred embodiment of this invention, a gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is mounted within blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to generate combustion products. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a gas manifold <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> connected to gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and having at least one gas outlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, preferably at least three gas outlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. It is apparent to those skilled in the art that any number of gas outlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be used in gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A control valve (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) is connected between gas manifold <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to control the amount of gas supplied to gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is connected to each gas outlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, for example at least one heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, is connected to each burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> at a first end portion of heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is mounted within blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and comprises a plurality of heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, preferably at least three heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> corresponding to the number of burners <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> second end portion of each heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extends into a header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is in communication with gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> so that the combustion products produced in gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> travel through heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and are collected within a volume of header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is connected to an inducer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> having a valve <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) that is moveable between a closed position, wherein convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> operates as a direct-fired combustion system, and an open position, wherein convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> operates as an indirect-fired combustion system. It is apparent that valve <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> can be actuated electronically, mechanically or by any other means known to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Preferably, at least one convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the same or similar to convection blower <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, is mounted within blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and mounted adjacent heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. In one preferred embodiment of this invention, convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has two convection impellers <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> mounted within blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is driven by a motor <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. Other means known to those skilled in the art may be used to drive convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> With valve <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> in the closed position, the combustion products produced by gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and collected within header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are in communication with cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The combustion products are circulated within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and directly contact the food being cooked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> With valve <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> in the open position, the combustion products produced by gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and collected within header <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are in communication with ambient air outside convection oven <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Thus, the combustion products do not enter cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and therefore do not directly contact the food being cooked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, gas supplied by gas supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to gas combustion system <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> travels through gas manifold <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is distributed to individual burners <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via gas outlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Within burner <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the gas combusts and generates combustion products. The combustion products travel through heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, for example at least one heat exchange tube <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> generates airflow across heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and heat is transferred from heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the air flowing across heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are configured to provide high airflow rates over heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and produce high heat transfer rates, reducing the surface area of individual heat exchange tubes <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> required for a desired heat exchange effectiveness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The heated air is forced into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Apertures <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in inlet baffle <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> allow circulated air within cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to flow into blower plenum <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by at least one convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> recirculates the air across heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to continue the cooking process whereby heat is transferred from heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the air flowing over heat exchange element <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and then forced into cooking chamber <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by convection impeller <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> While in the foregoing specification this invention has been described in relation to certain preferred embodiments, and many details are set forth for purpose of illustration, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that this invention is susceptible to additional embodiments and that certain of the details described in this specification and in the claims can be varied considerably without departing from the basic principles of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A convection oven, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas combustion system mounted with respect to the cooking chamber, the gas combustion system generating combustion products; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a duct connecting the gas combustion system and the cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a flue connected to the duct; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a convection blower in communication with the duct; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat exchanger positioned between the duct and the cooking chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a damper connected to the duct, the damper moveable between an open position wherein the combustion products are in communication with the flue and a closed position wherein the combustion products are in communication with the cooking chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gas combustion system comprises at least one burner connected to a fuel source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a vent in communication with the cooking chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the damper is electrically actuated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the damper is mechanically actuated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gas combustion system is in communication with the cooking chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gas combustion system is in communication with the flue. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the convection blower is mounted within the cooking chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gas combustion system comprises one of an induced draft system, a forced draft system and a natural draft system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A convection oven, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower plenum positioned adjacent the cooking chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inlet baffle positioned between the cooking chamber and the blower plenum, the cooking chamber thereby in communication with the blower plenum; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas combustion system mounted within the blower plenum, the gas combustion system generating combustion products; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat exchange element mounted within the blower plenum and connected to the gas combustion system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a header connected to the heat exchange element; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one convection impeller mounted within the blower plenum; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inducer connected to the header, the inducer having a valve moveable between an open position wherein the combustion products are in communication with ambient air and a closed position wherein the combustion products are in communication with the cooking chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas combustion system further comprises: 
<claim-text>a gas manifold connected to a gas supply, the gas manifold having at least one gas outlet; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a burner connected at a first end portion to each gas outlet of the at least one gas outlets and connected at a second end portion to a heat exchange element. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the heat exchange element comprises a plurality of heat exchange tubes, each heat exchange tube of the plurality of heat exchange tubes having a first end portion connected to a burner and a second end portion connected to the header. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a control valve connected between the gas manifold and the gas supply. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The convection oven of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the inlet baffle has a plurality of apertures.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
