<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000852</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896673</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65D085/30</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B65D085/57</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>206</class>
<subclass>308100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Lockable box</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>Malcolm</middle-name>
<family-name>Broadhead</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Grants Pass</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Bracewell &amp; Patterson, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 1600</address-1>
<address-2>201 Main Street</address-2>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>76102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A lockable box (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) for a DVD or other disc has at least two releasably interengageable locking members (<highlight><bold>10,20</bold></highlight>) (<highlight><bold>110,120</bold></highlight>) which, when interengaged, prevent the box from being opened. The locking members are entirely contained within the box when the box is closed, and they can be disengaged only with the use of a special tool. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a lockable box for pre-recorded media, notably a DVD box. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND TO THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Pre-recorded storage media such as digital versatile discs (DVDs) are usually put up for sale in a plastic box which carries information about the DVD as well as carrying sales promotional material or artwork to attract a purchaser. To prevent theft of the DVD from a store various lockable display containers have been proposed which house the DVD in its box and prevent a thief gaining access to the DVD without breaking the container or removing the container from the shop. The container can be fitted with alarm means so that it cannot be removed from the shop without actuating an alarm. Examples of such lockable containers are described in EP 0 312 172, EP 0 541 733, EP 0 666 954 and WO 00/61899. These display containers are effective but they increase the bulk of the product on display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Known products provide a locking member which is externally applied to the box. With such products, the box cannot be shrink-wrapped for &ldquo;sell-through&rdquo;, as there is then no means of removing the locking member without damaging the packaging. The locking members are also subject to being tampered with. Once the locking member has been removed in order to unlock the box (in a rental situation) it has to be safely stored for re-use later on. If the locking member is lost, the box can no longer be secured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The present invention seeks to provide an improved lockable disc box. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a lockable box for a DVD or other pre-recorded data carrier. The box has at least two releasably interengageable locking members which, when interengaged, prevent the box from being opened. The locking members are entirely contained within the box when the box is closed, and they can be disengaged only with the use of a special tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that the box is a DVD box, and the invention will be described with reference to this embodiment. However, it will be understood that the invention is also applicable to other pre-recorded data carriers, for example compact discs (CDs), videos and tape cassettes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The DVD box may be supplied to Record Label and Film Studio Companies as original packaging, filled with product and then sent to a retailer in either a locked or an unlocked state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Unlike existing products, which require a manual action to insert (lock) or remove (unlock) the locking member, the disc box of the present invention can be locked and unlocked in a hands-free manner. By incorporating a ferrous element in a movable locking member, the box may be locked and unlocked by swiping it against a suitable strong magnet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The box comprises a first box member and a second box member which are adjustable between a closed position in which they co-operate to define a substantially closed box, and an open position in which the inside of the box is accessible to permit a disc to be inserted into or removed from the box. Each box member has a locking member, and at least one of the locking members is adjustable between a locked position in which, when the box members are in the closed position, the locking members interengage so as to prevent the box from being opened, and an unlocked position in which the locking members permit the box members to be moved from the closed position to the open position. The two co-operating locking members comprise a locking mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The locking member on each box member could be movable relative to the box member. However it is preferred that one locking member is movable and the other is fixed relative to its box member. In a preferred embodiment, the movable locking member is pivotable between the locked and unlocked positions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> One of the locking members may be provided with a hole or recess in which the other locking member is disposed when the box is locked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another preferred embodiment, the movable locking member is slidable between the locked and unlocked positions. By providing each end of the slidable locking member with a ferrous element, locking and unlocking may be carried out means of a single swipe along an appropriate edge of the box. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Although the invention may employ only one locking mechanism, it is preferred that more than one locking mechanism, preferably two locking mechanisms, are provided. This preferred embodiment permits all three free edges of a conventional hinged DVD box to be locked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment where one locking member of a pair is fixed and the other is movable, both movable locking members may conveniently be provided on the same box member. However, it would also be possible to provide one movable locking member on each box member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The interior of the box may be provided with an electronic tag of a type known per se which activates an alarm system if an attempt is made to remove the DVD box from the store. It is particularly preferred that the tag may be remotely deactivated by electronic means. This permits the DVD box to be sold in shrink wrapping and to be both unlocked and alarm-deactivated at the point of sale without removing the wrapping. Suitable electronic tags are known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Other aspects and benefits of the invention will appear in the following specification, drawings and claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be further described, by way of example, with reference to the following drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a first embodiment of a lockable DVD box in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cutaway view of part of the box shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with the box closed and locked; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cutaway view similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, with the box unlocked and partially open; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a second embodiment of a lockable DVD box in accordance with the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a fragmentary view of part of the locking mechanism of the DVD box shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The DVD box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> connected together by a hinge <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The box members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are hollow shells, for example of polypropylene, which co-operate to form a closed box when pivoted about the hinge <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in known manner. The first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is provided with an annular disc-receiving member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> with a resilient mount <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in the middle, for releasably securing a DVD (not shown) as is well known in the art. The disc-receiving member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and mount <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> could additionally or alternatively be provided on the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Two locking members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are pivotally mounted on the inner surface of the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by means of pivot pins <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The tension between the pivot pin <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and its locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is such that the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> cannot be pivoted by shaking of the box; a greater force is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Upstanding lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are provided on the inner surface of the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> adjacent the distal ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and proximal ends <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the pivotable locking members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is provided with locking members comprising upstanding lugs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> on the inner surface. Each upstanding lug <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has a hole, and when the box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is closed pairs of lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are located face to face with the holes in alignment. The arrangement is such that, with the box members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in the closed position, pivoting of the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from the unlocked position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> to the locked position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> brings the ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> into disposition through the holes in both the aligned lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the pair. In this position, the box members <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are locked together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> With the box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> closed, the locking members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are pivotable only with the use of a special tool. It is preferred that the proximal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and distal <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> ends of the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are formed from a ferrous material or are provided with a ferrous insert or attachment. This permits the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be pivoted by means of a strong external magnet device. A suitable magnetic device is described in WO 00/61899. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> To lock the box, the box is closed, and then each short edge <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is swiped in turn against the magnet. The magnet attracts the ferrous insert of the distal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, causing the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to pivot and both ends to engage in holes in the associated pair of lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> To unlock the box, the long edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is swiped against the magnet so that the magnet attracts the distal ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the locking members <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and reverses the locking process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In practice, the magnet may be mounted on a checkout desk at the point of sale or rental. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Although the above arrangement is preferred for ease of unlocking, it will be appreciated that the opposite arrangement could also be used, whereby locking is achieved by a single swipe along the long edge of the box, and unlocking by a swipe along both short edges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> could be accessible via a hole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in an edge of the box. As illustrated in the drawings, the box could be locked by a user inserting a long thin tool through the hole <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the long edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> so as to push the proximal end <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and cause the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to pivot to the locked position. It would be possible for unlocking to be carried out by the same tool through a similar hole adjacent to the distal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. However it is preferred that exclusively magnetic means are used for unlocking and, preferably, for locking, the box because the use of a suitable magnet is quicker and permits the DVD box to be locked and unlocked while shrouded in shrink-wrap material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the proximal ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are provided with permanent magnets with like poles facing towards the long edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This permits the box to be locked with a single swipe of a suitable magnet with a like pole adjacent the long edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> so that the permanent magnets in the proximal ends <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are repelled. The box can be unlocked with a single swipe of a suitable magnet with the opposite polarity adjacent the long edge. Both types of magnets could be mounted at the point of sale or rental, one for locking and the other for unlocking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> It would be possible not to provide the lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> on the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> so that the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> engages only with the lugs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> on the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> when the box is locked. However, this would require the locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be relatively rugged and robust because it would need to resist upward force exerted by an attempt to prise the box members apart. In the preferred embodiment the ends of the locking members are disposed through lugs on both the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, so that the lugs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> on the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> prevent force from the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> being transmitted to the pivot pin <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The entire locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and its mount may be provided as a removable insert to enable its removal either at point of sale or by a customer. Alternatively, the pivot pin <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> could be made releasable by exerting an upward force on the pivotable locking member <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, an alternative embodiment of the invention employs a locking member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> which is slidably mounted on the first box member <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is provided with a plurality of fixed locking members comprising upstanding L-shaped hooks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. For each hook <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> there is a corresponding hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the slidable locking member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Under each hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> there is a space <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, as best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, for receiving a corresponding hook <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The proximal <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and distal <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> ends of both slidable locking members <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are provided with ferrous inserts (not shown) so that they are attractable by a magnet. By swiping a first long edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the box against a suitable magnet, the slidable locking member moves in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to an unlocked position in which the hooks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can enter and leave the spaces <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> via the holes <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. With the box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the closed position and the slidable locking member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in the unlocked position, the box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be locked by swiping the opposite long edge <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> against a magnet so as to move the slidable locking member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to the locked position in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Here, the hooks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are trapped in the slidable locking member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and the box is locked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the DVD box <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be locked and unlocked with a single swipe against a suitable magnet along the appropriate edge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In both embodiments, the locking members <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> on the inner surface which does not carry the mount <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for the DVD (in these examples, the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) are arranged to as to permit literature pertaining to the DVD to be inserted and removed. One or more clips (not shown) may be provided on the inner surface of the second box member <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> to releasably retain such literature, in a manner well known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments, it should be understood that modifications and variations of the invention may be constructed without departing from the scope of the invention defined in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A lockable box for a pre-recorded data carrier, the box comprising: 
<claim-text>a first box member and a second box member which are adjustable between a closed position in which they co-operate to define a substantially closed box, and an open position in which the inside of the box is accessible to permit a pre-recorded data carrier to be inserted into or removed from the box; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each box member having a locking member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the locking members being adjustable between a locked position in which, when the box members are in the closed position, the locking members interengage so as to prevent the box from being opened, and an unlocked position in which the locking members permit the box members to be moved from the closed position to the open position; wherein </claim-text>
<claim-text>the locking members are entirely contained within the box members when the box members are in the closed position, and the adjustment of the locking member to the unlocked position is achievable only with the use of a special tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the locking member on the first box member is movable relative to the first box member and the locking member on the second box member is fixed relative to the second box member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the movable locking member is pivotable between the locked and unlocked positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a part of one of the locking members comprises a ferrous material whereby the said locking member can be adjusted between the locked and unlocked positions by means of a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the fixed locking member on the second box member comprises an upright member which has a hole in which the movable locking member engages when adjusted to the locked position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second box members are each provided with two locking members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein two of the locking members are movable and two of the locking members are fixed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein both the locking members on the first box member are movable and both the locking members on the second box member are fixed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a part of each movable locking member comprises a ferrous material whereby they can be adjusted between the locked and unlocked positions by means of a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the said ferrous material is a permanent magnet and the magnets are arranged with like poles facing in substantially the same direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first box member is provided with an upright member having a hole therein, whereby when the box members are in the closed position and the movable locking member is in the locked position, the movable locking member is disposed through both the hole in the said upright member and the hole in the fixed locking member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, which has at least two opposed edges, wherein the said locking members are adjustable to the locked position by swiping one edge along a suitable magnet and wherein the said locking members are adjustable to the unlocked position by swiping the opposite edge past a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A lockable box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, which has two opposed long edges and two opposed short edges, wherein the said one edge and the said opposed edge are the long edges. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first box member and a second box member which are adjustable between a closed position in which they co-operate to define a substantially closed box, and an open position in which the inside of the box is accessible to permit a DVD to be inserted into or removed from the box; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the box members being provided with a mount for releasably securing a DVD thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the box being provided with two spaced apart releasable locking mechanisms, each comprising a locking member provided on the first box member and a locking member provided on the second box member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of each of the locking members in both locking mechanisms being adjustable between a locked position in which, when the box members are in the closed position, the locking members interengage so as to prevent the box from being opened, and an unlocked position in which the locking members disengage; wherein </claim-text>
<claim-text>the locking members are entirely contained within the box members when the box members are in the closed position, and the adjustment of the locking members to the unlocked position is achievable only with the use of a special tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the locking members on the first box member are movable and the locking members on the second box member are fixed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustable locking members are pivotable between the locked and unlocked positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a part of each movable locking member comprises a ferrous material whereby they can be adjusted between the locked and unlocked positions by means of a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each locking member has a first end and a second end, each end being provided with a ferrous insert or attachment whereby the said locking members can be adjusted between the locked and unlocked positions by means of a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein both locking members have a ferrous insert or attachment which is a permanent magnet, the magnets being arranged with like poles facing in substantially the same direction, whereby the said locking members can be reversibly adjusted between the locked and unlocked positions by means of a suitably orientated magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the box members have two opposed long edges and are connected together by a hinge along one of the long edges; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the locking members are arranged so that they are adjustable from the locked position to the unlocked position by swiping one of the said long edges of the box past a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustable locking members are slidable between the locked and unlocked positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a DVD mounted on the said mount and the box being shrouded in a shrink-wrap material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a remotely-deactivatable alarm tag within the box. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the locking members are adjustable from the unlocked position to the locked position by swiping one of the said long edges of the box past a suitable magnet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A lockable DVD box which has at least two releasably interengageable locking members which, when interengaged, prevent the box from being opened, the locking members being entirely contained within the box when the box is closed, and being disengageable only with the use of a special tool.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000852A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000852A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000852A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000852A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
