<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004573A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004573A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004573</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10201415</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020722</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F002/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>017110</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>908000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Bone implant and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10201415</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020722</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09609129</doc-number>
<document-date>20000701</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6447545</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>George</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bagby</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Spokane</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WELLS ST. JOHN ROBERTS GREGORY &amp; MATKIN P.S.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>601 W. FIRST AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1300</address-2>
<city>SPOKANE</city>
<state>WA</state>
<postalcode>99201-3828</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A bone joining implant includes a tubular body. The tubular body has an axially extending outer surface defining an outer dimension of substantially uniform cross-section and including a smooth leading insertion portion and a bone engaging trailing portion. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This Preliminary Amendment accompanies a request for a continuation application Examination of the claims in this Preliminary Amendment is requested. This application is a continuation application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/609,129. Original claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> filed in the original patent application have been cancelled. New claims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> have been added. Thus. claims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> remain in this application for consideration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Attached hereto for the convenience of the Examiner is a courtesy copy of the Letter Submitting Formal Drawings and drawings as filed concurrently herewith. These drawings were submitted and approved in the parent application.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This disclosure relates to surgical joining of bone bodies, and more particularly to instruments, implants and methods for self-alignment, instant fixation and staged bone fusion or arthrodesis of bone bodies, such as spinal vertebrae. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> This invention was specifically developed for the surgical joining of bone bodies, such as the fusing of contiguous spinal vertebrae so as to stabilize and prevent relative motion often resulting from a degenerative disc condition. Although the immediate effort leading to this disclosure is directed toward the lumbar, thoracic and cervical spine (anterior or posterior in approach), the described vertebral implants for immediate fixation and staged stabilization leading to arthrodesis (bone fusion) of bone bodies may be used in a bone fracture or osteotomy to fuse together resulting bone bodies, and across one or more joints or articulations. Furthermore, the implants may be used in the lumbar, thoracic and cervical spine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The use of fixation plates and screws to hold together disunited bone bodies has long been known to facilitate arthrodesis or bone-to-bone union, such as bone fusion, and healing of fractured bones. Typically, the separate bone bodies are formed when a single bone fractures, requiring bone reunion. Plates are secured across a fracture region with screws, joining together the bone bodies. The plates hold the bone bodies together in proximate relation, facilitating bone growth and fusion therebetween. In this manner, the bone bodies are supported in close proximity, or in direct contact which facilitates fusion therebetween. However, these techniques are not practical for certain joints such as joints formed between spinal vertebrae. Therefore, a significant number of stabilizing implants have been designed for joining together contiguous vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> One early technique for achieving arthrodesis between adjacent vertebrae across a joint or articulation is the well-known Cloward Technique for use in the human cervical spine. A solitary dowel of bone is tapped into place in a prepared circular bed that is smaller than the dowel of bone. The dowel acts as a wedge, distracting the surrounding soft tissues of the joint, and separating the bone bodies or vertebrae joined there along. The intervertebral disc substantially comprises the soft tissues of the joint. The dowel of bone is inserted, or wedged into place, providing its own stability by putting an annulus of the disc on stretch. Additionally, simple friction of the inserted dowel between adjacent vertebral bodies stabilizes axial dislocation. However, a second surgical procedure must be performed to extract or harvest the dowel of bone, substantially adding trauma to the procedure, increasing costs, as well as increasing the threat of infection to the patient. Alternatively, bank bone from human donors can be used, but bank bone is less osteogenic and may introduce infection, or even transmission of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS) or hepatitis. Furthermore, bone morphogenic protein, hydroxy apatite, or other bone stimulating material may be utilized. Additionally, there has been a need to ensure the implant remains axially secured which has lead to further developments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A step forward from the Cloward Technique was provided by Bagby (U.S. Pat. No. 4,501,269) wherein a metal dowel uses the same principle. A perforated cylindrical hollow implant is inserted between prepared surfaces across a vertebral joint. The inserted implant immediately stabilizes the joint by spreading the bony surfaces apart in wedged opposition to surrounding tissue. This initial stabilization is more substantial because a metal dowel, unlike a bone dowel, will not be absorbed or fatigue in use. Over time, fusion occurs through and around the implant which is filled with bone fragments. Use of the metal dowel eliminates the need for a second operation to harvest a dowel of bone. Bone fragments to be inserted in the implant are retrieved during preparation of the circular beds in each vertebra. Furthermore, such a metal implant avoids the disadvantage of having to use bone bank to obtain donor bone. The Bagby implant described in U.S. Pat. No. 4,501,269 has a smooth outer surface, interrupted only by numerous openings or fenestrations through which bone ingrowth and through growth can occur. Ends of the implant are substantially closed, with one end receiving an end cap such that bone fragments are contained therein. Bone morsels or bone grafts are typically harvested when preparing the circular bed in each vertebra, after which they are placed into the fenestrated metal cylindrical implant. The Bagby implant is then driven or tapped into place in a manner similar to the placement of Cloward&apos;s Bone Dowel, which was solely directed for use in the cervical spine. However, the original Bagby implant relies completely upon stretch of the annulus to stabilize the vertebrae during bone remodeling and fusion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Improvements have also been made to &ldquo;Cloward&apos;s Technique&rdquo; wherein two dowel bone grafts are posteriorly inserted (Wiltberger&apos;s Technique) between adjacent lumbar vertebral bodies. Furthermore, threaded surfaces have been added to such bone grafts in order to keep the grafts in place (Otero-Vich German Application No. 3,505,567, published Jun. 5, 1986). More recently, a number of U.S. Patents have proposed combining the threaded features from threaded bone grafts with a metal implant, resulting in rigid threaded implant structures for placement between adjacent spinal vertebrae. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> One threaded metal fusion implant disclosed in Michelson (U.S. Pat. No. 5,015,247) provides a cylindrical fusion implant having an outer diameter sized larger than the space between adjacent vertebrae to be fused. Threads provided on the exterior of the member engage the vertebrae to axially secure the implant therebetween. The implant has a plurality of openings configured along the cylindrical surface to promote bone ingrowth. However, the threads per se of the implant do not function as a fastener to fix together the adjacent vertebral bodies. Instead, the implant functions as a wedge, imparting a distraction force across the disc which stabilizes the articulation formed therebetween by stretching the annulus of the disc. In fact, the threaded implant relies solely on the annulus to provide stabilization between the vertebrae, in direct response to wedge-induced distraction created therebetween. Distraction of the annulus stabilizes the two vertebrae, enabling ingrowth to later occur within the implant. Therefore, through-growth and fusion (arthrodesis) occur between the adjacent vertebrae subsequent thereto depending on the immobilizing potential of an intact healthy annulus which may or may not be present. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Several additional problems result from the provision of threads on a cylindrical fusion implant. One significant problem with threaded metal fusion implants is that it is very difficult to thread the implant into alignment with prepared bone beds in adjacent vertebral bodies. In practice, such alignment can prove difficult, and the consequences of misalignment can detrimentally affect the ability to achieve fusion between the vertebral bodies and the ability to subsequently achieve arthrodesis. Aligned placement of such an implant is likely to lead to a higher incidence of arthrodesis. Additionally, for cases where a fusion implant does not have a physical retention mechanism for retaining the implant between bone beds, such implant may not be sufficiently mobilized to prevent movement. Such movement will also detrimentally affect the successful incidence of arthrodesis. Yet another problem results in that threads take up additional space which can make implantation in areas having limited anatomical space very difficult, such as in the posterior approach in the lumbar spine. Additionally, the threads effectively make the wall thickness greater which further separates bone provided inside the implant with bone provided outside the implant, which can delay initial bone union. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> For bone fusion to occur with any of the above devices, the invasion of new delicate blood vessels from the adjacent healthy bone is necessary for the creation of new living interconnecting bone. Where complete stabilization does not occur instantaneously upon implantation, motion can disrupt the in growth of delicate blood vessels. Disruption of the vessels then restricts or even prevents bone healing therebetween. The same problem occurs with any of the above mentioned implant techniques, including the threaded techniques of Otero-Vich and Michelson. Even when the annulus is completely on stretch, the threads per se of these constructions do not function in the manner of conventional screws, extending through one object and into another. Namely, they do not function to fasten together adjacent bodies by coaction of the implant with each body. For example, the threads merely act as a series of ridges that engage with each adjacent bone body, while the implant body functions as a wedge. The implant distracts apart the vertebral bodies which stretches the annulus, and stabilizes the articulation as a consequence thereof, while the thread functions solely to prevent axial dislodgement. Furthermore, the presence of threads requires the implant to be screwed in place via a torquing process, instead of tapping the implant directly into position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Hence, some recent designs have resulted in an implant that produces immediate fixation per se between bone bodies following insertion and independent of the annulus. Such designs show promise particularly for cases where the annulus structure is substantially or completely weakened or damaged at surgery. Where the annulus is damaged so significantly as to lose structural integrity, the wedge-effect of prior art threaded implants will not produce any distraction forces across the annulus. Also, when the implant is used to arthrodese and change angulation, a healthy annulus cannot be totally corralled to be placed on stretch. As a result, there is no form of stabilization or fastening between bone bodies sufficient to enable the occurrence of arthrodesis therebetween when the annulus is weakened or inadequate. Additionally, there exist additional shortcomings with such recent designs as discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> One such design that produces immediate fixation is disclosed in Bagby (U.S. Pat. No. 5,709,683) as a bone joining implant having a spline or undercut portion that engages in assembly with each bone body to be joined. However, such design requires the preparation of bone beds that are engaged in interlocking relation with a bone bed engaging portion provided by such undercut portions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Many of the previously described implants can be inserted between vertebrae while such vertebrae are distracted with a distraction tool. One such tool uses a threaded pin which is inserted laterally into each bone body, with such pins being rigidly secured therein. Such tool distracts the vertebrae by separating the pins and vertebrae which stretches the annulus. A drill is then used to drill out bone beds within the vertebrae, after which the implant is inserted therein. However, such procedure does not always impart sufficient distraction and takes time and space to implement. Therefore, techniques that provide further distraction are desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> For the case of vertebral inner body implants which lack the presence of any external threads, the implant is typically tapped into place between bone beds prepared in adjacent vertebral bodies. However, complete tapping of such an implant extending in an anterior to a posterior direction can be somewhat risky as the leading end of the implant is the spinal cord. Accordingly, improvements are desired to minimize any risks resulting from completely tapping an implant into place between pairs of adjacent vertebral bodies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there is a present need to provide an implant device that more accurately aligns itself with prepared bone beds between bone bodies upon implantation, enhances arthrodesis by encouraging bony fusion adjacent the implant, and ensures retention between adjacent bone bodies during insertion. There is also a need to provide such a device that facilitates accurate aligned placement and staged stabilization leading to bone fusion, in a manner that is relatively simple, more reliable, less complicated, has fewer parts, and leads to quicker and more thorough bone fusion and remodeling therebetween. The final stage of bone fusion through and around the implant substantially eliminates any need for the implant to maintain the fusion, thus allowing the bone union to provide primary support therebetween. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A self-aligning, self-fixating, and self-distracting vertebral fusion device is disclosed according to four distinct embodiments. Although not necessary, an additional feature is provided by less than all of the embodiments which encompasses bone joining features that entrap bone projections to instantly fix adjacent bone bodies together, such as instantly fixing adjacent vertebral bodies via the implant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the invention, a bone joining implant includes a tubular body. The tubular body has an axially extending outer surface defining an outer dimension of substantially uniform cross-section and including a smooth leading insertion portion and a bone engaging trailing portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, a vertebral fusion device includes a perforated fusion body. The perforated fusion body has an insertion portion with an axially extending uniform cross-sectional dimension adjacent a leading end and a bone fixating trailing portion adjacent a trailing end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the invention, a vertebral fusion implant includes an elongate, axially extending fusion body. The fusion body includes an insertion portion having an axially extending uniform cross-section and a threaded trailing portion provided at a trailing end of the fusion body. The insertion portion self-aligns the fusion body with bone beds of adjacent vertebrae during implantation. The threaded trailing portion self-fixates the fusion body between the bone beds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to a fourth aspect of the invention, a bone fusion device includes an axial extending body. The axial extending body has a cylindrical leading end portion communicating with a threaded trailing end portion. The threaded trailing end portion includes at least one thread segment extending radially outwardly of an outermost surface of the cylindrical leading end portion. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments of the invention are described below with reference to the following accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a vertebral structure showing a vertebral interbody implant embodying this invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a pair of adjacent vertebrae and illustrating a drill guide and drill bit used to prepare a bore that initiates preparation of bone beds within the vertebrae; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the pair of vertebrae of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, and illustrating a first hole saw used with the drill guide to cut a cylindrical kerf about the bore in order to further prepare the bone beds within the vertebrae; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a simplified side view illustrating a second hole saw of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> used to further cut a further widened cylindrical kerf within the pair of vertebrae; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a kerf cleaning/deburring tool for further widening the kerf produced in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and cleaning debris from the cylindrical kerf formed within the vertebral bodies; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view taken from the leading, insertion end of the vertebral interbody implant of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for insertion within the prepared bone beds of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view taken from the driven end of the vertebral interbody implant of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side view of the vertebral interbody implant of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a leading end view of the vertebral interbody implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a driven end view of the vertebral interbody implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an unrolled plan view of the outer peripheral surface of the vertebral interbody implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> further illustrating the smooth leading end and the threaded, retaining trailing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> end of the vertebral interbody implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13 a</cross-reference> perspective view illustrating an implant insertion tool usable for inserting and threading the implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> within the prepared bone beds of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a simplified frontal view illustrating a pair of vertebrae that have bone beds prepared according to the steps depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> comprising a cylindrical kerf; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a simplified frontal view illustrating the vertebrae of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> in an instantly fixed and slightly distracted position caused by inserting the implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> within the bone beds of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a simplified, sagittal and centerline view of the implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> prior to insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a simplified, sagittal and centerline view of the implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> during insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a simplified, sagittal and centerline view of the implant of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> after insertion; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a surgical time simplified sagittal view of the implant of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> received within the prepared bone beds of adjacent vertebrae and containing bone fragments immediately following implantation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a healed time simplified sagittal view of the implant of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> received within the prepared bone beds of adjacent vertebrae and illustrating the vertebra following bone remodeling and reorganization and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> showing arthrodesis; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a coronal view of the implant and healed bone comprising vertebrae and taken along line <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> and showing arthrodesis; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternatively constructed vertebral interbody implant similar to the embodiment depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for insertion within prepared bone beds formed solely by generating a bore as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternatively constructed vertebral interbody implant similar to the embodiment depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for insertion within prepared bone beds formed solely by generating a bore as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternatively constructed vertebral interbody implant similar to the embodiment depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for insertion within prepared bone beds formed solely by generating a bore as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> This disclosure of the invention is submitted in furtherance of the constitutional purposes of the U.S. Patent Laws &ldquo;to promote the progress of science and useful arts&rdquo; (Article 1, Section 8). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made to a preferred embodiment of Applicant&apos;s invention. Four exemplary implementations are described below and depicted with reference to the drawings comprising various self-aligning and self-fixating bone joining implants. A first embodiment is shown and described below in a first mounting configuration with reference generally to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Second through fourth embodiments are shown and described below with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, respectively. While the invention is described by way of several preferred embodiments, it is understood that the description is not intended to limit the invention to these embodiments, but is intended to cover alternatives, equivalents, and modifications which may be broader than these embodiments such as are defined within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In an effort to prevent obscuring the invention at hand, only details germane to implementing the invention will be described in great detail, with presently understood peripheral details being incorporated by reference, as needed, as being presently understood in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A preferred embodiment bone joining implant in accordance with the invention is first described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Such an implant is further described below with respect to a cylindrical, open-ended vertebral inter-body implant having self-aligning and self-fixating features. Additionally, an optional feature includes a leading open end in the form of a cylindrical inner surface that entraps bone projections, and a tapered leading end that provides limited self-distraction. The self-aligning and self-fixating implant is designated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> generally with reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> A first alternative implementation comprising a cylindrical vertebral inter-body implant similar to implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> above, but with a pair of end flanges and a central bulkhead flange, is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>. A second alternative implementation comprising a tubular, rectangular cross-section implant with a plurality of retaining tabs provided about a trailing surface portion is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>. A third alternative implementation comprising a cylindrical vertebral inter-body implant with a smooth leading outer surface portion and a plurality of retaining tabs provided about a trailing surface portion is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a rigid, unitary body having a cylindrical leading edge <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and a cylindrical outer surface <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, with an open leading end <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>). As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted within an aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> that has been prepared between a pair of adjacent vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> within a vertebral column <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is prepared within vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and along disc <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, according to the procedure and tools depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and described below in further detail. Aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> forms a pair of vertebral bone bodies <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> that are formed to have a cylindrical configuration comprising a cylindrical kerf <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). A leading cylindrical end of implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted into aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, causing vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to be instantly fixed together (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> below). An open leading end <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) of implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> entraps an intact living bone projection <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> on each respective vertebral body (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) which imparts immediate fixation between adjacent vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> upon implantation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> More particularly, vertebrae <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprise neighboring bone bodies of a vertebral column <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). A resilient articulation or joint is formed between vertebra <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by disc <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> extending between vertebrae <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Anatomically, the disc is made up of a central nucleus pulposus and an outer encircling annulus. The annulus and nucleus pulposus are composed of laminae of fibrous tissue and fibro-cartilage. The nucleus pulposus, located at the center of the disc, comprises a soft, pulpy, and highly elastic substance. The annulus is formed from laminae of fibrous tissue extending in a criss-crossing fashion to encircle the nucleus pulposus. Additionally, the intervertebral disc is adherent, by its cephalad and caudad surfaces, to a thin layer of hyaline cartilage that covers the top and bottom surfaces of adjacent vertebrae. In a healthy patient, adjacent vertebra <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are spaced apart by disc <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. However, degenerative disc disease and localized trauma can cause degradation or complete loss of the soft tissue components between neighboring vertebrae. For example, the annulus can partially or completely tear which can seriously degrade the structural condition of the articulation. Additionally, fluid can escape from the nucleus pulposus. When any of the above happens, vertebrae <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, loaded by the normal weight bearing of a patient, are is pressed into closer adjoining positions, which can result in pinching of nerves that extend from between vertebrae of the spinal column (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there is a need to recover the disc spacing provided by a normal healthy disc <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by way of inserting implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, there is a need to provide implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a fixation that aligns implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> during insertion and instantly interlocks adjacent vertebra <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> together upon being implanted. Furthermore, there is a need for such an implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that retains itself in place upon insertion, and that facilitates staged stabilization resulting in arthrodesis to occur between the vertebral bodies, following initial implantation. Even furthermore, there is a need to instantly fix adjacent vertebrae together since relative motion can otherwise cause pinching of nerve tissue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As a result, implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be inserted, preferably in a central location between adjacent vertebrae <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of patients who have bad, ruptured or degenerative discs. Furthermore, implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be axially oriented anterior to posterior, or even laterally. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In summary, implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is adapted for implantation between prepared bony surfaces or beds <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and across the articulation formed by disc <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A typical implantation might involve placement of one or more implants <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as required in order to stabilize and fix the joint during bone ingrowth and through-growth of the implant structure. Bone growth is also accomplished outside of and surrounding the implant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, a pair of somewhat smaller sized and laterally adjacent implants can also be used. However, such dual implant implementation uses individual implants that are sized smaller than the single implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As a result, such dual implant implementation uses smaller sized apertures which do not invade as much cancellous bone as the aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) prepared for receiving the larger sized single implant implementation depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> A solitary implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> invades cancellous bone since aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has a larger diameter. In contrast, smaller sized dual implants tend to invade mostly cortical bone on the end plates. However, cancellous bone is more desirable for bone growth during staged bony fusion since cancellous bone is more osteogenic than cortical bone. New growth bone, or callus bone, comprises soft cancellous bone that only becomes hard (cortical) over time via action of Wolff&apos;s Law of maturity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Applicant&apos;s implant depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generates a limited amount of self-distraction during insertion between a pair of vertebral bodies due to tapered portion <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Such feature provides an additional desirable benefit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> illustrate the various steps used to prepare aperture <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and bone beds <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> within vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, respectively (of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Such figures illustrate one technique for preparing a suitable pair of bone beds within adjacent vertebrae <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for receiving implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) such that self-alignment, self-fixation, self-distraction and immediate fixation are imparted between vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a tool guide <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and a drill bit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> that are used to drill a bore <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) into vertebral bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and disc <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Bore <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is drilled partially into bodies <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so as to leave sufficient intact living bone to create bone projections <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> after smooth insertion portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> has been received within bore <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, but prior to engaging interlocking trailing portion <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> therein. Additionally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates a substantial portion of disc <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> removed, or resected, prior to insertion of implant <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so as to facilitate arthrodesis as discussed below.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">In the claims: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. (New) A bone implant, comprising a body with a smooth leading portion, a bone-engaging trailing portion, and opposed lateral portions, each portion adapted for placement toward adjacent bone bodies, and the bone-engaging trailing portion including a plurality of retaining tabs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> wherein the smooth leading portion is configured to align the body between adjacent bone bodies during insertion between a pair of adjacent bone bodies. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> wherein a first retaining tab is provided in a first opposed lateral portion and a second retaining tab is provided in a second opposed lateral portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> wherein the body has a rectangular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> wherein the body comprises a tubular body having a rectangular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> wherein the at least one retaining tab comprises a plurality of retaining tabs raised from an outer surface of the trailing portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the retaining tabs are forcibly urged into engagement with bone beds of adjacent vertebra upon implantation of the bone implant therebetween so as to prevent movement of the bone implant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. (New) The bone implant of claim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> wherein the smooth leading portion aligns the body between adjacent bone bodies and the bone-engaging trailing portion interlocks the bone implant between the adjacent bone bodies. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. (New) A method for implanting a bone implant between adjacent bone bodies, comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a body having a smooth leading portion, a bone-engaging trailing portion, and opposed lateral portions adapted for placement toward adjacent bone bodies; </claim-text>
<claim-text>excavating a pair of adjacent bone bodies to receive the body therebetween </claim-text>
<claim-text>axially inserting the smooth leading portion of the body between the prepared adjacent bone bodies to axially align the body therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forcibly axially urging the bone-engaging trailing portion of the body between the adjacent bone bodies to retain the body therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030004573A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
