<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002009A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002009A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002009A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002009A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002009A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002009A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002009A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002009A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002009</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09892908</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02C009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>351</class>
<subclass>047000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Clip-on type sunglasses</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tsuyoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Shono</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kawasaki-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>STAAS &amp; HALSEY LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>700 11TH STREET, NW</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20001</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Clip-on type sunglasses are constituted by a pair of sunglass lenses and a bridge member connecting these lenses. The two lenses respectively have a mounting clip member for mounting to the front endpiece or the rim end portion of spectacles; in order to mount on the bridge of spectacles, the mounting clip members are formed integrally with the bridge member. For mounting on spectacles of the rimless or wire frame type, light weight and neat external appearance are realized. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to clip-on type sunglasses, and in particular to clip-on type sunglasses having a bridge member which mounts on the bridge of spectacles. Such sunglasses are also known as overlenses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> When going outdoors, and especially when experiencing glare when the weather is fine, sunglasses are generally worn. However, when a person wears spectacles for eyesight correction, removing the spectacles and putting on sunglasses is risky. A person who desires the function of both spectacles and sunglasses can eliminate or reduce the risk by mounting clip-on type sunglasses on the spectacles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Various clip-on type sunglasses have heretofore been proposed. For example, please refer to U.S. Pat. No. 5,696,571 or Japanese Registered Utility Model No. 3,032,862. These sunglasses have mounting clip members for mounting to the lenses of spectacles. The mounting clip members are shown by reference numbers <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> of the U.S. &apos;571 patent and by reference number <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> of the Japanese &apos;862 Utility Model. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, the rimless type of spectacles, without a &ldquo;rim which supports the (whole edge of the) lens&rdquo; (U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,748,280, 5,585,870), or the wire frame (metal wire frame) type of spectacles which support only the upper edge of the lens with a wire rim (metal wire rim) (for example, U.S. Pat. No. 6,070,978), have become popular. In the wire frame type, the lower edge of the lens is fixed in the wire rim and is kept up by a filament or fine wire. Because the rim supporting the lens is absent or small in these spectacles, the external appearance is neat as viewed by another person. Furthermore, because of the absent or small rim, there is the advantage that the spectacles are lightweight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the case of mounting clip-on sunglasses on such rimless type or wire rim type spectacles, the mounting clip member is disadvantageous. This is because cases can occur in which they cannot be mounted, because the thickness of the spectacle lenses differs according to their owner. Even in cases in which mounting is possible, it can then be that the mounting member comes into contact with the spectacle lens. The reason for this is that there is no rim on the lower edge of the lens. Because of this, the mounting member of the prior art clip-on type sunglasses risked damaging the lens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the prior art clip-on type sunglasses are equipped with a rim which supports the sunglass lens. Because of this, the clip-on type sunglasses are heavy. A person who has selected light, rimless type or wire frame type spectacles dislikes heavy sunglasses. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention has as its first object to provide clip-on type sunglasses whose mounting members do not risk damage to the lenses. A second object is to provide lightweight clip-on type sunglasses. A third object is to provide clip-on type sunglasses having a neat external appearance, with no rim. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The clip-on type sunglasses of the present invention comprise first and second sunglass lenses and a bridge member which connects these lenses; the said first and second sunglass lenses are equipped with first and second mounting clip members connected to the said bridge member at places on opposite sides. These members are in order to mount onto the front endpiece or rim end portion of the spectacles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The said bridge member is furthermore equipped with a third mounting clip member in order to mount this bridge member to the bridge of the spectacles; the said bridge member and the said third mounting clip member are formed integrally. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The first and second mounting clip members are preferably hook-shaped; this hook shape is mounted, overlapping from above, on the said front endpiece or rim end portion, and preferably, the third mounting clip member has an upward-open groove, the bridge of the spectacles being inserted into this groove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As another preferred feature, the first and second mounting clip members are hook-shaped; this hook shape is mounted, overlapping from below, on the front endpiece or rim end portion, and preferably, the third mounting clip member has a downward-open groove, and the bridge of the spectacles is inserted into this groove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> When the sunglasses are seen from the front, the said first mounting clip member, the said third mounting clip member, and the said second mounting clip member are preferably positioned on an upward-directed or downward-directed, gentle circular arc (on a line describing an arch). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In order for light weight, all the components of the clip-on type sunglasses of the present invention are preferably made of plastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The clip-on type sunglasses of the present invention are preferably mounted on rimless type or wire frame type spectacles.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an elevation, seen from the front, of one example of the clip-on type sunglasses of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of the sunglasses of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of the sunglasses of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an elevation, seen from the front, of the sunglasses of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in the state mounted temporarily on wire frame type spectacles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a top view of the sunglasses and spectacles of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of the sunglasses and spectacles of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross sectional diagram of the bridge member drawn in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an enlarged diagram; the neighborhood indicated by B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is enlarged.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A preferred mode of embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. However, the scope of the invention is not to be considered as limited by this embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> These sunglasses, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, comprise a first sunglass lens (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), a second sunglass lens (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), and a bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) connecting these lenses. The first and second sunglass lenses respectively have a first mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and a second mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), respectively connected to the said bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) at places on opposite sides. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, these mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) are hook-shaped (about the shape of the character &ldquo;<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>&rdquo;). The mounting of the mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) can be such that they overlap the front endpiece or rim end portion (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) of the spectacles from above. The sunglasses can be mounted on the spectacles in this manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The said bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, has a third mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). The bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and the mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) are integrally formed, comprising a single component. The third mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) mounts the bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) on the bridge (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) of the spectacles. Because the third mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) has, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> groove (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) opened in the upward direction, the bridge (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) fills up this groove (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The sunglasses are securely mounted to the spectacles by means of the three mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) integrally formed with the bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), together with the two mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), are preferably made of plastic. Here, in order to make them colorless and transparent, nylon or polyurethane was used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> However, if there is no great concern about color or transparency, other plastics may be used. For example, aliphatic polyamides, aromatic polyamides, ABS, AS resin, polyethylene (low density or high density), polystyrene, polypropylene, and the like polyolefins, polyvinyl chloride, polyvinylidene chloride, ethylene-(vinyl acetate) copolymer, polyvinyl alcohol, polyacetal, polycarbonate, polyethylene terephthalate, polybutylene terephthalate, and the like saturated polyesters, aromatic polyesters, polyether ketones, polyether ether ketones, polysulfones, polyether sulfones, polyetherimides, polyarylates, ionomers, liquid crystal polymers, polymethylpentene, polyimides, polyamide-imides, fluororesins, polyphenylene sulfides, (modified or unmodified) polyphenylene oxides, and the like thermoplastic resins, or, epoxy resins, unsaturated polyesters, polyimides and the like thermosetting resins, can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The mounting clip members and bridge member can be colored to a preferred color. However, it is preferable to make those members colorless and transparent, so that they do not attract attention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The method of mounting (fixing) the bridge member (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and the two mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) to the sunglasses (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) can be carried out by various methods according to the prior art. Here, opening a small, oblong elliptical (or even rectangular) hole in the frame, those members are mounted or fixed to the lens by means of hot caulking or ultrasonic caulking. Those members may also be fixed to the lenses by means of adhesives instead of by hot caulking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In the case that all the components are made of plastic, these sunglasses are lightweight (barely 1-4 g). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> For example, the sunglasses (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) are preferably made of acrylic resin, polycarbonate and the like thermoplastic resin, diethylene glycol diaryl dicarbonate (common name, CR-39) resin, and the like thermosetting resin. The reason is that these resins, in comparison with glass, are lightweight and safe, and the degree of freedom of shape is high. The degree of optical transmissivity can then be optionally reduced by means of coloration or dyeing of the resin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the case of dyeing, half dyeing or gradational dyeing may be adopted. However, the term &ldquo;sunglasses&rdquo; in the present invention is not limited to these, and the lenses may also be polarizing lenses or mirror lenses. Mirror lenses are those on which a mirror coating has been performed on the surface of the lenses. Here, polarizing lenses were used, made of polycarbonate 0.8 mm thick and dyed black to have a light ray transmissivity of <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>%. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> According to the case, the sunglass lenses (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) may be normal lenses having dioptric power. A correction is not possible with one pair of spectacles for a person who has become presbyopic. Such a person, even when wearing one pair of spectacles, cannot see near or cannot see far objects. In this case it is necessary to substitute spectacles equipped with special correcting lenses. Because substitution is troublesome, in such a case, clip-on type spectacles equipped with lenses having dioptric power are put on (mounted) on the spectacles already being worn. The present invention also provides clip-on type spectacles equipped with such lenses having dioptric power. In this case, lenses having dioptric power are used in place of the sunglass lenses (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) as described hereinabove. These lenses having dioptric power can of course have combined use as sunglass lenses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The mounting of the sunglasses of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> on spectacles is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. These spectacles are of the wire frame type. The principal portion of the wire frame is a wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) made by bending a single wire of 1 mm diameter. The wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) is constituted by lens support portions (left, right pair) which support the upper edges of the spectacle lenses (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>), and a bridge portion which connects these. A groove of 1 mm width is disposed in the narrow edge surface of the lenses (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) along the whole circumference. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) is inserted into the grooves in the upper edges of these lenses (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). Side end portions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) close to the temples (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) of the wire frame (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) are free, and do not contact the lenses (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> According to the case, these end portions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) can be regarded as a front endpiece. These end portions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), after being bent through about <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>E, continue to the hinges (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>). The temples (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) connect to the wire frame (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) via the hinges (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Two mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) are mounted to respective free end portions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>). Please refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 8</cross-reference>. In a special case which is not shown here, the free end portions in the mounted state are elastically deformed in comparison with their state prior to mounting. In the case of elastic deformation, a stress which may return the free end portions to the original state is exerted on the mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). Because of the stress, the mounting clip members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) and the end portions (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) press against each other. Because of this, in a particular case, the sunglasses come off the spectacles only with difficulty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The lower edges of the spectacle lenses (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) are supported by a subsidiary wire (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) of diameter 0.7 mm. The ends of the subsidiary wire (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) on the temple sides are wound around and joined to the respective wire rims (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). A second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A) is constituted close to the center of the subsidiary wire (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>). The second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) is about parallel to the bridge portion of the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). There is a curved portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>B) at each end of the second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A) in order to mount a nose pad. The second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A) of the subsidiary wire (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) and the bridge portion of the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) are both inserted into the groove (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) of the bridge member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>). In this state, the bridge portion of the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and the second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A) elastically deform in a direction to mutually narrow the gap. Because of this, stresses are exerted on the respective groove side surfaces at positions closer to the lenses of the two grooves (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) (that is, toward the left and right ends, when the groove is seen from above). Because of this, it is hard for the bridge portion of the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and the second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>A) to come out of the groove. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In addition to this, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the groove has a narrow width at the surface, and its width is wide in the middle. Because of this, the second bridge portion (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) comes out of the groove (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>A) only with difficulty, because of the overhang. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When the sunglasses are seen from the front, the first mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), the third mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>), and the second mounting clip member (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) are arranged on a gentle, upward-directed circular arc (on a line describing an arch). This arrangement can also be modified to a special arrangement. The special arrangement is an arrangement in which, by means of the action of mounting the sunglasses, the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) is bent comparatively slightly (elastic deformation) before mounting the sunglasses. When these members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) mount the sunglasses comprising the special arrangement to the wire rim, the metallic wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) returns to its original shape, and these members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) receive stress from the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). Due to this stress, the wire rim (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and these members (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) press against each other. In this manner, in the special arrangement, the restoring force of the wire rim is used to prevent the sunglasses from coming off the spectacles. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses constituted by first and second sunglass lenses, and a bridge member connecting these lenses, 
<claim-text>the said first and second sunglass lenses are equipped with first and second mounting clip members, on opposite sides at places connected to the said bridge member, in order to mount on the front endpiece or rim end portion of the spectacles; furthermore, the said bridge member is equipped with a third mounting clip member in order to mount this bridge member on the bridge of the spectacles, and the clip-on type sunglasses have the said bridge member and the said third mounting clip member formed integrally. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the said first and second mounting clip members are hook-shaped, this hook shape is mounted, overlapping from above, on the said front endpiece or rim end portion, the said third mounting clip member has a groove opened upward, and the said bridge is inserted into this groove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the said first and second mounting clip members are hook-shaped, this hook shape is mounted, overlapping from below, on the said front endpiece or rim end portion, the said third mounting clip member has a groove opened downward, and the said bridge is inserted into this groove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the sunglasses are seen from the front, the said first mounting clip member, the said third mounting clip member, and the said second mounting clip member, are arranged on a upward-directed or downward-directed, gentle circular arc. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein they are made completely of plastic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the said first and second sunglass lenses are polarizing lenses, mirror lenses, dyed lenses, or colored lenses. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type eyeglasses, constituted by first and second lenses having dioptric power, and a bridge member connecting these lenses, 
<claim-text>the said first and second eyeglass lenses having dioptric power are equipped with first and second mounting clip members, on opposite sides at places connected to the said bridge member, in order to mount in the front endpiece or rim edge portion of the spectacles; furthermore, the said bridge member is equipped with a third mounting clip member in order to mount this bridge member on the bridge of the spectacles, and the clip-on type eyeglasses have the said bridge member and the said third mounting clip member formed integrally. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second sunglass lenses have dioptric power. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in order to mount on rimless or wire frame type spectacles. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Clip-on type sunglasses having a weight of 1-4 g.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002009A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002009A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002009A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002009A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
