<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005370A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005370A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005370</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10145880</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020516</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>JP 2001-196505</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H03M013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>714</class>
<subclass>709000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Modem apparatus with error detection functions and error detection method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Keiichi</given-name>
<family-name>Tomita</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yokohama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nobuhiko</given-name>
<family-name>Noma</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yokohama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tatsuo</given-name>
<family-name>Imai</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Chigasaki-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Matsushita Graphic Communication Systems, Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>GREENBLUM &amp; BERNSTEIN, P.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1941 ROLAND CLARKE PLACE</address-1>
<city>RESTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>20191</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In multi-carrier communication, error amounts, which are deviations between the coordinate points of eye patterns detected from actual reception signals of each sub-carrier, and the target coordinate points of eye patterns from the reception signals are calculated by an eye pattern display controller and displayed on an oscilloscope. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a modem apparatus with error detection functions and an error detection method that detect communication errors from observations of reception status based on eye patterns detected from reception signals in multi-carrier communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, for a maintenance check of modem apparatuses, reception status is observed to detect factors for communication malfunction. A maintenance check is performed by connecting an oscilloscope to a modem, displaying an eye patterns that is detected on the oscilloscope from reception signals, and comparing the eye pattern with a normal eye pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates a normal eye pattern that is detected from 2-bit reception signals. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), normal eye patterns are detected at the same places without differing from one another; therefore, each point of the eye pattern is displayed in small dots on the oscilloscope screen as a result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates an abnormal eye pattern in case of imperfect line conditions. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), detected signal points are diverged compared to the normal signal points; thus, each point of the eye pattern is displayed in large dots on the oscilloscope screen as a result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and (<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrate eye patterns, in normal and abnormal situations respectively, both which are detected from 4-bit reception signals. A maintenance check of a modem apparatus is performed by comparing such normal and abnormal eye patterns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The above maintenance method for a modem apparatus can be used in single-carrier communication; however, the same cannot be applied for ADSL modems that employ multi-carrier communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In other words, in single-carrier communication, maintenance check can be performed by displaying one eye pattern of reception signals in a single-carrier, by an oscilloscope. However, in multi-carrier communication, due to the restriction of apparatuses, an oscilloscope can only display an eye pattern of reception signals in one of the multi-carriers, and eye patterns of reception signals of other carriers are not displayed. Therefore, in multi-carrier communication, it has been impossible to perform a maintenance check of modem apparatuses and to detect communication errors. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> This invention is provided in view of the above-described problems. The object of the present invention is to provide a modem apparatus with error detection functions and an error detection method that enable an observer to detect communication errors from observations of reception status based on eye patterns detected from reception signals, even in multi-carrier communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, in multi-carrier communication, error amounts, which are deviations between the coordinate points of eye patterns detected from actual reception signals of each sub-carrier, and the target coordinate points of eye patterns from the reception signals are displayed on an error detector, such as an oscilloscope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the error amount of reception signals of each sub-carrier can be displayed as an eye pattern on the error detector. Therefore, it is possible to enable an observer to detect communication errors, through observations of reception status, based on eye patterns that are detected from reception signals of all sub-carriers even in multi-carrier communication.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present invention is further described in the detailed description which follows, with reference to the noted plurality of drawings by way of non-limiting examples of exemplary embodiments of the present invention, in which like reference numerals represent similar parts throughout the several views of the drawings, and wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a configuration of a modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates frequency characteristics of multi-carriers in a DMT method, which is used in ITU-T standards, such as G.922.1; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating an error amount calculation of reception signals at the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a reception point of an actual reception signals and a target point plotted from the reception signals as coordinate points on an X-Y plane of an oscilloscope display screen, according to the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates sub-carriers that are processed to calculate error amounts of reception signals according to the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates an example of the oscilloscope screen displaying a normal error amount that is output by the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates an example of the oscilloscope screen displaying an abnormal error amount that is output by the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating a normal error amount calculation of reception signals by the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates an example of the oscilloscope screen displaying a normalized error amount in a normal condition, which is output by the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates an example of the oscilloscope screen displaying a normalized error amount in an abnormal condition, which is output by the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates an eye pattern in a normal condition that is detected by 2-bit reception signals (prior art); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates an eye pattern in an abnormal condition that is detected by 2-bit reception signals (prior art); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates an eye pattern in a normal condition that is detected by 4-bit reception signals (prior art); and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) illustrates an eye pattern in an abnormal condition that is detected by 4-bit reception signals (prior art).</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The embodiments of the present invention are explained in the following, in reference to the above-described drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> First Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a configuration of the modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the first embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an A/D (D/A) converter <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> performs a digital/analog conversion process (D/A conversion process) for signals that are output to a public switched telephone network (PSTN), and performs an analog/digital conversion process (A/D conversion process) for signals that are input from the PSTN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> An FFT (Fast Fourier Transform) processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> performs a Fourier conversion process for signals after the A/D conversion process by the A/D (D/A) converter <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The signals after the Fourier conversion process are output to a main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> An IFFT (Inverse Fast Fourier Transform) processor <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> performs a reverse Fourier conversion process for the signals that are delivered from the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, and outputs the signals to the A/D (D/A) converter <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> controls the entire modem apparatus that is provided with error detection functions. Also, based on the output from the FFT processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> (hereafter referred to as FFT output), the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> calculates a deviation (hereafter referred to as error amount) between a coordinate point (hereafter referred to as reception point) of an eye pattern that is displayed on an error detector, such as an oscilloscope, and a coordinate point (hereafter referred to as target point) of a target eye pattern that is plotted from the FFT output. The main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> comprises an eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> that controls to display the error amount as an eye pattern on the error detector. The error amount calculation at the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is later described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The data to show the error amount, which is calculated by the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, is input to the eye pattern display interface (I/F) <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> outputs the input data from the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> as coordinate information on an X-Y plane on the display screen of an oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, which functions as an error detector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The modem apparatus with error detection functions enables an observer to detect communication errors in multi-carrier communication adhering to ITU-T standards, such as G.992.1 (G.DMT) and G.992.2 (G.lite), through observations of the reception status, based on the eye patterns that are detected from reception signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In standards such as G.992.1, the DMT (Discrete Multi Tone) is employed as a modulating/demodulating method. The DMT method is a multi-carrier modulating/demodulating method that uses multiple carriers (sub-carriers) with different frequencies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates frequency characteristics of multi-carriers in the DMT method. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, lateral axis is frequency (f/kHz), and vertical axis is gain amount (G/db). The DMT method has 250 sub-carriers with different frequencies of 4 kHz range. In such standards, sub-carriers are usually divided into outbound signals (transmission signals) and inbound signals (reception signals); however, for the convenience of explanation, the sub-carriers in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> are all sub-carriers of inbound signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The modem apparatus with error detection functions, according to the present embodiment, unlike the conventional modem apparatuses, displays not only the eye patterns of reception signals on an oscilloscope, but also the error amounts (error amounts of reception signals), which are deviations between coordinate points of eye patterns of actual reception signals of each sub-carrier, and the coordinate points of the eye patterns that are originally plotted from the reception signals, on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. In other words, deviations of reception signals created in each sub-carrier, due to factors such as line conditions, are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> To display what is described above on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the modem apparatus with error detection functions according to the embodiment of the present invention, adds a carrier index with a number, to each sub-carrier. The carrier indexes are lined up in the order of their frequency amounts, from low to high frequencies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> From now on, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is used to illustrate a flow for the modem apparatus with error detection functions to calculate an error amount of reception signals. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating a calculation of error amounts of reception signals at the modem apparatus with error detection functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> This flow starts when the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, as an error detector, is connected to the modem apparatus with error detection functions, and the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> gives an instruction to display the eye pattern of reception signals. The flow ends when the connected oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> sends an instruction to end the display of the eye pattern of reception signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> When the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> is connected, and upon receiving of an instruction for eye pattern display of reception signals from the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> of the modem apparatus with error detection functions first initializes carrier indexes (N) (ST<highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>). Accordingly, the sub-carrier that is used to calculate the error amount of the reception signals becomes sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. Then, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> waits for a symbol interruption (ST<highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In the modem apparatus with error detection functions, a symbol interruption is performed every 250&mgr; second. The sample data of the reception signals are obtained about every 1&mgr; second. Accordingly, about every 1&mgr; second, the A/D (D/A) converter <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> performs the A/D conversion process and outputs the data to the FFT processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. If there is a symbol interruption, the FFT processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> performs the FFT process for the sampling data (ST<highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>). Thus, when the sampling data is stored for one symbol, the FFT processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> performs the FIT process once. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Here, the sub-carrier that is used to calculate the error amount of the reception signals is a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. Therefore, when the FFT process is performed, the sampling data that corresponds with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; is shown as a coordinate point of an I-R (Imaginary-Real) plane. The coordinate information of the I-R plane is output to the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> calculates the error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, based on the coordinate information of the I-R plane (ST<highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>). From now on, the error amount calculation of the reception signals by the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is further explained. The coordinate information on the I-R plane that is input by the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> represents the coordinate information of an X-Y plane on the display screen of the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an actual reception point of reception signals and a target point plotted from the reception signals as coordinate points on the X-Y plane of the display screen of the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the target point is (x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>), and the actual reception point of reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; is (x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> searches for the distance between these reception point and target point. The distance that is searched here represents the error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In particular, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> calculates (x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&minus;x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&plus;(y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&minus;y<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, and by retrieving the distance between these reception and target points, an error amount of reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; is calculated. In this embodiment, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated as an error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Upon calculating the error amount &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; to the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (ST<highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>). The eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, then outputs &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, as coordinate information of the X-Y plane on the display screen of the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. At this time, the coordinate information for X-axis is determined based on the carrier index, while the coordinate information for Y-axis is determined based on the calculated error amount. For example, the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;1&rdquo;, which is a corresponding value of Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, as the coordinate information for X-axis, while outputting &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, which is an error amount calculated from the reception signal for Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, as the coordinate information for Y-axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> After outputting the error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; to the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> increases the number of the carrier index (N) by one (ST<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). Accordingly, the sub-carrier that is used to calculate the error amount of the reception signals becomes a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Upon increasing the number of the carrier index (N) by one, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> checks whether the number indicates the maximum carrier index (ST<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>). At this time, Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo; is checked. In this embodiment, the maximum carrier index is &ldquo;255&rdquo;, for example. Therefore, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> goes to the process at Step <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, and waits for another symbol interruption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> If there is a symbol interruption, the FFT processor <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> performs the FFT process, similar to the process of Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; (ST<highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight>). In this case, the sub-carrier that is used to calculate the error amount of reception signals is a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;, therefore, after the FFT process, the sampling data that corresponds with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo; is displayed as a coordinate point on the I-R plane. The coordinate information of the I-R plane is output to the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> This time, at the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> calculates the error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo; (ST<highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>). In this case, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated as the error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> After the error amount &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; to the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (ST<highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>). Then, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> increases the number of carrier index (N) by one again (ST<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). Accordingly, the sub-carrier that is used to calculate the error amount of the reception signals becomes a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;3&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Likewise, the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the present embodiment calculates an error amount of reception signals of current sub-carrier, every time there is a symbol interruption, outputs the error amount to the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, and increases the sub-carriers that are used to calculate the error amount of the reception signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates sub-carriers that are used to calculate error amounts of reception signals. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the sub-carriers are increased, every time there is a symbol interruption. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates a sub-carrier for the first symbol interruption, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) is for the second symbol interruption, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>) is for the third symbol interruption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Therefore, when there is the first symbol interruption (symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00001"/>), an error amount of the reception signals of a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; is calculated. When there is the second symbol interruption (symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00002"/>, an error amount of the reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo; is calculated. Similarly, the carrier indexes are increased in order, so that the error amount of reception signals of each sub-carrier is individually calculated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Upon increasing the carrier indexes that are used to calculate error amounts of reception signals, and when a maximum carrier index is found at Step <highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> initializes the carrier index (N) (ST<highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>), and goes to the process at Step <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, and waits for another symbol interruption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) illustrates an example of the screen of oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, when the error amount that is output from the modem apparatus with error detection functions is displayed. After the above-described calculation, when there is symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00003"/>, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is displayed as an error amount of the reception signals of the sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, and when there is symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00004"/>, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is displayed as an error amount of the reception signals of the sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;. Similarly, for every symbol interruption, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&rdquo; . . . &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, and &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>&rdquo; are displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), carrier index is used for coordinate information for the X-axis, each plot is arranged from a predetermined point in the order of carrier index number, toward the positive direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the closer each error amount is to &ldquo;0&rdquo; (i.e., closer to X-axis), the less the error amount of reception signals of each sub-carrier. By repeating the flow of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the observer can observe error amounts of reception signals for each sub-carrier. For example, the error amounts shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) are averaged amounts of normal error amount of reception signals for each sub-carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In comparison with the observation of such averaged amounts, an observer can connect the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> to the modem apparatus with error detection functions, and check the error amounts of reception signals for each sub-carrier. Then, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) can be displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> to show error amounts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In this case, by comparing with the error amounts of reception signals observed before (error amounts of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>)), the observer can recognize that the current reception status is not normal. Also, with the display of error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the observer can confirm the actual level of error in each sub-carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> According to the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the present embodiment, error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> as an eye pattern. Therefore, from the observation of reception status based on the eye pattern, which is detected from the reception signals of all the sub-carriers, the observer can detect error amounts even in multi-carrier communication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Also, error amounts of reception signals for each sub-carrier are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the observer can confirm among the multi-carriers which sub-carrier has abnormal reception status. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Second Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The difference between the first and second embodiments is that the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment calculates error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier, while the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment calculates error amounts that are normalized from the error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier (normalized error amounts). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In ITU-T standards such as G.992.1 (G.DMT), suppression of data transmission quality degradation is performed by decreasing the data amount of sub-carriers that have transmitted wave hindrances such as noise. In particular, using results from C and R-Medley of G.992.1 (G.DMT), data amounts of each sub-carrier are set according to conditions such as line conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment focuses on the above-described point not only calculates error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier, but also calculates normalized error amounts that are normalized from the calculated error amounts. Specifically, after calculating error amounts in a similar method as the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment, the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment performs an exponential operation of &ldquo;2&rdquo; (2<highlight><superscript>n</superscript></highlight>), for the error amount, using data amount of each sub-carrier, which is the bit number (n) that is assigned to each sub-carrier, to retrieve a normalized error amount. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Particularly, the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment can confirm the actual level of communication error in each sub-carrier, however, it is unable to detect which sub-carrier is likely to have communication errors. The modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment is able to detect which sub-carrier is likely to have errors, by further normalizing calculated error amounts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment has the same configuration as the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment, except in the following areas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> has a function to normalize calculated error amounts, in addition to the functions of eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment has a function to calculate normalized error amount by performing the exponential operation of &ldquo;2&rdquo; (2<highlight><superscript>n</superscript></highlight>), for the calculated error amount, using the data amount set in each sub-carrier, which is the bit number (n) that is assigned to each sub-carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> From now on, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is used to illustrate the flow of calculating normalized error amounts from reception signals by the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flowchart to illustrate the calculation of normalized error amount of reception signals by the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the process with the same Step numberings as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> performs the same process as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The flow in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> also starts when the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> as an error detector is connected to the modem apparatus with error detection functions, and when an instruction is given for an eye pattern display of reception signals, by the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. The flow in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> finishes when an instruction is given to end the eye pattern display by the connected oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the process from initialization of carrier index (N) (ST<highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>) to the calculation of error amounts of carrier index (N) (ST<highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) is the same as the process of the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the first embodiment, therefore, the description of the same is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> In this explanation, error amount of Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; is calculated, and the error amount is &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;. 2 bit data is assigned for Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> After the error amount &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated at Step <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> performs the exponential operation of &ldquo;2&rdquo; (2<highlight><superscript>n</superscript></highlight>), for the calculated error amount &ldquo;E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, using the bit number (n) that is assigned to Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; to calculate normalized error amount (ST<highlight><bold>701</bold></highlight>). In this embodiment, &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated as a normalized error amount of reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> After the normalized error amount &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is calculated, the eye pattern display controller <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; to the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> (ST<highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>). The eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; as coordinate information of the X-Y plane on the display screen of the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. At this time, the coordinate information for X-axis is determined based on the carrier index, while the coordinate information for Y-axis is determined based on the calculated normalized error amount. For example, the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> outputs &ldquo;1&rdquo;, which is a corresponding value of Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, as the coordinate information for X-axis, while outputting &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, which is a normalized error amount calculated from the reception signal of Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;, as the coordinate information for Y-axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> After outputting the normalized error amount of reception signals with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo; to the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> increases the number of carrier index (N) by one (ST<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). Accordingly, sub-carrier that is used to calculate the normalized error amount of reception signals becomes a sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Similar to the process of the first embodiment, whether the current Carrier Index &ldquo;N&rdquo; is the maximum carrier index is checked (ST<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight>). If it is not the maximum carrier index, the process of Steps <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> -<highlight><bold>307</bold></highlight> is repeated. If the maximum carrier index is &ldquo;255&rdquo;, for example, normalized error amounts of reception signals of Carrier Indexes &ldquo;2&rdquo; to &ldquo;255&rdquo; are calculated and output to the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> via the eye pattern display I/F <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> When the maximum carrier index is processed, on the other hand, the main controller <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> initializes carrier index (N) (ST<highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>), and goes to the process at Step <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to wait for another symbol interruption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) shows an example of the screen of the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, when the normalized error amount, which is output from the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment, is displayed. As a result of the above-described calculation, when there is a symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00005"/>, &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is displayed as a normalized error amount of reception signals of sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;1&rdquo;. When there is a symbol interruption <custom-character file="US20030005370A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00006"/>, &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is displayed as a normalized error amount of reception signals of sub-carrier with Carrier Index &ldquo;2&rdquo;. Similarly, every time there is a symbol interruption, &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&rdquo; . . . &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>&rdquo;, and &ldquo;S<highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>&rdquo; are displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the closer each normalized error amount is to &ldquo;0&rdquo; (closer to X-axis), the less likely that there is communication errors for reception signals of each carriers. By repeating the flow of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the observer can observe the averaged value of normalized error amount of reception signals of each sub-carrier in normal status. For example, normalized error amounts of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), are averaged values of normalized error amount of reception signals of each sub-carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> When observing such averaged values, when the observer connects the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> to the modem apparatus with error detection functions, to check the normalized error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier, normalized error amounts of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) is displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> At this time, in comparison with the normalized error amounts of reception signals that are already observed (normalized error amounts in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>(<highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>)), the observer can recognize that, with the current reception status, it is likely to have communication errors. Also, since the normalized error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the observer can determine which sub-carrier actually is likely to have communication errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> According to the modem apparatus with error detection functions of the second embodiment, normalized error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. Therefore, even in multi-carrier communication, it is possible to detect communication errors through observations of reception status based on eye patterns that are detected from the reception signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Also, normalized error amounts of reception signals of each sub-carrier are displayed on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, therefore, the observer can determine which sub-carrier&apos;s reception status of multi-carriers is likely to have communication errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In the second embodiment, the explanation is done as a separate apparatus from the first embodiment. However, the present invention is not limited to the embodiment, and the calculation display of error amount of the first embodiment and normalized error amounts of the second embodiment can be switched according to the instruction of the observer, on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In this case, the display of error amounts and normalized error amounts can be switched on the oscilloscope <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> according to the instruction of the observer. Accordingly, the observer can confirm which reception status of sub-carrier of multi-carrier is having an abnormal condition, and determine which sub-carrier&apos;s reception status of multi-carrier is likely to have communication errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the above-described embodiments, and various variations and modifications may be possible without departing from the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> This application is based on the Japanese Patent Application No. 2001-196505 filed on Jun. 28, 2001, entire content of which is expressly incorporated by reference herein. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A modem apparatus with error detection functions comprising: 
<claim-text>a fast Fourier transformation processor that performs a fast Fourier transformation process on sampling data of a reception signal to obtains coordinate information an I-R plane; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a display controller that calculates a deviation amount between the coordinate information on the I-R plane obtained from the reception signal and target coordinate information on the I-R plane predicted from the reception signal, and displays the deviation amount as coordinate information on a display screen of an externally connected error detector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The modem apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said display controller displays the deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector, the deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of any one of multi-carriers with different frequencies, and further displays another deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector, the deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of a succeeding carrier, the carrier having a higher frequency than a frequency of the carrier used to calculate the previous deviation amount. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The modem apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further adds a number to each carrier of multi-carriers, 
<claim-text>wherein said display controller displays the deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector in association with the added number of each carrier, the deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of any one of carriers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The modem apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said display controller calculates a second deviation amount normalized by a predetermined operation process using data amount assigned to the carrier, the operation process being performed on a deviation amount calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of any one of the multi-carriers, and displays the second deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The modem apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further adds a number to each carrier of multi-carriers, 
<claim-text>wherein said display controller displays the second deviation amount on the display screen of the error detector as coordinate information in association with the added number of each carrier, the second deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of any one of carriers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The modem apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said display controller switches the deviation amount and the second deviation amount to be displayed as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An error detection method comprising: 
<claim-text>performing a fast Fourier transformation process on sampling data of a reception signal to obtain coordinate information on an I-R plane by; </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating a deviation amount between the coordinate information of the I-R plane obtained from the reception signal and coordinate information of the I-R plane predicted from the reception signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the deviation amount as coordinate information on a display screen of an externally connected error detector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The error detection method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>displaying the deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector, the deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of any one of multi-carriers with different frequencies; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>further displaying another deviation amount as coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector, the deviation amount being calculated from sampling data of a reception signal of a succeeding carrier, the carrier having a higher frequency than a frequency of the carrier used to calculate the previous deviation amount. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A modem apparatus having error detection functions detecting communication status of a communication that is performed under a multi-carrier method employing a plurality of carriers with different frequencies, the status being displayed on a display screen of an externally connected error detector, the modem apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>an AD converter that samples a reception analog signal received from a telephone line and outputs the sample data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fast Fourier transformation processor that performs a fast Fourier transformation on the sample data by a symbol unit to obtain coordinate information of an I-R plane in association with the sample data of any one of multi-carriers, the carrier configuring the reception analog signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a display controller that calculates a deviation amount between the coordinate information of the I-R plane obtained by said fast Fourier transformation processor and target coordination information of the I-R plane predicted from the reception analog signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a display interface that converts the deviation amount into coordinate information on the display screen of the error detector, and displays the coordinate information in association with the information of the carrier used for the error detection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030005370A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
