<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003548A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003548A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003548A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003548A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003548A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003548A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003548</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10138713</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020506</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>DE 199 50 409.1</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991020</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C12P013/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12P013/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C07H021/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N009/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12P021/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N001/21</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N015/74</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>106000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>115000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>069100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>320100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>252300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>194000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>536</class>
<subclass>023200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Nucleotide sequences which code for the pck gene</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10138713</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020506</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10059091</doc-number>
<document-date>20020130</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10059091</doc-number>
<document-date>20020130</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09455777</doc-number>
<document-date>19991207</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6420151</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bernhard</given-name>
<family-name>Eikmanns</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Heidenheim</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Christian</given-name>
<family-name>Riedel</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>New Ulm</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hermann</given-name>
<family-name>Sahm</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Julich</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bettina</given-name>
<family-name>Mockel</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bielefeld</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>PILLSBURY WINTHROP, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 10500</address-1>
<city>MCLEAN</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention relates to isolated nucleotide sequences from Coryneform bacteria which code for the pck gene encoding the enzyme phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase (PEP carboxykinase). The invention also relates a process for the fermentative preparation of L-amino acids, in particular L-lysine, L-threonine, and L-glutamate by attenuation of the pck gene. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a Continuation-in-Part of U.S. application Ser. No. 10/059,091, filed Jan. 30, 2002, which, in turn, is a Divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/455,777, filed Dec. 7, 1999. U.S. application Ser. No. 09/455,777 claims priority to German application 199 50 409.1 filed on Oct. 20, 1999.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention provides nucleotide sequences from coryneform bacteria which code for the pck gene and a process for the fermentative preparation of L-amino acids, in particular L-lysine, L-threonine, and L-glutamate by attenuation of the pck gene. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Amino acids, in particular lysine and threonine, are used in animal nutrition, in the foodstuffs industry, in the pharmaceuticals industry and in human medicine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It is known that these substances are prepared by fermentation of strains of coryneform bacteria, in particular <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>. Because of its great importance, work is constantly being undertaken to improve the preparation processes. Improvements to the processes can relate to fermentation measures, such as e.g. stirring and supply of oxygen, or the composition of the nutrient media, such as e.g. the sugar concentration during the fermentation, or the working up to the product form by e.g. ion exchange chromatography, or the intrinsic output properties of the microorganism itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Methods of mutagenesis, selection and mutant selection are used to improve the output properties of these microorganisms. Strains which are resistant to antimetabolites or are auxotrophic for metabolism products of regulatory importance and produce the desired amino acid are obtained in this manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Methods of the recombinant DNA technique have also been employed for some years for improving the strain of Corynebacterium strains which produce L-amino acid. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention provides an isolated polynucleotide from coryneform bacteria, comprising a polynucleotide sequence chosen from the group consisting of </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> a) polynucleotide which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to a polynucleotide which codes for a polypeptide which comprises the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID No. 2, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> b) polynucleotide which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to a polynucleotide which codes for the polypeptide mentioned and is contained on the plasmid pEK-pckA (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) or pEK-pckB (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> c) polynucleotide which codes for a polypeptide which comprises an amino acid sequence which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID No. 2, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> d) polynucleotide which is complementary to the polynucleotides of a), b) or c), </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> the polypeptide preferably having the enzymatic activity of the phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase (PEP carboxykinase). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a preferably recombinant DNA with Corynebacterium origin which is capable of replication in coryneform microorganisms and contains at least the nucleotide sequence which codes for the pck gene, shown in SEQ ID No. 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a DNA according to claim 1 which is capable of replication, comprising </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> (i) the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID no. 1, or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> (ii) at least one sequence which corresponds to sequence (i) within the range of the degeneration of the genetic code, or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> (iii) at least one sequence which hybridizes with the sequence complementary to sequence (i) or (ii), and/or optionally </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> (iv) sense mutations of neutral function in (i) which do not modify the enzymatic activity of the protein/polypeptide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> a polynucleotide according to claim <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, comprising the nucleotide sequence as shown in SEQ ID no. 1, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> a polynucleotide according to claim <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which codes for a polypeptide which comprises the amino acid sequence as shown in SEQ ID No. 2, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> a vector containing the polynucleotide according to claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, in particular pEK-pckA or pEK-pckB, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> polynucleotides comprising at least 15 successive nucleotides chosen from the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID No. 1 between positions 1 and 728, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> polynucleotides comprising at least 15 successive nucleotides chosen from the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID No. 1 between positions 1103 and 2021, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> polynucleotides comprising at least 15 successive nucleotides chosen from the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID No. 1 between positions 2022 and 3854, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> polynucleotides comprising at least 15 successive nucleotides chosen from the nucleotide sequence of SEQ ID No. 1 between positions 3885 and 3935, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> and coryneform bacteria serving as the host cell, into which the &Dgr;pck deletion has been incorporated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides polynucleotides which substantially comprise a polynucleotide sequence, which are obtainable by screening by means of hybridization of a corresponding gene library, which comprise the complete gene with the polynucleotide sequence corresponding to SEQ ID no. 1, with a probe which comprises the sequence of the polynucleotide mentioned, according to SEQ ID no. 1 or a fragment thereof, and isolation of the DNA sequence mentioned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Polynucleotide sequences according to the invention are suitable as hybridization probes for RNA, cDNA and DNA, in order to isolate, in the full length, cDNA which code for phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase and to isolate those cDNA or genes which have a high similarity of sequence with that of the phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase gene. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> They are also suitable for incorporation into so-called &ldquo;arrays&rdquo; or &ldquo;DNA chips&rdquo; in order to detect and determine the corresponding polynucleotides, e.g., m-RNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Polynucleotide sequences according to the invention are furthermore suitable as primers with the aid of which DNA of genes which code for the phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase can be prepared with the polymerase chain reaction (PCR). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Such oligonucleotides which serve as probes or primers comprise at least 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, or 30, with a maximum length of 35 or 40, preferably at least 20, 21, 22, 23, or 24, with a maximum length of 30 or 35, very particularly at least 15, 16, 17, 18, or 19, with a maximum length of 25 or 30, successive nucleotides. Oligonucleotides with a length of at least 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39 or 40, with a maximum length of 45 or 50, or at least 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, 49, or 50, with a maximum length of 55 or 60 nucleotides are also suitable. Oligonucleotides with a length of at least 100, 150, 200, 250 or 300 nucleotides with a maximum length of 350, 400, or 500 are optionally also suitable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Isolated&rdquo; means separated out of its natural environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Polynucleotide&rdquo; in general relates to polyribonucleotides and polydeoxyribonucleotides, it being possible for these to be non modified RNA or DNA or modified RNA or DNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The polynucleotides according to the invention include a polynucleotide according to SEQ ID No. 2 or a fragment prepared therefrom and also to those which are at least in particular 70% to 80%, preferably at least 81% to 85%, particularly preferably at least 86% to 90%, and very particularly preferably at least 91%, 93%, 95%, 97% or 99% identical to the polynucleotide according to SEQ ID No. 1 or a fragment prepared therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Polypeptides&rdquo; are understood as meaning peptides or proteins which comprise two or more amino acids bonded via peptide bonds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The polypeptides according to the invention include a polypeptide according to SEQ. ID No.:2, in particular those with the biological activity of phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase and also those which are at least 70% to 80%, preferably at least. 81% to 85%, particularly preferably at least 86% to 90%, and very particularly preferably at least 91%, 93%, 95%, 97% or 99% identical to the polypeptide according to SEQ ID No:2 and have the activity mentioned.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The invention will be described with reference to the drawings, in which the stated base pair numbers are approximate values obtained in the context of reproducibility, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a restriction map of the plasmid pEK-pckA; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a restriction map of the plasmid pEK-pckB; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a restriction map of the plasmid pk19mobsacB&Dgr;pck.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Amino acids, in particular L-lysine and L-threonine, are used in animal nutrition, in the foodstuffs industry, in the pharmaceuticals industry and in human medicine. There is therefore a general interest in providing new improved processes for the preparation of these products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Polynucleotide sequences according to the invention are suitable as hybridization probes for RNA, cDNA and DNA, in order to isolate, in the full length, cDNA which code for phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase and to isolate those cDNA or genes which have a high similarity of sequence with that of the phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase gene. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a process for the fermentative preparation of L-amino acids, in particular L-lysine and L-threonine, using coryneform bacteria which in particular already produce the L-amino acids and in which the nucleotide sequence(s) which code(s) for the pck gene are attenuated, in particular expressed at a low level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;attenuation&rdquo; in this connection describes the reduction or elimination of the intracellular activity of one or more enzymes (proteins) in a microorganism which are coded by the corresponding DNA, for example by using a weak promoter or using a gene or allele which codes for a corresponding enzyme with a low activity or inactivates the corresponding enzyme (protein), and optionally combining these measures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The microorganisms which the present invention provides can produce L-amino acids, in particular lysine and threonine, from glucose, sucrose, lactose, fructose, maltose, molasses, starch, cellulose or from glycerol and ethanol. They can be representatives of coryneform bacteria, in particular of the genus Corynebacterium. Of the genus Corynebacterium, there may be mentioned in particular the species <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>, which is known among specialists for its ability to produce L-amino acids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Suitable strains of the genus Corynebacterium, in particular of the species <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>, are, for example, the known wild-type strains </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC13032 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium acetoglutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC15806 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium acetoacidophilum </italic></highlight>ATCC13870 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium thermoaminogenes </italic></highlight>FERM BP-1539 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium melassecola </italic></highlight>ATCC17965 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium flavum </italic></highlight>ATCC14067 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium lactofermentum </italic></highlight>ATCC13869 and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Brevibacterium divaricatum ATCC14020 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> and L-amino acid-producing mutants or strains prepared therefrom, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> such as, for example, the lysine-producing strains </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>FERM-P 1709 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium flavum </italic></highlight>FERM-P 1708 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium lactofermentum </italic></highlight>FERM-P 1712 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>FERM-P 6463 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>FERM-P 6464 and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Corynebacterium glutamicum DSM5714 or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> such as, for example, the L-threonine-producing strains </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC21649 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium flavum </italic></highlight>BB69 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium flavum </italic></highlight>DSM5399 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium lactofermentum </italic></highlight>FERM-BP 269 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium lactofermentum </italic></highlight>TBB-10 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>MH20-22B-DR17. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The inventors have succeeded in isolating the new pck gene of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>which codes for the enzyme phosphoenol pyruvate carboxykinase (PEP carboxykinase) (EC 4.1.1.49). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> To isolate the pck gene or also other genes of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum</italic></highlight>, a gene library of this microorganism is first set up in <highlight><italic>E. coli</italic></highlight>. The setting up of gene libraries is described in generally known textbooks and handbooks. The textbook by Winnacker: Gene und Klone, Eine Einf&uuml;hrung in die Gentechnologie &lsqb;Genes and Clones, An Introduction to Genetic Engineering&rsqb; (Verlag Chemie, Weinheim, Germany, 1990) or the handbook by Sambrook et al.: Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Manual (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, 1989) may be mentioned as an example. A well-known gene library is that of the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>K-12 strain W3110 set up in &lgr; vectors by Kohara et al. (Cell 50, 495-508 (1987)). Bathe et al. (Molecular and General Genetics, 252:255-265, 1996) describe a gene library of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC13032, which was set up with the aid of the cosmid vector SuperCos I (Wahl et al., 1987, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences USA, 84:2160-2164) in the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>K-12 strain NM554 (Raleigh et al., 1988, Nucleic Acids Research 16:1563-1575). B&ouml;rmann et al. (Molecular Microbiology 6(3), 317-326)) in turn describe a gene library of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC13032 using the cosmid pHC79 (Hohn and Collins, Gene 11, 291-298 (1980)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> To prepare a gene library of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>in <highlight><italic>E. coli, </italic></highlight>it is also possible to use plasmids or plasmid vectors, such as, for example, pBR322 (Bolivar, Life Sciences, 25, 807-818 (1979)), pUC9 (Vieira et al., 1982, Gene, 19:259-268), pACYC177 (Chang and Cohen, Journal of Bacteriology 134, 1141-1156 (1978)) or pSC101 (Cohen and Chang, Journal of Bacteriology 132, 734-737 (1977)). Suitable hosts are, in particular, those <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>strains which are restriction- and recombination-defective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The gene library is then incorporated into an indicator strain by transformation (Hanahan, Journal of Molecular Biology 166, 557-580, 1983) or electroporation (Tauch et.al., 1994, FEMS Microbiological Letters, 123:343-347). The indicator strain is distinguished in that it has a mutation in the gene of interest which causes a detectable phenotype. In the context of the present invention, the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>mutant HG4 described by Goldie and Sanwal (Journal of Bacteriology 141: 1115-1121 (1980)) is of importance. This strain carried a mutation in the pck gene, as a result of which growth on succinate as the sole source of carbon is severely impaired. By transformation with a vector which contains the pck gene, growth on succinate can be re-established. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The long DNA fragments cloned with the aid of cosmids or other vectors can than be subcloned into known plasmid vectors in the form of shorter DNA fragments. Assignment of the gene according to the invention to a specific DNA section is made possible as a result. For this, plasmid vectors known from the prior art, such as e.g. pBR322 (Bolivar, Life Sciences, 25, 807-818 (1979)) or the pSU vectors described by Bartolom&eacute; et al. (Gene 102, 75-78 (1991)) are used. However, shuttle vectors which replicate both in <highlight><italic>Escherichia coli </italic></highlight>and in <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>, such as e.g. pZ1 (Menkel et al., Applied and Environmental Microbiology (1989) 64: 549-554) or pEK0 (Eikmanns et al., Gene 102 (1991)) are preferably used, so that investigations can be carried out in both species. Examples of these are the plasmids pEK-pckA (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and pEK-pckB (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), which were prepared starting from the plasmid vector pEK0 and carry the pck gene according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The DNA sections characterized in this manner are then again subcloned into the usual vectors suitable for DNA sequencing. Alternatively, the long DNA sections cloned in cosmids can be subcloned directly into sequencing vectors. Examples of such vectors which are suitable for DNA sequencing are the plasmids pGEM-5zf(&minus;) or pGEM-5zf(&plus;) from the company Promega Corporation (Promega Protocols and Application Guide, Second Edition, 1991, part number Y981, Promega Corporation, Madison, Wis., USA). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Methods of DNA sequencing are described, inter alia, by Sanger et al. (Proceedings of the National of Sciences of the United States of America USA, 74:5463-5467, 1977). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The DNA sequences obtained can then be investigated with known algorithms or sequence analysis programs, such as e.g. that of Staden (Nucleic Acids Research 14, 217-232(1986)), the GCG program of Butler (Methods of Biochemical Analysis 39, 74-97 (1998)) the FASTA algorithm of Pearson and Lipman (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences U.S. Pat. No. 85,2444-2448 (1988)) or the BLAST algorithm of Altschul et al. (Nature Genetics 6, 119-129 (1994)) and compared with the sequence entries which exist in databanks accessible to the public. Databanks for nucleotide sequences which are accessible to the public are, for example, that of the European Molecular Biologies Laboratories (EMBL, Heidelberg, Germany) of that of the </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI, Bethesda, Md., USA). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The new DNA sequence of <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>which codes for the pck gene and which, as SEQ ID No. 1, is a constituent of the present invention was obtained in this manner. The amino acid sequence of the corresponding protein has furthermore been derived from the present DNA sequence by the methods described above. The resulting amino acid sequence of the pck gene product is shown in SEQ ID No. 2. Endogenous enzymes are able to cleave the N-terminal amino acid methionine or formylmethionine of the protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Coding DNA sequences which result from SEQ ID No. 1 by the degeneracy of the genetic code are also a constituent of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In the same way, DNA sequences which hybridize with SEQ ID No. 1 or parts of SEQ ID No. 1 are a constituent of the invention. Conservative amino acid exchanges, such as e.g., exchange of glycine for alanine or aspartic acid for glutamic acid in proteins are furthermore known among experts as &ldquo;sense mutations&rdquo; which do not lead to a fundamental change in the activity of the protein, i.e., one of neutral function. It is furthermore known that changes on the N and C terminus of a protein cannot substantially impair or can even stabilize the function thereof. Information in this context can be found by the expert, inter alia, in Ben-Bassat et al. (Journal of Bacteriology 169:751-757 (1987)), in O&apos;Regan et al. (Gene 77:237-251 (1989)), in Sahin-Toth et al. (Protein Sciences 3:240-247 (1994)), in Hochuli et al. (Bio/Technology 6:1321-1325 (1988)) and in known textbooks of genetics and molecular biology. Amino acid sequences which result in a corresponding manner from SEQ ID No. 2 are also a constituent of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> In the same way, DNA sequences which hybridize with SEQ ID No. 1 are a constituent of the invention. Finally, DNA sequences which are prepared by the polymerase chain reaction (PCR) using primers which result from SEQ ID No. 1 are a constituent of the invention. Such oligonucleotides typically have a length of at least 15 nucleotides. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Instructions for identifying DNA sequences by means of hybridization can be found by the expert, inter alia, in the handbook &ldquo;The DIG System Users Guide for Filter Hybridization&rdquo; from Boehringer Mannheim GmbH (Mannheim, Germany, 1993) and in Liebl et al. (International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology (1991) 41:255-260). The hybridization takes place under stringent conditions, that is to say only hybrids in which the probe and target sequence, i.e., the polynucleotides treated with the probe, are at least 70% identical and formed. It is known that the stringency of the hybridization, including the washing steps, is influenced or determined by varying the buffer composition, the temperature and the salt concentration. The hybridization reaction is preferably carried out under a relatively low stringency compared with the washing steps (Hybaid Hybridisation Guide, Hybaid Limited, Teddington, UK, 1996). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> A b&times; SSC buffer at a temperature of approximately 50-60&deg; C., for example, can be employed for the hybridization reaction. Probes can also hybridize here with polynucleotides which are less than 70% identical to the sequence of the probe. Such hybrids are less stable and are removed by washing under stringent conditions. This can be achieved, for example, by lowering the salt concentration to 2&times; SSC and subsequently to 0.5&times; SSC (The DIG System User&apos;s Guide for Filter Hybridization, Boehringer Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany, 1995) a temperature of approximately 50-68&deg; C. being established. It is optionally possible to lower the salt concentration to 0.1&times; SSC. Polynucleotide fragments which are, for example, at least 70% or at least 80% or at least 90% to 95% identical to the sequence of the probe employed can be isolated by increasing the hybridization temperature stepwise in steps of approximately 1-2&deg; C. Further instructions on hybridization are obtainable on the market in the form of so-called kits (e.g., DIG Easy Hyb from Roche Diagnostics GmbH, Mannheim, Germany, Catalogue No. 1603558). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The inventors have found that coryneform bacteria produce L-amino acids, in particular lysine and threonine, in an improved manner after attenuation of the pck gene. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> To achieve an attenuation, either the expression of the pck gene or the catalytic properties of the enzyme protein can be reduced or eliminated. The two measures can optionally be combined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The reduction in gene expression can take place by suitable culturing or by genetic modification (mutation) of the signal structures of gene expression. Signal structures of gene expression are, for example, repressor genes, activator genes, operators, promoters, attenuators, ribosome binding sites, the start codon and terminators. The expert can find information on this e.g. in the patent application WO 96/15246, in Boyd and Murphy (Journal of Bacteriology 170: 5949 (1988)), in Voskuil and Chambliss (Nucleic Acids Research 26: 3548 (1998), in Jensen and Hammer (Biotechnology and Bioengineering 58: 191 (1998)), in Patek et al. (Microbiology 142: 1297 (1996) and in known textbooks of genetics and molecular biology, such as e.g. the texbook by Knippers (&ldquo;Molekulare Genetik &lsqb;Molecular Genetics&rsqb;&rdquo;, 6th edition, Georg Thieme Verlag, Stuttgart, Germany, 1995) or that by Winnacker (&ldquo;Gene und Klone &lsqb;Genes and Clones&rdquo;, VCH Verlagsgesellschaft, Weinheim, Germany, 1990). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Mutations which lead to a change or reduction in the catalytic properties of enzyme proteins are known from the prior art; examples which may be mentioned are the works by Qiu and Goodman (Journal of Biological Chemistry 272: 8611-8617 (1997)), Sugimoto et al. (Bioscience Biotechnology and Biochemistry 61: 1760-1762 (1997)) and M&ouml;ckel (&ldquo;Die Threonindehydratase aus <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>: Aufhebung der allosterischen Regulation und Struktur des Enzyms &lsqb;Threonine dehydratase from <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</italic></highlight>: Cancelling the allosteric regulation and structure of the enzyme&rsqb;&rdquo;, Reports from the Julich Research Centre, J&uuml;l-2906, ISSN09442952, J&uuml;lich, Germany, 1994). Comprehensive description can be found in known textbooks of genetics and molecular biology, such as e.g. that by Hagemann (&ldquo;Allgemeine Genetik &lsqb;General Genetics&rsqb;&rdquo;, Gustav Fischer Verlag, Stuttgart, 1986). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Possible mutations are transitions, transversions, insertions and deletions. Depending on the effect of the amino acid exchange on the enzyme activity, missense mutations or nonsense mutations are referred to. Insertions or deletions of at least one base pair in a gene lead to frame shift mutations, which lead to incorrect amino acids being incorporated or translation being interrupted prematurely. Deletions of several codons typically lead to a complete loss of the enzyme activity. Instructions on generation of such mutations are prior art and can be found in known textbooks of genetics and molecular biology, such as e.g. the textbook by Knippers (&ldquo;Molekulare Genetik &lsqb;Molecular Genetics&rsqb;&rdquo;, 6th edition, Georg Thieme Verlag, Stuttgart, Germany, 1995), that by Winnacker (&ldquo;Gene und Klone &lsqb;Genes and Clones&rsqb;&rdquo;, VCH Verlagsgesellschaft, Weinheim, Germany, 1990) or that by Hagemann (&ldquo;Allgemeine Genetik &lsqb;General Genetics&rsqb;&rdquo;, Gustav Fischer Verlag, Stuttgart, 1986). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> An example of a mutated pck gene is the &Dgr;pck allele contained in the plasmid pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The &Dgr;pck allele contains only the 5&prime; and the 3&prime; flanks of the pck gene; a section of the coding region 1071 bp long is missing (deletion). This &Dgr;pck allele can be incorporated into coryneform bacteria by integration mutagenesis. The abovementioned plasmid pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck, which is not capable of replication in <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum, </italic></highlight>is used for this. After transfer by conjugation or transformation and homologous recombination by means of a first &ldquo;cross-over&rdquo; event which effects integration and a second &ldquo;cross-over&rdquo; event which effects excision in the pck gene, the incorporation of the &Dgr;pck allele is achieved and a total loss of the enzyme function in the particular strain is achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Instructions and explanations on integration mutagenesis are to be found, for example, in Schwarzer and P&uuml;hler (Bio/Technology 9,84-87 (1991)) or Peters-Wendisch et al. (Microbiology 144, 915-927 (1998)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Examples of amino acid-producing strains of coryneforme bacteria with an attenuated pck gene are the lysine-producing strain MH20-22B&Dgr;pck and the threonine-producing strain DM368-2&Dgr;pck. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In addition, it may be advantageous for the production of L-amino acids to over-express one or more enzymes of the particular biosynthesis route, in addition to attenuation of the pck gene. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Thus, for example, for the preparation of L-lysine </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> at the same time the dapA gene which codes for dihydrodipicolinate synthase can be over-expressed (EP-B 0 197 335), or </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> at the same time a DNA fragment which imparts S-(2-aminoethyl)-cysteine resistance can be amplified (EP-A 0 088 166). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Thus, for example, for the preparation of L-threonine </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> at the same time the hom gene which codes for homoserine dehydrogenase (Peoples et al., Molecular Microbiology 2, 63-72 (1988)) or the hom<highlight><superscript>dr </superscript></highlight>or hom<highlight><subscript>FBR </subscript></highlight>allele which codes for a &ldquo;feed back resistant&rdquo; homoserine dehydrogenase (Archer et al., Gene 107, 53-59 (1991); Reinscheid et al., Journal of Bacteriology 173, 3228-3230 (1991)) can be over-expressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> In addition to attenuation of the pck gene it may furthermore be advantageous, for the production of L-amino acids, in particular lysine and threonine, to eliminate undesirable side reactions (Nakayama: &ldquo;Breeding of Amino Acid Producing Micro-organisms&rdquo;, in: Overproduction of Microbial Products, Krumphanzl, Sikyta, Vanek (eds.), Academic Press, London, UK, 1982). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> The microorganisms prepared according to the invention can be cultured continuously or discontinuously in the batch process (batch culture) or in the fed batch (feed process) or repeated fed batch process (repetitive feed process) for the purpose of production of L-amino acids, in particular L-lysine and L-threonine. A summary of known culture methods is described in the textbook by Chmiel (Bioprozesstechnik 1. Einf&uuml;hrung in die Bioverfahrenstechnik &lsqb;Bioprocess Technology 1. Introduction to Bioprocess Technology (Gustav Fischer Verlag, Stuttgart, 1991)) or in the textbook by Storhas (Bioreaktoren und periphere Einrichtungen &lsqb;Bioreactors and Peripheral Equipment&rsqb; (Vieweg Verlag, Braunschweig/Wiesbaden, 1994)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> The culture medium to be used must meet the requirements of the particular strains in a suitable manner. Descriptions of culture media for various microorganisms are contained in the handbook &ldquo;Manual of Methods for General Bacteriology&rdquo; of the American Society for Bacteriology (Washington D.C., USA, 1981). Sugars and carbohydrates, such as e.g. glucose, sucrose, lactose, fructose, maltose, molasses, starch and cellulose, oils and fats, such as e.g. soya oil, sunflower oil, groundnut oil and coconut fat, fatty acids, such as e.g. palmitic acid, stearic acid and linoleic acid, alcohols, such as e.g. glycerol and ethanol, and organic acids, such as e.g. acetic acid, can be used as the source of carbon. These substances can be used individually or as a mixture. Organic nitrogen-containing compounds, such as peptones, yeast extract, meat extract, malt extract, corn steep liquor, soya bean flour and urea, or inorganic compounds, such as ammonium sulphate, ammonium chloride, ammonium phosphate, ammonium carbonate and ammonium nitrate, can be used as the source of nitrogen. The sources of nitrogen can be used individually or as a mixture. Phosphoric acid, potassium dihydrogen phosphate or dipotassium hydrogen phosphate or the corresponding sodium-containing salts can be used as the source of phosphorus. The culture medium must furthermore comprise salts of metals, such as e.g. magnesium sulfate or iron sulfate, which are necessary for growth. Finally, essential growth substances, such as amino acids and vitamins, can be employed in addition to the abovementioned substances. Suitable precursors can moreover be added to the culture medium. The starting substances mentioned can be added to the culture in the form of a single batch, or can be fed in during culturing in a suitable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Basic compounds, such as sodium hydroxide, potassium hydroxide, ammonia or aqueous ammonia, or acid compounds, such as phosphoric acid or sulfuric acid, can be employed in a suitable manner to control the pH. Antifoams, such as e.g. fatty acid polyglycol esters, can be employed to control the development of foam. Suitable substances having a selective action, e.g. antibiotics, can be added to the medium to maintain the stability of plasmids. To maintain aerobic conditions, oxygen or oxygen-containing gas mixtures, such as e.g. air, are introduced into the culture. The temperature of the culture is usually 20&deg; C. to 45&deg; C., and preferably 25&deg; C. to 40&deg; C. Culturing is continued until a maximum of the desired L-amino acid has formed. This target is usually reached within 10 hours to 160 hours. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The following microorganism has been deposited at the Deutsche Sammlung f&uuml;r Mikrorganismen und Zellkulturen (DSMZ&equals;German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany) in accordance with the Budapest Treaty: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>Escherichia coli </italic></highlight>strain DH5&agr;/pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck as DSM 13047 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The process according to the invention is used for the fermentative preparation of L-amino acids, in particular L-aspartic acid, L-asparagine, L-homoserine, L-threonine, L-isoleucine, L-glutamate, and L-methionine, with coryneform bacteria, in particular the preparation of L-lysine, L-threonine, and L-glutamate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> The present invention is explained in more detail in the following with the aid of the following examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> For this purpose, inter alia, experiments were carried out with the lysine producer <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>strain MH20-22B and the threonine producer <highlight><italic>Brevibacterium flavum </italic></highlight>strain DM368-2. Strain MH20-22B has been deposited as DSM5715 (EP-B-0435 132) and strain DM368-2 as DSM5399 EP-B-0385 940) at the Deutsche Sammlung f&uuml;r Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen (DSMZ, Braunschweig, Germany) in accordance with the Budapest Treaty. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Isolation of the pck Gene </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> To isolate the PEP carboxykinase gene (pck) from <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>a cosmid gene library was set up on the basis of the cosmid pHC79 (Hohn and Collins, Gene 11 (1980) 291-298) by a known method (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press). For this, chromosomal DNA was isolated from <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>ATCC13032 (Eikmanns et al., Microbiology 140 (1994) 1817-1828) and partly digested with the restriction enzyme Sau3A. After ligation of the resulting fragments into the BamHI cleavage site of the cosmid pHC79, the batch was packed into the protein envelope of the lambda bacteriophage and the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>strain ED8654 (Murray et al. Molecular and General Genetics 150 (1997) 53-61) was transfected with this. The recombinant cosmids were packed into the protein envelope of the lambda phage by a method of Sternberg et al. (Gene 1 (1979) 255-280), and the transfection of <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>ED8654 was carried out by a method of Sambrook et al. (Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press). The corresponding cosmids were isolated from a total of 30 resulting recombinant <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>clones (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press) and subjected to a restriction analysis with the enzyme HindIII. It was found that 24 of the cosmids possessed inserts, and that the inserts had sizes of approximately 35 kb. A total of 2200 cosmid-carrying <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>clones were combined, and the cosmid DNA was prepared from this mixture by known processes (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> To isolate the pck gene from <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum, </italic></highlight>the cosmide gene library was transformed into the PEP carboxykinase-defective <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>mutant HG4 (Goldie and Sanwal, Journal of Bacteriology 141 (1980) 115-1121) by known processes (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press). Because it is PEP carboxykinase-defective, the mutant HG4 is no longer capable of growing on succinate as the only source of carbon. After transformation of the cosmid gene library into this mutant, a total of 1200 clones were obtained. Of these, a total of two clones showed growth on M9 minimal medium (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press) with succinate (0.4%) as the only source of carbon. After isolation of the corresponding cosmids (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press) from these clones and renewed transformation into the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>mutant HG4, the resulting clones were again capable of growing on M9 medium with succinate as the only source of carbon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> To limit the pck gene from <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>to a smaller fragment, the two complementing cosmids were digested with the restriction enzymes XhoI, ScaI and PvuII and separated in an electrical field on a 0.8% agarose gel by known methods (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press). Fragments in the size range above 3.0 kb were isolated from the gel by electroelution (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press) and ligated into the SalI (XhoI-digestion) or into the Klenow-treated EcoRI cleavage site (ScaI and PvuII digestion) of the vector pEK0 (Eikmanns et al., Gene 102 (1991) 93-98). <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>HG4 was transformed with the ligation batches and the resulting transformants were investigated again for their ability to grow on succinate as the sole source of carbon. Seven clones with plasmids which allowed growth of the mutant HG4 on succinate were found in the transformation batch with the PvuII ligation batch. The corresponding plasmids were isolated from the recombinant strains and subjected to restriction mapping. It was found that all seven plasmids carried the same 4.3 kb PvuII insert, three in one orientation and four in the other. The newly constructed plasmids were called pEK-pckA and pEK-pckB, depending on the orientation of the insert in the vector. The restriction maps of the two plasmids are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Sequencing of the pck Structural Gene and Adjacent Regions </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> For the sequencing, the approximately 3.9 kb EcoRI fragment was isolated from pEK-pckA (an EcoRI cleavage site here originates from the vector pEK0) by known methods. The overhanging ends of the fragment were filled up to blunt ends with Klenow polymerase (Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A Laboratory Handbook, 1989, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press) and ligated into the EcoRV cleavage site of the vector pGEM-5Zf(&plus;)(Promega Corporation, Madison, Wis., USA). The insertion of the plasmid thus generated was sequenced by the chain-stopping sequencing method (Sanger et al., Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences USA, 74 (1977) 5463-5467). It is shown as SEQ ID No. 1. The resulting nucleotide sequence of 3935 bp was analysed with the HUSAR program package (release 3.0) of the Deutsche Krebsforschungszentrum (DKFZ&equals;German Cancer Research Centre, Heidelberg, Germany). The sequence analysis of the fragments showed an open reading frame of 1830 bp in length, which codes for a protein consisting of 610 amino acids. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Over-Expression of the pck Gene </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> The plasmids pEK-pckA and pEK-pckB were introduced into the <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>strain ATCC13032 by electroporation with subsequent selection on kanamycin(50 &mgr;g/ml)-containing BHI agar plates (Liebl et al., FEMS Microbiology Letters 65 (1989) 299-304) and the resulting strains were called ATCC13032/pEK-pckA and ATCC13032/pEK-pckB. These two strains and the starting strain were cultured in Luria-Bertani complex medium &lsqb;Sambrook et al., Molecular Cloning, A laboratory manual (1989) Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press&rsqb; and the PEP carboxykinase test was carried out in accordance with the method described by Bentle and Lardy &lsqb;Journal of Biological Chemistry 251 (1976) 2916-2921&rsqb;. The result of the analysis is shown in table 1, and shows that the PEP carboxykinase activity in the two strains with the plasmids pEK-pckA and pEK-pckB is 10 to 12 times higher than in the starting strain.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase activity in various strains</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="77PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>(nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032</entry>
<entry>&ensp;120</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032/pEK-pckA</entry>
<entry>1270</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032/pEK-pckB</entry>
<entry>1510</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of an Integration Plasmid for Deletion Mutagenesis of the pck Gene </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> For inactivation of the PEP carboxykinase gene, the EcoRI-SacI fragment of the pck gene was isolated from the vector pEK-pckB (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and ligated into the vector pGEM-7Zf(&plus;) (Promega Corporation, Madison, Wis., USA). A pck-internal 1.07 kb HindII-HindIII fragment was deleted from the resulting plasmid, and the pck gene with the 1.07 kb deletion was then isolated as the BfrI-SacI frament and, after the overhanging ends had been filled up, was ligated into the vector pk19mobsacB, which is non-replicative in <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>(Sch&auml;fer et al., Gene 145, 69-73 (1994)). In the integration plasmid pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) constructed in this way, the 5&prime; region of the pck gene (350 bp) is directly adjacent to the 3&prime; region of the pck gene (340 bp); in the genome, the two regions are separated from one another by 1071 bp. Up to this step, all clonings were carried out in <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>DH5&agr; as the host. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Deletion Mutagenesis of the pck Gene in the Lysine Producer MH20-22B </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>S17-1 was then transformed with the integration plasmid pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck (Simon et al., Bio/Technology 1,784-791 (1983)). This strain allows transfer of a plasmid to <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>by conjugation (Sch&auml;fer et al., Journal of Bacteriology 172 (1990) 1663-1666). The lysine production strain <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>MH20-22B was used as the recipient of the conjugation (Schrumpf et al., Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology 37 (1992) 566-571)). Several transconjugants were obtained from the conjugation between <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>S17-1/pk19mobsacB&Dgr;pck and <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>MH20-22B and subsequent selection on Luria-Bertani agar plates with kanamycin (25 &mgr;g/ml) and nalidixic acid (50 &mgr;g/ml). For selection for the second recombination event, which is to lead to excision of the vector together with the pck gene, these transconjugants were cultured on antibiotic-free Luria-Bertani complex medium &lsqb;Sambrook et al; Molecular Cloning, A laboratory manual (1989) Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press&rsqb; with 1% glucose and then plated out on the same medium plus 10% sucrose. The sacB gene present on the vector pk19mobsacB codes for the enzyme levan sucrase and leads to synthesis of levan from sucrose. Since levan is toxic to <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum, </italic></highlight>only <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>cells which have lost the integration plasmid can grow on sucrose-containing medium (J&auml;ger et al., Journal of Bacteriology 174 (1992) 5462-5466). 30 sucrose-resistant clones were investigated for their kanamycin sensitivity. For 11 of the clones tested, in addition to the sucrose resistance, the desired kanamycin sensitivity could also be confirmed. In these 11 clones, the vector background had therefore been excised again. Whether the desired deletion had also taken place was tested by analysis by means of the polymerase chain reaction (PCR). For this, chromosomal DNA was liberated from a colony of the starting strain and from colonies of the 11 kanamycin-sensitive clones. For this, the particular colony was removed from the agar plate with a toothpick, suspended in 50 &mgr;l H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O and incubated for 5 minutes at 95&deg; C. 1 &mgr;l portions of the resulting solution were each employed as templates in the PCR. Oligonucleotides which cover the regions from nucleotide 2136 to 2158 and from 3815 to 3793 in SEQ ID No. 1 were used as primers. The PCR conditions were: prior denaturing: 150 seconds at 94&deg; C.; denaturing 60 seconds at 94&deg; C.; hybridization 30 seconds at 60&deg; C.; amplification 120 seconds at 72&deg; C.; 30 cycles, end extension 240 seconds at 72&deg; C. On the basis of the primers chosen, a PCR product of 1.68 kb was expected in the batch with the DNA of the starting strain. A PCR product of 0.61 kb was expected in the PCR with the pck deletion mutant. A PCR product 0.61 kb in size was obtained with one clone. The desired deletion of the internal 1071 bp pck fragment in this clone was thereby demonstrated. The clone was called MH20-22B&Dgr;pck. The 1.68 kb PCR product was detected in the batches of the other clones. In these, the vector had thus been excised such that the genomic starting situation was re-established. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> The strain MH20-22B&Dgr;pck and the starting strain MH20-22B were grown in Luria-Bertani complex medium plus 1% glucose and the PEP carboxykinase test was carried out in accordance with the method described by Bentle and Lardy (Journal of Biological Chemistry 251 (1976) 2916-2921). The result of the analysis (table 2) shows that PEP carboxykinase activity is no longer detectable in the mutant MH20-22B&Dgr;pck, in contrast to the starting strain MH20-22B.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase activity in various strains</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="140PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>(nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>MH20-22B</entry>
<entry>65</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>MH20-22B&Dgr;pck</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&lt;3*</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="left"><footnote id="FOO-00001">*3 nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>is the detection limit </footnote></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 6 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Production of L-lysine </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> To investigate the effect of the inactivation of the PEP carboxykinase gene on lysine production, the strain MH20-22B (Schrumpf et al., Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology 1992, 37:566-571) and the PEP carboxykinase-negative mutant MH20-22B&Dgr;pck (example 5) were cultured in Luria-Bertani complex medium plus 1% glucose and the fermentation medium CGXII (Keilhauer et al., Journal of Bacteriology 1993, 175:5595-5603) was inoculated from the two pre-cultures (5% inokulum, optical density at 600 nm approximately 0.5). The medium additionally comprised 3 mM leucine, since the two strains are leucine-auxotrophic. The batches each comprise 60 ml culture, obtained in 500 ml conical flasks with baffles. After culture for 24 hours at 28&deg; C. on a rotary shaking machine of the Certomat S/50 type (B. Braun Biotech International, Melsungen, Germany) at 120 rpm, the concentration of the lysine secreted into the medium was determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> The amino acid concentration was determined by means of high pressure liquid chromatography (Jones und Gilligan, Journal of Chromatography 1983, 266:471-482). The result of the fermentation is shown in table 3.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 3</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Lysine concentration in the culture supernatant of the strains</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>MH20-22B and MH20-22B&Dgr;pck</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>L-Lysine (mM)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>MH20-22B</entry>
<entry>54</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>MH20-22B&Dgr;pck</entry>
<entry>65</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 7 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Deletion Mutagenesis of the pck Gene in the Threonine Producer DM368-2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> As in the case of the lysine producer MH20-22B, using the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>strain S17-1/pk19mobsacB&Dgr;pck a conjugation with the threonine producer DM368-2 with subsequent selection for the first and second recombination was carried out (see example 5). Of 30 sucrose-resistant clones, 14 were kanamycin-sensitive. Of these, the 1071 bp deletion in the pck gene could be detected with the aid of the PCR analysis described in example 5 in two clones, called DM368-2&Dgr;pck16 and DM368-2&Dgr;pck18. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> An enzyme test with the starting strain DM368-2 and the two pck deletion strains DM368-2&Dgr;pck16 and DM368-2&Dgr;pck18, carried out as described in example 5, showed that no PEP carboxykinase activity is detectable in these mutants (Table 4).  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 4</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase activity in various strains</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="21PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>(nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1</superscript></highlight>)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DM368-2</entry>
<entry>79</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DM368-2B&Dgr;pck16</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&lt;3*</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DM368-2B&Dgr;pck18</entry>
<entry>&ensp;&lt;3*</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="left"><footnote id="FOO-00002">*3 nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>is the detection limit </footnote></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 8 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Production of L-threonine </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> Analogously to the experiments on L-lysine production, the accumulation of threonine in the culture supernatant of the PEP carboxykinase-defective strain DM368-2B&Dgr;pck16 was investigated in comparison with the starting strain DM368-2. For this, the two strains were cultured in Luria-Bertani complex medium plus 1% glucose and the fermentation medium CGXII was inoculated from the precultures. After culture for 24 hours at 28&deg; C. on a rotary shaking machine at 120 rpm, the concentration of the threonine secreted into the medium was determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> The amino acid concentration was determined by means of high pressure liquid chromatography (see above). The result of the fermentation is shown in table 5.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00005">
<number>5</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 5</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Threonine concentration in the culture supernatant of the strains</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>DM 368-2 and DM 368-2&Dgr;pck16</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>L-Threonine (mM)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DM368-2</entry>
<entry>&ensp;8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DM368-2&Dgr;pck16</entry>
<entry>22</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 9 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Deletion Mutagenesis of the pck Gene in <highlight><italic>C. glutamicum </italic></highlight>Wild-Type Strain ATCC13032 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> A conjugation with the <highlight><italic>C. gutamicum </italic></highlight>wild type-strain ATCC13032 was carried out with the <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>strain S 17-1/pK19 mobsacB&Dgr;pck (example 4) as in the case of the lysine producer MH20-22B (example 5) and of the threonine producer DM368-2 (example 7). The selection on the first and second recombination event was carried out as in example 5. Of 52 saccharose-resistant clones, 8 were kanamycin-sensitive. Of these, the 1071 bp deletion in the pck gene was able to be demonstrated with the aid of the FCR analysis described in example 5 in three clones designated as ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2, ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29 and ATCC13032&Dgr;pck30. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> An enzyme test with the initial strain ATCC13032 and two of the three pck deletion strains, ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2 and ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29, carried out as described as in example 5, showed that no PEP carboxkinase activity can be demonstrated in both mutants (table 6).  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00006">
<number>6</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 6</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase activity In different strains</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>PEP carboxykinase</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032</entry>
<entry>132&emsp;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2</entry>
<entry>&lt;3*</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29</entry>
<entry>&lt;3*</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="left"><footnote id="FOO-00003">*3 nmol min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>mg protein<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>is the demonstration limit </footnote></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 10 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Production of L-glutamate </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> The accumulation of L-glutamate in the culture supernatant of the PEP carboxykinase-defective strains ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2 and ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29 in comparison to the initial strain ATCC13032 was also investigated in analogy with the experiments on the production of L-lysine and of L-threoninc (examples 6, 8). To this end the three strains were cultivated in Luria-Bertani complex &lsqb;complexing&rsqb; medium plus 1% glucose and the fermentation medium CGXII (see example 6) from these precultures inoculated. 15 mg Tween 60 per ml were added to the medium 4 hours after the inoculation for the induction of the production of L-glutamate. After cultivation for 24 hours at 30&deg; C. on a rotary agitator at 120 rmp the concentration of the glutamate excreted into the medium was determined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> The determination of the concentration of amino acid took place by means of high-pressure liquid chromatography (see example 6). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The result of the fermentation is shown in table 7, in which the indicated values represent average values from two experiments in each instance. It turns out that the inactivation of the PEP carboxykinase gene results in a 4 to 5-fold increase of the concentration of glutamate in the medium.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00007">
<number>7</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 7</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Concentration of glutamate in the culture supernatant of the strains</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ATCC13032, ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2 and ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="28PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="126PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Strain</entry>
<entry>L-glutamate (mM)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032</entry>
<entry>11.24</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032&Dgr;pck2</entry>
<entry>49.45</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ATCC13032&Dgr;pck29</entry>
<entry>52.17</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> In the Figures, the abbreviations and designations that are used have the following meanings:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00008">
<number>8</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="154PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>sacB:</entry>
<entry>sacB gene</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ori V:</entry>
<entry>Replication origin V</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ori T:</entry>
<entry>Replication origin for the transfer</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Km-r:</entry>
<entry>Kanamycin resistance</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>KpnI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme KpnI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>HindIII:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme HindIII</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>HindII:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme HindII</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>PstI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme PstI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SphI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme SphI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>XbaI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme XbaI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SalI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme SalI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>SacI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme SacI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>BfrI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme BfrI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ScaI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme ScaI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>BamHI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme BamHI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>EcoRI:</entry>
<entry>Cleavage site of the restriction enzyme EcoRI</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>pck&prime;:</entry>
<entry>3&prime; terminal fragment of the pck gene</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>pck&Prime;:</entry>
<entry>5&prime; terminal fragment of the pck gene</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>pck:</entry>
<entry>pck gene</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<sequence-cwu id="SEQLST-1">
<number>1</number>
<sequence-list-new-rules>
<s100>
<s160>2 </s160>
</s100>
<s200>
<s210>1 </s210>
<s211>3935 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Corynebacterium glutamicum </s213>
<s220>
<s221>CDS </s221>
<s222>(2022)..(3851) </s222>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 1 
ctggcagttc tcctaattga tcgcgggaat tatcagaaat agacattatt tgttattttt     60 
cctgttcaac tttaaaactt caatattcgt gagtttggat gaatccctag agcactacct    120 
tttagacctc tcgctgcaat ttaggccagt tgagatttaa gctttccgac gattcttctc    180 
attactgcaa tcgtaccggc gatggtggac acgatgacat gaaagagcat taaagcaatc    240 
aagtacaggc tgaagtagtt aaaccactcc actccggtgc tctgtgataa aaaatgcgca    300 
cccaaactca aagtgccaac tgggaaggta ctggcccacc atgtggggct gtatgtcgcc    360 
cctttgaaaa cagctctgta gaacacaaag tgagcgatgg ctcccagagg aatcgtaaaa    420 
attcccatga tgatgccgta aataatgccc attgtgattg ctgtcttgga tccaaaggac    480 
gcaccgatga gctgagctgc tgcagtggat tggcccacca tacccaaagg aatccatgat    540 
gttggtgttg ccatcagtgg gatgccctgc gccttggggc cgaaatagta gaaatacact    600 
cgggtaaaaa ctgctggtgc agacgccaaa gttaaaagga agagcccgaa agaaacccac    660 
agcatcgccg gaagttcaaa gtgctcatgg agttgtgctg ccgaggtgga agcaaccatc    720 
ggcgtgacaa gaggaagacc ccacgcaaaa gttggtgtgc ccgccttaga tcgcaaaatg    780 
gccgttatat ataaggaata ggcaacaagt cccacggctg tgccaataga ccagcacaca    840 
aacataaatc cccacagatc atcacccaaa actacggggc ttgcagttcc caatgcgatc    900 
aaacccatgg acagcattgc ccatgccggc atgacttcag ttttgaatga aggagagcgg    960 
tagattagcc aaccgccaat aatgacaatt gccaccacaa cagctaacgc gaagaagaaa   1020 
tctgcgacga ctggaaaacc atggattttc aacagtgatg acaacaatga gatgcccatg   1080 
agggaaccag cccacgaggg gccaggtgga ggtaagaccg cagcgtagct tttggtcgaa   1140 
gaaggagtgg gcatgcccat tactttaagc ctttggggca gtgaaaccgc taaatgggag   1200 
cgttgtgcgc tcgatcactg gtctagacct ttgggctcca aaagttgcaa tttcgcgaat   1260 
acttcaacac ttgtttgcaa tgtttgttaa taaatgggtt cgctagtgga ttctgtcgtt   1320 
agtactggcc gtcgtggtgg ggtcatgtat ttaggtaggg caaagttaag atcagagcac   1380 
tttttgatac gactaactgg atataacctt tggggtaacg tggggatgtg tgtgagtaat   1440 
tttcaaagta tttaaaaggg ggatctaggg taaaaatttg gcttcaagta catatcttta   1500 
gttcggtagt tgagggcggg tggtgacagt gcgggcatgc atgtgagtgt aaatgttgtt   1560 
ttaaaaaggt gtgtactgac agtgggccgg tttgtgctgg tcggccacta gcggagtgct   1620 
tggattgtga tggcagggta agggaaaggg attaccatta ccgctgttct tggcgttttg   1680 
ttgcctattg tccgaatgtt aagtgttaat ggtgggaaaa ctgggaaagt tgtcccctgg   1740 
aatgtgtgag aattgcccaa atctgaaccc aatggccatg gacggggaat gaactgtcgg   1800 
agaacggttg aggttaattc ttgaaaccac ccccaaaata ggctatttaa acgggtgctc   1860 
tcatattaaa gaaagtgtgt agatgcgtgt gggcaggggg taggtccact ggtaatgaca   1920 
aatgtgtccg ttgtctcacc taaagtttta actagttctg tatctgaaag ctacgctagg   1980 
gggcgagaac tctgtcgaat gacacaaaat ctggagaagt a atg act act gct gca   2036 
                                              Met Thr Thr Ala Ala 
                                                1               5 
atc agg ggc ctt cag ggc gag gcg ccg acc aag aat aag gaa ctg ctg     2084 
Ile Arg Gly Leu Gln Gly Glu Ala Pro Thr Lys Asn Lys Glu Leu Leu 
                 10                  15                  20 
aac tgg atc gca gac gcc gtc gag ctc ttc cag cct gag gct gtt gtg     2132 
Asn Trp Ile Ala Asp Ala Val Glu Leu Phe Gln Pro Glu Ala Val Val 
             25                  30                  35 
ttc gtt gat gga tcc cag gct gag tgg gat cgc atg gcg gag gat ctt     2180 
Phe Val Asp Gly Ser Gln Ala Glu Trp Asp Arg Met Ala Glu Asp Leu 
         40                  45                  50 
gtt gaa gcc ggt acc ctc atc aag ctc aac gag gaa aag cgt ccg aac     2228 
Val Glu Ala Gly Thr Leu Ile Lys Leu Asn Glu Glu Lys Arg Pro Asn 
     55                  60                  65 
agc tac cta gct cgt tcc aac cca tct gac gtt gcg cgc gtt gag tcc     2276 
Ser Tyr Leu Ala Arg Ser Asn Pro Ser Asp Val Ala Arg Val Glu Ser 
 70                  75                  80                  85 
cgc acc ttc atc tgc tcc gag aag gaa gaa gat gct ggc cca acc aac     2324 
Arg Thr Phe Ile Cys Ser Glu Lys Glu Glu Asp Ala Gly Pro Thr Asn 
                 90                  95                 100 
aac tgg gct cca cca cag gca atg aag gac gaa atg tcc aag cat tac     2372 
Asn Trp Ala Pro Pro Gln Ala Met Lys Asp Glu Met Ser Lys His Tyr 
            105                 110                 115 
gct ggt tcc atg aag ggg cgc acc atg tac gtc gtg cct ttc tgc atg     2420 
Ala Gly Ser Met Lys Gly Arg Thr Met Tyr Val Val Pro Phe Cys Met 
        120                 125                 130 
ggt cca atc agc gat ccg gac cct aag ctt ggt gtg cag ctc act gac     2468 
Gly Pro Ile Ser Asp Pro Asp Pro Lys Leu Gly Val Gln Leu Thr Asp 
    135                 140                 145 
tcc gag tac gtt gtc atg tcc atg cgc atc atg acc cgc atg ggt att     2516 
Ser Glu Tyr Val Val Met Ser Met Arg Ile Met Thr Arg Met Gly Ile 
150                 155                 160                 165 
gaa gcg ctg gac aag atc ggc gcg aac ggc agc ttc gtc agg tgc ctc     2564 
Glu Ala Leu Asp Lys Ile Gly Ala Asn Gly Ser Phe Val Arg Cys Leu 
                170                 175                 180 
cac tcc gtt ggt gct cct ttg gag cca ggc cag gaa gac gtt gca tgg     2612 
His Ser Val Gly Ala Pro Leu Glu Pro Gly Gln Glu Asp Val Ala Trp 
            185                 190                 195 
cct tgc aac gac acc aag tac atc acc cag ttc cca gag acc aag gaa     2660 
Pro Cys Asn Asp Thr Lys Tyr Ile Thr Gln Phe Pro Glu Thr Lys Glu 
        200                 205                 210 
att tgg tcc tac ggt tcc ggc tac ggc gga aac gca atc ctg gca aag     2708 
Ile Trp Ser Tyr Gly Ser Gly Tyr Gly Gly Asn Ala Ile Leu Ala Lys 
    215                 220                 225 
aag tgc tac gca ctg cgt atc gca tct gtc atg gct cgc gaa gaa gga     2756 
Lys Cys Tyr Ala Leu Arg Ile Ala Ser Val Met Ala Arg Glu Glu Gly 
230                 235                 240                 245 
tgg atg gct gag cac atg ctc atc ctg aag ctg atc aac cca gag ggc     2804 
Trp Met Ala Glu His Met Leu Ile Leu Lys Leu Ile Asn Pro Glu Gly 
                250                 255                 260 
aag gcg tac cac atc gca gca gca ttc cca tct gct tgt ggc aag acc     2852 
Lys Ala Tyr His Ile Ala Ala Ala Phe Pro Ser Ala Cys Gly Lys Thr 
            265                 270                 275 
aac ctc gcc atg atc act cca acc atc cca ggc tgg acc gct cag gtt     2900 
Asn Leu Ala Met Ile Thr Pro Thr Ile Pro Gly Trp Thr Ala Gln Val 
        280                 285                 290 
gtt ggc gac gac atc gct tgg ctg aag ctg cgc gag gac ggc ctc tac     2948 
Val Gly Asp Asp Ile Ala Trp Leu Lys Leu Arg Glu Asp Gly Leu Tyr 
    295                 300                 305 
gca gtt aac cca gaa aat ggt ttc ttc ggt gtt gct cca ggc acc aac     2996 
Ala Val Asn Pro Glu Asn Gly Phe Phe Gly Val Ala Pro Gly Thr Asn 
310                 315                 320                 325 
tac gca tcc aac cca atc gcg atg aag acc atg gaa cca ggc aac acc     3044 
Tyr Ala Ser Asn Pro Ile Ala Met Lys Thr Met Glu Pro Gly Asn Thr 
                330                 335                 340 
ctg ttc acc aac gtg gca ctc acc gac gac ggc gac atc tgg tgg gaa     3092 
Leu Phe Thr Asn Val Ala Leu Thr Asp Asp Gly Asp Ile Trp Trp Glu 
            345                 350                 355 
ggc atg gac ggc gac gcc cca gct cac ctc att gac tgg atg ggc aac     3140 
Gly Met Asp Gly Asp Ala Pro Ala His Leu Ile Asp Trp Met Gly Asn 
        360                 365                 370 
gac tgg acc cca gag tcc gac gaa aac gct gct cac cct aac tcc cgt     3188 
Asp Trp Thr Pro Glu Ser Asp Glu Asn Ala Ala His Pro Asn Ser Arg 
    375                 380                 385 
tac tgc gta gca atc gac cag tcc cca gca gca gca cct gag ttc aac     3236 
Tyr Cys Val Ala Ile Asp Gln Ser Pro Ala Ala Ala Pro Glu Phe Asn 
390                 395                 400                 405 
gac tgg gaa ggc gtc aag atc gac gca atc ctc ttc ggt gga cgt cgc     3284 
Asp Trp Glu Gly Val Lys Ile Asp Ala Ile Leu Phe Gly Gly Arg Arg 
                410                 415                 420 
gca gac acc gtc cca ctg gtt acc cag acc tac gac tgg gag cac ggc     3332 
Ala Asp Thr Val Pro Leu Val Thr Gln Thr Tyr Asp Trp Glu His Gly 
            425                 430                 435 
acc atg gtt ggt gca ctg ctc gca tcc ggt cag acc gca gct tcc gca     3380 
Thr Met Val Gly Ala Leu Leu Ala Ser Gly Gln Thr Ala Ala Ser Ala 
        440                 445                 450 
gaa gca aag gtc ggc aca ctc cgc cac gac cca atg gca atg ctc cca     3428 
Glu Ala Lys Val Gly Thr Leu Arg His Asp Pro Met Ala Met Leu Pro 
    455                 460                 465 
ttc att ggc tac aac gct ggt gaa tac ctg cag aac tgg att gac atg     3476 
Phe Ile Gly Tyr Asn Ala Gly Glu Tyr Leu Gln Asn Trp Ile Asp Met 
470                 475                 480                 485 
ggt aac aag ggt ggc gac aag atg cca tcc atc ttc ctg gtc aac tgg     3524 
Gly Asn Lys Gly Gly Asp Lys Met Pro Ser Ile Phe Leu Val Asn Trp 
                490                 495                 500 
ttc cgc cgt ggc gaa gat gga cgc ttc ctg tgg cct ggc ttc ggc gac     3572 
Phe Arg Arg Gly Glu Asp Gly Arg Phe Leu Trp Pro Gly Phe Gly Asp 
            505                 510                 515 
aac tct cgc gtt ctg aag tgg gtc atc gac cgc atc gaa ggc cac gtt     3620 
Asn Ser Arg Val Leu Lys Trp Val Ile Asp Arg Ile Glu Gly His Val 
        520                 525                 530 
ggc gca gac gag acc gtt gtt gga cac acc gct aag gcc gaa gac ctc     3668 
Gly Ala Asp Glu Thr Val Val Gly His Thr Ala Lys Ala Glu Asp Leu 
    535                 540                 545 
gac ctc gac ggc ctc gac acc cca att gag gat gtc aag gaa gca ctg     3716 
Asp Leu Asp Gly Leu Asp Thr Pro Ile Glu Asp Val Lys Glu Ala Leu 
550                 555                 560                 565 
acc gct cct gca gag cag tgg gca aac gac gtt gaa gac aac gcc gag     3764 
Thr Ala Pro Ala Glu Gln Trp Ala Asn Asp Val Glu Asp Asn Ala Glu 
                570                 575                 580 
tac ctc act ttc ctc gga cca cgt gtt cct gca gag gtt cac agc cag     3812 
Tyr Leu Thr Phe Leu Gly Pro Arg Val Pro Ala Glu Val His Ser Gln 
            585                 590                 595 
ttc gat gct ctg aag gcc cgc att tca gca gct cac gct taaagttcac      3861 
Phe Asp Ala Leu Lys Ala Arg Ile Ser Ala Ala His Ala 
        600                 605                 610 
gcttaagaac tgctaaataa caagaaaggc tcccaccgaa agtgggagcc tttcttgtcg   3921 
ttaagcgatg aatt                                                     3935 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>2 </s210>
<s211>610 </s211>
<s212>PRT </s212>
<s213>Corynebacterium glutamicum </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 2 
Met Thr Thr Ala Ala Ile Arg Gly Leu Gln Gly Glu Ala Pro Thr Lys 
  1               5                  10                  15 
Asn Lys Glu Leu Leu Asn Trp Ile Ala Asp Ala Val Glu Leu Phe Gln 
             20                  25                  30 
Pro Glu Ala Val Val Phe Val Asp Gly Ser Gln Ala Glu Trp Asp Arg 
         35                  40                  45 
Met Ala Glu Asp Leu Val Glu Ala Gly Thr Leu Ile Lys Leu Asn Glu 
     50                  55                  60 
Glu Lys Arg Pro Asn Ser Tyr Leu Ala Arg Ser Asn Pro Ser Asp Val 
 65                  70                  75                  80 
Ala Arg Val Glu Ser Arg Thr Phe Ile Cys Ser Glu Lys Glu Glu Asp 
                 85                  90                  95 
Ala Gly Pro Thr Asn Asn Trp Ala Pro Pro Gln Ala Met Lys Asp Glu 
            100                 105                 110 
Met Ser Lys His Tyr Ala Gly Ser Met Lys Gly Arg Thr Met Tyr Val 
        115                 120                 125 
Val Pro Phe Cys Met Gly Pro Ile Ser Asp Pro Asp Pro Lys Leu Gly 
    130                 135                 140 
Val Gln Leu Thr Asp Ser Glu Tyr Val Val Met Ser Met Arg Ile Met 
145                 150                 155                 160 
Thr Arg Met Gly Ile Glu Ala Leu Asp Lys Ile Gly Ala Asn Gly Ser 
                165                 170                 175 
Phe Val Arg Cys Leu His Ser Val Gly Ala Pro Leu Glu Pro Gly Gln 
            180                 185                 190 
Glu Asp Val Ala Trp Pro Cys Asn Asp Thr Lys Tyr Ile Thr Gln Phe 
        195                 200                 205 
Pro Glu Thr Lys Glu Ile Trp Ser Tyr Gly Ser Gly Tyr Gly Gly Asn 
    210                 215                 220 
Ala Ile Leu Ala Lys Lys Cys Tyr Ala Leu Arg Ile Ala Ser Val Met 
225                 230                 235                 240 
Ala Arg Glu Glu Gly Trp Met Ala Glu His Met Leu Ile Leu Lys Leu 
                245                 250                 255 
Ile Asn Pro Glu Gly Lys Ala Tyr His Ile Ala Ala Ala Phe Pro Ser 
            260                 265                 270 
Ala Cys Gly Lys Thr Asn Leu Ala Met Ile Thr Pro Thr Ile Pro Gly 
        275                 280                 285 
Trp Thr Ala Gln Val Val Gly Asp Asp Ile Ala Trp Leu Lys Leu Arg 
    290                 295                 300 
Glu Asp Gly Leu Tyr Ala Val Asn Pro Glu Asn Gly Phe Phe Gly Val 
305                 310                 315                 320 
Ala Pro Gly Thr Asn Tyr Ala Ser Asn Pro Ile Ala Met Lys Thr Met 
                325                 330                 335 
Glu Pro Gly Asn Thr Leu Phe Thr Asn Val Ala Leu Thr Asp Asp Gly 
            340                 345                 350 
Asp Ile Trp Trp Glu Gly Met Asp Gly Asp Ala Pro Ala His Leu Ile 
        355                 360                 365 
Asp Trp Met Gly Asn Asp Trp Thr Pro Glu Ser Asp Glu Asn Ala Ala 
    370                 375                 380 
His Pro Asn Ser Arg Tyr Cys Val Ala Ile Asp Gln Ser Pro Ala Ala 
385                 390                 395                 400 
Ala Pro Glu Phe Asn Asp Trp Glu Gly Val Lys Ile Asp Ala Ile Leu 
                405                 410                 415 
Phe Gly Gly Arg Arg Ala Asp Thr Val Pro Leu Val Thr Gln Thr Tyr 
            420                 425                 430 
Asp Trp Glu His Gly Thr Met Val Gly Ala Leu Leu Ala Ser Gly Gln 
        435                 440                 445 
Thr Ala Ala Ser Ala Glu Ala Lys Val Gly Thr Leu Arg His Asp Pro 
    450                 455                 460 
Met Ala Met Leu Pro Phe Ile Gly Tyr Asn Ala Gly Glu Tyr Leu Gln 
465                 470                 475                 480 
Asn Trp Ile Asp Met Gly Asn Lys Gly Gly Asp Lys Met Pro Ser Ile 
                485                 490                 495 
Phe Leu Val Asn Trp Phe Arg Arg Gly Glu Asp Gly Arg Phe Leu Trp 
            500                 505                 510 
Pro Gly Phe Gly Asp Asn Ser Arg Val Leu Lys Trp Val Ile Asp Arg 
        515                 520                 525 
Ile Glu Gly His Val Gly Ala Asp Glu Thr Val Val Gly His Thr Ala 
    530                 535                 540 
Lys Ala Glu Asp Leu Asp Leu Asp Gly Leu Asp Thr Pro Ile Glu Asp 
545                 550                 555                 560 
Val Lys Glu Ala Leu Thr Ala Pro Ala Glu Gln Trp Ala Asn Asp Val 
                565                 570                 575 
Glu Asp Asn Ala Glu Tyr Leu Thr Phe Leu Gly Pro Arg Val Pro Ala 
            580                 585                 590 
Glu Val His Ser Gln Phe Asp Ala Leu Lys Ala Arg Ile Ser Ala Ala 
        595                 600                 605 
His Ala 
    610
</s400>
</sequence-list-new-rules>
</sequence-cwu>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An isolated polynucleotide from coryneform bacteria, comprising a polynucleotide sequence chosen from the group consisting of 
<claim-text>a) a polynucleotide which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to a polynucleotide which codes for a polypeptide which comprises the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID No. 2, </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) a polynucleotide which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to a polynucleotide which codes for the polypeptide mentioned and is contained on the plasmid pEK-pckA (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) or pEK-pckB (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a polynucleotide which codes for a polypeptide which comprises an amino acid sequence which is identical to the extent of at least 70% to the amino acid sequence of SEQ ID No. 2, </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) a polynucleotide which is complementary to the polynucleotides of a), b) or c) and </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) a polynucleotide comprising at least 15 successive bases of the polynucleotide sequence of a), b), c) or d). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide is a preferably recombinant DNA which is capable of replication. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the polynucleotide is an RNA. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the nucleic acid sequence as shown in SEQ ID No. 1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. DNA as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> which is capable of replication, comprising 
<claim-text>(i) the nucleotide sequence shown in SEQ ID no. 1, or </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) at least one sequence which corresponds to sequence (i) within the range of the degeneration of the genetic code, or </claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) at least one sequence which hybridizes with the sequence complementary to sequence (i) or (ii), and/or optionally </claim-text>
<claim-text>(v) sense mutations of neutral function in (I). </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The polynucleotide sequence as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, which codes for a polypeptide which comprises the amino acid sequence shown in SEQ ID No. 2. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A vector pEK-pckA, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A vector pEK-pckB, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A vector pk19mobsacB&Dgr;pck, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and deposited in the strain <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>DH5a under number DSM 13047. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Coryneform bacteria serving as a host cell, which contain one of the vectors as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claims 6</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">8</dependent-claim-reference> or into which the &Dgr;pck deletion has been incorporated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A process for the fermentative preparation of L-amino acids, wherein bacteria in which 
<claim-text>a) the polynucleotide as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> is attenuated or the activity of the polypeptide for which the polynucleotide mentioned codes is reduced. </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) the desired product is concentrated in the medium or in the cells of the bacteria and </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) the product is isolated are employed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein bacteria of the genus <highlight><italic>Corynebacterium glutamicum </italic></highlight>are employed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the attenuation is achieved by integration mutagenesis with the aid of the plasmid pK19mobsacB&Dgr;pck, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and deposited as DSM 13047. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The process as claimed in 12, wherein for the preparation of L-lysine, bacteria in which optionally 
<claim-text>at the same time the dapA gene which codes for dihydrodipicolinate synthase is over-expressed, and/or </claim-text>
<claim-text>at the same time a DNA fragment which imparts S-(2-aminoethyl)-cysteine resistance is amplified, </claim-text>
<claim-text>are fermented. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The process as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein for the preparation of L-threonine, bacteria in which optionally at the same time the hom gene which codes for homoserine dehydrogenase and/or hom<highlight><superscript>dr </superscript></highlight>or hom<highlight><superscript>FBR </superscript></highlight>alleles which code for a &ldquo;feed back resistant&rdquo; homoserine dehydrogenase are over-expressed are fermented.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003548A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003548A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003548A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
