<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000804A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000804A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000804</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895901</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65G041/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>198</class>
<subclass>385000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>SOFT TOUCH LIFTER</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dominique</given-name>
<family-name>Baulier</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Windsor</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>GIFFORD, KRASS, GROH, SPRINKLE</name-1>
<name-2>ANDERSON &amp; CITKOWSKI, PC</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>280 N OLD WOODARD AVE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 400</address-2>
<city>BIRMINGHAM</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48009</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A &ldquo;soft touch&rdquo; lifter for an automotive &ldquo;Body in White&rdquo; geometry station like a framing system is disclosed having a unique lifting assembly for elevating both the automotive body and the underbody tooling to a geometry position. The system includes a lift assembly which is vertically slidably mounted to a stationary base and movable between a first position in which the lift frame is positioned beneath a skid positioned at the geometry station and upon which the automotive body is supported, and a second position elevated from the first position. An underbody tooling assembly is mounted to the lift frame, and this tooling assembly includes a plurality of locators which register with position receptors on the automotive underbody when the skid is positioned at the geometry station. A pair of T-shaped lift arms are slidably mounted to the stationary base at opposite ends of the skid, and these lift arms are movable between a lower and an upper position. In their lower position, the lift arms register with the skids so that movement of the lift arms from their lower and to their upper position simultaneously elevates the skid with its supported automotive body to an upper position. A closed loop belt mechanically connects the lift arms to both the stationary base and the lift frame so that the lift arms move from their lower and to their upper position at a speed substantially one-half of the speed of movement of the lift frame from its first and to its second position. Furthermore, as the lift frame approaches its second position and the lift arms simultaneously approach their upper position, the tooling locators fully engage the receptors in the automotive body and slightly elevate the automotive body from the skid to the geometry position to avoid any geometrical impact from the handling system to the part located by the geometry tooling. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> I. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a &ldquo;soft touch&rdquo; lifter for automotive Body in White geometry stations like framing stations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> II. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In automotive Body in White geometry stations, automotive bodies in which the automotive body components have not been initially fixedly secured together, typically by welding, are supported on a skid. The skid, in turn, is moved by a conveyor system such as a roller table or belt conveyor along the conveyor line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In order to form the final geometry and secure the automotive body components together, the skid together with the automotive body components supported by the skid is moved to a geometry station. Automotive tooling is provided at the geometry station, and a part of the tooling is initially positioned beneath the skid as the skid is moved into this geometry station. This underbody tooling typically includes a plurality of locators which register with receptors, such as locating holes, and N.C. blocks and clamps unit locating the outer surface of the body component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The underbody tooling is generally movable at the geometry station between a lower and an upper position. In its upper position, the locators engage the receptors in the automotive underbody components and slightly elevate the automotive body components upwardly from the skid to the geometry position. Since the position of the tooling locators is fixed relative to the receptors, the tooling accurately positions the automotive body components relative to each other at the geometry position. With the automotive body components accurately positioned relative to each other, the body components are secured together by any conventional means, such as welding, clinching, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One disadvantage of these previously known lifter for automotive Body in White geometry systems is that the cycle time for elevating the automotive body components above the skid and to the final geometry position by the machine tools is rather prolonged thus increasing the overall cycle time of the automotive production line. This protracted time to first engage the underbody tooling, then to elevate the automotive body components to the geometry position in contact with upper tooling, since the tooling used to elevate the body components to the assembly position must undergo a double acceleration/deceleration cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> More specifically, with the skid positioned at the geometry station, the underbody tooling is first accelerated from a position largely beneath the skid and towards the automotive body components to deeply engage tooling into underbody cavities. In order to prevent damage to the automotive body components which would otherwise be caused by a rapid impact of the tooling against the body components, the tooling must be decelerated prior to contacting the body components so that only a &ldquo;soft&rdquo; impact occurs between the tooling and the body components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Following the soft impact of the tooling against the body components, the tooling is again reaccelerated thus elevating the body components up to the contact of the upper tooling, creating at the end of the stroke a slight clearance between the body and skid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Such acceleration, deceleration, reacceleration and final deceleration of the tooling, even if performed by a CAME system or an epicycloidal gear box, appreciably increases the overall cycle time for the framing system. This is particularly true, since the underbody tooling together with its movable support frame typically weighs several thousand pounds. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a &ldquo;soft touch&rdquo; lifter for an automotive Body in White geometry station which overcomes all of the above-mentioned disadvantages of the previously known devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In brief, as in the previously known devices, the automotive body components are supported by a skid prior to welding of the body components together. The skid itself is conveyed by any conventional conveyor system, such as a roller conveyor system, such that the skid together with its supported body components are introduced in a geometry station having a stationary base. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A pair of lift frames is vertically slidably mounted to the base at the geometry station so that the lift frame is movable between a first position and a second position. At its first position, the lift frame is largely positioned beneath the skid at the assembly station while, conversely, in its second position, the lift frame is moved to an elevated position relative to its first position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Conventional underbody tooling is secured to the lift frame so that the underbody tooling moves in unison with the lift frame. Such tooling typically includes a plurality of locators which register with receptors, typically locating holes formed in the body components. Thus, as the locators engage their corresponding receptors and elevate the body components toward the upper tooling, and slightly away from the skid, the set of tooling precisely locates the body components relative to each other. The body components are then secured together in any conventional fashion, such as by welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Unlike the previously known lifters for geometry stations like framing systems, however, the lifter system of the present invention includes a pair of lift arms with one lift arm being vertically slidably mounted to the base frame at each end of the lift frame. These lift arms are thus movable between a lower position and an upper position. Furthermore, the lift arms register with the skid so that, as the lift arms are moved from their lower and to their upper position, the lift arms engage and elevate the skid together with the body components supported on the skid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment of the invention, an elongated belt drivingly connects each lift arm with the lift frame. These elongated belts ensure that the lift arms move in synchronism with the lift frame. Just as importantly, however, is that the elongated belts move the lift arms from their lower and to their upper position at a speed one-half the speed of movement of the lift frame from its first and to its second position. Furthermore, as the lift frame approaches its second position and the lift arms simultaneously approach their upper position, the underbody tooling finally engages the automotive underbody and slightly elevates the automotive body components up from the skid at the very end of the upward stroke or upward movement of the lift arm and the lift frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Since the lift arms simultaneously move the skid in an upward direction prior to impact of the underbody tooling upon the automotive body components at the end of the stroke, the speed of impact of the tooling against the automotive body components is effectively reduced by the upward speed of the lift arms and thus of the skid. Consequently, unlike the previously known framing systems, the present system eliminates the need to decelerate the tooling in the middle of its stroke prior to impact against the automotive body components.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A better understanding of the present invention will be had upon reference to the following detailed description, when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawing, wherein like reference characters refer to like parts throughout the several views, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an elevational view illustrating a preferred embodiment of the present invention installed inside of an automotive body framing station; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side view illustrating the preferred embodiment of the present invention installed inside of an automotive body framing station; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an exploded fragmentary view illustrating the lifting arm assembly of the present invention with its belt actuator shown separately; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are fragmentary side views illustrating the operation of the preferred embodiment of the present invention shown in retracted (down) and extended (up) positions; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> are side views of the lifting arm assemblies illustrated in different operational positions and incidental event situations.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF A PREFERRED EMBODIMENT OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> With reference first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an elevational view of an automotive framing system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including a soft touch lifter of the present invention is illustrated. In the conventional fashion, a skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supports two or more automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which are either not attached together or only loosely attached together. These automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are supported on the upper surface of the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, together with its supported body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, is transported by any conventional means, such as a roller conveyor system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (illustrated diagrammatically) to a geometry station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the geometry station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which is fixed relative to a ground support surface. A lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is vertically slidably mounted to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and movable between a lower position, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and an upper position, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. In the conventional fashion, an automotive underbody tooling assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is secured to the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> so that the underbody tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> moves in unison with the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of locators <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) which register with receptors <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (illustrated only diagrammatically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 6</cross-reference>) in the automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. These receptors <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> typically comprise locating holes formed in the automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Consequently, with the tooling locators <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> positioned within their associated receptors <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> on the automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the automotive underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is precisely positioned. With the automotive underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> thus positioned, the other body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> will be located by upper tooling <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> before being secured together in any conventional fashion, such as by welding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, with the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> positioned in a first or lower position, both the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is positioned beneath the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> when the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is introduced in the geometry station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is vertically slidably mounted to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and movable to a second elevated position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) in which the tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> engages the underbody components <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in the previously described fashion thus supporting the body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at an assembly position illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Any conventional means, such as hydraulic actuators, electric actuators, or the like <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are used to move the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> from its first position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and to its second position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, a pair of lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are supported by the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> so that the lift arms are positioned at opposite ends of the assembly station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). Each lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is generally T-shaped thus having a vertical leg <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and an upper crossbeam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are vertically slidably mounted to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and movable between a lower position, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, and an upper position, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> via an intermediate situation illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Although any conventional means may be used to vertically slidably mount the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in the preferred embodiment a plurality of &ldquo;Ve Rollers&rdquo; <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are rotatably mounted to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and engage opposite sides of the vertical leg <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Still referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3, 7</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, in order to move the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> between its lower and upper positions, a first roller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the top of the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> while, similarly, a second roller <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the bottom of the vertical leg <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The rollers <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are preferably aligned with the center leg <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> An elongated belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is disposed around the rollers <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and a mid-portion of the belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is secured to the base <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by a retaining block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The retaining block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> thus fixes a mid-portion of the belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> against vertical movement relative to the base. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The free ends of the belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are secured to the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> through a retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> preferably comprises a pivot plate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which is pivotally mounted to the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by a pivot bar <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A pair of spring retainers <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (only one illustrated) urge the plate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> up to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> while a pair of tensioning springs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> provide longitudinal tensioning on the upper loop of the belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, however, is wrapped around a stationary roller <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> mounted to the pivot plate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> so that, during normal operation of the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the overall length of the band <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, i.e. the length from the retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and around both the top and the <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> bottom of the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, is generally fixed. Furthermore, the longitudinal length of the band <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> from the retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and around the top roller <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the retaining block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is substantially the same as the longitudinal length of the belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> from the retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, around the bottom roller <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and to the retaining block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, the band <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> together with the retaining block <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> drivingly connects the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> together so that both the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> move in synchronism with each other. However, the vertical speed of the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is one-half the vertical speed of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> With reference now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the operation of the system of the present invention will now be described. With the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supporting its automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> positioned at the assembly station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the opposite ends of the horizontal supports <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are positioned beneath the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Consequently, one lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is aligned with the front end of the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> while the other lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is aligned with the rear end of the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> begins to move from its first and to its second position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> engage the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and move the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> upward together with its supported body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in unison with the upward movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with its tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. However, as previously described, the upward speed and stroke of the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is one-half the speed and stroke of upward movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are movable from a lower position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) to an upper position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) in synchronism with the movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> from its lower position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) to its second or upper position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). Furthermore, as both the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> near their intermediate position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> starts to engage the underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Consequently, as the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> attains its second position and the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> attain their uppermost position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>), the tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> not only engages the underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> but elevates the body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> above the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> thus accurately positioning the underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in preparation for accurate positioning of the other body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by the upper tooling <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, prior to securement of the body components to each other. After the body components are secured together, typically by welding, the lift frame is returned to its first or lower position thus automatically moving the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to their lower position and returning not only the automotive body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, but the skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to the roller conveyor system <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with the now assembled body components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is transported by the conveyor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for further processing while a new skid <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supporting its unattached body components is moved into the assembly station <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> where the above process is repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> An important advantage of the present invention is that, since the skid is elevated from its lower and to its upper position at one half the speed and stroke of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> containing the tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the speed of impact of the tooling <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> against the underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is effectively reduced by the upward speed of the lift arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and because the impact occurs also at the end of the stroke rather than at the middle. This, in turn, eliminates the previously known necessity of decelerating the lift frame in the middle of its stroke prior to the impact of the tooling against the underbody components <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. By eliminating the previously known necessity of decelerating the lift frame prior to impact of the tooling against the underbody <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the cycle time of the framing station of the present invention is effectively reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> With reference again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, in the event of a malfunction or jam of the framing system, the synchronism between the lifting arms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be disrupted. Such disrupting can occur on either the upward or downward stroke of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> When the disruption between the synchronous movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> occurs on the upward stroke of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, i.e. the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is maintained stationary despite upward movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, this relative movement will cause the plate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the retainer assembly <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to pivot downward as shown in phantom line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> against the force of the spring retainer <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. A sensor <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (illustrated diagrammatically) detects this pivotal action of the retainer plate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and generates an output signal to disable or deactivate the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> thus preventing damage to the automotive component <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as well as the system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Conversely, if a malfunction occurs during the downward stroke of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> such that the lift arm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is maintained stationary despite the continued downward movement of the lift frame <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the upper loop of belt <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> will be effectively elongated thus causing compression of the belt tensioning springs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> as shown in phantom line. When this occurs, a further sensor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> (illustrated diagrammatically) detects the compression of the springs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and again generates an output signal to deactivate or shut down the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing, it can be seen that the present invention provides a novel lift assembly for an automotive framing system which is not only simple in construction, but effective in use. A primary advantage of the present invention is that it reduces the overall cycle time for the geometry station like a framing station. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Having described my invention, however, many modifications thereto will become apparent to those skilled in the art to which it pertains without deviation from the spirit of the invention as defined by the scope of the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. For use in conjunction with a skid which supports an automotive body and a conveyor which transports the skid to an assembly station, a lift assembly for elevating the automotive body at the assembly station to an assembly position comprising: 
<claim-text>a base, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lift frame vertically slidably mounted to said base at the assembly station and movable between a first position in which said lift frame is positioned beneath the skid positioned at the assembly station, and a second position elevated from said first position, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tooling assembly mounted to said lift frame, said tooling assembly having a plurality of locators which register with position receptors on the automotive body when the skid is positioned at the assembly station, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of lift arms, said lift arms being vertically slidably mounted to said base adjacent opposite ends of the assembly station and movable between a lower position in which the lift arms are positioned beneath the skid when positioned in said assembly station and an upper position, each lift arm having a portion which registers with the skid, </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for moving at a first speed said lift frame from said first position to said second position, </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for moving at a second speed said lift arms from said lower position to said upper position in synchronism with said lift frame as said lift frame moves from said first position to said second position, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second speed is slower than said first speed, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein with said lift frame in said second position and said lift arms in said upper position, said locators engage said receptors and elevate the automotive body from the skid. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> and comprising means for vertically slidably mounting said lift arms to said base frame. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said means for vertically slidably mounting said lift arms to said base frame comprises at least two rollers rotatably mounted to said base, said rollers mechanically engaging opposite sides of the lift arms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said means for moving said lift arms comprises: 
<claim-text>an elongated belt having two ends, said belt being disposed around a top and a bottom of said lift arm, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said belt having a mid-point secured against movement to the base, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said ends of said belt being secured to said lift frame. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> and comprising at least one tension spring which longitudinally tensions the upper loop of said belt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> and comprising a sensor which detects movement of said tension spring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> and comprising a mounting assembly which secures said ends of said belt to said lift frame, said mounting assembly comprising a plate pivotally mounted to said lift frame about a horizontal axis, said being pivotal between a first position and a second position and a spring which resilient urges said plate toward said first position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> and comprising a sensor which detects movement of said mounting assembly plate from said first and towards said second position and provides an output signal representative of said movement of said mounting assembly plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The invention as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said lift arm is T-shaped thus having a vertical base and a horizontal upper cross support, and means for slidably mounting the vertical base of each lift arm to said base frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000804A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
