<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000779A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000779A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000779</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894875</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62B005/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>188</class>
<subclass>019000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Bicycle disc brake hub</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Takanori</given-name>
<family-name>Kanehisa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Shimano Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SHINJYU GLOBAL IP COUNSELORS, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1233 20TH STREET, NW, SUITE 700</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036-2680</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A bicycle disc brake hub is provided with a hub axle, a hub shell, a first spoke attachment portion, a second spoke attachment portion and a brake rotor attachment portion disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion. The first spoke attachment portion has a plurality of first spoke holes, while the second spoke attachment portion has a plurality of second spoke holes. The first spoke attachment portion is disposed at the first hub shell end, while the second spoke attachment portion is disposed at the second hub shell end. The brake rotor attachment portion has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes with predetermined diameters and center axes spaced a second radial distance from the center axis of the hub axle. The first spoke attachment portion and the brake rotor attachment portion are arranged relative to each other such that spokes can easily be installed into the first spoke holes. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention generally relates to a bicycle disc brake hub. More specifically, the present invention relates a bicycle disc brake hub with an integral rotor attachment portion or flange. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Background Information </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Bicycling is becoming an increasingly popular form of recreation as well as a means of transportation. Moreover, bicycling has become a very popular competitive sport. Whether the bicycle is used for recreation, transportation or competition, the bicycle industry is constantly improving their components. Recently, the braking systems for bicycles have included the use of disc brakes. The use of disc brakes has resulted in modifications to the bicycle hub of the bicycle wheel so that a brake rotor can be mounted thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The most basic bicycle wheels have a hub, a plurality of spokes and an annular rim. The hub is attached to a part of the frame of the bicycle for relative rotation. The inner ends of the spokes are coupled to the hub and extend outwardly from the hub. The annular rim is coupled to the outer ends of the spokes and has an outer portion for supporting a pneumatic tire thereon. Typically, the spokes of the bicycle wheel are thin metal wire spokes. The ends of the hub are provided with a flange that is used to couple the spokes to the hub. In particular, holes are provided in the hub flanges. The wire spokes are usually bent on their inner end and provided with an enlarged head or flange that is formed in the shape of a nail head. The inner end is supported in one of the holes in one of the hub flanges. The outer ends of the spokes typically are provided with threads for engaging spoke nipples, which secure the outer ends of the wire spokes to the rim. In particular, the spoke nipples have flanges, which engage the interior surface of the rim. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With a spoke constructed in this manner, the nipples are installed in nipple holes formed in the rim. The spokes are inserted sideways through the holes in the hub flange until the enlarged head or flanges of the spokes engaging the areas surrounding the holes in the hub flange. The male threads on the ends of the spokes are threaded into the female threads of the spoke nipples installed in the openings of the rim. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the hub is a disc brake hub, installation and/or replacement of the spokes can be difficult. In the case of a disk brake hub, one end of the hub usually has a brake rotor attachment portion. Often, the brake rotor attachment portion is a plurality of blind bores that receive bolts to directly mount the disc brake rotor to the end of the hub. Thus, the disc brake rotor makes it difficult to insert the spokes in a sideways direction. To overcome this problem, the spoke attachment portion adjacent the brake rotor attachment portion is often made to be larger in diameter than the brake rotor attachment portion. This increases the weight of the disk brake hub as well as the cost to manufacture the disk brake hub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Moreover, hubs that have blind bores for mounting a disc brake rotor are time consuming to form and often become damaged. When the blind bores become damaged, the entire hub must be replaced. Thus, these prior hubs are expensive to manufacture and replace. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In view of the above, there exists a need for a bicycle hub which overcomes the above mentioned problems in the prior art. This invention addresses this need in the prior art as well as other needs, which will become apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> One object of the present invention is to provide a bicycle hub with an integrated brake rotor attachment portion disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion such spokes can easily be installed into first spoke holes of the first spoke attachment portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a bicycle hub with an integrated brake rotor attachment portion disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion that is relatively lightweight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a bicycle hub with an integrated brake rotor attachment portion disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion that is relatively inexpensive to manufacture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The foregoing objects can be attained by providing a bicycle disc brake hub comprising a hub axle, a hub shell, a first spoke attachment portion, a second spoke attachment portion and a brake rotor attachment portion. The hub axle has a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end. The hub shell has an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with the hub axle being rotatably supported in the interior passageway. The first spoke attachment portion has a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between the first and second axially facing surfaces. The first spoke holes have center axes spaced a first radial distance from the center axis of the hub axle. The first spoke attachment portion is disposed at the first hub shell end with the second axially facing surface facing towards the second hub shell end. The second spoke attachment portion has a plurality of second spoke holes. The second spoke attachment portion is disposed at the second hub shell end. The brake rotor attachment portion has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes with predetermined diameters and center axes spaced a second radial distance from the center axis of the hub axle. The brake rotor attachment portion is disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion with the first axially facing surface facing towards the brake rotor attachment portion. The first spoke attachment portion and the brake rotor attachment portion are arranged relative to each other to attach spokes to the first spoke holes through the rotor mounting holes of the brake rotor attachment portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first spoke holes are individually viewable in the axial direction from a location looking axially towards the brake rotor attachment portion. The first axially facing surface of the first spoke attachment portion and the first radial distance of the first spoke holes are less than the second radial distance plus half of the predetermined diameter of one of the rotor mounting holes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The foregoing objects can also be attained by providing a bicycle disc brake hub comprising a hub axle, a hub shell, a first spoke attachment portion, a second spoke attachment portion and a brake rotor attachment portion. The hub axle has a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end. The hub shell has an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with the hub axle being rotatably supported in the interior passageway. The first spoke attachment portion has a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between the first and second axially facing surfaces. The first spoke attachment portion being disposed at the first hub shell end with the second axially facing surface facing towards the second hub shell end. The second spoke attachment portion has a plurality of second spoke holes, the second spoke attachment portion being disposed at the second hub shell end. The brake rotor attachment portion has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes and an outer peripheral surface that lies within an imaginary circle circumscribing the outer peripheral surface. The brake rotor attachment portion is disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion with the first axially facing surface facing towards the brake rotor attachment portion. The first spoke holes is located radially inward of the imaginary circle circumscribing the outer peripheral surface of the brake rotor attachment portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The foregoing objects can further be attained by providing a bicycle disc brake hub comprising a hub axle, a hub shell, a first spoke attachment portion, a second spoke attachment portion and a brake rotor attachment portion. The hub axle has a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end. The hub shell has an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with the hub axle being rotatably supported in the interior passageway. The first spoke attachment portion has a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between the first and second axially facing surfaces. The first spoke attachment portion is disposed at the first hub shell end with the second axially facing surface facing towards the second hub shell end. The second spoke attachment portion has a plurality of second spoke holes. The second spoke attachment portion being disposed at the second hub shell end. The brake rotor attachment portion has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes. The brake rotor attachment portion is disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion with the first axially facing surface facing towards the brake rotor attachment portion. The brake rotor attachment portion and the first spoke attachment portion have maximum outer diameters with the maximum outer diameter of the first spoke attachment portion being no greater than the maximum outer diameter of the brake rotor attachment portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description, which, taken in conjunction with the annexed drawings, discloses preferred embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the attached drawings which form a part of this original disclosure: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a conventional bicycle with front and rear disc brake hubs in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic elevational view of the rear disc brake assembly coupled to a rear fork and a rear disc brake operating mechanism of the bicycle illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic elevational view of the front disc brake assembly coupled to a front fork and a front disc brake operating mechanism of the bicycle illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the rear disc brake hub and the rear disc brake rotor of the rear wheel illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with the sprockets removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a partial exploded cross-sectional view of the rear rim and the rear disc brake hub shell with a spoke being installed thereon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the front disc brake hub and the front disc brake rotor of the front wheel illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the disc brake rotor in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the rear disc brake hub and the rear disc brake rotor in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the front disc brake hub and the front disc brake rotor with the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the rear disc brake hub and the rear disc brake rotor in accordance with a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the front disc brake hub and the front disc brake rotor with the third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the disc brake rotor used with the rear and front disc brake hubs of the third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the rear disc brake hub and the rear disc brake rotor in accordance with a fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the rear disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> is a partial longitudinal cross-sectional view of the front disc brake hub and the front disc brake rotor with the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference> is a left end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> is a right end elevational view of the front disc brake hub illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> with the disc brake rotor removed; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the disc brake rotor used with the rear and front disc brake hubs of the fourth embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Referring initially to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated with rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention as discussed below. The rear disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> rotatably couples a rear wheel <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to a rear portion of a frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, while the front disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; rotatably couples a front wheel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to a front fork <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> also includes a seat <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> adjustably coupled to the frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a handlebar <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> coupled to the front fork <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for turning the front wheel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and a drive train <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> for propelling the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Since these most of the parts of the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are well known in the art, the parts of the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will not be discussed or illustrated in detail herein, except for the parts relating to the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; of the present invention. Moreover, various conventional bicycle parts such as brakes, derailleurs, additional sprocket, etc., which are not illustrated and/or discussed in detail herein, can be used in conjunction with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As best seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is also provided with rear and front disc brake assemblies <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;. The rear disc brake assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a caliper <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> operatively coupled to a brake lever <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and a rear disc brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> fixedly coupled to the rear disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the rear wheel <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the front disc brake assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime; includes a caliper <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>&prime; operatively coupled to a brake lever <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; and a front disc brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (same as rear rotor) fixedly coupled to the front disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; of the front wheel <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 7</cross-reference>, the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; of the and front wheels <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> have a plurality of spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> extending outwardly therefrom. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the outer ends of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are fixedly coupled to the rim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> by spoke nipples <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A tire <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is located on the outer surface of each of the rims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in ac conventional manner. The disc brake rotors <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are attached to the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; by bolts <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, as explained below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> While the illustrated embodiment of the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is used to create a pair of twenty-four spoke wheels, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that other spoke arrangements are possible without departing from the present invention. For example, a thirty-two spoke wheel or a thirty-six spoke wheel can be constructed in accordance with the present invention without departing from the present invention as seen in the later embodiments. Basically, the number of spoke holes depends upon the rim to be used with the hub of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the rims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the spoke nipples <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are all conventional parts that are used with the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; of the present invention. In other words, the unique design of the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; allows it to be used with conventional parts, e.g., conventional tangential spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and conventional rims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when the wheels <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are assembled, the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> extend tangentially from imaginary circles centered on the center axes of rotations O and O&prime; of the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;conventional spokes&rdquo; as used herein are spokes that have a straight section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a bent end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with an enlarged head <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>such that straight section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extends at an angle of about 95&deg; relative to the bent end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Such spokes are well known in the bicycle art. While the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are illustrated as being tangentially arranged relative to the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that other spoke arrangements are possible without departing from the present invention. For example, one end or both ends of the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; can have radially extending spokes. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the illustrated embodiment each have an outer threaded end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that is located at the opposite end of the center straight section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the bent end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(inner end portion) with the enlarged head <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The bent end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a center axis that forms an angle of about 95&deg; with the center axis of the straight section <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are designed to be received within the first and second spoke holes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The rim <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can be any conventional rim that has a plurality of spoke holes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for receiving the spoke nipples <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for attaching the outer threaded ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> thereto. In the illustrated embodiment of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the rims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; are conventional steel or alloy rims having a U-shaped cross section with twenty-four spoke holes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The spoke holes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are equally spaced apart in a circumferential direction. The spoke holes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are preferably lie in a single plane P that divides the cross section in half as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Of course, rims with fewer or more spoke holes <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be used with a hub of the present invention, if needed and/or desired. For example, the rims <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can have thirty-two or thirty-six spoke holes instead of twenty-four spoke holes, if the rear and front disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; are modified to have more spoke holes as explained below. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Rear Hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As best seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, a hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is basically a conventional hub, except for the configuration of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Thus, conventional parts of the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will not illustrated and/or discussed in detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a center axis O extending in an axial direction between a first axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a second axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a center bore <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>such that a quick release mechanism (not shown) is coupled to the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in a conventional manner. The hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> rotatably supports the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by first and second bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The second axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has a freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> operatively coupled between the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in a conventional manner. The hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is fixed with respect to the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in one rotational direction by the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, while the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> allows the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to freely rotate with respect to the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the opposite rotational direction. The first and second ends <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are threaded for receiving a pair of nuts <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that applies an axial force on the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is a tubular member that has an interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extending between first and second hub shell ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> being rotatably supported in the interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In particular, the first and second bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>rotatably mount the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> within the interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> also has a center tubular portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>located between the first and second hub shell ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>which are integral formed with the center tubular portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>as a one-piece, unitary member. The first and second spoke attachment portions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are integrally formed with the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as a one-piece, unitary member. In particular, the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> integrally mounted thereon, while the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> integrally mounted thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>has the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> fixedly coupled thereto. The freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is attached between the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to allow the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to rotate freely relative to the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in one direction, but fixedly couples the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> relative to the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the opposite rotational direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>rotatably support the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> on the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Since the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are well known in the bicycle art, they will not be discussed or illustrated in detail herein. The bearing assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>basically includes a plurality of balls located between an inner race member and an outer race member in a conventional manner. Similarly, the bearing assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>basically includes a plurality of balls located between an inner race member and an outer race member in a conventional manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Bicycle freewheels, such as the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, are well known in the bicycle art, and thus, the freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> will not be illustrated or discussed in detail herein. The freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is used to transmit a driving force from the chain to the rear bicycle wheel in one rotation direction only. The freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> allows the bicycle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to advance freely without any rotation of the pedals. The freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is fastened to the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as integral part of the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in a conventional manner. The freewheel <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> basically includes an outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, an inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a one-way clutch <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is installed radially inwardly of the outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>so that the inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is free to rotate relative to the outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The one-way clutch <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is installed between the outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for transmitting the driving force from the outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in one rotational direction only. The outer tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a plurality of gears or sprockets (not shown) mounted thereon, while the inner tubular part <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is fixedly mounted on the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is preferably an annular spoke flange located at the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> has a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> has twelve of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> equally spaced apart about an imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>that is centered about the center axis O. The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are arranged to receiving the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> have their center axes A parallel to the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>that is centered on the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. In particular, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> has a first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and a second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> with the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> extending axially between the first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Thus, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is disposed at the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with the second axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> facing towards the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> have their center axes A spaced a first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>from the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> has a transverse cross section with a semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a notched section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that extends outwardly from the semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in a radial direction relative to its center axis A. This shape of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> allows for easy insertion of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> into the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> during assembly of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>preferably extends at least about 180&deg; and more preferably about 300&deg; to securely retain the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> therein. The notched section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>preferably extends outwardly at least about half of the diameter of the semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the circumference of the circle defining the second semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are oriented so that every other one of the notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>points towards the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, while other notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>point in a circumferential direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Similarly, as best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is provided with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for receiving the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In the illustrated embodiment, the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is provided with twelve of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> equally spaced apart about the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>that is centered on the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Each of the spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is also designed to receive one of the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is designed to have twenty-four spokes extending outwardly therefrom in a generally tangential direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is preferably an annular spoke flange located at the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> have their center axes A parallel to the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>centered on the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. In particular, the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and a second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> with the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extending axially between the first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Thus, the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is disposed at the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with the second axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> facing towards the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> have their center axes A spaced a radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>from the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The center axes A of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are circumferentially offset from the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> such that the spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are located between the spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> has a transverse cross section with a semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a notched section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that extends outwardly from the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in a radial direction relative to its center axis A. This shape of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> allows for easy insertion of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> into the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> during assembly of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>preferably extends at least about 180&deg; and more preferably about 300&deg; to securely retain the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> therein. The notched section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>preferably extends outwardly at least about half of the diameter of the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the circumference of the circle defining the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Preferably, the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are identical in cross section, but have different orientations of the notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are designed to be used with conventional tangential spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be radially arranged in either or both of the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the first and second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are substantially identical, except for the orientations of the notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. Of course, it is possible that the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be different from the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> such that the first and second spoke attachment portions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can have different types of spoking arrangements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is integrally formed with the first hub end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as a one-piece, unitary member of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes or bores <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> with predetermined diameters D and center axes B spaced a second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>from the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> with the first axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> facing towards the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is formed with six attachment members or mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> with the mounting holes or bores <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extending axially therethrough. The mounting holes <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are preferably internally threaded. Thus, the disc brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is fixedly coupled the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> by the bolts <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are arranged relative to each other such that the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are individually viewable in the axial direction from a location looking axially towards the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the first axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. In particular, the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are individually viewable in the axial direction through the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and between the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. While six individual mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> are illustrated, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that fewer or more attachment points can be utilized. Moreover, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> can be a continuous flange with addition holes such that each of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are individually viewable in the axial direction through the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> In this first embodiment, the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, while the mounting holes <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> lie on an imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>that is smaller than the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>. The first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are less than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>plus half of the predetermined diameter D of one of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. This arrangement allows one of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> to be view through each of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. Thus, the annular spoke flange forming the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> has an outer diameter that is no greater than an effective outer diameter formed by the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. In fact, this arrangement allows the outer diameter of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to be less than the effective outer diameter formed by the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> To aid in the installation of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> into the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are preferably offset from the center axes B of the corresponding ones of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>that is larger than the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>having the center axes B of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. Thus, the first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> from the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is greater than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the center axes B of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> from the center axis of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Of course, the first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> from the center axis O of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can be less than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of the center axes B of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> from the center axis of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> as seen in the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; of FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Front Hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;</heading>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Turning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is illustrated in accordance with the present invention. The front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is substantially identical to the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, except that the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; does not have a freewheel and the spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; lie on imaginary circles C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; having smaller diameters than the imaginary circles C<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>formed by the spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;, a hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime;, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;. The bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is basically a conventional hub, except for the configuration of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;. Thus, conventional parts of the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; will not illustrated and/or discussed in detail herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; has a center axis O&prime; extending in an axial direction between a first axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and a second axle end <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime;. The hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; has a center bore <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>&prime; such that a quick release mechanism (not shown) is coupled to the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; in a conventional manner. The hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; rotatably supports the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; by first and second bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime;. The first and second ends <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; are threaded for receiving a pair of nuts <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; that applies an axial force on the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; and the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b&prime;. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> The hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; is a tubular member that has an interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>&prime; extending between first and second hub shell ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; with the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; being rotatably supported in the interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>&prime;. In particular, the first and second bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; rotatably mount the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; within the interior passageway <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>&prime;. The hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; also has a center tubular portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>&prime; located between the first and second hub shell ends <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime;, which are integral formed with the center tubular portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>&prime; as a one-piece, unitary member. The first and second spoke attachment portions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; are integrally formed with the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; as a one-piece, unitary member. In particular, the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; has the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; integrally mounted thereon, while the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; has the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; integrally mounted thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; rotatably support the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; on the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. Since the bearing assemblies <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; are well known in the bicycle art, they will not be discussed or illustrated in detail herein. The bearing assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; basically includes a plurality of balls located between an inner race member and an outer race member in a conventional manner. Similarly, the bearing assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; basically includes a plurality of balls located between an inner race member and an outer race member in a conventional manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; is preferably an annular spoke flange that is located at the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; has a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime;. In this embodiment, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; has twelve of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; equally spaced apart about the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime;. The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are arranged to receiving the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; have their center axes A&prime; parallel to the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; that is centered on the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. In particular, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; has a first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime; and a second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>&prime; with the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; extending axially between the first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime; and the second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>&prime;. Thus, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; is disposed at the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; with the second axially facing surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>&prime; facing towards the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime;. The first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; have their center axes A&prime; spaced a first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; from the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, each of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; has a transverse cross section with a semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and a notched section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; that extends outwardly from the semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; in a radial direction relative to its center axis A&prime;. This shape of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; allows for easy insertion of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; into the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; during assembly of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; to the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;. The semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>a&prime; preferably extends at least about 180&deg; and more preferably about 300&deg; to securely retain the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; therein. The notched section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; preferably extends outwardly at least about half of the diameter of the semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; from the circumference of the circle defining the second semi circular section <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime;. The notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are oriented so that every other one of the notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; points towards the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;, while other notched sections <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; point in a circumferential direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Similarly, the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; is provided with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; for receiving the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;. In the illustrated embodiment, the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; is provided with twelve of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; equally spaced apart about the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; that is centered on the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. Each of the spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; is also designed to receive one of the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;. Accordingly, the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; is designed to have twenty-four spokes extending outwardly therefrom in a generally tangential direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; is preferably an annular spoke flange located at the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; have their center axes A&prime; parallel to the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; that is centered on the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. In particular, the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; has a first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>&prime; and a second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>&prime; with the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; extending axially between the first (outer) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>&prime; and the second (inner) axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>&prime;. Thus, the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; is disposed at the second hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; with the second axially facing surface <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>&prime; facing towards the first hub shell end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime;. The second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; have their center axes A&prime; spaced a radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; from the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, preferably, the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; are identical. Thus, each of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; has a transverse cross section with a semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; and a notched section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; that extends outwardly from the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; in a radial direction relative to its center axis A&prime;. This shape of the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; allows for easy insertion of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; into the second spoke holes <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; during assembly of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; to the bicycle disc brake hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;. The semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; preferably extends at least about 180&deg; and more preferably about 300&deg; to securely retain the bent ends <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; therein. The notched section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; preferably extends outwardly at least about half of the diameter of the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; from the circumference of the circle defining the semi circular section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a&prime;. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> As mentioned above, the first and second spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; are designed to be used with conventional tangential spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;. Alternatively, the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; can be radially arranged. Preferably, the first and second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; are substantially identical. Of course, it is possible that the second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; can be different from the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; such that the first and second spoke attachment portions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; can have different spoking arrangements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; is integrally formed with the first hub end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime; of the hub shell <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; as a one-piece, unitary member. The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; has a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes or bores <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime; with predetermined diameters D&prime; and center axes B&prime; spaced a second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; from the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. The brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; is disposed adjacent the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; with the first axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime; of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; facing towards the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; is formed with six attachment members or mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime; with the mounting holes or bores <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime; extending axially therethrough. The mounting holes <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime; are preferably internally threaded. Thus, the disc brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is fixedly coupled the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; by the bolts <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; are arranged relative to each other such that the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are individually viewable in the axial direction from a location looking axially towards the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; and the first axially facing surface <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime; of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime;. In particular, the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are individually viewable in the axial direction through the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>&prime; and between the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. While six individual mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime; are illustrated, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that fewer or more attachment points can be utilized. Moreover, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; can be a continuous flange with addition holes such that each of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are individually viewable in the axial direction through the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; is less than the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. Moreover, the first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are greater than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; minus half of the predetermined diameter D&prime; of one of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. This arrangement allows one of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; to be view through each of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. Thus, the annular spoke flange forming the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; has an outer diameter that is no greater than an effective outer diameter formed by the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. In fact, this arrangement allows the outer diameter of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; to be less than the effective outer diameter formed by the mounting flanges <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> To aid in the installation of the spokes <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; into the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime;, the center axes A&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; are preferably offset from the center axes B&prime; of the corresponding ones of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. In this first embodiment of the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, the center axes A&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; lie on the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; that is smaller than the imaginary circle C<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; having the center axes B&prime; of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime;. Thus, the first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the center axes A&prime; of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; from the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; is less than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the center axes B&prime; of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime; from the center axis of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime;. Of course, the first radial distance R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the center axes A of the first spoke holes <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime; from the center axis O&prime; of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; can be greater than the second radial distance R<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&prime; of the center axes B&prime; of the rotor mounting holes <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>&prime; from the center axis of the hub axle <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; as seen in the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Bicycle Brake Rotor </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> basically includes an annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>a plurality (nine) of outwardly extending connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>integrally formed with annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and an inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>integrally formed with the connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Accordingly, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is a one-piece, unitary member. Preferably, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is constructed of any suitable rigid material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is preferably vented with a plurality of holes. The annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>forms an outer braking portion of the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The outer ends of the connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are equally spaced about the inner edge of the annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>form an intermediate connecting portion of the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> extending between the annular braking ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>These connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extend tangentially from the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>The connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>have triangular openings located therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>has a plurality (six) of axially extending attachment holes <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight>The attachment holes <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>have diameters of at least seven millimeters, preferably diameters of eight millimeters. The attachment holes <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are equally spaced about the circumference of the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>also has a plurality of cutouts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>with one of the cutouts <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>located at the base of one of the inner ends of the connecting arms <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Second Embodiment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, a pair of alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; are illustrated in accordance with second embodiments of the present invention. These alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; are designed to be used with the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. In view of the similarity between the first and second embodiments, the descriptions of the parts of the second embodiment that are identical to the parts of the first embodiment may be omitted for the sake of brevity. Moreover, the parts of the second embodiment that have the same functions as the parts of the first embodiment will be given the same reference numerals as the parts of the first embodiment, but increased by one hundred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> As seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the rear disc brake hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, a hub shell <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>. The rear hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, except that the rear hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> has circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> instead of spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> As seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, the front disc brake hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>&prime;, a hub shell <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>&prime;, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>&prime;, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>&prime;, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>&prime;. The front hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; is substantially identical to the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, except that the front hub <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>&prime; has circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>&prime; instead of spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Third Embodiment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a pair of alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>&prime; are illustrated in accordance with third embodiments of the present invention. These alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>&prime; are designed to be used with the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. In view of the similarity between the first and third embodiments, the descriptions of the parts of the third embodiment that are identical to the parts of the first embodiment may be omitted for the sake of brevity. Moreover, the parts of the third embodiment that have the same functions as the parts of the first embodiment will be given the same reference numerals as the parts of the first embodiment, but increased by two hundred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the rear disc brake hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>, a hub shell <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. The rear hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, except for the configuration of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight> of the rear hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has sixteen circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> instead of twelve spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. Moreover, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> only has four mounting flanges <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> instead of six mounting flanges <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight> as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> As best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the front disc brake hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>&prime; basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>231</bold></highlight>&prime;, a hub shell <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>&prime;, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>&prime;, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>&prime;, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>&prime;. The front hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>&prime; is substantially identical to the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, except for the configuration of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>&prime;. Specifically, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>233</bold></highlight>&prime; of the front hub <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>&prime; has sixteen circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>&prime; instead of twelve spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. Moreover, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>&prime; only has four mounting flanges <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>&prime; instead of six mounting flanges <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>&prime; as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> basically includes an annular braking ring <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a plurality (nine) of outwardly extending connecting arms <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>integrally formed with annular braking ring <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and an inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>integrally formed with the connecting arms <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Accordingly, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> is a one-piece, unitary member. Preferably, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> is constructed of any suitable rigid material. The bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> is basically identical to the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, except that the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>has four mounting axially extending attachment holes <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>instead of six attachment holes. The attachment holes <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>have diameters of at least seven millimeters, preferably diameters of eight millimeters. The attachment holes <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are equally spaced about the circumference of the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Fourth Embodiment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a pair of alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>&prime; are illustrated in accordance with fourth embodiments of the present invention. These alternate bicycle disc brake hubs <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>&prime; are designed to be used with the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference>. In view of the similarity between the first and fourth embodiments, the descriptions of the parts of the fourth embodiment that are identical to the parts of the first embodiment may be omitted for the sake of brevity. Moreover, the parts of the fourth embodiment that have the same functions as the parts of the first embodiment will be given the same reference numerals as the parts of the first embodiment, but increased by three hundred. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> As seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the rear disc brake hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>, a hub shell <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>. The rear hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is substantially identical to the rear hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, except for the configuration of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> of the rear hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> has eighteen circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> instead of twelve spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. Moreover, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> only has three mounting flanges <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> instead of six mounting flanges <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> As seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the front disc brake hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>&prime; basically comprising a hub axle <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>&prime;, a hub shell <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>&prime;, a first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of first spoke holes <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>&prime;, a second spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>&prime; with a plurality of second spoke holes <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>&prime;, and a brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>&prime;. The front hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>&prime; is substantially identical to the front hub <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;, except for the configuration of the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>&prime; and the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>&prime;. Specifically, the first spoke attachment portion <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>&prime; of the front hub <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>&prime; has eighteen circularly shaped spoke holes <highlight><bold>343</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>&prime; instead of twelve spoke holes that are notched as in the first embodiment. Moreover, the brake rotor attachment portion <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>&prime; only has three mounting flanges <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight>&prime; instead of six mounting flanges <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight>&prime; as in the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference>, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> basically includes an annular braking ring <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a plurality (nine) of outwardly extending connecting arms <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>integrally formed with annular braking ring <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and an inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>integrally formed with the connecting arms <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Accordingly, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> is a one-piece, unitary member. Preferably, the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> is constructed of any suitable rigid material. The bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> is basically identical to the bicycle brake rotor <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, except that the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>has three mounting axially extending attachment holes <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>instead of six attachment holes. The attachment holes <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>have diameters of at least seven millimeters, preferably diameters of eight millimeters. The attachment holes <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are equally spaced about the circumference of the inner mounting portion <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> The terms of degree such as &ldquo;substantially&rdquo;, &ldquo;about&rdquo; and &ldquo;approximately&rdquo; as used herein mean a reasonable amount of deviation of the modified term such that the end result is not significantly changed. These terms should be construed as including a deviation of at least &plusmn;5% of the modified term if this deviation would not negate the meaning of the word it modifies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> While only selected embodiments have been chosen to illustrate the present invention, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this disclosure that various changes and modifications can be made herein without departing from the scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. Furthermore, the foregoing description of the embodiments according to the present invention are provided for illustration only, and not for the purpose of limiting the invention as defined by the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A bicycle disc brake hub comprising: 
<claim-text>a hub axle having a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hub shell having an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with said hub axle being rotatably supported in said interior passageway; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first spoke attachment portion having a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between said first and second axially facing surfaces, said first spoke holes having center axes spaced a first radial distance from said center axis of said hub axle, said first spoke attachment portion being disposed at said first hub shell end with said second axially facing surface facing towards said second hub shell end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second spoke attachment portion having a plurality of second spoke holes, said second spoke attachment portion being disposed at said second hub shell end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a brake rotor attachment portion having a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes with predetermined diameters and center axes spaced a second radial distance from said center axis of said hub axle, said brake rotor attachment portion being disposed adjacent said first spoke attachment portion with said first axially facing surface facing towards said brake rotor attachment portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion and said brake rotor attachment portion being arranged relative to each other to attach spokes to said first spoke holes through said rotor mounting holes of said brake rotor attachment portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>selected ones of said first spoke holes are individually viewable in the axial direction through corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said center axes of said selected-ones of said first spoke holes are offset from said center axes of said corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first radial distance of said center axes of said first spoke holes from said center axis of said hub axle is less than said second radial distance of said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first radial distance of said center axes of said first spoke holes from said center axis of said hub axle is greater than said second radial distance of said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said annular spoke flange has an outer diameter that is no greater than an effective outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said annular spoke flange has an outer diameter that is less than an effective outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said annular spoke flange has an outer diameter that is no greater than an effective outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first and second spoke attachment portions and said brake rotor attachment portion are integrally formed with said hub shell as a one-piece, unitary member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes are individually viewable in the axial direction from a location looking axially towards said brake rotor attachment portion and said first axially facing surface of said first spoke attachment portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said rotor mounting holes are threaded bores. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an intermediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally form ed with said intermediate connecting portion , said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and threaded in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an intermediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally formed with said intermediate connecting portion, said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and secured in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has six of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has twelve of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has four of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has sixteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has three of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has eighteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a circular transverse cross section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a transverse cross section with a semi circular section and a notched section that extends outwardly from said semi circular section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said second spoke holes extending axially therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A bicycle disc brake hub comprising: 
<claim-text>a hub axle having a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hub shell having an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with said hub axle being rotatably supported in said interior passageway; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first spoke attachment portion having a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between said first and second axially facing surfaces, said first spoke attachment portion being disposed at said first hub shell end with said second axially facing surface facing towards said second hub shell end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second spoke attachment portion having a plurality of second spoke holes, said second spoke attachment portion being disposed at said second hub shell end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a brake rotor attachment portion having a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes and an outer peripheral surface that lies within an imaginary circle circumscribing said outer peripheral surface, said brake rotor attachment portion being disposed adjacent said first spoke attachment portion with said first axially facing surface facing towards said brake rotor attachment portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first spoke holes being located radially inward of said imaginary circle circumscribing said outer peripheral surface of said brake rotor attachment portion </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>selected ones of said first spoke holes are individually viewable in the axial direction through corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said selected ones of said first spoke holes have center axes that are offset from center axes of said corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said center axes of said first spoke holes are radially spaced from said center axis of said hub axle by a distance less than said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said center axes of said first spoke holes are radially spaced from said center axis of said hub axle by a distance greater than said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes-an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion has a maximum outer diameter that is no greater than a maximum outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion has a maximum outer diameter that is no greater than a maximum outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first and second spoke attachment portions and said brake rotor attachment portion are integrally formed with said hub shell as a one-piece, unitary member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said rotor mounting holes are threaded bores. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an intermediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally form ed with said intermediate connecting portion, said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and threaded in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an inter-mediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally formed with said intermediate connecting portion, said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and secured in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has six of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has twelve of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has four of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has sixteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has three of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has eighteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a circular transverse cross section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a transverse cross section with a semi circular section and a notched section that extends outwardly from said semi circular section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said second spoke holes extending axially therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A bicycle disc brake hub comprising: 
<claim-text>a hub axle having a center axis extending in an axial direction between a first axle end and a second axle end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hub shell having an interior passageway extending between first and second hub shell ends with said hub axle being rotatably supported in said interior passageway; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first spoke attachment portion having a plurality of first spoke holes extending axially between said first and second axially facing surfaces, said first spoke attachment portion being disposed at said first hub shell end with said second axially facing surface facing towards said second hub shell end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second spoke attachment portion having a plurality of second spoke holes, said second spoke attachment portion being disposed at said second hub shell end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a brake rotor attachment portion having a plurality of axially extending rotor mounting holes, said brake rotor attachment portion being disposed adjacent said first spoke attachment portion with said first axially facing surface facing towards said brake rotor attachment portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion and said first spoke attachment portion having maximum outer diameters with said maximum outer diameter of said first spoke attachment portion being no greater than said maximum outer diameter of said brake rotor attachment portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>selected ones of said first spoke holes are individually viewable in the axial direction through corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said selected ones of said first spoke holes have center axes that are offset from center axes of said corresponding ones of said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said center axes of said first spoke holes are radially spaced from said center axis of said hub axle by a distance less than said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said center axes of said first spoke holes are radially spaced from said center axis of said hub axle by a distance greater than said center axes of said rotor mounting holes from said center axis of said hub axle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion has a maximum outer diameter that is no greater than a maximum outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said first spoke holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion includes a plurality of circumferentially arranged mounting flanges with each of said mounting flanges having one of said rotor mounting holes formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke attachment portion has a maximum outer diameter that is no greater than a maximum outer diameter formed by said mounting flanges. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first and second spoke attachment portions and said brake rotor attachment portion are integrally formed with said hub shell as a one-piece, unitary member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said rotor mounting holes are threaded bores. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an intermediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally formed with said intermediate connecting portion, said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and threaded in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a brake rotor having an outer braking portion, an intermediate connecting portion integrally formed with said outer braking portion, and an inner mounting portion integrally formed with said intermediate connecting portion, said inner mounting portion having a plurality of axially extending attachment holes with an inner diameter of at least seven millimeters and a plurality of bolts extending through said attachment holes and secured in said rotor mounting holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has six of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has twelve of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has four of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has sixteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said brake rotor attachment portion has three of said rotor mounting holes, and said first spoke attachment portion has eighteen of said first spoke holes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a circular transverse cross section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first spoke holes have a transverse cross section with a semi circular section and a notched section that extends outwardly from said semi circular section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second axle end has a freewheel coupled thereto. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The bicycle disc brake hub according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second spoke attachment portion includes an annular spoke flange with said second spoke holes extending axially therethrough.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030000779A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
