<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000219A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000219A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000219A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000219A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000219A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000219A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000219</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10174947</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020620</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>01115026.5</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010620</filing-date>
<country-code>EP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F23R003/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>060</class>
<subclass>772000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>060</class>
<subclass>752000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Gas turbine combustion chamber and air guidance method therefore</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Tiemann</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Witten</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARNESS, DICKEY &amp; PIERCE, P.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O.BOX 8910</address-1>
<city>RESTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>20195</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In order to provide a method of air guidance and a design for a gas turbine combustion chamber which permits improved cooling and reduced pressure losses and which avoids the overcooling phenomena by specific reaction to hot spots, a gas turbine combustion chamber includes a casing and at least one hollow element. The at least one hollow element is in connection with air guidance regions of the combustion chamber via at least two openings. As such, a tangential through-flow exists with a subsequent axial flow to the burner. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present application hereby claims priority under 35 U.S.C. Section 119 on European Patent application number 01115026.5 filed Jun. 20, 2001, the entire contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to a gas turbine combustion chamber. More preferably, it relates to one having a casing accommodating a combustion chamber and at least one burner arranged in an end region. In addition, the invention generally relates to an air guidance method in a gas turbine combustion chamber. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Combustion chambers of the generic type, in particular closed, cooled combustion chambers, are employed for highly efficient gas turbines. These usually include a multishell construction of essentially conical design, usually with circular cross section, with at least one, usually also a plurality of burners, arranged at one end, an air/fuel mixture being supplied to which burner. The burners protrude into an essentially conical configuration of combustion space. The combustion chamber must, on the one hand, be cooled and, on the other hand, the air guided to the burner has to preheat the fuel gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the case of closed, cooled combustion chambers known from the prior art, air is guided by impingement cooling through a support structure onto a plate exposed to the fuel gas and flows through the gap between plate and support structure in the axial direction to the burner. In this region, the plate cools convectively. Such designs have the disadvantage that, in the case of the narrow but axially long designs, the cooling in the convective region can only be mastered by relatively high flow velocities of the cooling air, which leads to increased pressure losses and therefore to sacrifices in efficiency. A further disadvantage of known solutions consists in the fact that there is no possibility of partial adjustment onto hot spots which have been found, so that the tendency is for components to be overcooled. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the present invention is based on an object of providing an air guidance method and/or a design for a gas turbine combustion chamber which, on the one hand, permit improved cooling at reduced pressure losses; and, in addition, avoid overcooling by specific reaction to hot spots, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> With respect to the technical solution, the design side of an embodiment of the invention proposes that it should exhibit at least one hollow element, which is in connection with other air guidance regions of the combustion chamber by at least two openings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention provides for the arrangement or configuration of hollow elements on the combustion chamber, which hollow elements are in connection, via openings, with air guidance regions of the combustion chamber which are separated from the hollow elements. The configuration of the hollow elements can be directly achieved during the manufacture of the casing or they can be subsequently arranged in the casing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment of the invention, the hollow elements are provided with at least two openings and are advantageously arranged or configured in such a way that they are used for tangential air guidance. The hollow elements can be arranged within the combustion chamber and can be in connection with air guidance regions in the outer region of the combustion chamber. Hollow elements can also be arranged on the outer region of the combustion chamber and be in connection with air guidance regions within the combustion chamber. Also within the scope of the invention is a multilayer construction, in which hollow elements are arranged on both the inside of the combustion chamber and the outside of the combustion chamber and are in connection with air guidance regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to a particularly advantageous configuration of an embodiment of the invention, the air guidance regions can be configured between internally and externally located hollow elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment of the invention, one hollow element is configured as a tangential element. An embodiment of the invention provides for the inner wall region of a combustion chamber to be at least partially configured with hollow elements, which are in connection via openings with regions on the outside of the combustion chamber. The combustion chambers, which can have an essentially arbitrary cross section, can be directly configured with hollow elements during manufacture or can be covered subsequently with hollow elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The hollow elements are advantageously configured as radial segments covering an internal surface of the combustion chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The outside of the combustion chamber is advantageously subdivided into air guidance regions separated from one another, for which purpose&mdash;in an advantageous proposal of an embodiment of the invention&mdash;essentially axially extending ribs are formed on the outside of the combustion chamber. In this arrangement, air guidance regions are configured which are used for the supply of air through openings into the hollow elements configured or arranged in the combustion chamber, and air guidance regions, into which the air coming from the hollow elements is introduced, are configured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The hollow elements are closed hollow space configuration elements, in metallic, ceramic and/or comparable materials, which are in connection with the outside of the combustion chamber exclusively via the openings. The hollow elements are advantageously provided as radial segments with openings, in such a way that there is forced tangential air guidance in the peripheral direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous proposal of an embodiment of the invention, the casing can have a single-shell configuration. In addition, the casing can be integrally manufactured with ribs configured on the outside, by casting for example. According to an advantageous proposal of an embodiment of the invention, one pair of ribs is respectively provided with a cover in order to separate the air guidance regions. This, therefore, produces air guidance regions which are closed by a cover between two ribs, and which respectively enclose adjacent inter-rib spaces with an uncovered configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In the design according to an embodiment of the invention, therefore, simple separation into air guidance regions separated from one another can take place by means of even-numbered rib configuration on the outside of the combustion chamber. The air guidance regions provided without cover are used for air supply. In this case, openings are configured in the axial direction which lead to hollow elements arranged on the inside of the combustion chamber. The hollow elements then preferably have further openings offset in the peripheral direction (tangentially), which openings lead into the inter-rib spaces provided with cover and adjacent to the air supply region, the air being further guided in these inter-rib spaces. The air is then supplied to the burner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous proposal of an embodiment of the invention, it is also possible to introduce the air, which is removed from the axially front regions, into further hollow elements and to further distribute it there. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In terms of cast-ability and complexity of the overall design, the design according to an embodiment of the invention is substantially simplified as compared with the multi-shell concepts known from the prior art. The cast-on ribs, furthermore, also provide desirable stiffening of the casing in the case of axially long designs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The design described as above can also have a reverse configuration if the ribs protruding into the combustion chamber are covered in pairs in order to form axial air guidance regions. In this case, hollow elements are positioned further outside the air guidance regions in the casing in order to form a tangential air guidance system there. The air guidance regions connected to the hollow elements can also be positioned between the internally and externally located hollow elements. In these cases also, single-shell casing designs are possible but multi-shell designs, in which tangential and axial air guidance regions are alternatively configured, can also be realized. In this way, axial air guidance regions can be formed in the described manner by rib formation with covering in pairs, while tangential air guidance regions are likewise formed by suitable rib configuration and coverings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention realizes a completely new method of air guidance in a gas turbine combustion chamber, in which the air is distributed in the peripheral direction (tangentially) into the combustion chamber cooling regions on the inside of the combustion chamber. This provides the possibility of specifically cooling individual regions in which, for example, hot spots occur. Here again, reversals of the method are within the scope of the invention, i.e. the alternative or additional configuration of air guidance regions through which air flows tangentially on the combustion chamber outer region or a central region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> With respect to the method, an embodiment of the invention proposes that air should be introduced from a first region outside the combustion chamber through at least one first opening into a hollow element arranged within the combustion chamber, continues through this by means of at least one second opening into a second region outside the combustion chamber and finally continues in the direction of the burner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The tangential air guidance system, according to an embodiment of the method, for cooling the combustion chamber and the subsequent axial guidance to the burner effect an improved and specific cooling of the combustion chamber without increased pressure losses and, therefore, without sacrifices of efficiency. Even axially long designs can be sufficiently cooled using normal cooling air flow velocities. Overcooling effects are unnecessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The radial cooling principle according to an embodiment of the invention additionally permits, without substantial design complexity, combination with impingement cooling arrangements, known per se. Thus, arbitrary adaptation possibilities for the cooling in the axial direction are not only provided by the radial cooling principle according to an embodiment of the invention but also due to its variability with respect to combinations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An embodiment of the invention proposes a gas turbine combustion chamber design which can be manufactured at low economic cost and an effective air cooling principle, which obviate the disadvantages of the prior art.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Further advantages and features of the invention are given by the following description using the figures. In these: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a perspective representation of an exemplary embodiment of a gas turbine combustion chamber; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a representation according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with the additional representation of the air guidance; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a section through a combustion chamber as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a representation in principle of an alternative exemplary embodiment of a gas turbine combustion chamber and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a further representation in principle of a further alternative exemplary embodiment of a gas turbine combustion chamber.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In the figures, similar parts are provided with similar designations. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> show a combustion chamber <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which, in the exemplary embodiment shown, includes a cast, single-shell casing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> onto which ribs <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are cast. In respective pairs, the ribs are closed by subsequently applied cover sheets <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, for example. This therefore produces closed air guidance regions <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and open air guidance regions <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Openings <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are respectively configured in the open air guidance regions <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the closed air guidance regions <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and these openings <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are guided directly to hollow elements <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> arranged on the inner wall of the combustion chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A burner <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, whose fuel gas guidance leads into the combustion chamber in the usual way, is arranged at the end of the combustion chamber. Hollow elements <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are guided toward the burner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The hollow elements <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> are metallic elements, ceramic elements, hollow bricks or similarly suitable elements, which are also formed from combinations of the materials quoted. The hollow elements are, respectively, essentially connected to a central region with an opening <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of an open air guidance region <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and into the end regions, respectively with openings <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, of a closed air guidance region <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The result is the air guidance system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The open air guidance regions <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are used for the air supply <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, from which the flow <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through the opening into the hollow elements <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> branches off. Flow-influencing auxiliary elements, air guide plates, baffles, opening expansions and the like can be employed for support and/or for control. After the flow <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through the opening, an essentially tangentially extending radial flow <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> occurs through the hollow elements. In the end regions of the hollow elements, the return flow <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> through the openings <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> takes place in respectively closed air guidance regions <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The air removal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> then takes place in these as far as the burner <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Hollow elements <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can also be employed here for direct air supply support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> An alternative exemplary embodiment is represented diagrammatically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. This differs from the previously described example in that an inner shell <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is configured with ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> pointing into the combustion chamber, which ribs <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are covered in pairs by covers <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Axial air guidance regions <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, which are separated from one another, are therefore formed. Hollow elements <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are arranged outside the inner shell <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and these are connected in the manner described via at least two openings to the axial air guidance regions <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> separately located inside, so that a tangential air flow <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> forms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a further representation in principle of an exemplary embodiment in which, in the case of a combustion chamber <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, both internally located hollow elements <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and externally located hollow elements <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are configured, axial air guidance regions <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> being formed between them. The air guidance principle corresponds to the previous exemplary embodiments, i.e. air is supplied through axial air guidance regions <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and is introduced through openings (not shown) in hollow elements in the inner region and outer region, where a tangential airflow occurs, the air subsequently re-entering from the hollow elements into axial air guidance regions and being supplied to the burner or the burners. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The exemplary embodiment described is only used for explanation and is not limiting.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>List of designations</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="84PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1.</entry>
<entry>Gas turbine combustion chamber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2.</entry>
<entry>Casing</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3.</entry>
<entry>Rib</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4.</entry>
<entry>Cover</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5.</entry>
<entry>Air guidance region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6.</entry>
<entry>Air guidance region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7.</entry>
<entry>Opening</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8.</entry>
<entry>Opening</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9.</entry>
<entry>Hollow element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10.</entry>
<entry>Air supply</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11.</entry>
<entry>Flow through opening</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12.</entry>
<entry>Radial flow</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13.</entry>
<entry>Return flow through opening</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>14.</entry>
<entry>Air removal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>15.</entry>
<entry>Burner</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>16.</entry>
<entry>Hollow element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>17.</entry>
<entry>Inner shell</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>18.</entry>
<entry>Ribs</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>19.</entry>
<entry>Cover</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>20.</entry>
<entry>Hollow element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>21.</entry>
<entry>Axial air guidance region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>22.</entry>
<entry>Tangential air guidance</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>23.</entry>
<entry>Axial air guidance region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>24.</entry>
<entry>Combustion chamber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>25.</entry>
<entry>Hollow element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>26.</entry>
<entry>Hollow element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>27.</entry>
<entry>Axial air guidance</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The invention being thus described, it will be obvious that the same may be varied in many ways. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention, and all such modifications as would be obvious to one skilled in the art are intended to be included within the scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A gas turbine combustion chamber, comprising: 
<claim-text>a casing, wherein at least one burner is arranged in an end region of the casing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one hollow element, wherein the at least one hollow element is in connection with air guidance regions of the combustion chamber via at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is connected with the air guidance regions via the at least two openings, such that tangential air guidance can occur. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged within the combustion chamber and is in connection with an outer region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged outside the combustion chamber and is in connection with an inner region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of hollow elements are arranged both within and outside the combustion chamber, the hollow elements being in connection with intermediately located air guidance regions via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is configured as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an inner surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an outer surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air guidance regions, which are connected to the at least one hollow element via the two openings, are configured as air guidance regions which are separate from one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the two openings of the at least one hollow element is used for the air supply from a first air guidance region of the combustion chamber to the at least one hollow element and at least one second opening is used for the removal of air from the at least one hollow element into a second air guidance region of the combustion chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air guidance regions of the combustion chamber are formed by ribs which essentially extend axially. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one pair of ribs forming a space is respectively connected by a cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ribs are integrally configured with the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the casing includes a single-shell configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein air from a region between two ribs, which are not connected by a cover, is guided through a first opening into a hollow element and is guided back through at least one second opening into the region between two ribs connected by a cover and is guided to the burner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of air guidance in a gas turbine combustion chamber including a casing, wherein a burner is arranged in an end region of the casing, comprising: 
<claim-text>introducing air from a first region outside the combustion chamber, through at least one first opening into a hollow element arranged within the combustion chamber, wherein the air continues through this hollow element and through at least one second opening into a second region, outside the combustion chamber, and finally continues in the direction of the burner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air is guided through first and second openings arranged in a tangential section of the combustion chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged within the combustion chamber and is in connection with an outer region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged outside the combustion chamber and is in connection with an inner region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged within the combustion chamber and is in connection with an outer region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is arranged outside the combustion chamber and is in connection with an inner region of the combustion chamber via the at least two openings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element is configured as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an inner surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an outer surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an inner surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow element covers a part of an outer surface of the combustion chamber as a tangential segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air guidance regions, which are connected to the at least one hollow element via the two openings, are configured as air guidance regions which are separate from one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of the two openings of the at least one hollow element is used for the air supply from a first air guidance region of the combustion chamber to the at least one hollow element and at least one second opening is used for the removal of air from the at least one hollow element into a second air guidance region of the combustion chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air guidance regions of the combustion chamber are formed by ribs which essentially extend axially. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one pair of ribs forming a space is respectively connected by a cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ribs are integrally configured with the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the casing includes a single-shell configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein air from a region between two ribs, which are not connected by a cover, is guided through a first opening into a hollow element and is guided back through at least one second opening into the region between two ribs connected by a cover and is guided to the burner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the combustion chamber includes at least a plurality of hollow elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the combustion chamber includes at least a plurality of hollow elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are metallic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are ceramic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are hollow brick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are metallic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are ceramic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one hollow elements are hollow brick. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least two openings are in the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least two openings are in the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A gas turbine combustion chamber, comprising: 
<claim-text>a casing, wherein at least one burner is adapted to be arranged in an end region of the casing; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one hollow element, wherein the at least one hollow element is in connection with an air guidance region of the combustion chamber via at least one opening in the casing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least two hollow elements are included, each in connection with an air guidance region of the combustion chamber via at least one separate opening in the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an air guidance region of the combustion chamber is formed by ribs, essentially extending axially from the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one pair of ribs forming a space is respectively connected by a cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the ribs are integrally configured with the casing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein air from a region between two ribs, which are not connected by a cover, is guided through a first opening into a hollow element and is guided back through at least one second opening into the region between two ribs connected by a cover and is guided to the burner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The gas turbine combustion chamber as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the air guidance regions, which are each connected to one hollow element via one of the at least two openings, are configured as air guidance regions which are separate from one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000219A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000219A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000219A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
