<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001461A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001461A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001461</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894452</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L041/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>310</class>
<subclass>359000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Rosen type piezoelectric transformer with multiple output electrodes, and stabilizer for multiple light source using that</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jong-Sun</given-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jang-Hyoun</given-name>
<family-name>Youm</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Samsung Electro-Mechanics Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Don W. Bulson, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>Renner, Otto, Boisselle &amp; Sklar, P.L.L.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>19th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>1621 Euclid Ave.</address-2>
<city>Cleveland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>44115</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention is disclosed a piezoelectric transformer with multiple outputs for lighting a plurality of cold cathode fluorescent lamps at the same time by forming a plurality of output electrodes as one body and a stabilizer having the piezoelectric transformer with multiple output electrodes. The piezoelectric transformer includes a piezoelectric plate; an input electrode formed on an upper surface of the plate; a plurality of output electrodes having an identical band shape, arranged in equal distance in the longitudinal direction of the plate at an outer side of the input electrode, and connected electrically to one ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps respectively; and a common electrode formed on a bottom surface of the plate, confronting to the input electrode, commonly connected to ground of the stabilizer and other ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer constituting a stabilizer for cold cathode fluorescent lamp being used for back light of liquid crystal display (LCD) device, more particularly, to a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes for lighting a plurality of cold cathode fluorescent lamp at the same time by forming multiple output electrodes as one body and a stabilizer for multiple light source using that. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. DESCRIPTION OF THE PRIOR ART </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As well known to those skilled in the art, a fluorescent lamp needs high voltage at initial lighting in order to emit required thermal electrons for an electric discharge. And, after electric discharge, the voltage impressed on the fluorescent lamp has negative resistance characteristics reduced when lamp current increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Especially, a cold cathode fluorescent lamp being used for backlight of liquid crystal display (LCD) device is fight source using cold emission (electron emission caused by forcing strong electric field to cathode surface). In order to light the Backlight comprised of the cold cathode fluorescent lamp, it needs about 500 V need. And, generally, a step-up transformer is used for convert the commercial AC power source to the driving voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The stabilizer is a lamp lighting device applying the driving voltage for lighting on the fluorescent lamp with properties mentioned above, and comprises, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, rectifying section <highlight><bold>621</bold></highlight> which rectifies AC commercial source <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> to DC voltage in some level, power factor compensation section <highlight><bold>622</bold></highlight> compensating for the power factor caused by the fluctuation of AC commercial voltage source in respect of the output voltage of the rectifying section <highlight><bold>621</bold></highlight>, AC voltage generating section <highlight><bold>623</bold></highlight> converting the DC voltage inputted through the power factor compensation section <highlight><bold>622</bold></highlight> to proposed AC voltage of high frequency, and a resonating section <highlight><bold>624</bold></highlight> for resonating with the output voltage of a AC voltage generating section <highlight><bold>623</bold></highlight> and supplying the AC voltage on the fluorescent lamp <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As above-mentioned, AC voltage generating section <highlight><bold>623</bold></highlight> is called an inverter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> And, said resonating section <highlight><bold>624</bold></highlight> is conventionally constructed to generate the resonance by the inductance of the winding type transformer and the capacitance of a resonance capacitor with connection of the winding type transformer. But the winding type transformer has some problems that the rate of producing poor quality is high and the credibility of the stabilizer is reduced because the deviation of the quality of core is excessive, so said winding type transformer is recently replaced with a piezoelectric transformer such that the resonance is generated by the inductance of the inductor with the capacitance of the piezoelectric transformer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> But the above statement is the case of connecting one fluorescent lamp to one stabilizer. On the other hand, in case of lighting more than two fluorescent lamps by connecting the fluorescent lamps into one stabilizer, if one of numerous fluorescent lamps is lighted, other fluorescent lamps connected to the wound-type transformer in parallel is not lighted because a lower voltage is supplied to the other fluorescent lamps by lighting the one fluorescent lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, in the case of connecting two or more fluorescent lamps to the one stabilizer, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, the ballast capacitor is directly connected between fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and transformers <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> such that the voltage required for initial lightening is impressed on the fluorescent lamp even if a certain fluorescent lamp is lighted ahead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Hence, the conventional stabilizer used for a plurality of light sources is constructed as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the stabilizer comprises a circuit section <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>, which includes the rectifying section <highlight><bold>621</bold></highlight>, the power compensating section <highlight><bold>622</bold></highlight>, the AC voltage generating section <highlight><bold>623</bold></highlight>, and the resonance capacitor of the resonating section <highlight><bold>624</bold></highlight>, the piezoelectric transformer <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight> of which input electrode is connected to the resonance capacitor of the circuit section <highlight><bold>711</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of ballast capacitors <highlight><bold>713</bold></highlight> being connected to output electrode of the piezoelectric transformer <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight> in parallel. Wherein the number of ballast capacitors is same that of lamps. Furthermore, a plurality of fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is connected to other terminal of the plurality of ballast capacitors <highlight><bold>713</bold></highlight> of the stabilizer <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the stabilizer for a plurality of fluorescent lamps having a wound-type transformer comprises a circuit section <highlight><bold>811</bold></highlight>, which includes the rectifying section <highlight><bold>621</bold></highlight>, the power compensating section <highlight><bold>622</bold></highlight>, the AC voltage generating section <highlight><bold>623</bold></highlight>, and the resonance capacitor of the resonating section <highlight><bold>624</bold></highlight>. And the stabilizer comprises the wound-type transformer <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> of which input electrode is connected to a resonance capacitor of the circuit section <highlight><bold>811</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of ballast capacitors <highlight><bold>813</bold></highlight> being connected to output electrode of the wound-type transformer <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> in parallel. Furthermore, the plurality of fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is connected to other terminal of the plurality of ballast capacitors <highlight><bold>713</bold></highlight> of the stabilizer <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In the stabilizer above, because AC voltage supplied by the wound-type transformer <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight> or the piezoelectric transformer <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> is divided equally among the plurality of fluorescent lamps via the ballast capacitor <highlight><bold>713</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>813</bold></highlight>, the plurality of fluorescent lamps can be lighted at the same time. Wherein the ballast capacitor <highlight><bold>713</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>813</bold></highlight> has a high withstand voltage characteristic, and its size is also big. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> or <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, because the stabilizer needs the ballast capacitors in proportion to the number of the connected fluorescent lamp, a volume and the number of components increase, and a cost increases also. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Thus, in the case of constituting a stabilizer as mentioned above, there have been some problems that numbers of components and the volume increase and the production cost rise because a ballast capacitor is required proportion to numbers of connected fluorescent lamp. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to provide a Rosen type piezoelectric transformer having a plurality of output electrodes with uniform output property which makes the fluorescent lamp light stably, the operation be simple, and the cost be reduced. the present invention provides a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes, being used for a stabilizer to light a plurality of cold cathode fluorescent lamps, comprising: a piezoelectric plate; an input electrode formed at an upper surface of the plate; a plurality of output electrodes having an identical band shape, arranged in equal distance in the longitudinal direction of the plate at an outer side of the input electrode, and connected electrically to one ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps respectively; and a common electrode formed at a bottom surface of the plate, confronting to the input electrode, commonly connected to ground of the stabilizer and other ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features and other advantages of the present invention will be more clearly understood from the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of a stabilizer for a plurality of lamps having a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer in accordance with the primary embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of the Piezoelectric Transformer in accordance with the present invention in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention and a stabilizer for lighting four lamps; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of the modified Piezoelectric Transformer as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention and a stabilizer for a plurality of lamps applying that; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of the modified Piezoelectric Transformer as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a block diagram of a conventional fluorescent lamp stabilizer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of a stabilizer for a plurality of lamps applying a conventional winding type piezoelectric transformer; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of a stabilizer for a plurality of lamps applying a conventional piezoelectric transformer.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Reference now should be made to the drawings, in which the same reference numerals are used throughout the different drawings to designate the same or similar components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a view of an embodiment of a piezoelectric transformer and a stabilizer using the piezoelectric transformer, in this embodiment the <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> light sources is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> Rozen type piezoelectric transformer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises an input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed at the center of the upper surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction of the plate and connected to a circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a stabilizer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> formed on the bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> opposed to the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and two output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> formed on the both confronting side surface in the longitudinal direction of the plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> And, the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are connected to an output of the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the stabilizer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the two output electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is respectively connected to one ends of two cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a lamp section <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and the other ends of two cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. That is, two cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to the piezoelectric transformer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As described above, the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> converts the commercial voltage source of 220 V or 110 V with AC voltage of a predetermined voltage level and frequency. And then The AC voltage is impressed the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. As result, it brings about a longitudinal vibration. The longitudinal vibration is transmitted the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and then a AC voltage outputs between the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The AC voltage outputted the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is related to the distance to the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the thickness of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> placed on the confronting side surface has the same output property because each of the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has the same condition. Thus, the uniform voltage is impressed to two cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> such that all of the fluorescent lamp <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be lighted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a perspective view of the modified Piezoelectric Transformer as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The piezoelectric transformer is made by multi-layering first piezo-sheet <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> printing the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on the surface and second piezo-sheet <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>&prime; printing the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> on the surface in turns. The input electrodes <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on first piezo-sheet <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is connected each other and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>s on second piezo-sheet <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>&prime; is connected each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> show perspective views of a Piezoelectric Transformer in accordance with an embodiment of the present invention and a stabilizer for <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> light sources applying that. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As shown in the drawings, the piezoelectric transformer has an input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed at the center of the upper surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the direction of its width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In multi-layer type, the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed on the surface of a piezo-sheet. The input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is connected to the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> And, Four output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed to the positions divided into equal distance on the upper surface and the both confronting side surface in longitudinal direction. And the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is formed on a the bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> opposed to the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is connected to the output of generating AC voltage of the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The four output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are connected to the one ends <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. And the other ends <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>B of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the ground of the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected to the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Additionally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> show perspective views of a piezoelectric transformer in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, an input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is formed at one end of the upper surface of the plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and connected to the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed on a side surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in a direction of thickness of the plate and is formed on a upper surface in a band shape, being arranged in an equal distance. And, the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is formed on the bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> opposed to the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and is connected to the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the other ends <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>B of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> at the same time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> connected to the circuit section <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed on the surface of a piezo-sheet, and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is formed on the surface of the other piezo-sheet. And a piezo-sheet formed the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and output electrods <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the other piezo-sheet formed the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is layered in turns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The operational effect of the present invention will be described herein below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In order to satisfy restricting the noise, lowering the spending power, making the device miniaturization, and the like, a piezoelectric transformer having the piezoelectric effect is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The basic principle of the piezoelectric transformer is the following. A deformation of another section of the piezoelectric transformer is generated due to a deformation generated by impressing a voltage to one section of the piezoelectric transformer, and a second voltage is then generated on another section. The principle above is applied to the Rosen type, which is the simplest type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A piezoelectric plate is formed by stacking a plurality of sheets to which internal electrodes is printed in some patterns and stacked, an external input electrode is formed on one longitudinal side of upper and bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate, and an output electrode is formed at a confronting position of the input section on the side of the piezoelectric plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> If the voltage having resonance frequency is impressed to the external output electrode, a longitudinal vibration mode is generated in the internal electrode, and the longitudinal vibration is generated in the output electrode formed on the side surface of the piezoelectric plate by the generated longitudinal vibration mode, and the voltage is generated in the output electrode as a piezoelectric effect occurred by the produced stress. And then the voltages of the output terminal rise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> formed on the upper and bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are connected to the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. If a voltage having a resonance frequency from the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is supplied to the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the output electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> formed on both side of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> vibrates is generated in a direction of length by longitudinal vibration mode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A voltage is applied to the output electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by the piezoelectric effect produced by the stress of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a high voltage is impressed on the cold cathode fluorescent lamp <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> connected through the terminal <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> And the same voltage is impressed through the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> placed in the bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is formed at confronting position of the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the other terminals <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>B of a plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> such that the cold cathode lamp <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is impressed a high voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In addition, as shown in the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the resonance frequency is impressed by means of inputting the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> placed in the upper and bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or made from stacking into the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Then the longitudinal vibration mode occurs in the internal section, and this makes the longitudinal vibration in the direction of length of the multiple output electrodes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> placed on the both surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the surface of the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> A voltage is applied to the output electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by the piezoelectric effect produced by the stress, and boosting is produced to impress high voltage on the cold cathode fluorescent lamp <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> connected through the terminal <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> And the same voltage is impressed through the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> placed on the bottom surface of the piezoelectric plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is formed at confronting position of the input electrode <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the common electrode <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the AC voltage generator <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the other terminals <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>B of a plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> such that the cold cathode lamp <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is impressed a high voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is possible to reduce the number of the components and minimize the size of the inverter by using the piezoelectric transformer with multiple outputs of the present invention, and this removes the retraction of designing and the needs of installation of high internal voltage condenser, an additional grounding equipment is also unnecessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is possible to generate a multiple output voltage having an uniform output property by using the multiple output electrodes. Thus, by providing a cold cathode fluorescent lamp using the piezoelectric transformer with multiple outputs, a easy working and a cost savings may be realized without an additional ballast capacitor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Finally, by minimizing a volume of stabilizer, a design restriction of the stabilizer may be lower, and it is not necessary to design about the isolation additionally. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In addition, multiple outputs are easily obtained by applying the piezoelectric transformer of the present invention and various vibration modes (including length type, width type, area type, radial type, ring type vibration mode, and the like) to a power converting circuit (for example, DC-DC converter, AC-DC converter, DC-AC converter) transmitting a power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Although various embodiments of this invention have been shown and described, it should be understood that variations, modifications and substitutions, as well as rearrangements and combinations of the preceding embodiments can be made by those skilled in the art without departing from the novel spirit and scope of this invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes, being used for a stabilizer to light a plurality of cold cathode fluorescent lamps, comprising: 
<claim-text>a piezoelectric plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an input electrode formed on an upper surface of the plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of output electrodes having an identical band shape, arranged in equal distance in the longitudinal direction of the plate at an outer side of the input electrode, and connected electrically to one ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps respectively; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a common electrode formed on a bottom surface of the plate, confronting to the input electrode, commonly connected to ground of the stabilizer and other ends of the plurality of the cold cathode fluorescent lamps. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said input electrode is formed at center of the upper surface of the plate in the longitudinal direction of the plate, and said output electrodes includes two first output electrodes formed on the both confronting side surface in the longitudinal direction of the plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said output electrodes further comprise a plurality of second output electrodes on the upper side of the plate, wherein the distances between the neighboring electrodes being identical each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the piezoelectric transformer is made by multi-layering first piezo-sheets printing both the input electrode and the output electrodes on the surface, and second piezp-sheets printing the common electrode on the surface in turn. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said input electrode is formed on one end of the upper surface of the plate in the longitudinal direction of the plate, and said multiple output electrodes comprise a first output electrode formed on a side surface of the plate in a direction of thickness of the plate, adjacent to the other end of the upper surface of the plate, and at least one second output electrode formed in a band shape, each second output electrode being arranged apart in an equal distance between the input electrode and first output electrode in the longitudinal direction on the upper side of the plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A stabilizer for multiple light sources, using a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes, comprising: 
<claim-text>a rectifying section rectifying AC commercial electric power source to DC electric power; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power factor compensation section compensating the power factor caused by the fluctuation of the voltage of AC commercial electric power source so as to maintain the voltage of DC electric power generated from the rectifying section in uniform level; </claim-text>
<claim-text>AC voltage generating section converting the DC power inputted from the power factor compensation section to AC electric power having a predetermined frequency; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a Rosen type Piezoelectric Transformer with multiple output electrodes having a identical band shape, wherein the output electrodes is arranged in parallel to a input electrode, have an equal distance between neighboring electrodes, are electrically connected to a plurality of cold cathode fluorescent lamps respectively; </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby identical voltages are applied simultaneously to a plurality of fluorescent lamps.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001461A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
