<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001730A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001730A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001730</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09437624</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>19991110</filing-date>
<continued-prosecution-application>This is a publication of a continued prosecution application (CPA) filed under 37 CFR 1.53(d).</continued-prosecution-application>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60Q001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>427000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>539000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>825720</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>REMOTE CONTROL APPARATUS AND METHOD</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60107984</doc-number>
<document-date>19981112</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60111463</doc-number>
<document-date>19981209</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>CURTIS R.</given-name>
<family-name>PIPER</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>HAYWARD</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>R. THOMAS</given-name>
<family-name>MUELLER</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>SAN RAMON</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KNOBBE MARTENS OLSON &amp; BEAR LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2040 MAIN STREET</address-1>
<address-2>FOURTEENTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>IRVINE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92614</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A remote control is remotely mounted and controlled by an activation switch. The remote control is mounted within a cavity of a motorcycle and in electrical communication with an activation switch. The activation switch is mounted for easy access and manipulation. A feedback device is provided for communicating that the remote control has been activated. A universal mounting bracket allows the operator to selectively mount the activation switch and feedback device in any location they desire. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to remote control devices for motor vehicles. Specifically, the present invention relates to a remote activation device for a remote control and a method of installing and using the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Previously, remote garage door openers were provided with bulky transmitters which were easily lost or misplaced. For the operators of motorcycles, the use of such transmitters was replete with inconveniences. For instance, due to limited on-board storage locations, the transmitter is commonly placed in pockets or carried with the operator while not on the motorcycle. Accordingly, the transmitter is often misplaced or inconveniently located when the operator is ready to leave home. Additionally, the transmitter must be fished from the pocket when attempting to use it. As can be imagined, it is extremely difficult and dangerous to operate such a transmitter while also attempting to maneuver or balance a motorcycle. The level of difficulty is additionally augmented when the operation of the motorcycle is in adverse or cold weather conditions (i.e., the operator is wearing gloves which decrease tactile sensitivity). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, one aspect of the present invention involves the recognition that an on-board configuration for a motorcycle remote control is desirable. The on-board configuration allows for ease of use and eliminates the need to find and handle a separate transmitter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention involves concealing and mounting the remote control apparatus within a cavity of the motorcycle. Such a mounting location decreases the weather-exposure of the apparatus and increases the security of the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A further aspect of the present invention involves connecting a remote activating switch and an activation confirmation indicator to the remote control and mounting the pair in an easily accessible and easily viewed location. The activating switch desirably being placing to be actuated with the hand or foot of the operator. The activation confirmation indicator allowing the operator to have auditory, visual or tactile confirmation of the operation of the remote control.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> These and other features of the invention will now be described with reference to the drawings of a preferred embodiment which is intended to illustrate and not to limit the invention, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an exemplary motorcycle illustrating a portion of a remote control apparatus having features and aspects in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are plan views of the motorcycle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are side views of the motorcycle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with a portion broken away to illustrate an activation switch or switches and a confirmation indicator; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is schematic view of a remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is another schematic view of a remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic view of an optional battery holder that may be used with the remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is yet another schematic view of an optional battery holder that may be used with the remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a plan view of a motorcycle dash board illustrating a preferred mounting arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a top schematic view illustrating a mounting arrangement for a remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a rear view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a detailed drawing of a universal mounting bracket illustrative of one embodiment of a universal mounting bracket; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a photocopy of a photograph illustrating a remote control apparatus arrangement having features, aspects and advantages in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference> are photocopies of packaging utilized to ship the remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an optional receiver; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a plan view of an exemplary motorcycle illustrating a portion of a remote control apparatus having features and aspects in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a side view of the motorcycle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a plan view of a motorcycle dash board illustrating a preferred mounting arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a side cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a top schematic view illustrating a mounting arrangement for another remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is another top schematic view illustrating a mounting arrangement for a remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is another schematic view of a remote control apparatus arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a side view of a motorcycle illustrating the location of the upper dash panel relative to the gasoline tank; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a rear view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a rear view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Also attached hereto is Exhibit A having instructions for use and further drawings of a remote control apparatus having features, aspects and advantages in accordance with the present invention. Exhibit A is numbered consecutively with this specification following the abstract.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a motorcycle having a remote control apparatus is illustrated. The remote control communicates with a receiver to control any of a number of devices. For instance, the remote control may be configured to operate all major brands of garage door and gate openers. Thus, the remote control and receiver are designed, in part, to allow access to property, structures or other secured areas from a motorcycle or a similar vehicle. Additionally, the remote control and receiver may also be configured to turn on or off other devices such as house lights, house alarms, or any other appliances as desired by the operator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As is well known, the motorcycle to which the remote control is mounted generally comprises a frame to which at least one fuel tank is mounted. In the illustrated embodiment, the motorcycle has two fuel tanks mounted to the frame such that one fuel tank is arranged on either side of the frame. The motorcycle provides an exemplary environment in which the present remote door opening remote control finds utility. As will be recognized by those of skill in the art, the present remote door opening remote control may also be used in all-terrain vehicles, snowmobiles, bicycles, wheelchairs, lawnmowers, golf carts and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the remote door opening remote control generally comprises a concealed remote control, an activation switch and a confirmation indicator. The activation switch and the confirmation indicator are desirably arranged to be readily accessible and within a clear view of an operator of the motorcycle. In the illustrated embodiment, the activation switch and the confirmation indicator are mounted to one side of the upper dash panel of the motorcycle. The activation switch and confirmation indicator can also be attached to the lower dash panel as well. Desirably, they are proximate to the ignition switch, below the speedometer and arranged among the other gauges which are often viewed by the operator. As will be recognized by those of skill in the art, the activation switch and confirmation indicator need not be located in tandem, as illustrated, but may be arranged remotely from one another. Additionally, the activation switch may be located in other easily accessible locations, such as, for instance, the handlebars adjacent to the handgrips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present remote control utilizes a universal mounting bracket which allows the ultimate operator to determine an advantageous location for mounting the activation switch. As illustrated, the universal mounting bracket generally comprises a pair of c-shaped clamps which, when fastened together, form a clam-shell arrangement. The structure of the c-shaped clamps allow the clamps to accommodate a variety of pipe sizes. The mounting bracket may be made from aluminum, steel, plastic or any other suitable material. Additionally, the mounting bracket may be stamped, forged, molded or manufactured in any other suitable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Following identification of a desired mounting location, the location is prepared for the installation. Specifically, the location may be wrapped with a rubberized tape or other vibration-reducing component. The rubberized tape also protects the surface finish in the event the remote control is later removed from the motorcycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Following preparation of the location, the confirmation indicator and the activation switch are inserted into their respective mounting holes in the mounting bracket. The activation switch may be attached using a retaining nut and washer as is well known in the art. The confirmation indicator may be attached using a vinyl grommet as is also well known in the art. The grommet can also be of any pliant material, such as rubber, for instance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Having mounted the activation switch and the confirmation indicator, the two halves of the clam-shell mounting bracket can be joined together around the prepared pipe. In the illustrated embodiment, the halves are joined using threaded fasteners, such as a machine bolt and a lock nut. Having secured the bracket to the pipe, the positioning of the bracket may be adjusted to a desired rotational orientation. The wires may then be connected as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the confirmation indicator is an led lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the confirmation indicator is a 3-ohm led with a snap-in mounting ring. Other led lamps may also be used. Moreover, other confirmation indicators can also be used. For instance, the confirmation indicator can be an existing indicator lamp, a tactile alert such as a vibrating element, or an auditory signal. Additionally, any combination of indicators can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The illustrated activation switch is desirably a momentary push button switch. Specifically, the activation switch is a momentary push button switch rated to about 0.5 amps at about 125 volts AC. As will be recognized, other activation switches may also be used. Importantly, because of the application, it is desired that the switch allow the remote control to transmit a signal for a brief duration. It is contemplated that a timing circuit could be incorporated to accomplish this; however, it is preferable to utilize a momentary switch. An additional switch can also be provided to operate more than one device as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the activation switch and the confirmation indicator are mounted to the upper dash pad and desirably extend through the dash pad. The leads of each of the elements are accessible in this location. The leads may form a male electrical connector or be attached in known manners to such a male electrical connector. In this fashion, the activation switch and confirmation indicator are easily connected to the remote control and to a remote power source which may have a female connector. Of course, one of skill in the art will readily recognize that the configuration of male and female connectors can be interchanged without changing the effective coupling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment, the remote control is mounted within a cavity defined, in part, by the two fuel tanks and the frame of the motorcycle. Advantageously, the remote control is mounted below the lower dash panel or below the seat to be readily accessible through an access opening. This placement allows easy access for reprogramming and repair should repair become necessary. Additionally, this internal location helps to reduce the exposure of the circuitry to adverse weather and excessive water. Desirably, the remote control is supplied with a vibration damping element or otherwise configured or mounted to reduce the amplitude and degree of vibration transferred into the remote control. Additionally, any switchable elements (i.e., frequency and dip switches) may be altered to resist movement induced by vibration. For instance, the switches may be mini-slide switches or the like which require a positive application of force to move. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> While any suitable fastening technique may be used, Applicants have found that two part Velcro performs adequately in most applications. In such applications, the surfaces must be clean and dry to allow proper adhesion of the backing surface of each Velcro part. Additionally, double face tape or the like may be utilized. It is also contemplated that a bracket which extends away from the frame of the motorcycle may be utilized. In such an instance, the bracket could be mounted to the frame in conjunction with the fuel tank mounting brackets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The illustrated remote control is a remote control having a programmable configuration. For instance, the remote control is provided with a frequency and code control configuration allowing the operator to pre-program a code which corresponds to a code of the apparatus that is controlled thereby. Moreover, the remote control may have a key pad to allow an access code to be entered. In some embodiments, such a key pad will be no larger than a telephone touch pad so that the key pad can be easily mounted within the lower dash of the motorcycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The key pad allows four and six digit access codes, such as those commonly used for entrance gates, to be entered while seated on the motorcycle. Additionally, this arrangement increases security as the operator can remain safely on the motorcycle while gaining entrance to his house, garage or the like, or activating or deactivating a number of appliances such as lights, alarms and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the remote control has a set of dip switches which control the code setting. To operate a device, the remote control code must match the receiver code. By moving each of the dip switches up or down to match those of the receive, the required code can be duplicated. In the illustrated embodiment, the switches have a top, middle, and bottom position; however, in some receivers only a top and bottom position are provided. Accordingly, the top position of the remote control corresponds to the top position of the receiver and the bottom position of the remote control corresponds to the bottom position of the receiver. The middle position is not utilized in such configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The remote control also has a programmable frequency switch. In one configuration, the switch simply adjusts between three preset frequencies. Simply matching the preset frequency to the frequency of the receiver may be necessary. By changing the frequency, the receiver and remote control may be distinguished from the receiver and remote control of neighboring facilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The remote control is in electrical communication with a power source. The power source is preferably independent from the motorcycle&apos;s electrical system. In such instances, the remote control is in electrical communication with either an internal battery or a battery holder which may be remotely located relative to the remote control. For instance, the battery holder may be mounted within the same cavity as the remote control. Moreover, similar to the remote control, the battery holder may be secured using double side tape, Velcro or any other suitable fastening technique, as discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The power sources, such as batteries, desirably provide ample power to allow the remote control to function. In the illustrated embodiment, the battery holder carries a single 12 volt battery. It is contemplated that other power sources can also be used. For instance, but without limitation, depending upon the application, a rechargeable battery may be used which is recharged either by a wall plug in as is known or by a trickle of electrical power from the vehicle&apos;s electrical system. Advantageously, the battery holder and/or remote control may be mounted in a rear portion of the cavity to be easily accessed through an access opening which may be formed below the seat or below the lower dash panel. In this fashion, the batteries may be readily accessed and changed when their stored power falls below a predetermined level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> While the above-described remote control arrangement allows the operator to use a pre-existing receiver, it is also contemplated that the remote control could be utilized with a new or altered receiver. The receiver could be wired in series to the original receiver and allow the remote control to communicate with the new receiver while allowing existing remote controls to communicate with the existing receiver. The new receiver could have an antenna allowing the range of the receiver to be increased. Additionally, the receiver could be a so-called &ldquo;smart receiver&rdquo; which is able to learn a code from an individualized remote control. The receiver technology can scramble the frequency code with each use. The new code is used once and scrambled again as is known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the new receiver may plug into a wall outlet. As will be recognized by those of skill in the art, the receiver will have a receiving antenna which will detect the emission of an appropriate signal from a transmitter, such as a remote control. The receiver is wired through an existing wall switch to control a device, by overriding the existing wall switch for instance. In this fashion, very little wiring is affecting in the existing device and structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Although the remote control is arranged within a sheltered cavity, the remote control can be provided with a weather-proof enclosure. Additionally, the wires may be connected with weatherproof shrouds or all-weather electrical connectors. In this fashion, the remote control can work in all types of weather and under even the most adverse conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Although this invention has been described in terms of a certain embodiment, other embodiments apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art also are within the scope of this invention. Thus, various changes and modifications may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A remote control actuator for a motorcycle having a split fuel tank, the actuator comprising a transmitter being positioned between the fuel tanks in a substantially enclosed compartment. A switch being in electrical communication with said transmitter and being positioned away from said transmitter outside of said substantially enclosed compartment, said switch turning said transmitter on such that said transmitter emits a signal to be received by a remotely positioned receiver.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030001730A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
