<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004582A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004582A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004582A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004582A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004582A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004582A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004582A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004582A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004582A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004582A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004582</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893887</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61F002/66</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>049000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>623</class>
<subclass>038000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multi-axis prosthetic ankle joint</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chi</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Columbus</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Colvin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hilliard</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Arbogast</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Mt. Sterling</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>OHIO WILLOW WOOD COMPANY</organization-name>
<address>
<city>MOUNT STERLING</city>
<state>OH</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OBLON SPIVAK MCCLELLAND MAIER &amp; NEUSTADT PC</name-1>
<name-2>FOURTH FLOOR</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1755 JEFFERSON DAVIS HIGHWAY</address-1>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A multi-axis prosthetic ankle includes a bottom component connected to a prosthetic foot, a lower leg connection component connected to a prosthetic lower leg, an elastomeric material securely connecting the bottom component with the lower leg connection component, and a mechanical device suspended in the elastomeric material. The mechanical device is formed of a first bracket connected to the bottom component and a second bracket connected to the lower leg connection component. The first and second brackets interlockingly float in the elastomeric material, and are not in direct contact with one another, thereby permitting relative movement of the bottom component and the lower leg connection component by deformation of the elastomeric material. At least one mechanical stop is positioned to prevent the relative angular movement of the ankle from deforming the elastomeric material beyond the elastic limit thereof. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to prosthetic devices, and more particularly to a multi-axis prosthetic ankle joint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Discussion of the Background </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A prosthetic ankle is a component which connects a prosthetic foot with a prosthetic lower leg. For smooth walking, especially, across uneven ground, it is important for the ankle to be designed for a full range of foot motion with respect to the lower leg prosthesis. Most prosthetic ankles currently on the market are modular in design and do not provide optimally controlled multi-axis motion. Often the prosthetic ankle has such a low stiffness that it effectively reduces any functional capabilities of the attached prosthetic foot, resulting in a choppy, unnatural and uncomfortable gait. Some ankles require adjustments to the assembly in order to achieve the desired function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A full range of motion may be accomplished by the use of multiple axes of rotation in the ankle joint. However, conventional prosthetic ankle joints that provide multi-axis motion tend to require extensive maintenance including the replacement of parts in order to function properly. This is because the conventional ankle joint designs require elastic members to slide in contact with either a rigid surface, which is typically metallic, or another elastic surface. This surface-to-surface sliding motion is the primary cause of material breakdown. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a multi-axis prosthetic ankle joint which does not suffer from the shortcomings of the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to a feature of the invention as set forth in the claims, a multi-axis prosthetic ankle comprises a bottom component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic foot, a lower leg connection component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic lower leg, an elastomeric material securely connecting the bottom component with the lower leg connection component, and a mechanical device suspended in the elastomeric material. The mechanical device comprises a first rigid element connected to the bottom component but not to the lower leg connection component, and a second rigid element connected to the lower leg connection component but not to the bottom component. The first and second elements interlockingly float in the elastomeric material, and are not in direct contact with one another, so as to permit relative movement of the bottom component and the lower leg connection component by deformation of the elastomeric material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> By &ldquo;interlockingly float&rdquo; it is meant that the first and second elements are suspended in the elastomeric material in close relation to one another, but do not contact one another except through the intermediary of the elastomeric material. Since the deformation of the elastic material permits multi-axis relative movement of the bottom component and the lower leg connection component, including translational movement, the ankle joint of the invention can simulate natural ankle motion by providing plantar flexion, dorsi flexion, inversion, eversion, translation and internal/external rotational movement. Such motion is optimally controlled by the multi-axis deformation of the elastic material, without sacrificing the energy return of the prosthetic foot. Further, since the components of the mechanical device are bonded to, and encased by, the elastomeric material, the ankle has the ability to absorb and damp both rotational and linear impacts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Since there is no surface-to-surface sliding motion within the ankle, the material breakdown which might otherwise occur due to surface-to-surface sliding motion is reduced or eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> As force is applied to the ankle, the ankle moves in rotation and translation with a fluid motion by deforming the rubber medium. According to a further feature of the invention, at least one mechanical stop is positioned to prevent the relative angular movement of the ankle from deforming the elastic material beyond the elastic limit thereof. Since the deformation of the elastomeric material is thus always kept within the elastic limit, any tendency of breakdown in the elastomeric material is further reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to a further feature of the invention, the mechanical device comprises a generally U-shaped first part connected to the bottom component so as to define a first aperture, and a generally U-shaped second part connected to the lower leg connection component so as to define a second aperture. The first part floatingly extends through the second aperture, and the second part floatingly extends through the first aperture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to yet a further feature of the invention, a multi-axis prosthetic ankle comprises a bottom component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic foot, a lower leg connection component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic lower leg, an elastomeric material securely connecting the bottom component with the lower leg connection component, and mechanical means for limiting a deformation of the elastic material.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A more complete appreciation of the invention and many of the attendant advantages thereof will be readily obtained as the same becomes better understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top plan view of an embodiment of a multi-axis prosthetic ankle according to the invention, showing the encasing elastomeric material in phantom lines; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front elevation view of the multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side elevation view of the multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the lower leg connection component of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a front elevation view of the lower leg connection component of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a front elevation view of the bracket mounted to the lower leg connection component in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the bottom component of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along lines VIII-VIII of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a sectional view of taken along lines IX-IX of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the attached figures which illustrate a non-limiting embodiment of a multi-axis prosthetic ankle according to the invention, and more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 3</cross-reference> which, for clarity of illustration, show the elastomeric casing in phantom lines to reveal the encased components of the mechanical device (rigid mechanical means), the main components of the multi-axis prosthetic ankle are the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the mechanical device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (rigid mechanical means) and the elastomeric casing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> bonded to the bottom component and the lower leg connection component, and floatingly encasing the elements of the mechanical device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a generally circular disk like base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and a first &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (first rigid element) projecting perpendicularly upwardly from the base. The first bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extends generally diametrically on the base and defines a slot like first aperture <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having respective top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and first bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are preferably integrally formed from a rigid material such as stainless steel, but could be formed of any other rigid material such as titanium, aluminum or rigid plastic. The base <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> preferably includes a threaded center hole <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to accept a bolt for the securement of the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a prosthetic foot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also has a generally circular disk like base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and has a pyramid part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> projecting perpendicularly upward from a central portion of the upper surface of the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for connection of the ankle joint to a lower leg prosthesis. The pyramid part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be of a generally conventional design. The lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is also preferably integrally formed of stainless steel, but can also be formed of other rigid materials including titanium, aluminum or rigid plastic. A lower portion <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the pyramid part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be circular to accept a separate aluminum snap on dome <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> (second rigid element) is mounted to the lower surface of the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, for example by bolts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> passing through bolt holes <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the legs of the second bracket. The second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is also &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped to define a slot like second aperture <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> having, when mounted to the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, respective top and bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Moreover, a shim <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may be positioned between one leg of the bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the bottom of the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, as will be explained below. To this end, one of the legs <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is shorter than the other. The bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is preferably formed of aluminum alloy, but can be formed of other rigid materials, including stainless steel, titanium or a hard plastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> During assembly of the multi-axis prosthetic ankle, the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is interlockingly positioned within the slot like aperture <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the first bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to form the mechanical device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, after which the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is bolted to the lower surface of the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via the bolts <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the shim <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. At this time, a shim <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of a proper thickness is selected on the basis described below, and is positioned between the end of the shorter one of the legs of the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the lower surface of the base <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. As will be readily understood by those skilled in the art, the shim has a through hole for the bolt <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and the legs <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> have respective threaded through holes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight>The resulting assembly is generally shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, the assembly of the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is placed within a mold (not shown). At this time, the assembly of the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is held in a slightly elevated position so that the surfaces <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second aperture <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> do not contact either of the surfaces <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the first bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Instead, the second bracket <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is held so as to float without contact with the first bracket <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. While the ankle components are held in this condition, rubber is injected into the mold and permitted to harden. The rubber is preferably a thermoset rubber polymer having a high resistance and memory under cyclical loading. Examples are butyl rubber, ethylene-propylene rubber, neoprene rubber, nitrile rubber, polybutadiene rubber, polyisoprene rubber, stereo rubber, styrene-butadiene rubber, natural rubber or a combination of two or more of these rubbers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The polymer rubber (elastomeric material) thereby encases and bonds to the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the mechanical device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> composed of the interlocking brackets <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The rigid components are thus fused together with the polymer rubber to form a flexible assembly. This allows for a smooth transition through the entire gait cycle, from heel strike, through midstance to toe off. As can be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the interlocking brackets <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> do not contact one another but instead are floatingly bonded through the intermediary of the intervening rubber material <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the casing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The peripheral surfaces of the bases <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the bottom component and the lower leg connection component, respectively, have annular concave recesses <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at their circumferential peripheries. These annular recesses improve the grip of the rubber material bonded to the components <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The snap on dome <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is then mounted to the pyramid part <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and the ankle assembly is incorporated into a lower leg prosthesis in a conventional manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> During walking, relative motion (translation and multi-axis rotation) between the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> mounted to the foot prosthesis, and the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> mounted to the lower leg prosthesis is permitted by the elastic deformation of the rubber material of the casing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The motion is thus polycentric and multi-axial with no fixed center of rotation or translation. Moreover, there is no surface to surface contact of the rigid parts <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the mechanical device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and so the material breakdown which could otherwise occur due to surface rubbing is minimized or avoided. The rubber material of the casing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> also absorbs impact energies and so acts as a vibration dampening device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The casing may optionally include a protruding enlargement <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> at the posterior part of the ankle. The tendon <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> serves to stiffen the ankle when the toe is loaded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> By selecting a shim <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the proper thickness, one can control the thickness of the rubber material <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the spaces which separate the brackets <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. One can thereby control the compliance of the joint depending upon the expected loads, which can be anticipated by the weight and general physical activity level of the intended user. This done by selecting a shim <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> providing a desired height &ldquo;H&rdquo; for the aperture <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which allows a predetermined spacing between the brackets, and by the selection of the hardness of the rubber material of the casing <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A shore hardness A of between 70 and 99 is usually selected for adults, whereas a shore hardness A of between 50 and 70 is usually selected for children. For easy reference, the snap on dome <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be color coded to the rubber hardness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The angular degree of rotational motion between the bottom component <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the lower leg connection component <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is limited by stops. In the preferred embodiment, the stops take the form of a limit of the compression of the rubber material of the casing due to the turning of the interlocking brackets <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. That is, by selecting a proper shim for providing a desired height &ldquo;H&rdquo; for the aperture <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, one also selects the resulting thickness of the rubber material present between the brackets, e.g., the intervening rubber material at <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. As the ankle pivots during walking, the rigid surfaces of the brackets <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> approach one another while compressing the intervening rubber material of the casing. The resistance of the rubber material to further compression increases as the ankle pivots. When this resistance equals the turning load on the ankle, the rubber material acts as a fixed stop against further rotation. Since the expected load on the ankle and the compression resistance of the rubber material are known, one skilled in the art can select a shim for a desired height &ldquo;H&rdquo; to permit a predetermined rotation stop for the ankle. Of course, other forms of the rigid stops could instead be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The ankle according to the invention has a higher load range of increasing moment of resistance, compared to prior art ankles which flatten out over lower load ranges. Preferable angles of movement permitted by the stops are as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Internal/External rotation: &plusmn;11&deg; to 15&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Plantar flexion: 13&deg; to 15&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Dorsi flexion: 13&deg; to 15&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Inversion/Eversion: &plusmn;5&deg; to 10&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Anterior/Posterior translation: &plusmn;0.10 to 0.375 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Medial/Lateral translation: &plusmn;0.05 to 0.250 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Vertical displacement: 0.030 to 0.375 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Obviously, numerous modifications and variations of the present invention are possible in light of the above teachings. It is therefore to be understood that the invention may be practiced otherwise than as specifically described herein. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A multi-axis prosthetic ankle comprising: 
<claim-text>a bottom component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic foot; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower leg connection component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic lower leg; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastomeric material securely connecting said bottom component with said lower leg connection component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mechanical device suspended in said elastomeric material, said mechanical device comprising a first rigid element connected to said bottom component and not to said lower leg connection component, and a second rigid element connected to said lower leg connection component and not to said bottom component, wherein said first and second elements interlockingly float in said elastomeric material, and are not in direct contact with one another, such as to permit relative movement of said bottom component and said lower leg connection component by deformation of said elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is bonded to said bottom component, said lower leg connection component and said mechanical device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one mechanical stop adapted to limit rotation of said bottom relative to said lower leg connection component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first rigid element comprises a generally &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped first part connected to said bottom component so as to define a first aperture, and wherein said second rigid element comprises a generally &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped second part connected to said lower leg connection component so as to define a second aperture, wherein said first part floatingly passes through said second aperture and said second part floatingly passes through said first aperture. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower leg connection component includes a pyramid connector and a dome. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is a polymer rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is a polymer rubber having a shore A hardness of 50 to 99. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a snap on dome mounted to said lower leg connection component, said dome being coded to the hardness of the polymer rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a height of one of said first and second apertures is adjustable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A multi-axis prosthetic ankle comprising: 
<claim-text>a bottom component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic foot; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower leg connection component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic lower leg; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastomeric material securely connecting said bottom component with said lower leg connection component; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a generally &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped first rigid part connected to said bottom component so as to define a first aperture; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a generally &ldquo;U&rdquo; shaped second rigid part connected to said lower leg connection component so as to define a second aperture, wherein said first part floatingly extends through said second aperture and said second part floatingly extends through said first aperture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is bonded to said bottom component, said lower leg connection component, and said first and second rigid parts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising at least one mechanical stop positioned to prevent a deformation of said elastomeric material from reaching the elastic limit thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower leg connection component includes a pyramid connector and a dome. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is a polymer rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is a polymer rubber having a shore A hardness of 50 to 99. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a snap on dome mounted to said lower leg connection component, said dome being coded to the hardness of the polymer rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A multi-axis prosthetic ankle comprising: 
<claim-text>a bottom component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic foot; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower leg connection component adapted to be connected to a prosthetic lower leg; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastomeric material securely connecting said bottom component with said lower leg connection component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>rigid mechanical means suspended in said elastomeric material for limiting a deformation of said elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower leg connection component includes a pyramid connector and a dome. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is a polymer rubber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said elastomeric material is casing having a enlargement located circumferentially opposite the toe of the prosthetic foot when the bottom component is connected to the prosthetic foot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one mechanical stop is comprised by a compression resistance of said elastomeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the elastomeric material is a polymer rubber having a shore hardness A of between 50 and 99. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The multi-axis prosthetic ankle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one stop permits Internal/External rotation of &plusmn;11&deg; to 15&deg;; Plantar flexion of 13&deg; to 15&deg;; Dorsi flexion of 13&deg; to 15&deg;; Inversion/Eversion of &plusmn;5&deg; to 10&deg;; Anterior/Posterior translation of &plusmn;0.10 to 0.375 inches; Medial/Lateral translation of &plusmn;0.05 to 0.250 inches; and Vertical displacement of 0.030 to 0.375 inches.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004582A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004582A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004582A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004582A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004582A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
