<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002635A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002635A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002635</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894257</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04M001/64</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>379</class>
<subclass>088170</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Retrieving voice-based content in conjunction with wireless application protocol browsing</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Koch</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Norcross</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>A.</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>McQuaide</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Berkley</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>BellSouth Intellectual Property Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MERCHANT &amp; GOULD PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2903</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402-0903</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A WAP-enabled device can request text-based and/or voice based content from a WAP Server. The WAP device communicates over a conventional wireless service provider network using a base station connected to a conventional Mobile Switching Center. The wireless service provider network provides a connection between the WAP device and a WAP Gateway. The WAP Gateway operates as a gateway between the wireless service provider network and the TCP/IP-based Internet. WAP data requests are sent from the WAP gateway through the Internet to the WAP Server. Requests for voice-based content can also be delivered to the WAP Server over this path. When a request for voice-based content delivery is received by the WAP Server, the WAP Server responds by sending a TCP/IP instruction to a Voice Portal Node. The Voice Portal Node is operative to establish a voice-based communication session with the WAP device. The WAP Server will transmit voice-based content to the Voice Portal Node for delivery to the WAP device. An audible transmission is then played over the telephone connection established between the Voice Portal Node and the WAP device. Thus, voice-based content is delivered to the WAP device in response to a request initiated by the WAP device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to delivering content to wireless devices. More particularly, the present invention relates to delivering voice-based content over existing telephony and Internet infrastructure thereby enabling combined voice-based and visual-based content delivery to a single wireless device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) is a telecommunications industry standard that has been developed to deliver data content to cellular telephones and other wireless devices. WAP was developed in large part to promote uniform specifications for technology useful for developing applications and services that operate over wireless communication networks. WAP specifies an application framework and network protocols for wireless devices such as mobile telephones, pagers, and personal digital assistants (PDAs). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One objective of the WAP specification is to extend mobile networking technologies (such as digital data networking standards) and Internet technologies (such as XML, URLs, scripting, and various content formats). WAP-enabled devices have been used to deliver Internet content and other data services to users of wireless devices. Conventional WAP-based systems have been used to deliver text-based content to wireless devices. Examples of text-based content that has been delivered using WAP-based systems include: email, sports scores, headlines, and news stories. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Voice Extensible Markup Language (VXML) is another new standard directed to delivering Internet content and data so that the content and data are accessible through voice-based devices. One objective of the VXML standard is to provide speech-enabled applications over the Internet. For example, VXML might be used to deliver the XML-formatted contents of a web page in an audible format for delivery to the computer speaker of a sight-impaired user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Although WAP and VXML provide new ways of accessing web-based information, each standard has its limitations. Typically, VXML is implemented in applications involving speech recognition in which spoken commands are used to access information or complete transactions. Often, information in audio form is convenient, but applications are often limited by the need for a limited vocabulary or by a requirement that the user remember arcane verbal commands. While speech recognition technology is advancing, errors frequently occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> WAP-enabled devices support the use of icons and other text-based menu selection tools to access information. For example, most WAP-enabled cellular telephones can deliver content in text-format and rudimentary graphics. Because the WAP-enabled cellular telephone must remain portable, WAP cellular telephone displays must remain small. Hence, it is likely to remain difficult for such cellular telephones to provide large amounts of text-based content or sophisticated graphics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Therefore, there is a need in the art for an infrastructure that can deliver voice-based content to WAP-enabled wireless device, thereby enabling the device to deliver Internet content in an audible format. Preferably, the infrastructure will conform to a content format standard, such as VXML, and will enable the delivery of audible messages to a WAP-enabled wireless device and the processing of speech commands. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention integrates components of a telephone system and existing and new Internet components to deliver voice-based content to Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) enabled wireless device, such as a cellular telephone. A WAP-enabled device can request text-based and/or voice based content from a WAP Server. The WAP device communicates over a conventional wireless service provider network using a base station connected to a conventional Mobile Switch. The wireless service provider network provides a connection between the WAP device and a WAP Gateway. The WAP Gateway operates as a gateway between the wireless service provider network and the TCP/IP-based Internet. WAP data requests are sent from the WAP gateway through the Internet to the WAP Server. Requests for voice-based content can also be delivered to the WAP Server over this path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> When a request for voice-based content delivery is received by the WAP Server, the WAP Server responds by sending a TCP/IP instruction to a Voice Portal Node. The Voice Portal Node acts as a gateway between the wireless service provider network and the TCP/IP-based Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The Voice Portal Node is operative to establish a voice-based communication session with the WAP device. The Voice Portal Node does this by using the out-bound dialing module to initiate a wireless telephone call to the WAP device. The call initiation request is transmitted from the Voice Portal Node to a conventional AIN Central Office. The Central Office routes the call from the Voice Portal Node to the MSC. The MSC provides the necessary switching to connect the call between the Voice Portal Node and the WAP device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> When a telephonic connection has been established between the Voice Portal Node and the WAP device, the Voice Portal Node can provide a delivery authorization prompt to the WAP device. If the WAP device provides a voice-based delivery authorization to the Voice Portal Node, the Voice Portal Node will recognize the authorization by use of the speech recognition engine and will initiate the voice-based session. Once the voice session is begun, the Voice Portal Node will notify the WAP Server that the WAP device is ready for voice-based content delivery. The WAP Server will transmit voice-based content to the Voice Portal Node for delivery to the WAP device. The voice-based content is then delivered as an audible message played over the telephone connection established between the Voice Portal Node and the WAP device. Thus, voice-based content associated with the WAP-based content is delivered to the WAP device in response to a request initiated by the WAP device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The various aspects of the present invention may be more clearly understood and appreciated from a review of the following detailed description of the disclosed embodiments and by reference to the drawings and claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting a conventional wireless application protocol content-delivery system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a conventional cellular telephone Wireless Application Protocol device displaying Wireless Application Protocol information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts a conventional cellular telephone Wireless Application Protocol device displaying a page of Wireless Application Protocol content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts two cellular telephone Wireless Application Protocol devices that are exemplary embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts two cellular telephone Wireless Application Protocol devices that are exemplary embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts a voice and data content-delivery system that is an exemplary embodiment of present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart depicting an exemplary method for providing voice and text-based content to a Wireless Application Protocol device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting an alternative embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting a conventional Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) content-delivery system. Using a WAP device such as a cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a user can contact a WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> via a wireless service provider system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Typically, the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> will communicate directly with a base station <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> that is connected through a Mobile Switching Center (MSC) <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to a WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> will receive instructions from the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and will provide content to the cellular telephone, in response to those instructions. Typically, the data link between the MSC <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> will be a data-only connection <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. That is, instructions will be sent from the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in a data channel. Likewise, content will be delivered from the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> over a data channel, not a voice channel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> retrieves content from a WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> by sending content requests over the Internet <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The WAP data can be sent from the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in various formats (e.g., Hypertext Markup Language), but would preferably be provided in Wireless Markup Language (WML). The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can communicate by Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP). Communications between the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can be channeled through a firewall <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The firewall <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is a well-known security device for protecting a server or other network component from &lt;unauthorized access via the Internet <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>.&gt; Another firewall (not shown) could be used to protect the WAP gateway from &lt;&gt;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The WAP Server has a portal database <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to which it can be connected over communications channel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The portal database <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may store the content that is used by the WAP Server to provide content to the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can be connected to the portal database <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> over a data link <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The data link <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> can be a TCP/IP connection, a hardwire connection, or a local area network connection. Of course, the portal database could also be integrated into the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> could be used to provide content to WAP devices from various WAP portals. In such a case, the WAP Server may have more than one portal database <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The desired portal can be identified initially by the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a domain name format. For example, the WAP device may submit a domain name <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that identifies a &ldquo;BellSouth&rdquo; portal. The domain name <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may also include an indication that the WAP device <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is requesting WAP content. In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the domain name includes this indication as &ldquo;/wap&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may obtain raw content from the portal database <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and compile the data into WML pages that are formatted specifically for a particular WAP device&apos;s display. For example, the request from the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may include a device identifier that can be used by the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to determine the display capabilities of the WAP device. Once the server has packaged the WML content, it transmits the content over the Internet <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to the WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> converts the packaged WAP content into a form that can be transmitted over the infrastructure of the wireless service provider <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and transmits that content to the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via MSC <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and base station <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The conventional WAP infrastructure depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> provides content to the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a text-based format. The WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be used to enter a portal domain name <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to establish a WAP communication session with the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Once the WAP session is begun, the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can be used to traverse a menu provided by the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and to request content that is identified in that menu. Once the content has been identified by the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can provide the requested content in the form of WML pages. The pages are displayed on the WAP device&apos;s display. The user of the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> can &ldquo;browse&rdquo; from page to page by pressing a predetermined key on the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Each key press may send a request to the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> for the next page of content. Alternatively, the WAP device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may include a memory buffer that permits the storage of multiple pages of WAP content that can be browsed without requiring single page requests to be sent to the WAP Server <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. While the conventional WAP device is ideal for menu navigation, the presentation of content is hampered by the limited ability of the WAP device to visually present content to a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a conventional cellular telephone WAP device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> that has WAP information on its display <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. The WAP device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can be used to display a menu structure <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. By using a selection key <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, a user of the WAP device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can select menu items from the menu <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> for which the user would like to see WAP content. Once selected, the user can press a predefined submission button <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> to submit the request to the WAP Server (not shown). In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the submission key <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is labeled &ldquo;OK&rdquo; and corresponds to a submission message <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> on the display <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts a conventional cellular telephone WAP device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> displaying a page of WAP content. The display <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the WAP device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is displaying a second page of a menu structure provided by the WAP Server (not shown). In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the menu page presented on the display <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is provided in response to the selection of the &ldquo;News&rdquo; menu item from the menu page depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The menu structure <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> provides three menu items. The selection of one of the menu items can result in the display of one or more headlines. The selection button <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and the submission button <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> of the WAP device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> could be used to select a headline. The selection of the headline would be sent back to the WAP Server (not shown) as a WAP content request. The WAP Server would return the associated WAP content (i.e., the news story) to the WAP device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The WAP device <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> would then display the WAP content on the WAP device&apos;s display <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts two cellular telephone WAP devices that are exemplary embodiments of the present invention. The first WAP device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is displaying three headlines that are provided, in response to the selection of the &ldquo;U.S.&rdquo; menu item, as described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. A particular headline can be selected by use of the selection key <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. In the conventional WAP-enabled cellular telephone, the selection of a headline would result in the delivery of WAP content to the cellular telephone. However, the WAP device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of an exemplary embodiment of the present invention can receive text-based content as well as voice-based content. The voice-based content will be delivered to the WAP device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, in response to the selection of the &ldquo;Listen&rdquo; menu item <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the &ldquo;Back&rdquo; menu item <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> can be selected to move back one level in the menu structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> If the Listen menu item <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> is selected, the WAP device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> will send a request for voice-based content to the WAP Server through the WAP Gateway (not shown). When the Listen menu item is selected, the display will show a &ldquo;STANDBY: NOW RETRIEVING VOICE CONTENT&rdquo; message as shown on the display <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> of the WAP device <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the data session need not end in response to the commencement of the voice session. An alternative embodiment of the present invention enables the simultaneous delivery of voice and data sessions. This embodiment will be described in more detail in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts two cellular telephone WAP devices <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> that are exemplary embodiments of the present invention. The cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is shown with the &ldquo;Data Session Ended&rdquo; message on the display <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. However, the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> has received a voice-based communication from the WAP Server (not shown). The voice-based communication is referred to as a voice session. The voice-based content requested will be delivered to the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, when the cellular telephone user responds to a delivery prompt. As described above, the Voice Portal Node establishes a voice-connection with the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, thereby enabling the delivery of the voice-based content. The Voice Portal Node makes an out-bound call to the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> using the cellular telephone&apos;s directory number that is provided by the WAP Gateway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> prompts the user by playing an audible message &ldquo;to hear requested information, say &lsquo;go&rsquo;&rdquo; <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the delivery prompt could be text-based and the delivery authorization could be a key press, rather than an audible command. If the user issues the delivery authorization, the cellular telephone <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> will begin delivery of the voice-based content <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> depicts a voice and data content delivery system that is an exemplary embodiment of the present invention. As described in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> can request text-based data from a WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>. The WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> communicates over the wireless service provider network <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, using base station <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> which is connected to an MSC <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>. The wireless service provider network <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> provides a connection between the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> and a WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> acts as a gateway between the wireless service provider network and the TCP/IP-based Internet <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight>. WAP data requests are sent from the WAP gateway <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> through the Internet <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight> to the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>. In addition, requests for voice-based content can also be delivered to the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> over this path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> When a request for voice-based content delivery is received by the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>, it responds by sending a TCP/IP instruction to a Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> over a communication link <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>. The Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> acts as a gateway between the wireless service provider network and the TCP/IP-based Internet <highlight><bold>614</bold></highlight>. An exemplary Voice Portal Node has four main components: a) a VXML interpreter; b) a text-to-speech module; c) a speech recognition engine; and d) a out-bound dialing module. The Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> can establish a voice-based communication session with the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> by using the dialing module to initiate a wireless telephone call to the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. The WAP Gateway <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> passes a directory number of the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> to the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> as part of the TCP/IP instruction. The call initiation request is transmitted from the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> to a conventional Advanced Intelligent Network central office <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight>. The central office <highlight><bold>628</bold></highlight> routes the call from the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> to the MSC <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>. The MSC <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> provides the necessary switching to connect the call between the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> and the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Once the call has been established between the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> and the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>, the Voice Portal Node can provide a delivery authorization prompt to the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. If the WAP device provides a voice-based delivery authorization to the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight>, the Voice Portal Node will initiate the voice-based session. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Once the voice session is begun, the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> will notify the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> that the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> is ready for voice-based content delivery. The Voice Portal Node will request voice-based content. The WAP Server will transmit voice-based content to the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> for delivery to the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment of the present invention, the voice-based content will be transmitted from the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> to the Voice Portal Node in Voice Extensible Markup Language (VXML). The Voice Portal Node uses the VXML interpreter to receive the voice-based content and then uses the text-to-speech module to convert the received content to an audible message. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that virtually any data format could be used to transmit the voice content between the WAP Server <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> and the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight>. The Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> converts the VXML voice data to an audible transmission. The audible transmission is then played back over the telephone connection established between the Voice Portal Node <highlight><bold>626</bold></highlight> and the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. Thus, voice-based content is delivered to the WAP device <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> in response to a request initiated by the WAP device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart depicting an exemplary method for providing voice and text-based content to a WAP device. The method starts at step <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> and proceeds to step <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight>, a request for WAP data is received. The method then proceeds to step <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>, wherein a WAP data request is transmitted to a WAP Gateway. The WAP data request includes the telephone number (directory number) of the WAP device that has generated the data request. The method proceeds from step <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> to step <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>, the WAP Server is contacted and a WAP session is established. The method then proceeds to step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> At step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>, a two-way transmission (data session) is established between the cellular device and the WAP Server. The method proceeds from step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> to decision block <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>. At decision block <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether voice content is requested. If voice content is not requested, the method branches to decision block <highlight><bold>740</bold></highlight> (via connector A). At decision block <highlight><bold>740</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether the WAP session is terminated. For example, the WAP session may be terminated by the selection of a menu item ending the data session. If the data session is terminated, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>736</bold></highlight> and ends. If the data session is not terminated, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> and two way data transmission is continued between the cellular device and the WAP Server. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Returning now to decision block <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight>, if a determination is made that voice content has been requested, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>712</bold></highlight>, a voice-based content request is sent to the WAP Gateway. The method then proceeds to step <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>, the voice content request is submitted to the WAP Server. The method then proceeds to step <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight>, wherein a call is placed to the cellular device. As discussed above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, this step may be performed by a Voice Portal Node using the cellular device&apos;s directory number obtained from the WAP Gateway. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The method then proceeds to decision block <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight>. At decision block <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether the call is accepted. If the call is not accepted, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>720</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>720</bold></highlight>, an alert is transmitted to the cellular device indicating that the voice-based content cannot be delivered. The method then branches to decision block <highlight><bold>740</bold></highlight> and proceeds as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Returning now to decision block <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight>, if a determination is made that the call is accepted, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>722</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>722</bold></highlight>, a prompt is provided for authorization to deliver voice content to the cellular device. The method then proceeds to decision block <highlight><bold>724</bold></highlight>. At decision block <highlight><bold>724</bold></highlight>, a determination is made whether a delivery authorization is received before some predefined time out period. If a determination is made that the authorization was not received, the method branches to decision block <highlight><bold>740</bold></highlight> and proceeds as described above. If, on the other hand, a determination is made at decision block <highlight><bold>724</bold></highlight> that authorization has been received, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>726</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> At step <highlight><bold>726</bold></highlight>, the Voice Portal Node retrieves the voice content from the WAP server and delivers the voice content to the cellular device. This step <highlight><bold>726</bold></highlight> may include a conversion step in which, for example, VXML-based data is translated to an audible transmission. The method then proceeds to decision block <highlight><bold>728</bold></highlight>. At decision block <highlight><bold>728</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether there is a queued content request. That is, a determination is made as to whether the user of the cellular device has requested the delivery of voice content in addition to the voice content delivered in step <highlight><bold>726</bold></highlight>. If a queued voice content request exists, the method branches back to step <highlight><bold>726</bold></highlight> and that voice content is delivered. This loop can be continued as long as voice content requests are queued. If a determination is made at step <highlight><bold>728</bold></highlight> that no voice content requests are queued, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>730</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> At step <highlight><bold>730</bold></highlight>, the wireless connection is terminated between the Voice Portal Node and the cellular device. The method proceeds from step <highlight><bold>730</bold></highlight> to decision block <highlight><bold>732</bold></highlight>. At decision block <highlight><bold>732</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether any data content requests are queued. That is, a determination is made as to whether the cellular device user has requested the delivery of additional data content. If a determination is made that additional data content has been requested, the method branches to step <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> and proceeds as described above. If, on the other hand, a determination is made that no further data content has been requested, the method branches from decision block <highlight><bold>732</bold></highlight> to step <highlight><bold>734</bold></highlight>. At step <highlight><bold>734</bold></highlight>, the connection between the cellular device and the WAP Gateway is terminated. In an alternative embodiment, step <highlight><bold>734</bold></highlight> may be conditioned on a determination that the user has affirmatively requested the termination of the connection between the cellular device and the WAP Gateway. The method branches from step <highlight><bold>734</bold></highlight> to step <highlight><bold>736</bold></highlight> and ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment of the present invention, both voice-based and WAP-based content can be delivered to the WAP device simultaneously. In this embodiment, the WAP session is not ended, prior to the initiation of the voice session. Consequently, the user of the WAP device can listen to voice-based content and then navigate a WAP-based menu structure to find other voice-based content that can be delivered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a block diagram depicting an alternative embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, the WAP device <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> can be used to request delivery of content through other means. For example, the WAP device <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> could be used to request that content be delivered to an email address. The WAP Server <highlight><bold>812</bold></highlight> could request the entry of the email address, via the WAP device keypad. Alternatively, the WAP Server could maintain an email address for each WAP device in an email profile <highlight><bold>852</bold></highlight> maintained in the portal database <highlight><bold>822</bold></highlight>. In either case, the WAP Server could be equipped with an email server <highlight><bold>854</bold></highlight> that functions to route email-versions of the WAP content to one or more email addresses identified by the WAP device user or by the WAP device&apos;s email profile <highlight><bold>852</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The content could then be delivered to the entered email address. Of course, the email profile <highlight><bold>852</bold></highlight> could maintain an address book for a WAP device user and could permit the user to email content to various email addresses. An email recipient could be identified through the use of a menu on the WAP device&apos;s display or through a spoken command. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the same technique could be used to deliver the content to other delivery points, including, but not limited to, a physical street address. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described in connection with various exemplary embodiments, those of ordinary skill in the art will understand that many modifications can be made thereto within the scope of the claims that follow. Accordingly, it is not intended that the scope of the invention in any way be limited by the above description, but instead be determined entirely by reference to the claims that follow. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) system for delivering voice-based content to a user of a wireless device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a WAP Server operative to deliver voice-based information to the wireless device over a connection, in response to the receipt of a voice-based content request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a WAP Gateway operative to receive the voice-based content request from the wireless device and to deliver the voice-based content request to a Voice Portal Node; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the Voice Portal Node is operative to place a call to the wireless device, thereby establishing the connection between the wireless device and the WAP Server. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Gateway and the Voice Portal Node communicate over a Transport Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) data channel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Gateway delivers a directory number of the wireless device to the Voice Portal Node over the TCP/IP data channel, thereby enabling the Voice Portal Node to place the call to the wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Server and the WAP Gateway communicate over a Transport Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) data channel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the Voice Portal Node is further operative to retrieve the voice-based content from the WAP Server and to deliver the voice-based content to the wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the voice-based content is delivered to the Voice Portal Node in Voice Extensible Markup Language (VXML) format. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein Voice Portal Node is operative to convert VXML content received from the WAP Server to an audio message and is further operative to deliver the audio message to the wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Server is further operative to send an email message containing the voice-based content in a text form to an email address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Server is equipped with an email server operative to format and transmit the email message. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The WAP system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP Server is further operative to simultaneously deliver voice-based and text-based content to the wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method for delivering voice-based content and text-based content to a Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) device, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>establishing a WAP-based connection between the WAP device and a WAP Server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>establishing a telephonic connection between the WAP device and a Voice Portal Node; </claim-text>
<claim-text>retrieving the voice-based content from the WAP server and delivering the voice-based content to the WAP device over the telephonic connection; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>delivering the text-based content to the WAP device over the WAP-based connection. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of modifying the delivery of the voice-based content in response to receiving a user instruction over the telephonic connection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of modifying the delivery of the voice-based information in response to receiving a user instruction over the WAP-based connection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of modifying the delivery of the WAP-based information in response to receiving a user instruction over the telephonic connection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of modifying the delivery of the WAP-based information in response to receiving a user instruction over the WAP-based connection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the WAP-based connection between the WAP device and a WAP Server is made through a WAP Gateway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of translating Voice Extensible Markup Language (VXML) data to an audible message for delivery as the voice-based content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of translating an audible voice user instruction to Voice Extensible Markup Language (VXML) data for delivery to the WAP Server. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>accessing a WAP-enabled web site associated with the WAP Server; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting a voice content request to the WAP Server, via the WAP-enabled web site. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) system for delivering voice-based content to a user of a wireless device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a WAP Server operative to deliver voice-based information to a the wireless device over a connection, in response to the receipt of a voice-based content request; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a WAP Gateway operative to receive the voice-based content request from the wireless device and to deliver the voice-based content request to the Voice Portal Node, the voice-based content request including a directory number of the wireless device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the Voice Portal Node is operative to place a call to the directory number of the wireless device, thereby establishing the connection between the wireless device and the WAP Server; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the WAP Server is further operative to simultaneously deliver the voice-based content and to deliver text-based content to the wireless device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>7</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002635A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
