<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003623A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003623A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003623A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003623A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003623</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10219515</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020815</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>19744012.6</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19970926</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L023/22</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>106000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>127000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>678000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>687000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electronic component mounted on a flat substrate and padded with a fluid filler</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10219515</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020815</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09516605</doc-number>
<document-date>20000403</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6445074</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10219515</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020815</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09160889</doc-number>
<document-date>19980925</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6057178</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Klaus-Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Galuschki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Berlin</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Heinz</given-name>
<family-name>Pilz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Berlin</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KENYON &amp; KENYON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>One Broadway</address-1>
<city>New York</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of padding an electronic component, mounted on a flat substrate, with a fluid filler, in which the fluid filler that is applied in a tight-fitting manner to the electronic component mounted on the substrate. The arrangement composed of substrate and electronic component is then heated. The substrate is provided with at least one through orifice in the area of the electronic component prior to applying the filler. The filler is applied at the end of the through orifice faring away from the electronic component. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method of padding an electronic component, mounted on a flat substrate, with a free-flowing filler, in which the fluid filler is applied in a tight-fitting manner to the electronic component mounted on the substrate and flows into the arrangement composed of the substrate and electronic component under the effect of heat. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The document &ldquo;Adhesive Dispensing for Flip Chip-on-Board,&rdquo; <highlight><italic>Electronic Packaging &amp; Production </italic></highlight>October 1995, Advertising Insert pp. 9-11 describes a method of padding an electronic component. In this method, the electronic component, which may be a semiconductor chip, for example, is padded with a free-flowing filler after being mounted on a flat substrate, for example, on a printed circuit board, so that the filler is linearly applied to at least one edge of the electronic component using a dispenser. Under the effect of heat, the filler becomes fluid and penetrates by capillary action into the space between the electronic component and the substrate. Additional amounts of filler are then applied to those edges of the electronic component along which no filler was previously applied, so that a meniscus-shaped seal is achieved on all the edges of the electronic component. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a method for padding an electronic component mounted on a flat substrate with a free-flowing filler that is relatively easy to accomplish. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> To achieve this object, the substrate is provided with at least one through orifice in the area of the electronic component prior to the application of the filler, and the filler is applied on the end of the orifice facing away from the electronic component. The substrate may be a printed circuit board or foil, a ceramic substrate, or a load frame, for example; the electronic component is a flip chip or a ball grid array, for example. Filler is understood as being a mixture of resin and inorganic additives or particles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the invention is that when padding the electronic component, the filler penetrates underneath the electronic component into the space between the component and the substrate, so the filler expands in the space basically from the inside out in a way that all the air is displaced from the space between the electronic component and the substrate, while complete padding is achieved. Padding is done relatively rapidly, since the filler can expand on all sides from the at least one through orifice into the space between the electronic component and the substrate. Another advantage is that in the method according to the present invention, a meniscus-shaped seal forms by itself on all the edges of the electronic component, so that no subsequent operation is required. The cost of providing the at least one through orifice is relatively low. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the method according to the present invention, the filler can be applied on the substrate if the electronic component is located as usual above the substrate. This applies particularly in the case when only a relatively small amount of filler is to be applied to the substrate due to a relatively small electronic component. This relatively small amount of filler does not drip off when heated, but is &ldquo;sucked in&rdquo; as known upward by capillary action through the orifice into the space between the electronic component and the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the case of electronic components of typical dimensions, it is considered advantageous in the method according to the present invention if the arrangement composed of the substrate and the electronic component is brought into a position where the substrate faces upward prior to applying the filler. In this embodiment of the method according to the present invention, a relatively large amount of the filler applied also remains in the area of the through orifice and can flow into the space between the electronic component and the substrate under the effect of heat and capillary action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In order to pad the electronic component in a particularly rapid manner, pressure is exerted on the filler applied by the method according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In order to pad the space between the electronic component and the substrate as quickly and reliably as possible overall, it is considered advantageous if the through orifice is provided in the substrate centered with respect to the electronic component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In the method according to the present invention it is not necessary that the filler be applied onto the substrate using a dispenser. The filler can be applied by pouring, as long as the arrangement composed of the substrate and electronic component faces upward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the method according to the present invention, the through orifice can be advantageously used as a reservoir for the required amount of filler if the through orifice is sufficiently large. The filler that becomes fluid under the effect of heat cannot then expand on the side of the substrate facing away from the electronic component, but remains in the through orifice. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> It is, however, also possible to provide the substrate with an ring-shaped piece mounted at the end of the through orifice facing away from the electronic component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> With the method according to the present invention, the filler can also be applied by pressing or stamping, in addition to applying it with a dispenser. Spraying the filler onto the substrate on the end facing away from the electronic component of the through orifice is also possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention also relates to an arrangement with a flat substrate and an electronic component mounted on it, with the space between the electronic component and the substrate being padded with a fluid filler. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In order to design such an arrangement so that it is easy to manufacture, at least one through orifice is provided in the substrate under the electronic component for applying the filler. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> If a single through orifice is provided for the arrangement, this is preferably centered in the substrate with the electronic component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the arrangement according to the present invention, the through orifice has a volume that is at least equal to that of the filler required for padding the electronic component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In the arrangement according to the present invention, the volume in the area of the through orifice can be prepared so that the through orifice, configured as a through hole, for example, has a cross-section of a proper dimension. It is considered particularly advantageous if the through orifice, on its side facing away from the electronic component, has a pot-shaped widening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The volume required for holding the fluid filler can also be provided in the area of the through orifice in the arrangement according to the present invention by providing a ring-shaped piece mounted on the through hole on its side facing away from the electronic component.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically shows a device for carrying out the method according to the present invention with an arrangement including a substrate and an electronic component shown in cross-section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an arrangement including a substrate and an electronic component padded by the method according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows another arrangement including a substrate and an electronic component also padded by the method according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a transport device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, with which an arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> including a substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and an electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> mounted on it is transported into the operating range of a dispenser <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and an electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is positioned on transport device <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, so that substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is located above electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> further shows, electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the area of electrical contacts <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> forming arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and is brought into the range of dispenser <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in this form. Prior to this, a through orifice <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is provided in substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, at the center of electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. If arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> thus prepared and heated is brought into the position illustrated with respect to dispenser <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, free-flowing filler is applied from the dispenser onto end <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, facing away from electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, of through orifice <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The amount applied of filler <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> becomes fluid under the effect of heat and is drawn into the space <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> between substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by capillary action. The air is displaced from the area of through orifice <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> by filler flowing in. Ultimately, filler <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is fully distributed in space <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and forms a meniscus-shaped seal at edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of electronic component <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is transported further either to pad with filler another electronic component mounted or to pad another substrate having an electronic component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an arrangement <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> padded according to the present invention with a substrate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and a mounted electronic component <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, in which substrate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has a pot-shaped widening <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> at end <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, facing away from electronic component <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, of a through orifice <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Filler <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is filled into this pot-shaped widening <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in the padding process. The filler that has become fluid under the effect of heat flows into space <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> between substrate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and electronic component <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by capillary action from the inside out and forms a meniscus-shaped seal at edges <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of electronic component <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Arrangement <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which includes a substrate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and an electronic component <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, basically corresponds to the arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. It differs from the arrangement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> basically by the fact that substrate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is provided, on its side <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> facing away from electronic component <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, with a piece <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> surrounding through orifice <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> forming a reservoir for filler <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of padding an electronic component mounted on a flat substrate, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing the substrate with at least one through orifice in an area of the electronic component; </claim-text>
<claim-text>after the providing step, applying a free-flowing filler in a tight-fitting manner to the electronic component, the filler being applied at an end of the through orifice facing away from the electronic component; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the free-flowing filler, the heated free-flowing filler flowing into an arrangement, the arrangement including the electronic component and the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>prior to the applying step, positioning the arrangement to face the substrate upward. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>exerting a pressure on the applied free-flowing filler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the providing step includes the step of centering the through orifice in the substrate with respect to the electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the applying step includes the step of applying the free-flowing filler via one of a dispenser and pouring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one orifice forms a reservoir for the free-flowing filler. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of: 
<claim-text>providing the substrate with a ring-shaped piece on the end of the orifice. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the applying step includes the step of pressing the free-flowing filler. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An arrangement, comprising: 
<claim-text>a flat substrate having at least one through orifice; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic component mounted on the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid filler padding a space between the flat substrate and the electronic component, the at least one through orifice positioned under the electronic component for applying the fluid filler. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The arrangement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one through orifice is centered with respect to the electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The arrangement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the through orifice has a volume that is at least equal to the amount of fluid filler needed for padding the electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The arrangement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the through orifice has a pot-shaped widening at an end facing away from the electronic component. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The arrangement according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a ring-shaped piece mounted on an end of the orifice that faces away from the electronic component.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003623A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003623A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
