<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000476A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000476A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000476</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10106200</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020327</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-196539</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C23C016/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>719000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>729000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>715000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>733000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Substrate processing apparatus, conveying unit thereof, and semiconductor device fabricating Method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tatsuhisa</given-name>
<family-name>Matsunaga</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Sekiyama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hitachi Kokusai Electric Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Eugene Mar</name-1>
<name-2>BACON &amp; THOMAS</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>625 Slaters Lane - 4th Floor</address-1>
<city>Alexandria</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A substrate processing apparatus includes a process chamber, a sealed chamber arranged, a movable member disposed inside the sealed chamber, an extendable/contractible structure having a first and a second extendable/contractible member respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, and a driving mechanism, disposed in the extendable/contractible structure, for driving the movable member. The driving mechanism is isolated from an inner surface of the sealed chamber. The interiors of the first and the second extendable/contractible member communicate with an exterior of the sealed chamber. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a substrate processing apparatus, conveying unit thereof, and a semiconductor device fabricating method using the apparatus; and, more particularly, to a conveying unit for use in a sealing chamber of a substrate processing apparatus, and a semiconductor device fabricating method using the apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Generally, a substrate processing apparatus is used to form a chemical vapor deposition (CVD) film, such as an insulating film or a metal film, on a semiconductor wafer or to diffuse impurities onto the wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There is provided a conventional substrate processing apparatus in the U.S. Pat. No. 5,571,330, which discloses a load lock chamber for a vertical type heat treatment apparatus. The load lock chamber is arranged below a treatment chamber of the vertical type heat treatment apparatus, and can load, under a gas proof condition, a boat for placing wafers into the treatment chamber and unload the boat therefrom through a lower part of the treatment chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The load lock chamber is formed by a vertically extendible/contractible hollow structure including a first and a second bellows, having different sizes, and a connecting member therebetween. The first and the second bellows are telescopically nested in the connecting member when the hollow structure is maximally contracted. The open upper end of the hollow structure is hermetically coupled with the treatment chamber located thereabove, while the lower end thereof is airtightly closed by a movable member on which the boat is mounted. The connecting member and the movable member are engaged with an elevator mechanism located outside the hollow structure so that the boat mounted inside the hollow structure can be driven to move up and down by the elevator mechanism hermetically isolated therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned load lock chamber for the vertical type heat treatment apparatus, however, has a critical deficiency. If the vertical type heat treatment apparatus processes a wafer having a diameter of 300 mm, the diameters of the first and the second bellows need to be larger than 400 mm and 500 mm both inclusive, respectively. In that case, whenever the first and the second bellows are in a vacuum state, forces of about 2000 kgf (about 20000 N) and 1200 kgf (about 12000 N) respectively act on the first and the second bellows because of a pressure difference between the atmospheric pressure (1 kgf/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, or about 98 kPa) and the vacuum pressure of each bellows. As a result, when the wafer processed by the vertical type heat treatment apparatus has the diameter of 300 mm, a very large-sized drive mechanism should be employed to drive a vertically extending/contracting mechanism of the load lock chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Japanese Patent Laid-Open Publication No. P10-181870 discloses a hermetically enclosed conveyor of a different type for use in a conventional substrate processing apparatus. The hermetically enclosed conveyor includes a supporter contained in a sealed enclosure to support an article, and a drive mechanism for driving the supporter. The sealed enclosure includes a conveying space and a drive mechanism housing space, in which an electric wiring is laid. The two spaces are hermetically separated from each other by means of a first bellows and a second bellows, such that the pressure in the conveying space and that in the drive mechanism housing space are individually controlled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It can be contemplated to employ the above-mentioned hermetically enclosed conveyor for a boat elevator mechanism that vertically moves a boat in the vertical type heat treatment apparatus. In that case, however, the inner pressures of the first and the second bellows need to be controlled based on a pressure variation inside the load lock chamber for the purposes of: protecting the first and the second bellows from a possible deformation thereof resulting from the pressure difference between the inside and the outside of each bellows; and individually contracting or extending the first and the second bellows. In order to achieve the above-mentioned purposes, however, a complicated pressure control valve system and a control system thereof should be employed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is, therefore, a primary object of the present invention to provide a substrate processing apparatus having a boat elevator mechanism of an economic size, such that a simple control scheme can be adopted therefor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the present invention, there is provided a substrate processing apparatus, which includes: a process chamber for processing substrates; a sealed chamber arranged adjacent to the process chamber; a movable member, disposed inside the sealed chamber, for supporting the substrates; an extendable/contractible structure including a first extendable/contractible member and a second extendable/contractible member respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, wherein interiors of the first and the second extendable/contractible member communicate with an exterior of the sealed chamber; and a driving means, disposed in the extendable/contractible structure, for moving the movable member, wherein the driving means is isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the extendable/contractible structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a semiconductor device fabricating method using a substrate processing apparatus including a sealed chamber, a process chamber, and a substrate conveying unit positioned in the sealed chamber, wherein the substrate conveying unit includes a) a movable member for supporting a boat, b) a first and a second extendible/contractible member respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, interiors of the first and the second extendible/contractible member communicating with an exterior circumstance, and c) a driving means, disposed in the first and the second extendible/contractible member, for moving the movable member, the driving means being isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the first and the second extendible/contractible member, the method including the steps of: loading at least one substrate into the boat staying in the sealed chamber; loading the boat into the process chamber from the sealed chamber by using the substrate conveying unit; and processing said at least one substrate loaded in the boat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a conveying unit used in a sealed chamber, the conveying unit including: a movable member arranged in the sealed chamber, the movable member supporting an article; a first extendible/contractible structure and a second extendible/contractible structure respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, wherein interiors of the first and the second extendible/contractible structure individually communicate with an exterior of the sealed chamber; and a driving means, disposed in the first and the second extendible/contractible structure, for moving the movable member, wherein the driving means is isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the first and the second extendible/contractible structure</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects and features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of preferred embodiments given in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> presents a sectional plan view of a batch type CVD apparatus in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a sectional side view taken along a line II-II of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> represents a sectional side view taken along another line III-III of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts a partial extended side view of a boat elevator; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> shows a sectional view taken along a line a-a of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> describes a sectional view taken along a line b-b of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> provides a sectional view taken along a line c-c of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> illustrates a sectional view that corresponds to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, in accordance with another preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> sets forth a sectional side view showing a process stage in which a boat is loaded into a process chamber; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> gives a sectional rear view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, a substrate processing apparatus in accordance with preferred embodiments of the present invention will be described in detail. Like numerals represent like parts in the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The substrate processing apparatus in accordance with the preferred embodiments is a batch type vertical diffusion/CVD apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (referred to as a batch type CVD apparatus hereinafter), which is adapted for use in a CVD process for forming a CVD film, e.g., an insulating film or a metal film on a wafer or an impurity diffusion process for diffusing impurities onto the wafer. The batch type CVD apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> adopts a front opening unified pod (FOUP, referred to as a pod hereinafter) for a wafer conveying carrier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In the following descriptions, a front, a rear, a left and a right side are defined on the basis of parts shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. That is to say, the front side refers to where a pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is positioned; the rear side, a load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>; the left side, a clean air unit <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>; and finally the right side, an elevator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of a wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the batch type CVD apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Disposed at the rear side of the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> that forms therein an antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, where a boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is located. The antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is a sealed enclosure capable of maintaining therein a sub-atmospheric pressure. The load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is of a shape of an approximately rectangular box large enough to accommodate therein the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Formed through a front wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is a wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, which is selectively opened or closed by a gate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Formed through a rear wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is a repair/inspection opening <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. For a repair or inspection, the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is loaded into or unloaded from the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> through the repair/inspection opening <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, which is usually closed by another gate <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> except for the repair or inspection time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, an exhaust line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a gas supply line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are individually connected to a bottom wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The exhaust line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> serves to exhaust the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> such that the inner pressure thereof reduces below the atmospheric pressure. Nitrogen (N2) gas is introduced into the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> through the gas supply line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, whenever it is needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, a boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which is selectively opened or closed by a shutter <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, is formed in a ceiling wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A heater unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is vertically arranged on the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and a process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> having a process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed in the hollow space therein is arranged inside the heater unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is of a cylindrical shape having a closed upper portion and an opened lower portion and is concentrically arranged with the heater unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is supported by a manifold <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> located on the ceiling wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a gas supply line <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and an exhaust line <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are connected to the manifold <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, wherein source gas or purge gas is introduced into the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through the gas supply line <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is exhausted through the exhaust line <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The manifold <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is concentrically arranged with the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Arranged at a rear left side of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is a conveying unit or a boat elevator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> serving to vertically move the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The boat elevator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and a feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which are vertically arranged between an upper installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a lower installation plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> guides an elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> serving as a mover. The elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is screw-coupled with the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, such that the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can move up or down along the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> while the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are rotating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> For facilitating a smooth operation and a proper backlash, a ball screw mechanism is preferably applied to the coupling of the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. An upper edge portion of the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> sequentially passes through the upper installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the ceiling wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, finally projecting from the top of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A motor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> installed outside the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is coupled to the upper edge portion of the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, thereby rotating the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> either clockwise or counterclockwise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> An arm <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> horizontally protrudes from a side of the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and a sealing cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> running parallel to the arm <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is arranged on a vertically protruding member provided at an edge portion of the arm <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The sealing cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> vertically supports the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and functions to airtightly close the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> serving as a furnace mouth of the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> concentrically accommodates a multiplicity of wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; (for example, 25, 50, 100, 125, or 150 wafers). Then, the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is loaded into or unloaded from the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in accordance as the sealing cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is elevated or descended by the boat elevator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> arranged inside the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is configured to transfer the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo;. The wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a rotary actuator <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, which drives a first linear actuator <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> installed thereon such that the first linear actuator <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can rotate on a horizontal plane. A second linear actuator <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is installed on the first linear actuator <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which horizontally moves the second linear actuator <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A moving stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is installed on the second linear actuator <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, which horizontally moves the moving stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> On the moving stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, a number of horizontal tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> (5 pairs in this preferred embodiment) are arranged with an equal pitch therebetween. Each pair of the tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> serves to support the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; disposed thereon. The wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is elevated or descended by the elevator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> having a feed screw mechanism or the like. The clean air unit <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is arranged opposite to the elevator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Further, a reference numeral <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> refers to a notch coupling unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, another wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is formed through a front wall of the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so that wafers can be loaded into or unloaded from the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> therethrough. The pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is arranged at the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> has a loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for mounting a pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; thereon and a cap device <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The cap device <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>serves to remove or restore the cap of the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; mounted on a loading stage <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, thereby opening or closing a wafer-way of the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo;. The pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is supplied to or removed from the loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by means of a pod conveying system (not shown), such as a rail guided vehicle (RGV). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a preferred embodiment illustrated in detail with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>D, a first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> as a first extendable/contractible structure and a second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as a second extendable/contractible structure are respectively arranged on top and bottom of the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, wherein the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> as well as the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is accommodated in the vertically extended inner space defined by the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are hermitically isolated from that of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> A first communicating hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is formed through the ceiling wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the upper installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. A second communicating hole <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is also formed through the bottom wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> as well as the lower installation plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The first and the second communicating hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> make the inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> individually communicate with the environment so that the whole inner spaces defined by the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be maintained at the atmospheric pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Each of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is provided with a multiplicity of horizontal reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> (4 sheets in this preferred embodiment), which are arranged at equi-distance vertically. The reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> serve to prevent the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> from being deformed from their vertical or horizontal profile. Each reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is of a shape of a thin disk having a diameter larger than those of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). Formed through each reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> are an escape hole <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and a multiple number of guide holes <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> (3 holes in this preferred embodiment). The main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> pass through the escape hole <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Passing through the guide holes <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, a corresponding number of auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> (3 auxiliary guide rails in this preferred embodiment) are vertically arranged between the upper and the lower installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, inside the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> smoothly slide up and down along the auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Because of the auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, the reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be safely guided in the vertical direction without a transversal motion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In addition, the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> has a main guide hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a screw hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and auxiliary guide holes <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> smoothly passes through the main guide hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>while each auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> smoothly passes through its corresponding auxiliary guide hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is screw-coupled with the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> via the screw hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, a female screw. Furthermore, instead of adopting the large escape hole <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> through which the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> as well as the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> passes, a major guide hole <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> for the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and an escape hole <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>for the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be individually formed on the reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> By the reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, the first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is divided into a plural of sub-bellows portions <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(5 portions in this preferred embodiment) vertically arranged with an approximately equal length. An upper circumference of the sub-bellows portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is airtightly fastened on the bottom surface of a reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> positioned thereabove, and a lower circumference thereof is airtightly fastened on the top surface of another reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> positioned therebelow. However, the upper circumference of the uppermost sub-bellows portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is fastened on a bottom surface of the upper installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and the lower circumference of the lowermost sub-bellows portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is fastened on the top surface of the other upper installation plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided on the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is also divided into a multiple of sub-bellows portions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>each being airtightly fastened to corresponding reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, the lower installation plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and/or another lower installation plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>provided under the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A bellows-receiving portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is recessed at a bottom corner of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, such that the bellows-receiving portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can receive the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> when the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is maximally contracted. That is, the other bottom corner is raised above the bellows-receiving portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, up to a level, e.g., just permitting the lower limit of the moving stroke of the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, such that the inner space of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> decreases by an amount corresponding to the raised portion. As much as the peripheries of the bellows-receiving portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are raised, the bottom wall of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> comes off a floor, thereby providing a space <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> therebetween. An electrical circuit box <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> as well as the exhaust line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the gas supply line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be disposed in the space <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The above-described batch type CVD apparatus is used for a semiconductor device fabricating method in accordance with the preferred embodiment. Hereinafter, there will be explained a film forming process, which is a substrate processing method constituting a part of the semiconductor device fabricating method in accordance with the preferred embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> A plurality of wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo;, on each of which a film will be formed, are accommodated in the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; and conveyed to the batch type CVD apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by means of a conveying system (not shown). As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the conveyed pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is mounted on the loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The cap of the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is subsequently removed by the cap device <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, so that the wafer entrance of the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is opened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> After the wafer entrance of the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is opened by the pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, the tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> disposed inside the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> pick up the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; from the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo;. At this point, the tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> pick up five wafers at one time. Subsequently, the tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> load the five picked up wafers into the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> through the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> thereof. After the five wafers are loaded into the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the gate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> opens the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, the five wafers supported by the tweezers <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are charged into the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by means of the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, the above-explained charging operation is repeated to move the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; from the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; to the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by means of the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. During the charging operation, the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is closed by the shutter <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, such that the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is protected from a high temperature condition of the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; being charged or under charging are protected from the high temperature condition, so that any adverse effect, such as a natural oxidation of the wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo;, resulting from the exposure to the high temperature can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, if a predetermined number of wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; are charged into the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is closed by the gate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. In addition, the repair/inspection opening <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the load lock chamber <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is closed by the gate <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is closed by the shutter <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the above-explained load lock state, the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is exhausted to vacuum through the exhaust line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and then nitrogen (N2) gas is introduced thereinto through the gas supply line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such that oxygen or moisture remaining therein is eliminated. Because the volume of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> has decreased as a result of the uplifted peripheries of the bellows-receiving portion <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, processing time for the vacuum exhaust as well as the purge gas supply is saved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> After oxygen and moisture are removed from the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by the vacuum exhaust and the purge gas supply, the shutter <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> opens the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Subsequently, the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the boat elevator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> elevates the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> supported by the sealing cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, such that the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is loaded into the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. After the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> reaches the upper limit of the moving stroke of the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, peripheries of an upper surface of the sealing cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> supporting the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> airtightly closes the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Consequently, the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the process pipe <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is hermetically sealed. At this point, because oxygen or moisture is previously removed from the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, it is ensured that the oxygen or moisture is prevented from being introduced into the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> while the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is being loaded thereinto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> When the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> moves up to transfer the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> into the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are upwardly contracted and extended, respectively. In accordance with the present invention, because the first and the second communicating hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> respectively provide the atmospheric pressure to the inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the upward contraction of the first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the upward extension of the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be readily accomplished. Further, because the hollow inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are hermitically isolated from the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Therefore, it is ensured that oxygen or moisture contained in the inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is prevented from being introduced into the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> during the above-mentioned contraction and extension, particularly, the contraction of the first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. For the same reason, a vaporized gas produced from a grease of the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the screw hole <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and/or the feed screw <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is also prevented from contaminating the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> during the above-mentioned contraction and extension of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Then, the airtightly closed process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the process tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is exhausted down to a predetermined pressure via the exhaust line <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and then the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is heated up to a predetermined temperature by the heater unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A process gas is subsequently introduced into the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at a predetermined flow rate via the gas supply line <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, thereby forming a desirable film on each wafer &ldquo;W&rdquo; under a preset processing condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> After a predetermined processing time has elapsed, the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the boat elevator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> lowers the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, so that the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> accommodating the processed wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; is unloaded from the process chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is returned into the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As previously explained, the first and the second communicating hole <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> respectively provide the atmospheric pressure to the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Therefore, as the elevator stage <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> moves down, the downward extension of the first bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the down contraction of the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> can be readily accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Further as previously explained, the inner spaces of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are hermitically isolated from that of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Therefore, it is ensured that contaminants in the inner spaces thereof are prevented from being introduced into the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> during the above-mentioned contraction and extension, particularly, the contraction of the second bellows <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> After the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is returned into the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the load lock state of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is released at the same time when the shutter <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> closes the boat loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. That is to say, the gate <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> opens the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in such a way that the processed wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; can be discharged from the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, the pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> opens the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as well as the cap of an empty pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; mounted on the loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Then, the processed wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; discharged by the wafer transfer unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are reloaded into the empty pod &ldquo;P&rdquo;, which is mounted on the loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, via the wafer loading/unloading opening <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> After a predetermined number of processed wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; are reloaded into the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo;, the cap device <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the pod opener <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> restores the cap to the pod &ldquo;P&rdquo;. The pod &ldquo;P&rdquo; is subsequently conveyed from the loading stage <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to a next process stage by the conveying system. The above-explained discharge and reload step are repeated until all the processed wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; in the boat <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are conveyed to the next process stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, the above-explained operations are repeated to apply the batch process for a predetermined number of wafers, e.g., 25, 50, 100, 125, or 150 wafers &ldquo;W&rdquo; by means of the batch type CVD apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As previously explained, the inner space of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are separated from the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> while communicating with the environment of the atmospheric pressure. Therefore, if the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is exhausted to vacuum, each of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may deform from its vertical or horizontal profile because of the pressure difference between the inside and the outside thereof. In the preferred embodiment, however, the horizontal reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> are vertically arranged in the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> along the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> or the auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the deformation of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is surely prevented in spite of the above-mentioned pressure difference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In other words, because the vacuum exhaust of the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> causes the pressure difference between the inside and the outside of each of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, a force is radially acted on inner surfaces of the first or the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In spite of the radial force acted on the inner surfaces thereof, however, the vertical or horizontal profiles of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are prevented from being displaced since each end of the sub-bellows portion <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is fixed to the reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, the upper installation plates <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, or the lower installation plate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and, also, each reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is guided by the main guide rail <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and/or the auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Further, because the plurality of auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> safely guide the reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> during their elevating or descending motion, each reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can smoothly elevate or descend without yawing. Accordingly, it is ensured that each reinforcing sheet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> rarely affects the extension or contraction of the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Further, because the reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and the auxiliary guide rails <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> are disposed inside the first and the second bellows <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, it is ensured that the antechamber <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is protected from contaminants produced by the sliding motion of the reinforcing sheets <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the number of threads of each bellows needs to be increased for a long service life, and a height of the contracted bellows is proportional to the number of the threads thereof. Since the boat reciprocates once for each batch process, the bellows used for the boat elevator extends as well as contracts once for each batch process. If it is assumed that each batch process takes about an hour, the extension/contraction number of each bellows becomes 24 in a day and reaches 42,000 after five years, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Compared with that, in case that 125 wafers are processed during each batch process, though the elevator serving as the wafer transfer system of the batch type CVD apparatus carries 5 wafers at one time, the elevator reciprocates 25 times for each batch process. Therefore, the bellows for the elevator of the wafer transfer system needs 50 times longer service life than that of the boat elevator. To achieve 50 times longer service life, because the height of the maximally contracted bellows is proportional to the number of the threads, the bellows for the elevator of the wafer transfer system needs to have a 1.5 to 2 times larger maximally contracted height than that of the bellows for the boat elevator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In other words, in case that the bellows is used for the boat elevator, the maximally contracted height of the bellows for the boat elevator can be significantly decreased in comparison to that for the elevator of the wafer transfer system while a desirable service life of the bellows for the batch type CVD apparatus is secured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Following advantages can be provided in accordance with the above-explained embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> 1) The first and the second bellows are respectively disposed on and under the elevator stage of the boat elevator installed in the antechamber. The inner spaces of the first and the second bellows individually communicate with the exterior environment of the atmospheric pressure. Therefore, even though pressure varies in the antechamber, because equal pressures are respectively acted on top and bottom of the elevator stage, driving mechanisms including the feed screw or the motor to vertically move the elevator stage of the elevator can be small-sized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> 2) Because the hollow inside of the first and the second bellows individually communicate with the exterior circumstances to automatically sustain the atmospheric pressure therein, the first and the second bellows can independently contract or extend without additional pressure control devices or the like. Therefore, there is no need to install and maintain a complicated pressure control valve mechanism and a control system therefor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> 3) The feed screw or the guide rail of the boat elevator is hermitically isolated from the antechamber by the first and the second bellows. Therefore, it is ensured that oxygen or moisture in the interiors of the first and the second bellows is prevented from being introduced into the antechamber during the contraction or extension of the first and the second bellows. For the same reason, a vaporized gas produced from a grease of the guide rail, the elevator stage, or the feed screw is also prevented from being introduced into the antechamber during the above-mentioned contraction and extension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> 4) Because the plurality of reinforcing sheets are vertically arranged along the main guide rail or the auxiliary guide rails disposed inside the first and the second bellows, the first and the second bellows are prevented from being deformed, even though pressure differs between the inside and the outside of each of the first and the second bellows. Therefore, it is ensured that the inner spaces of the first and the second bellows can communicate with the exterior environment to automatically maintain the atmospheric pressure therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> 5) The plurality of auxiliary guide rails safely guide each reinforcing sheet, such that each reinforcing sheet can be smoothly elevated or lowered without a transversal motion, in accordance as the elevator stage elevates or descends. Therefore, each reinforcing sheet rarely affects the contraction or extension of the first and the second bellows, and it is ensured that the antechamber is protected from possible contaminants that may be produced during the sliding motion of the reinforcing sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> 6) The bellows-receiving portion, accommodating the maximally contracted second bellows therein, is recessed at a bottom corner of the antechamber. That is, the peripheries of the bellows-receiving portion are relatively uplifted such that the inner space of the antechamber decreases by an amount corresponding to the uplifted portions. Therefore, processing time for the vacuum exhaust as well as the purge gas supply can be reduced, such that the throughput of the batch type CVD apparatus, the film forming process, and also the semiconductor fabrication method can be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> 7) Because the boat elevator and the bellows mechanism are disposed at a corner region of the antechamber, a wasted area of the batch type CVD apparatus can be reduced. Further, because the inner space of the antechamber is also reduced, processing time required for the vacuum exhaust and the purge gas supply can be reduced. As a result, the throughput of the batch type CVD apparatus, the film forming process, and also the semiconductor fabricating method can be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment of the present invention, the bellows-receiving portion has been described as being provided at the bottom of the antechamber. The bellows-receiving portion, however, may be alternatively formed at the upper region of the antechamber, or two of them may be provided at the bottom and the upper region thereof, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The bellows is selected for each of the first and the second expendable/contractible structure, each having the inner space, in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention. Instead of adopting the bellows, however, the first or the second extendable/contractible structure may have a bag-like shape made of a thin wall having appropriate strength and flexibility. Further, the first or the second extendable/contractible structure may have a telescope-like shape, where a plurality of tubes are telescopically connected or nested with each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The batch type CVD apparatus described above can be employed in not only to the film forming process but also to an oxidation process or a diffusion process. Though the preferred embodiment has been described with respect to the batch type CVD apparatus, the present invention also can be applied to other types of the substrate processing apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown and described with respect to the preferred embodiments, it will be understood to those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A substrate processing apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a process chamber for processing substrates; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sealed chamber arranged adjacent to the process chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a movable member, disposed inside the sealed chamber, for supporting the substrates; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an extendable/contractible structure including a first extendable/contractible member and a second extendable/contractible member respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, wherein interiors of the first and the second extendable/contractible member communicate with an exterior of the sealed chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving means, disposed in the extendable/contractible structure, for moving the movable member, wherein the driving means is isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the extendable/contractible structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the first extendable/contractible member and the second extendable/contractible member is provided with a reinforcing member for preventing the first and the second extendable/contractible member from being deformed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the movable member is connected to a boat accommodating the substrates, the boat being selectively loaded into and unloaded from the process chamber by the movable member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a bellows-receiving portion is arranged in the sealed chamber, the bellows-receiving portion receiving at least one of the first extendable/contractible member and the second extendable/contractible member, each being maximally contracted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sealed chamber is selectively in a vacuum or in an inert gas condition. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extendable/contractible member is arranged at a corner portion of the sealed chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the extendable/contractible structure vertically extends and contracts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device fabricating method using a substrate processing apparatus including a sealed chamber, a process chamber, and a substrate conveying unit positioned in the sealed chamber, wherein the substrate conveying unit includes a) a movable member for supporting a boat, b) a first and a second extendible/contractible member respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, interiors of the first and the second extendible/contractible member communicating with an exterior circumstance, and c) a driving means, disposed in the first and the second extendible/contractible member, for moving the movable member, the driving means being isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the first and the second extendible/contractible member, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>loading at least one substrate into the boat staying in the sealed chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>loading the boat into the process chamber from the sealed chamber by using the substrate conveying unit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing said at least one substrate loaded in the boat. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A conveying unit used in a sealed chamber, the conveying unit comprising: 
<claim-text>a movable member arranged in the sealed chamber, the movable member supporting an article; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first extendible/contractible structure and a second extendible/contractible structure respectively disposed on both opposing sides of the movable member, wherein interiors of the first and the second extendible/contractible structure individually communicate with an exterior of the sealed chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving means, disposed in the first and the second extendible/contractible structure, for moving the movable member, wherein the driving means is isolated from an inner space of the sealed chamber by the first and the second extendible/contractible structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000476A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
