<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005330A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005330A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005330</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897656</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04L009/32</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>713</class>
<subclass>201000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Portable wireless device and software for printing by reference</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alan</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Berkema</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Granite Bay</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jeff</given-name>
<family-name>Morgan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cupertino</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Pat</given-name>
<family-name>Stoltz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Todd</given-name>
<family-name>Fischer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city></city>
<state></state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A portable wireless device wirelessly communicates a reference to a print device causing the print device to use the reference to obtain a desired set of print content and further causing the print device to print the desired print content. The portable wireless device may also wirelessly communicate the reference to a print service which may respond to the reference by obtaining the desired print content, formatting the desired print content for printing, and communicating the desired print content to the print device for printing. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> A field of the invention is portable wireless devices. An additional field of the invention is printing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Portable wireless devices such as personal digital assistant (PDA) devices and portable wireless handsets, e.g., cell phones, enjoy widespread popularity. In particular, the portable, hand-held characteristics of these devices provide users with access to information and communication outlets in ways that were never before available. To ensure the continued popularity of portable wireless devices, attempts are being made to further expand the flexibility and capabilities of these portable wireless devices and to further enhance the services available to users of portable wireless devices. For example, portable wireless devices capable of accessing the Internet are available and Internet service providers that provide Internet access to portable wireless device users are becoming increasingly more common. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, the limited memory, display and bandwidth capabilities of portable wireless devices restrict the Internet content readily available to a portable wireless device user. Specifically, the Internet content available to the portable wireless device user is typically presented in a bare bones format so that portable wireless device capabilities are conserved. As a result, users will typically favor the richer Internet content available through traditional Internet connections such as workstations and computers unless circumstances such as travel prevent access to such computers. Thus, PDA devices and wireless handsets are typically used either to access highly basic content or to access content when circumstances prevent the user from accessing content from another device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Printing offers the opportunity for a user to view rich content, and is often favored over viewing content through a full web browser or other application on a personal computer or work station. Unfortunately, the portable wireless devices, having limited capabilities, lack convenient printing mechanisms. Moreover, connecting a portable wireless device to a printer via a wired connection tends to defeat the purpose of having a portable wireless device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One answer to these concerns is found in efforts to have the portable wireless devices communicate with peripherals and other devices through wireless communications. The Bluetooth RF communication format is. directed toward expanding the utility of portable wireless devices by providing a short range, typically about ten meters, communication channel for communications between portable wireless devices and other Bluetooth capable devices. However, standing alone, the communication channel offers little to solve the print content dilemma faced by users of portable wireless devices. Specifically, due to memory and bandwidth limitations portable wireless devices are relatively poor portals to push content from or through to a printer, even with the convenience of a Bluetooth or other similar wireless communication capability.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a communication network including a portable wireless device, a print device, an Internet content provider and a print service; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram of the portable wireless device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow chart representing a method for discovering the print device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves supplying a security access code to a print device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves providing a security access code to a print device in response to a security challenge from the print device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves providing a security access code for use by the print device in accessing print content; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves providing a security access code for use by a print service in accessing print content; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves providing a reference to a print service and receiving print content from the print service at a portable wireless device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> is a communication flow diagram illustrating a method for performing a print by reference request that involves providing a reference to a print service and causing the print service to deliver print content to a print device for printing.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A portable wireless device wirelessly communicates with a print device to thereby provide a reference that indicates the location of a desired set of print content. In a typical preferred example, the portable wireless device might obtain a reference to desired print content, e.g., a Universal Resource Locator, while performing an operation such as web browsing over a wireless network. The portable wireless device includes the print content reference in a wireless communication signal to the print device which responds to the signal by accessing the network, retrieving the desired print content and then printing the desired print content. Alternatively, the print device may supply the reference to a print service which may retrieve the desired print content and format the desired print content for printing. The formatted content may then be transmitted directly or indirectly to the print device for printing. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A simple form of the invention is a portable wireless device having a set of wireless communication equipment that allows the portable wireless device to communicate with a set of wireless communication equipment disposed in a print device. The portable wireless device transmits a reference indicating a location of desired print content to the print device causing the print device to use the reference to obtain and print the desired print content. The print device may obtain the print content from the Internet content provider directly or may instead forward the reference to a print service which obtains the print content from the Internet content provider, converts the print content to a print ready format and then transmits the converted print content back to the print device for printing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> I. The Portable Wireless Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having print by reference capabilities may comprise, for example, a personal digital assistant (PDA) or a mobile communication device that includes an Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for providing access to an Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and/or for providing access to an Internet/network based print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, although preferably able to support communication via cellular telephony, may instead communicate with the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via any desired method, e.g., via satellite communication. Further, although the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is described herein as enabling a print by reference feature for obtaining print content from the Internet, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be used to obtain print content from any type of network including, for example, a local area network, a wide area network, and an intranet. Thus, the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may represent any network content provider and the Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may interface with any type of network. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further includes an RF communication interface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> that allows the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to communicate with an RF communication interface <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> disposed in a print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> such as, for example, a printer or a multi-function peripheral including a print function. Although, in a preferred embodiment the RF communication interface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> communicates with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> using a Bluetooth wireless communication protocol and OBEX packet exchange format, the RF communication interface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may instead communicate with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> using any desired wireless protocol and packet format. For example, in a preferred embodiment, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be implemented with a Bluetooth enabled notebook computer having a Bluetooth PC card manufactured by 3Com that operates according to the Bluetooth 1.1 specification and the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be implemented using a Hewlett Packard Deskjet 995c inkjet printer having integrated Bluetooth communication capabilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further includes data processing and memory storage capabilities sufficient to enable a print by reference feature that allows the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to cause the print device to print print content. The data processing and memory storage capabilities may be implemented using, for example, a processor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and a memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for storing software instructions and further using a temporary memory buffer <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A set of software instructions stored in the memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and executed by the processor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> enable the print by reference features described herein. In addition, any number of hardware components may further be used to supplement or even replace the processor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the software instructions and the memory devices <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> provided that the print by reference feature is supported thereby. As will be appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, the processor <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any suitable processor or controller capable of executing software instructions or otherwise controlling the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to enable the print by reference features described herein. Further, the memory devices <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any memory devices capable of storing data. The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further may include a display (not shown) for displaying data and a control panel (not shown) by which a user may interface with the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> II. A Print By Reference Feature </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A. Establishing Communication With A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A set of methods are now described as being illustrative of the variety of ways in which the print by reference feature may be implemented. Further, the methods, which are described with reference to a set of figures, i.e., FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A/B, are described as being implemented using the wireless portable device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in cooperation with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Thus, an understanding of the methods described with respect to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A/B may additionally require reference to the components illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the print by reference feature may cause the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to execute a first print by reference method <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for causing a set of desired web pages or other desired print content to be printed. The first method <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may begin when the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> establishes communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the RF communication interface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. As will be understood by one having ordinary skill in the art, the portable wireless device may perform any number of steps necessary to establish communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in accordance with the communication protocol being used by the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> B. Communicating A Reference To A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> 1. Communicating A Reference </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> After receiving the communication signal, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may respond by, for example, informing the wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that communication has been successfully established (step <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). In response, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may wirelessly communicate a reference that identifies a location of the print content (step <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>). Wirelessly communicating the reference to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may further include any number of additional steps such as, for example, supplementing the reference with additional data to support different levels of print content retrieval and printing. For example, the reference may include only enough information to locate the desired print content, e.g., a content locator or URL. Alternatively, the reference may include a plurality of references, each reference representing separate print content and a separate print document. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> 2. Adding Information To A Reference </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Still further, the reference may be supplemented to include a set of extensions or attribute fields that allow additional information to be supplied with the reference including, for example, a set of security access codes that may be used in response to security challenges to gain access to the print content, a URL that represents the location of a remote print service such as print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to be used in accessing and formatting the print content for printing, and the time/date that the reference was sent to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Other attribute fields may be defined to include, for example, a label providing a descriptive name for the location identified by the reference, a URL that represents a proxy service required to access the print content referred to by the reference, an internet address of the portable wireless device, an alternative reference or address for obtaining the same or substitute print content, and data indicating when print content should be printed beginning on a new sheet. Further, attribute fields may be defined to include information used to restrict access to the reference. For example, a type attribute may be defined to include an encoding type that indicates how the print content at the location identified by the reference is encoded. Further, a cookie attribute may be defined to associate a print by reference print job with previous information concerning reference content or a portable wireless device seeking to access referenced content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As a further example, the reference may include a billing attribute that enables billing for services rendered. Specifically, any or all of the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and/or the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may require payment for usage thus requiring that each reference include information that identifies the user of the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that originated the print by reference request so that the user may be billed for the services used. For example, the user may be provided with an account number upon subscribing to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Further, the account number may be stored in the memory <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> disposed in the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may supply the account number in an extension of the reference each time that a print by reference request is executed. The print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may verify that the account number is valid before rendering service, i.e., before processing a print by reference request for the user each time that a new print by reference request is transmitted. As will be appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, the reference extension may further be used to enable billing for services rendered using any of a variety of other methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> 3. Using A Reference To Obtain Print Content </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> After having received the reference, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may respond by using the reference to download the print content associated with the reference from the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, provided, of course, that the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is able to directly access the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may instead respond to the print request by providing the reference to a network/internet based print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> that retrieves the referenced print content from the Internet service provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, formats the referenced print content for printing and transmits the formatted pages to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for printing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> C. Receiving/Displaying Status Information </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> After communicating the reference, the portable wireless device may communicate a request for status information to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>). The print device may respond by communicating status information such as, whether the print content was successfully retrieved from the Internet and/or whether the print content was successfully printed (step <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>). Alternatively, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may transmit the status message to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> after the print content has been successfully retrieved and before the print content has been printed and therefore only provide status as to the retrieval of the print content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Upon receiving the status information, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may perform any number of tasks including, for example, automatically displaying the message, causing the message to be stored in the memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> disposed in the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and sounding an alarm that alerts the user as to the presence of the message, or simply causing the message to be stored in the memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> disposed in the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that the user may retrieve the message at a convenient time. Alternatively, instead of communicating a request for status information, the wireless device may instead wait for the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to transmit the status information automatically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> III. Obtaining A Reference </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The reference specified in the print by reference request sent to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) may have been obtained by the user from the Internet while using the Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Specifically, while using the Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to surf the Internet, the user may encounter the desired print content and, upon deciding to download the desired data, may cause the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to store a copy of a URL identifying the location of the desired print content into the memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> disposed in the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This may occur, for example, when the user clicks on a hyperlink that causes the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to transmit a reference to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through the Internet interface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In addition, selecting the hyperlink may further cause the wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to invoke the print by reference feature thereby causing the method <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> to be performed using the reference obtained by selecting the hyperlink. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The reference supplied via the hyperlink may include additional data concerning the printing of the associated print content including, for example, the print policy of the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the additional data included by way of the hyperlink may limit the number of copies of the requested print content that may be printed in response to the current print by reference request. Further, the additional data included by way of the hyperlink may include a reference identifying the location of a print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> that is suited for obtaining and formatting the desired print content, and may additionally include information associated with the cost of retrieving the print content and/or the method of billing the user for retrieval. For example, the reference may identify the location of the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> by including a URL or other network address that may be used to locate the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the URL may have been typed by the user directly into the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for storing in the memory <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, or the URL may have been stored in the memory device <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> by the user via a voice recognition/recording feature. Instead, the URL may have been received at the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via, for example, an e-mail message and then stored in the memory <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Regardless of the method by which the URL was obtained or stored, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may obtain the URL from the memory device before performing the step of communicating the URL to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> IV. Methods For Identifying A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> A. Identifying A User Specified Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to which the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> forwards the reference for processing may be determined using any number of methods. For example, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be preconfigured to transmit the packet of data having the print content reference to a specific print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> that is proximally located to the user during the user&apos;s daily routine, i.e., a print device residing in the user&apos;s office where the user spends most of the work day. As will appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be preconfigurable using any number of methods, including for example, a menu driven method wherein the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> displays a print device selection menu that allows the user to select one or more print devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may supply a data input field in which the user may specify a default or preferred print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> B. A Method For Discovering A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in another embodiment, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be configured to perform a method <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> for locating a print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by transmitting a discovery signal according to a conventional local network discovery protocol. Specifically, a user may initiate the network discovery protocol using, for example, a print device discovery command (step <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>) which may cause the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to transmit discovery signals that include an embedded request for information (step <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>). The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may then wait until a response is received from one or more locally disposed print devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, conventional network discovery features allow a user operating a network device to discover other devices attached to the network. Further, the discovery feature is typically defined at least in part by the communication standard or specification associated with the network in use. Thus, the portable wireless device may transmit discovery signals according to the communication protocol for which the portable wireless device is configured. For example, if configured to operate using a Bluetooth communication protocol, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may perform the discovery feature using a Service Discovery Protocol defined in the Bluetooth communication specification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The responsive signals may include, for example, instructions regarding the location of the responding print devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> so that the user may proceed to the nearest print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and cause the desired print content to be printed thereon by initiating a print by reference request (step <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>). The responsive signals may further include information pertaining to the capabilities of the responsive print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. For example, the responsive signals may include information specifying whether the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has color printing capabilities, whether the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is equipped for printing specialized graphics files and further specifying the costs associated with using the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to print a document. The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may display the responsive information or otherwise communicate the information to the user so that the user may determine which of the responding print devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to select. Of course, if no responsive signals are received at the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may again transmit print device discovery signals (step <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>) for any number of times, until a responsive signal is received, or until the user halts the print device discovery method <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The print device discovery feature may be especially useful for the traveling user who frequents airports or other public places that may include, for example, kiosks equipped with print devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for use by airport visitors. Thus, the responding print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may provide the user with an airport terminal name and gate at which the kiosk is located. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As will further be appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may initiate a network discovery protocol in response to any number of user inputs. For example, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may display a menu having a plurality of options wherein one of the available options allows the user to initiate the network discovery protocol. Alternatively, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be equipped with a control switch or button that, when depressed by the user, causes the network discovery protocol to be invoked and when depressed a second time causes the network discovery protocol to be halted. Instead, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be configured to automatically invoke the network discovery protocol every time the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is powered up or every time a print by reference request is initiated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> V. Print By Reference Methods Requiring Security Access Codes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> A. Transmitting A Security Access Code Upon Establishing Communication </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the first method for performing a print by reference request may be modified to allow for the transmission of security information by the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and thereby enable access to an otherwise restricted-access print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or to enable access to secure print content. More particularly, when performing a print by reference request, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may further transmit one or more security access codes that enable access to a print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Thus, a print by reference method <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> involving the transmission of security information required to access the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may begin when the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> establishes communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>) and provides a security access code that allows access to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Upon receiving the access code from the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> verifies that the proper access code has been supplied and, if the proper access code has been received, then responds to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a message that indicates that communication has been successfully established (step <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>). After being informed that communication has been established, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may respond by transmitting a reference that indicates the location of the desired print content (step <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>). Thereafter the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> either accesses the print content directly via the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or instead supplies the reference to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so that the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may retrieve and format the print content as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> After communicating the reference the wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may communicate a request for status information (step <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which may respond by sending the status information (step <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>). The wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may then receive and store the status information or display the status information for viewing by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> B. Transmitting A Security Access Code In Repsonse To A Security Access Challenge </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may instead be configured to withhold the security access code required to control the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> until prompted according to yet another method <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> that begins when the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> establishes communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>). The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> processes the request to establish communication and responds with a security challenge indicating that the wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not authorized to use the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>). In response, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may again attempt to establish communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, this time providing the access code required by the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>). The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> verifies the access code and, if proper, supplies a message to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> indicating that communication has been successfully established (step <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>). Of course, if the access code is improper, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may again indicate that the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not authorized to use the print device (step <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Once communication has been successfully established, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> communicates the reference associated with the desired print content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for processing (step <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>). The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> then uses the reference to download and print the desired print content from the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> supplies the reference to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for retrieval and formatting as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the steps of re-attempting to establish communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>) and communicating the reference (step <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) may be performed in a single step. Specifically, in response to the security challenge, the wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may communicate the reference having the security access code to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may respond to the reference by verifying the security access code and then obtaining and printing the print content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> After the print by reference request has been processed, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may supply a status message to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> indicating whether the print by reference request has been successfully processed (step <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> C. Transmitting A Security Access Code To Gain Access To Print Content Via A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may further supply a security access code to gain access to the print content. Specifically, assuming that the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has successfully established communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, then, in accordance with a set of methods <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, respectively, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may communicate the reference to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (steps <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>). Next, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> forwards the reference to either the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>; see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) or the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>; see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) depending on whether the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is configured to access the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> directly or whether the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is instead configured to access the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. If supplied directly to the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, then the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may attempt to retrieve the desired print content residing at the location represented by the reference. If a security access code is required to access the desired print content, the website at which the desired print content is located may respond to the attempted retrieval of the desired print content with a security challenge thereby requesting that a security access code be supplied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> causes the request for a security access code to be transmitted back to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>) which, in turn, supplies the request to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>). The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may respond to the request by transmitting a reference including the required security access code to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>). The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> then supplies the security access code to the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>) which uses the access code to enable access to the print content. Provided that the security access code is acceptable, the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> forwards the desired content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for formatting and printing therein (step <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>). In addition to printing the desired print content, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may transmit a message to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> indicating that the desired print content has been successfully retrieved and printed (step <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> D. Transmitting A Security Access Code To Gain Access To Print Content Via A Print Device And A Print Service </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> If, instead, the reference is supplied by the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> (step <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>), then the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> uses the reference to attempt to access the desired print content via the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>). As described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may attempt to retrieve the desired print content residing at the location represented by the reference. If a security access code is required to access the desired print content, the website at which the desired print content is located may respond to the attempted retrieval of the desired print content with a security challenge thereby requesting that a security access code be supplied before access to the desired content is granted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> causes the request for a security access code to be transmitted back to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>) which, in turn, supplies the request to print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for routing to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (steps <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>). The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may respond to the request by transmitting a reference including the required security access code (step <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>) to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may then supply the security access code to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>) which may use the security access code to access the desired print content via the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>). Provided that the access code is acceptable, the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> allows the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> access to the desired print content (step <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>). The print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> thereafter formats the print content for printing and then forwards the formatted print content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for printing (step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>). In addition to printing the desired print content, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may transmit a message to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> indicating that the desired print content has been successfully retrieved and printed (step <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Instead of withholding the security access code until prompted, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may instead transmit the relevant security access code with the reference thereby eliminating the need for the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to request that the desired security access code be provided and thus eliminating the need to send the request from the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> back to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Similarly, when a plurality of references, each having a different security access code, are transmitted to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via a single print by reference request, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may similarly be configured to either transmit the security access codes with the references or to withhold each security access code until a request for the access codes, either individually or jointly, is received from the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> VI. Methods For Obtaining Print Content Via A Print Service </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> A. Downloading Print Content From A Print Service To A Print Device Via A Portable Wireless Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>A, in yet another embodiment, instead of sending the print by reference request to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may communicate directly with the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Specifically, according to yet another method <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may communicate the reference to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>) which may respond by retrieving the desired content via the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (steps <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight>). The print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may then format the print content for printing and transmit the formatted print content to a specified print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>A). The identity of the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may have been specified, for example, in the reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Provided that the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has the capability to convert the print content to a print ready format, the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may instead supply the print content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a non-print ready format, in which case, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will be required to perform any format conversions necessary to enable printing of the print content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> B. Downloading Print Content From A Print Service To A Print Device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Referring also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>B, according to still another method <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>B, the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may transmit the print ready print content back to the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>B) which may then cause the print ready print content to be forwarded for printing to a print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of choice using a method similar to the method shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. More particularly, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may establish communication with the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>) and, after communication has been established, may transmit the formatted print content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> accompanied by a print request that causes the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to respond by printing the print content (step <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>). Further, the print content received at the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is preferably communicated to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> using a store and forward operation, e.g., streaming, which may be performed using any of a variety of steps including temporarily storing the data received from the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the memory buffer <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> disposed in the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and then converting the buffered data to a format suitable for transmission via the RF interface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. After printing the print content, the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may transmit a status message indicating that the content has been printed (step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may further receive one or more error messages from one or more of the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may perform any of a variety of desired tasks in response to any of the received error messages. For example, upon receiving an error message indicating that communication was not successfully established, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may make any number of further attempts to establish communication. In addition, upon receiving a security access code error, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may resend the required security access code. Further, in response to an error message indicating that the reference does not exist or cannot be accessed, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may display a message informing the user as to the inaccessible status of the reference. A message may also be displayed by the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> when a status message is received from the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> indicating the content of the status message. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing description, it should be understood that a portable wireless device having a print by reference feature has been shown and described, having many desirable attributes and advantages. In particular, the portable wireless device provides a user with print capabilities. Specifically, the portable wireless device transmits a reference corresponding to a location at which desired network content is located to a print device. The print device, in turn, either accesses a network content provider to retrieve the desired network content or instead forwards the reference to a print service which accesses a network content provider to retrieve the desired network content. After retrieval, the print service formats the network content for printing and then delivers the formatted network content to the print device for printing. Likewise, if retrieved by the print device, the network print content is adapted for printing and then printed by the print device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated by one having ordinary skill in the art, network security devices such as network firewalls typically prevent the reception of print content or any other information from the Internet at a user device unless initiated by the user. In some cases, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may initiate a print by reference request and then act as a conduit to transfer the print content to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In that case, the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may supply or push data to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In either case, data transferred from the Internet content provider <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to either of the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is preferably performed using a data download or data pull operation wherein the data transfer is initiated by either the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This avoids the firewall problem. Of course, if network security is not an issue, a data transfer may occur in any other manner. Likewise, data transferred from the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be pushed or uploaded from the portable wireless device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the print service <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and to the print device <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> While various embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it should be understood that other modifications, substitutions and alternatives are apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art. For example, in addition to having data processing and memory storage capabilities sufficient to enable a print by reference feature, the portable wireless device may further include data processing and memory storage capabilities that enable a variety of other tasks. For example, the portable wireless device may include data processing and memory storage capabilities that allow the portable wireless device to function as a telephone, a personal computer, or to instead function as a personal assistant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Further, although the print by reference feature is described as being implemented through the execution of a set of software instructions, the print by reference feature may instead be implemented using hardware or a combination of hardware and software. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Such modifications, substitutions and alternatives can be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention, which should be determined from the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Various features of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A computer program product comprising a computer readable code stored on a computer readable medium that, when executed, causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>wirelessly communicate a reference to a print device, the reference identifying a location at which a print content is located on a network, wherein the reference causes the print device to retrieve the print content from the network and to print the print content. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the network comprises the Internet, and wherein the print content comprises Internet content, and further wherein the reference comprises a content locator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> . The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the content locator comprises a Universal Resource Locator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the reference further comprises billing data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reference causes the print device to retrieve the print content from the network by causing the print device to supply the reference to a print service adapted to retrieve the print content from the network and further adapted to format the retrieved print content for printing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of claim l, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>establish communication with the print device before wirelessly communicating the reference to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>download the reference from the network; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>convert the reference to a format that is compatible with a communication protocol used by the print device, wherein the computer readable code causes the computer to cause the reference to be downloaded and converted before the computer wirelessly communicates the reference to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to download the reference from the network in response to a user input indicating that a hyperlink associated with the reference has been selected. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>wirelessly communicate a security access code to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the security access code enables usage of the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the security access code enables access to the print content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to wirelessly communicate the security access code in response to a security challenge received from the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>wirelessly communicate a discovery signal to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>receive a responsive signal transmitted by the print device wherein the responsive signal identifies the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the print device has one or more print capabilities and wherein the responsive signal further identifies one or more of the print capabilities of the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the responsive signal further identifies a physical location at which the print device is located. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to add information to the reference before wirelessly communicating the reference to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the information added to the reference comprises a locator, the locator identifying a location of a print service. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the information added to the reference comprises a security access code. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the information added to the reference comprises billing information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the information added to the reference comprises print format data, the print format data instructing the print device to print the reference beginning on a new sheet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the computer readable code further causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>communicate a request for status information to the print device; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>receive status information from the print device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A computer program product comprising a computer readable code stored on a computer readable medium that, when executed, causes the computer to: 
<claim-text>wirelessly communicate a reference to a print service, the reference identifying a location at which a print content is located on a network, wherein the reference causes the print service to retrieve the print content. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of claim <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, wherein the reference comprises data identifying a print device and wherein the reference further causes the print service to transmit the retrieved print content to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The computer program product of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reference further causes the print service to convert the retrieved print content to a print ready format and wherein the reference further causes the print service to transmit the converted print content to a print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A portable wireless device comprising: 
<claim-text>a communication interface adapted to enable wireless communication between the portable wireless device and a print device; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor coupled to the communication interface, the processor being adapted to cause the communication interface to wirelessly communicate a reference to the print device, wherein the reference identifies the location of a print content on a network, and wherein the reference causes the print device to use the reference to retrieve the print content from the network and further causes the print device to print the print content. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the communication interface is adapted to communicate using a Bluetooth communication protocol. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of claim <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, wherein the communication interface comprises a first communication interface, and wherein the portable wireless device further comprises: 
<claim-text>a second communication interface coupled to the processor, the second communication interface being adapted to enable communication between the processor and the network. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second communication interface is adapted to communicate using a protocol associated with cellular telephony. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the processor is further adapted to download the reference from the network via the second communication interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the processor is further adapted to discover the location of the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the processor is further adapted to cause the communication interface to communicate a security access code to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the security access code enables usage of the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the security access code enables access to the print content. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a memory device coupled to the processor, the memory device being adapted to store the reference, wherein the processor is further adapted to obtain the reference from the memory device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a memory device coupled to the processor, the memory device being adapted to store information identifying the print device, wherein the processor is adapted to use the information identifying the print device to cause the communication interface to wirelessly communicate the reference to the print device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A portable wireless device comprising: 
<claim-text>a first communication interface adapted to enable communication between the portable wireless device and a print service; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second communication interface adapted to enable wireless communication between the portable wireless device and a print device; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor coupled to the first communication interface, the processor being adapted to cause the first communication interface to communicate a reference that identifies the location of a print content to the print service, wherein communicating the reference to the print service causes the print service to retrieve the print content from a network and further causes the print service to transmit the print content to the portable wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein communicating the reference to the print service further causes the print service to format the print content for printing before transmitting the print content to the portable wireless device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The portable wireless device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the processor is further coupled to the second communication interface and wherein the processor is further adapted to cause the second communication interface to transmit the print content to the print device for printing.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>8</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030005330A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
