<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002026A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002026A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002026A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002026A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002026A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002026A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002026A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002026A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002026</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178958</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-36699</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010626</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03B001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>355</class>
<subclass>133000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus for monitoring discharge of photoresist</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jang</given-name>
<middle-name>Seok</middle-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Suwon-shi</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ROTH &amp; GOLDMAN, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>523 W. 6TH STREET</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 707</address-2>
<city>LOS ANGELES</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90014</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus is disclosed, in which the photoresist discharge rate is monitored during its discharge by a discharge pump, and based on this monitoring, the discharge pump is controlled, so that a constant photoresist discharge rate is ensured, thereby making it possible to prevent any occurrence of process defects due to the discharge pump. If the photoresist discharge rate is decreased due to the exhaustion of the life expectancy of the chemical filter, a filter replacement necessity is displayed on a display part. The apparatus includes the following elements. That is, a PR (photoresist) discharge rate sensor senses the photoresist discharge rate, the discharge rate being decided by the discharge pump. Further, a PR discharge rate controller monitors the output signals of the PR discharge rate sensor to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump, and judges on a chemical filter replacement necessity upon the arrival of the operating limit in the step motor so as to output filter replacement signals. Thus in the present invention, the cause of the process defects can be detected. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus. Particularly, the present invention relates to a photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus in which the photoresist discharge rate is monitored during its discharge by a discharge pump, and based on this monitoring, the discharge pump is controlled, so that a constant photoresist discharge rate is ensured, thereby making it possible to prevent any occurrence of process defects due to the discharge pump. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> At the photoresist treatment step in the semiconductor device fabricating process, a photoresist is spread on the surface of the treating object such as a wafer to form a photoresist film on it. Then the photoresist film is exposed to a predetermined pattern, and then, a development is carried out by using a certain development fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The spreading of the photoresist is carried out in the following manner. That is, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the photoresist is discharged from a photoresist-containing vessel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by a discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in accordance with pumping signals which are supplied from a spinner control device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Under this condition, the photoresist is discharged after foreign materials are filtered off by a chemical filter <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and when the photoresist is discharged by the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the photoresist passes through a cut-off/suck-back valve <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a nozzle <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to be spread on a wafer <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> When the photoresist is discharged by the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the photoresist is discharged at a constant rate. However, if a facility malfunction occurs, or if the life expectancy of the chemical filter <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has been exhausted to the degree of a filtering failure, then the photoresist cannot be spread to a proper degree, with the result that a wafer defect occurs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention is intended to overcome the above described disadvantage of the conventional technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Therefore it is an object of the present invention to provide a photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus in which the photoresist discharge rate is monitored during its discharge by the discharge pump, and based on this monitoring, the discharge pump is controlled so as to ensure a constant discharge rate of the photoresist. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus in which if the photoresist discharge rate is decreased due to the exhaustion of the life expectancy of the chemical filter, a filter replacement necessity is displayed, thereby making it possible to prevent any occurrence of process defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In achieving the above objects, the photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus used in discharging a photoresist from a photoresist-containing vessel by driving a discharge pump and a step motor according to the present invention includes: a PR (photoresist) discharge rate sensor for sensing the photoresist discharge rate, the discharge rate being decided by the discharge pump; and a PR discharge rate controller for monitoring the output signals of the PR discharge rate sensor to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump, and for judging a chemical filter replacement necessity upon an arrival of an operating limit in the step motor so as to output filter replacement signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The PR discharge rate controller includes: a PR discharge rate calculating part for calculating the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump based on pulses of the PR discharge rate sensor; a PR discharge rate control part for sending the pumping control signals to the discharge pump based on calculated values of the PR discharge rate calculating part to control the step motor so as to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate, and for outputting the filter replacement necessity signals by judging on the filter replacement necessity upon arrival of the operating limit in the step motor; and a display part for displaying the filter replacement necessity signals and other signals from the PR discharge rate control part. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The above objects and other advantages of the present invention will become more apparent by describing in detail the preferred embodiment of the present invention with reference to the attached drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically illustrates the constitution of the general photoresist spreading apparatus; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the overall constitution of the photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates in detail the constitution of the PR discharge rate controller of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Now the preferred embodiment of the present invention will be described in detail referring to the attached drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the overall constitution of the photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus according to the present invention. That is, in the present invention, the following elements are added to the general photoresist spreading apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> That is, there are added: a PR (photoresist) discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for sensing the photoresist discharge rate, the discharge rate being decided by the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>; and a PR discharge rate controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> for monitoring the output signals of the PR discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and for judging a chemical filter replacement necessity upon the arrival of the operating limit in a step motor so as to output chemical filter replacement signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The elements which are common to the conventional apparatus will be assigned with the same reference codes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The PR discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> outputs certain signals in accordance with the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The PR discharge rate controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes: a PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, a PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and a display part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> calculates the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> based on pulses of the PR discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> sends pumping control signals to the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> based on the calculated values of the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to control the step motor so as to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate; and outputs filter replacement necessity signals by judging on the filter replacement necessity upon arrival of the operating limit in the step motor. The display part displays the filter replacement necessity signals and other signals from the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In the present invention constituted as described above, the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> discharges the photoresist from a photoresist-containing vessel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in accordance with the pumping signals which are furnished from a spinner control device (not illustrated). Under this condition, the spinner control device sends a discharge execution signal to the PR discharge rate controller <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, thereby notifying the starting of the discharge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> When the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> discharges the photoresist, the PR discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> outputs pulses in accordance with the photoresist discharge rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The pulses thus outputted from the PR discharge rate sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are inputted into the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> calculates the photoresist discharge rate based on the pulses to input the calculated data into the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> automatically controls the driving of the step motor (which drives the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) based on the data inputted from the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, thereby making the discharge rate constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> That is, the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has a reference driving value for the step motor (which drives the discharge pump <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) in a predetermined state. Thus if the photoresist discharge rate which is inputted from the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is smaller than the reference driving value, then the driving of the step motor is increased, so that the photoresist discharge rate would increase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, if the photoresist discharge rate which is inputted from the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is larger than the reference driving value, then the driving of the step motor is slowed down, so that the photoresist discharge rate would decrease, thereby making it possible to maintain a constant photoresist discharge rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> If the discharge rate is insufficient in spite of the fact that the step motor has been driven to the upper limit of operation, then it is judged that it is the time for replacement of the chemical filter <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> outputs filter replacement signals to the display part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, thereby displaying a message for a filter replacement necessity. Under this condition, the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> sends the filter replacement necessity signals or other error signals also to the spinner control device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Further, the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> outputs the discharge rate display signals to the display part <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> at every unit period based on the photoresist discharge rates which are inputted from the PR discharge rate calculating part <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, thereby displaying the photoresist discharge rate at every unit period. Thus the photoresist discharge rate can be monitored. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Further, if the total photoresist storage amount of the photoresist-containing vessel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is recorded in the PR discharge rate control part <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, then the remaining amount of the photoresist in the photoresist-containing vessel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be known at every moment, because the already discharged amount of the photoresist can be calculated at any moment (the rate is the amount per unit time). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the above, the present invention was described based on the specific preferred embodiment and the attached drawings, but it should be apparent to those ordinarily skilled in the art that various changes and modifications can be added without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention, which will be defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention as described above, the following effects can be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> First, the discharge rate of the photoresist can be monitored, and therefore, based on the monitored data, a constant photoresist discharge rate can be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Second, by utilizing the reference driving value and the operation limit of the step motor, there can be judged on the chemical filter replacement necessity. This replacement necessity is displayed on the display part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Third, the monitoring for the discharge of the photoresist is possible, and therefore, the causes of the process defects can be detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Fourth, the photoresist discharge rate is known, that is, the discharged amount of the photoresist per unit time is known, and therefore, the remaining amount of the photoresist in the containing vessel can be known, as well as the remaining discharge time. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus used in discharging a photoresist from a photoresist-containing vessel by driving a discharge pump and a step motor, comprising: 
<claim-text>a PR (photoresist) discharge rate sensor for sensing the photoresist discharge rate, the discharge rate being decided by the discharge pump; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a PR discharge rate controller for monitoring output signals of the PR discharge rate sensor to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump, and for judging a chemical filter replacement necessity upon an arrival of an operating limit in the step motor so as to output filter replacement signals. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the PR discharge rate sensor outputs certain pulses in accordance with the photoresist discharge rate during pumping of the photoresist by the discharge pump. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The photoresist discharge monitoring apparatus as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the PR discharge rate controller comprises: 
<claim-text>a PR discharge rate calculating part for calculating the photoresist discharge rate of the discharge pump based on pulses of the PR discharge rate sensor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a PR discharge rate control part for sending pumping control signals to the discharge pump based on calculated values of the PR discharge rate calculating part to control the step motor so as to automatically control the photoresist discharge rate, and for outputting filter replacement necessity signals by judging on a filter replacement necessity upon arrival of an operating limit in the step motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a display part for displaying the filter replacement necessity signals and other signals from the PR discharge rate control part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002026A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002026A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002026A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002026A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
