<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002408A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002408A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002408</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10230078</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020829</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>10-6081</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19980114</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B007/0045</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>369</class>
<subclass>047280</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>369</class>
<subclass>047300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Information recording apparatus for writable recording media</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10230078</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020829</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09227532</doc-number>
<document-date>19990108</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kazuo</given-name>
<family-name>Kuroda</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokorozawa-City</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Pioneer Electronic Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MORGAN LEWIS &amp; BOCKIUS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1111 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An information recording apparatus capable of smoothly reproducing in succession written data and data additionally written subsequent to the written data on a recording medium without disturbing a synchronization operation for read data during reproduction of information. The apparatus comprises a writing clock generating circuit for generating a writing clock signal for writing the new data into a recording medium while establishing synchronization with new data; a clock reproducing circuit for reading the written data from the recording medium, and reproducing a synchronization clock signal of the written data to generate a reproduced clock signal; and a phase adjusting circuit for synchronizing the phase of the writing clock signal with the phase of the reproduced clock signal. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to an information recording apparatus, and more particularly to an information recording apparatus for recording information on an additionally writable recording medium such as a write once (WO) type optical disc on which information can be written only once at the same location or on a rewritable (RW) optical disc on which information can be rewritten any number of times at the same location. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In an information recording apparatus of the type mentioned above, when information data is written on an additionally writable recording medium, a writing clock signal is generated for writing the information data on the disc while establishing synchronization with the information data to be written. Stated another way, the information data is generally written on the disc in synchronism with the generated writing clock signal having a stable predetermined frequency (for example, so-called bit synchronization is established). The writing clock signal is typically generated from a reference clock generator, for example, a quartz oscillator or the like which can provide an oscillation output by itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> However, when a write-once or additional write operation is performed on a disc, which has information data partially written thereon, for writing new information data subsequent to the written information data, a writing clock signal used for the written information data may differ in phase from a writing clock signal used for the new information data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In this event, in an operation for reading the resulting disc after recording the new information data to sequentially reproduce the old and new information data, it is often difficult to reproduce clock signals for synchronizing the data read from the disc near the junction of the old and new information data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Particularly, when information data is subsequently written on a disc on which information data has been written by an information recording apparatus using a different information recording apparatus, different writing clock signals are generated at respective recording times from different clock sources, even if these information recording apparatus belong to the same type, whereby preceding information data and subsequent information data are inevitably written with different writing clock signals having different frequencies as well as different phases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Reproduction of a clock signal for synchronizing read data involves the use of a PLL (Phase Locked Loop) circuit which is supplied with the read data as an input. A disc having recorded thereon preceding and subsequent information data with writing clock signals largely different in phase and frequency from each other will significantly disturb the synchronization operation of the PLL circuit near the junction of the preceding data and the subsequent data. As a result, a decoder for decoding read data based on the clock signal for synchronizing read data may erroneously detect a variety of data in the read data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Also, data is written on a disc in a format which includes a particular synchronization signal for each data block for carrying a predetermined amount of information in addition to the bit synchronization as mentioned above, such that an associated data block is synchronized during reproduction. Even such a particular synchronization signal is located in data based on the writing clock signal. Therefore, the writing clock signals largely different in phase and frequency from each other, generated as mentioned above, will cause the interval between a particular synchronization signal located at the end of the preceding information data and a particular synchronization signal located at the beginning of the subsequent information data to be largely different from intervals before and after that interval, possibly resulting in the inability of detecting the particular synchronization signal and erroneous detection during reproduction. Particularly, this would be a grave problem for a player having poor performance of detecting such a particular synchronization signal. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECT AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Thus, the present invention has been made in view of the problem mentioned above, and its object is to provide an information recording apparatus which is capable of employing a recording form for a recording medium which permits written data and additional data written subsequent thereto to be smoothly reproduced in sequence without disturbing a synchronization operation for read data upon reproduction of information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> To achieve the above object, the present invention provides an information recording apparatus capable of additionally recording new data subsequent to previously written data on a recording medium, which comprises writing clock generating means for generating a writing clock signal for writing the new data into the recording medium while establishing synchronization with the new data, clock reproducing means for reading the written data from the recording medium, and reproducing a synchronization clock signal of the written data to generate a reproduced clock signal, and phase adjusting means for synchronizing the phase of the writing clock signal to the phase of the reproduced clock signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the information recording apparatus mentioned above, the written data is data including a particular synchronization signal for every predetermined data block. The information recording apparatus may be configured to further comprise synchronization signal detecting means for detecting the particular synchronization signal from the written data, counting means responsive to detection timing of the particular synchronization signal by the synchronization signal detecting means to start a counting operation based on the reproduced clock signal, and control means for determining a writing start time at which the new data is written into the recording medium, based on a count value presented by the counting means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the information recording apparatus mentioned above, the phase adjusting means may synchronize the phase of the writing clock to the phase of a reproduced clock signal derived from the written data in a predetermined period before an additional recording start position for the new data on the recording medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Further, in the information recording apparatus mentioned above, the phase adjusting means, after synchronizing the phase of the writing clock signal to the phase of the reproduced clock signal, may be configured to return the writing clock signal to a frequency and a phase inherent to the writing clock generating means with a predetermined time constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention also provides an information recording apparatus capable of additionally recording new data subsequent to previously written data on a recording medium, which comprises comparing means for comparing, in terms of value, an end data portion corresponding to a predetermined amount of data located at the end of the written data with a top data portion corresponding to the predetermined amount of data located at the beginning of the new data, and control means for changing values in the new data when the comparing means determines that values in the end data portion are coincident with values in the top data portion.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the structure of a data sector of a DVD-R for carrying an original recording information; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> are diagrams showing the structure of an ECC block which is built using the data sector of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are diagrams showing a physical format for data recorded on a DVD-R; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view illustrating the structure of a recording layer of the DVD-R; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram representing a correspondence relationship between grove tracks, data of a synch frame sequence written thereon, and pre-pits formed in a land track in a DVD-R; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a general configuration of an information recording apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J are time charts showing operational waveforms and operational forms at respective portions in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the former half of a procedure for additional recording processing executed by a CPU in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the latter half of the procedure for the additional recording processing executed by the CPU in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an example of a specific configuration of an S/H timing generating circuit in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a general configuration of an information recording apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>I are time charts showing operational waveforms and operational forms at respective portions in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the former half of a procedure for additional recording processing executed by a CPU in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating the latter half of the procedure for the additional recording processing executed by the CPU in the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a general configuration of an information recording apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>E are time charts showing characteristic operational forms provided by the information recording apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention will hereinafter be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> First, a general physical format for writing information into a DVD-R (Digital Video Disc-Recordable), as an additionally recordable recording medium, will be described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Error correction processing performed for the DVD-R is based on an ECC (Error Correction code) block as its error unit. Such an ECC block is formed on he basis of a data sector shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Original information recorded on the DVD-R is constituted by a physical structure including a plurality of data sectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The data sector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises, from its beginning, ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> indicative of the starting position of the data sector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>; an ID information error correction code (IEC) <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for correcting possible errors in the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>; spare data <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>; data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for carrying main information to be essentially recorded on an associated disc, such as video, audio or computer data and so on; and an error detection code (EDC) <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for detecting possible errors in the data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. These fields are arranged in this order to form block data. In the DVD-R, a plurality of the data sectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are successively arranged to constitute original information which should be recorded thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The data sector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as mentioned is used to build up the ECC block in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A, 2B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> First, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, one data sector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is divided into 172-byte data areas, and the divided data areas (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;data block <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&rdquo;) are aligned in the vertical direction. This result in 12 rows of data blocks <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> aligned in the vertical direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Next, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B, a</cross-reference> 10-byte ECC IN code (PI (Parity In) code) <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is assigned to each of the data blocks <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The ECC IN code <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is added to the end of each of the data blocks <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to constitute a correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. At this stage, 12 rows of correction blocks <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> including the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are aligned in the vertical direction. Then, the addition of the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> as mentioned is repeated for 16 data sectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to provide 192 rows of correction blocks <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Further, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, the block data formed by 192 rows of vertically aligned correction blocks <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as mentioned above is then vertically divided every one byte, and 16 ECC OUT codes (PO (Parity Out) code) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are added to the divided data. The ECC OUT code <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is also added to the portion of ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> within the correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Consequently, one ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> including 16 data sectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed. As is understood from the foregoing description, the total amount of information carried by one ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is calculated by:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>(172&plus;10) bytes&times;(192&plus;16) rows&equals;37856 bytes</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Within this amount of information, the information data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> occupies:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>2048 bytes&times;16&equals;32768 bytes</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, each one-byte data constituting the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is designated by a format &ldquo;D&num;.*&rdquo;. For example, &ldquo;D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&rdquo; indicates one-byte data positioned in the first row and the 0<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>column, and &ldquo;D<highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>&rdquo; indicates one-byte data positioned in the 190<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>row and the 170<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>column. Therefore, the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are positioned in the 172<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>to 181<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>columns, while the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are positioned in the 192<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>to 207<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>rows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Further, since one correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is successively recorded on a DVD-R, the entire block may possibly be damaged by errors. However, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is organized to include both the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that horizontally aligned data in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> can be corrected by the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, while vertically aligned data in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> can be corrected by the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In this way, double error correction can be performed in the horizontal and vertical directions in the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, thereby providing more effective error correction as compared with error correction processing used in conventional CD (Compact Disk) or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Describing in greater detail with this respect, for example, even if one correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (including a total of <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> bytes including one line portion of the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> as mentioned above and successively recorded on a DVD-R) is entirely destructed by external scratches or the like on a DVD-R, this is merely data destruction of only one byte for one column of ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, when viewed from the vertical direction. Therefore, even if one correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is entirely destructed, it can be correctly reproduced by performing the error correction using the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> corresponding to the respective columns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> A specific recording sequence for recording the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as mentioned on a DVD-R is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D. It should be noted that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D, one byte data designated by &ldquo;D&num;. *&rdquo; is the same as that designated in the same manner in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> First, the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is aligned in a horizontal direction in a line for each correction block <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, and interleaved. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, the ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is transformed into 16 recording sectors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by the interleaving. In this transformation, one recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes 2366 bytes (37856 bytes/16) of information in which the data sectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> or the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are mixed. However, each recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) in the data sector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> positioned at the top thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is divided into 91-byte data <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and a header H is added to each of the 91-byte data <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, the recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the headers added thereto is 8-16 modulated, and transformed into sync frames <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for every data <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and a header associated therewith, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference>. After the transformation, each sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is composed of a header H&prime; and data <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Also, one sync frame <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> has the amount of information calculated by:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>91 bytes&times;8&times;(16/8)&equals;1456 channel bits (note that the amount of information is 1488 channel bits when including synch information)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> This synch frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is written into a DVD-R in a successive form. In this event, one recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes 26 sync frames <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> When information has been recorded on a DVD-R in accordance with the physical format described above, the original ECC block can be recovered by performing 8-16 demodulation and deinterleaving on the information upon reproduction (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>), and the information can be correctly reproduced after the effective error correction is conducted thereon as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As a result, information is recorded on a DVD-R in the form of sync frame sequence as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>D, wherein the information is recorded on previously defined tracks on the DVD-R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the structure of a recording layer of a DVD-R including tracks which serve as positions at which the information as mentioned is recorded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Referring specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed with groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on which a pigment film <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is formed and information in the sync frame sequence can be written; and land tracks <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> positioned adjacent to the groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for guiding a laser beam B to the associated groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as reading light or writing (recording) light. The groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are formed in concave, viewed from the source of the laser beam B, while the land tracks <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are formed in convex viewed from the source so as to carry a gold deposited surface <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> as a light reflecting surface for reflecting off the beam B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Each of the groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is undulated in a direction parallel to the flat surface of the disc at a predetermined frequency (for example, a frequency corresponding to a proper rotating speed of the disc). In other words, so-called wobbling is applied to the groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. With the use of such wobbling, the rotation of the disc can be controlled when information is read therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Each of the land tracks <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is formed with pre-pits <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for carrying recording control information such as address information indicative of a recording position on the DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, timing control information for controlling recording timing, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The wobbling and pre-pits <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> as well as the groove tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the land tracks <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are pre-formed when the DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is fabricated. Additionally, the wobbling and the pre-pits <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> function as preformed recording information which has previously been formed (recorded) before information is written for the first time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> When information is recorded on the DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having the structure as described above, the DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is irradiated with a light beam B such that the center of the light beam B matches the center of a groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to form pits corresponding to the sync frame sequence on the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In this event, a spot SP of the light beam B is sized such that a portion of the spot SP is also irradiated to the land track <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. A portion of reflected light of the light spot SP irradiated to the land track <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is used to detect the pre-pits <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> through a push-pull method, thus acquiring preformed recording information inherent to the disc indicated by the pre-pits. The reflected light of the light spot SP irradiated to the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is further used to detect a wobble signal in accordance with the wobbling of the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to control the DVD-R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for rotation based on the detected wobble signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, data in a sync frame sequence to be written into the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and pre-pits (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;LPP&rdquo; (Land Pre Pit)) <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> formed in the land track <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are placed in a correspondence relationship as represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, data in the sync frame sequence, which is information to be recorded, is recorded on the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> along a center line thereof. This recording is controlled so as to record one sync frame for every eight wobbling periods exhibited by the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A wobbling frequency is constantly set at 140 kHz (value converted from the proper reading rate) over all sync frames. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The sync frame has the header H&prime; positioned at the top thereof, as described in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference>. The header H&prime; in turn is assigned a synchronization signal SY at the leading end. The synchronization signal SY is provided for establishing synchronization of the sync frame, and has identical waveform symbols over a length of 14T. Here, T corresponds to a bit interval in the data sequence before the 8-16 modulation, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference>. A sync frame has a length of 1488T. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The LPPs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, on the other hand, are formed at positions corresponding to upward arrows in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Specifically, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the LPPs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may be formed in land tracks <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> adjacent to three positions corresponding to peeks or valleys of the waves exhibited by the wobbling of the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, counted from the top of the sync frame. However, in one recording sector (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference>), the LPPs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are formed only in even-numbered sync frames (EVEN frames) or in odd-numbered sync frames (ODD frames). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the case where LPPs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are formed only in EVEN frames, so that they are not formed at positions corresponding to upward dotted arrows. The LPP <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> positioned closest to the top of a sync frame is provided for synchronization, so that it is formed without fail corresponding to a determined even- or odd-numbered frame. The LPP <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for synchronization carries address information on a recording surface of the DVD-R, and the address information is identified in units of recording sectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As can be seen also from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the LPPs <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are formed at positions substantially corresponding to the position at which the synchronization signal SY is recorded within sync frame data written into the groove track <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The information recording apparatus according to this embodiment is capable of handing a DVD-R which is formed with the previously recorded information in the manner mentioned above and on which data in sync frame sequences is written. Details on the information recording apparatus will be described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a general configuration of the information recording apparatus according to this embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Referring specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> DVD-R <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (hereinafter simply referred to the &ldquo;disc&rdquo;), while rotated by a spindle motor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, is irradiated with a laser beam from a pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> serving as an optical head capable of outputting laser light both at a reading light level and at a writing light level. The laser light incident on the disc reaches a reflecting surface (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of the disc, and reflects off the reflecting surface as reflected light in accordance with recorded information, which is then guided to the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, which incorporates an opto-electrical transducing circuit including a light receiving element, receives the reflected light from the disc, and opto-electrically transduces the received light in accordance with its received light level and condition. The opto-electrically transduced output is supplied to a reproducing amplifier <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> as a read signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The reproducing amplifier <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> amplifies the read signal supplied thereto, and supplies the amplified read signal to a wobble detecting circuit <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and an LPP (pre-pit) detecting circuit <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> through a bandpass filter (BPF) <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The wobble detecting circuit <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> detects or extracts the wobble signal from the read signal, and supplies it to one input of a cross-talk removing circuit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The LPP detecting circuit <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> detects the pre-pits <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> from the read signal, and generates a pre-pit signal in accordance with the detection result. The pre-pit signal is supplied to the other input of the cross-talk removing circuit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> as well as to a pre-pit (LPP) decoder <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The cross-talk removing circuit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> has a function of removing a jitter component included in the wobble signal due to cross-talk based on the pre-pit signal, and supplies the jitter free wobble signal to a PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> for generating a wobble synchronization clock. The resulting wobble signal will have an accuracy depending upon a detection accuracy for the pre-pit signal based on residual errors which cannot be completely eliminated on the time base by a time base servo such as a spindle servo or the like. In other words, the resulting wobble signal includes an error (approximately &plusmn;5T) of the pre-pit signal due to the residual errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> comprises a phase comparator <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> for comparing the cross-talk removed wobble signal received at the one input with another input signal received at the other input in terms of phase to output an error signal corresponding to a difference in phase between the two signals; a low pass filter (LPF) <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> for passing therethrough a low frequency component of the error signal; a VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> for changing an oscillating frequency in response to the output of the filter <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; and a frequency divider <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> for dividing an oscillation output clock signal of the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> to generate a signal at a frequency equivalent to that of the wobble signal and for supplying the generated clock signal to the other input of the phase comparator <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The output clock signal of the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> serves as the basis of a writing clock, and is supplied to a phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as an original writing clock signal WCKO which is synchronized in phase with the output of the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, i.e., the wobble signal. The PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> corresponds to a writing clock generating means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The amplified read signal from the reproduction amplifier <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is also supplied to a main data decoder <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, a bit clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, and a sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The main data decoder <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> performs data processing such as 8-16 demodulation and deinterleaving on the read signal, and also performs the processing for recovering data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> while conducting the error correction processing from ECC blocks (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D), and transfers recovered data to a CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> sends the recovered data transferred thereto to a reproduced data processing system, not shown, for providing an actual audio output, video output, or data output. The LPP decoder <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, on the other hand, detects address information indicative of a recording position on the recording surface of the disc, and sync frame synchronization information from the detected pre-pit signal, and sends them to the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> utilizes addresses based on this pre-pit signal and the sync frame synchronization information for performing a variety of processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, which reproduces a bit synchronization clock (having a period T) for data carried on the read signal, supplies its output to the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as a reproduced clock RCK. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> detects the synchronization signal SY (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) as a particular synchronization signal included in the read signal. The sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> generates, for example, a pulsative sync detecting signal SY&prime; in response to detection of the synchronization signal SY. The sync detecting signal is supplied to the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> comprises a phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> capable of shifting the phase of the original writing clock signal WCKO which is synchronized in phase with the wobble signal from the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>; a phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> for comparing an output signal of the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> received at one input thereof with the reproduced clock signal RCK from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> received at the other input thereof to output an error signal corresponding to a difference in phase between the two signals; a low pass filter (LPF) <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> for passing therethrough a low frequency component of the error signal; a sample and hold (S/H) circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> for sampling and holding the value of the output signal from the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> in response to a sample/hold timing signal; an adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> for adding the value of an output signal from the sample and hold circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and an offset value; an offset value generating circuit <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> for supplying the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> with a predetermined offset value; a loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> for receiving an addition output of the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> at one input and a reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> corresponding to a phase shift amount in a normal state of the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> as the other input to selectively output one of these two inputs to the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> in accordance with a loop control signal from the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>; and an S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> for generating the sample/hold (S/H) timing signal to the S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> based on the output reproduced clock signal of the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, the output sync detecting signal of the sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>, and a control signal from the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> serves as a phase adjusting means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, when the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> generates a loop control signal to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to select the output of the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> (for closing the loop), a phase error between a phase shifted writing clock signal WCK and the reproduced clock signal RCK is produced from the phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, and sampled values of the phase error are produced by the sample and hold circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Then, the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> supplies the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> with a feedback signal in accordance with the addition value of the sample value and the offset value through the switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>. Here, the feedback signal supplied to the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> sets in the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> a phase shift amount corresponding to the phase error, more specifically, the amount of phase shift (a value indicating to which extent the phase should be shifted) that converges the addition value of the phase error value and the offset value to zero. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Thus, with a feedback control performed by a loop formed of the foregoing phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> and offset value generating circuit <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, and loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, the phase of the writing clock signal WCK is gradually brought, from the time the loop is closed, to match a phase which is the sum of the phase of the reproduced clock signal RCK from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and the offset value. The writing clock signal WCK having the phase matched in this way is derived from the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, and supplied to an encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> forming part of an information recording system as a bit clock for code conversion. The offset employed herein is preferably a value that corresponds to a time period from the irradiation of a writing beam onto the disc to the actual formation of recording marks. In this way, the data can be written in conformity to the recording characteristics of the disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> On the other had, when the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> generates a loop control signal to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to select the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (for opening the loop), a phase shift amount corresponding to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is set in the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, so that the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> shifts the phase of the original writing clock signal WCKO by the set phase shift amount to generate the writing clock signal WCK. Therefore, when the loop is open, the writing signal WCK is generated with its phase adjusted as determined by the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> without relying on the reproduced clock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Details on the S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> will be described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> performs final stage encoding for data to be written into the disc, transferred from the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Here, a code conversion is performed for executing the 8-16 modulation as referred to the aforementioned <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D. The CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> receives an original signal of data to be written from a writing data supply system, not shown, and performs data processing other than the 8-16modulation processing on the original signal. More specifically, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> adds the aforementioned ECC IN codes <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the ECC OUT codes <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the original signal to form ECC blocks <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and interleaves the ECC blocks <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to generate data to be transferred to the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. Such transfer of the data involves the use of a built-in memory <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m. </italic></highlight>The data to be transferred is once stored in the memory <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>m, </italic></highlight>and sequentially read at predetermined timing determined by the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The data finally encoded by the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> is sent to a power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> generates a control signal for specifying the laser power in accordance with the encoded data sent thereto from the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> in a writing mode, and a laser driving circuit <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> generates a driving signal at a level corresponding to an actual source laser of the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in response to the control signal. In this way, the intensity of the recording (writing) laser light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the disc is varied corresponding to the encoded data. In a reading mode, on the other hand, the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> does not respond to the encoded data sent thereto from the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, but generates a control signal for specifying low level and substantially constant laser power for reading. Then, the laser driving circuit <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> generates a driving signal at a level corresponding to the actual source laser of the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in response to the control signal. In this way, the disc is read with the reading laser light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> at a constant low level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The output wobble signal from the wobble detecting circuit <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is also used for controlling the rotation of the disc, as previously mentioned. Specifically, the wobble signal is supplied to one input of a phase comparator <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the other input of which receives a reference clock signal supplied from a local oscillator, not shown. The phase comparator <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> produces a frequency error and a phase error between the two inputs, and supplies a spindle control signal in accordance with these errors to a driver circuit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which in turn generates a driving signal for a motor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in accordance with the spindle control signal. In this way, the rotation of the motor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is controlled such that the frequency of the wobble signal detected from the read signal is coincident with the frequency of the reference clock signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Next, the operation of the information recording apparatus according to this embodiment will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J are time charts showing operational waveforms and operational forms at respective portions of the information recording apparatus illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> which is in an additional recording mode where data (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;new data&rdquo;) is additionally written subsequent to a sequence of written data (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;old data&rdquo;) which has previously been written into a disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, when the old data has been written, dummy data (hereinafter referred to as the &ldquo;old dummy data&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> corresponding to an entire data portion of a first sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>F and a 86-byte portion of data in a second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S in the top recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>T of an ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>T, which should be located next to a final ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>E of the old data, is recorded subsequent to the old data together with sync information SY and ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> When an additional recording start instruction is issued from an instructing means, not shown, for the disc on which the old data has been written in the manner as mentioned, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> executes additional recording processing as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Specifically, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> first starts a reading mode in response to the additional recording start instruction (step S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). In this processing, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> controls the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> such that the intensity of the light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the disc <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is at such a relatively low constant reading light level that does not cause a writing action on the recording surface of the disc <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, without responding to input data from the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Next, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> searches for an address N corresponding to ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in order to retrieve the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> on the top side of a recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>E in which last one of the old data is recorded (step S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). This processing is executed on the basis of an output signal of the decoder <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> It is assumed herein that the address indicated by the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> located on the top side of the final recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>E in the final ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>E within the old data is the address N, and the address indicated by the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> located at the beginning of the recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>T, in which the old dummy data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is recorded subsequent thereto, is the address (N&plus;1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> When the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address N is detected (see time t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J), the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> starts reading data recorded in the recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>E subsequent to the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address N and data in the recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>T subsequent thereto (step S<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Then, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> determines based on a modulated output of read data, i.e., an output signal of the decoder <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> whether or not the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address (N&plus;1) has been detected (step S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). If the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address (N&plus;1) has not been detected at step S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> continues to read data until it is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> When the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address (N&plus;1) has been detect at step S<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> (see time t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J), the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> searches for a second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S in the recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>T corresponding to the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address (N&plus;1), and proceeds to make a search based on acquired read data (step S<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). More specifically, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> receives from the sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> a detection signal SY&prime; for the synchronization signal SY at the beginning of the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S after the detection of the ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding to the address (N&plus;1), and detects the arrival of the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S with the receiving timing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> When the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S is thus detected (see time t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J), the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> issues a permission instructing signal to the S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> for permitting the same to supply the S/H timing signal to the S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). The CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> also starts counting the reproduced clock from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in response to the detection of the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S (step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is configure, for example, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Referring specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> comprises an AND circuit <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>G which receives the permission instructing signal and a sync detecting signal SY&prime; from the sync detecting circuit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> as inputs; an SR flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which receives an output signal of the AND circuit <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>G as a set input; a counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C which receives a Q output signal of the SR flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as an inverting reset input and an enable input, and the reproduced clock from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> as a trigger input; a first comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for determining whether a count value of the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C matches a predetermined first count value; a second comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for determining whether the count value of the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C matches a predetermine second count value to supply its matching determination output to a reset input of the flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; and an SR flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which receives a matching determination output of the first comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as a set input and the matching determination output of the second comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as a reset input. The SR flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> generates an S/H timing signal from a Q output to the S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing configuration, the AND circuit <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>G generates a high-level signal when the permission instructing signal and the sync detecting signal SY&prime; both become significant, and the flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is set in response to the high-level signal. This leads to the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C released from a reset state to enter a countable state for counting the reproduced clock. Thus, the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C starts its counting operation in response to the permission instructing signal and the sync detecting signal SY&prime; both becoming significant. The comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> detects that a count output of the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C has reached the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and brings the flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in a set state. As the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C subsequently goes counting, the comparator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>CM<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> detects that the count output has reached the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and brings the flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in a reset state. In this way, the flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> raises the S/H timing signal at the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and falls the same at the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Thus, the SR flip-flop <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>F<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> generates from the Q output the S/H timing signal which has the waveform as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7F</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7D, 7E</cross-reference>, the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is chosen to be a value corresponding to, for example, 40 bytes of the old dummy data in the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S, while the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is chosen to be a value corresponding to 86 bytes of the old dummy data in the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S, and the difference between the two count values is set to 46 bytes corresponding to substantially one half of one sync frame. Stated another way, the timing at which the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C reaches the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> corresponds to the time at which 40 bytes of the old dummy data in the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S have been read, and the timing at which the counter <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>C reaches the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> corresponds to the time at which 86 bytes of the old dummy data in the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S have been read, so that a period in which the S/H timing signal maintains the high level corresponds to 46 bytes of the old dummy data. It should be noted however that the first and second count values N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the difference therebetween are not limited to the values mentioned above, but may be changed to any appropriate different values. As an embodiment which can change these values, memories <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>V<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be used for storing these predetermined count values in such a manner that they can be changed as appropriate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> also functions as a counting means and starts counting the reproduced clock from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in response to the detection of the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S, and determines whether or not the count value from the start of the count has reached the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>). If the count value has reached the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> raises the loop control signal as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>E, and forces the switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to close the servo loop of the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). This loop closing timing corresponds to the timing of a rising edge of the S/H timing signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> continues its counting operation, and determines whether or not the count value has reached the second value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (step S<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>). If determining that the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> has counted up to the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (see time t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J), the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> functions as a control means and starts a writing mode (step S<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>). In this processing, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> controls the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in accordance with input data from the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> to enter a record mode in which the intensity of the light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the disc <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is changed between a writing light level which causes a writing action on the recording surface of the disc and a reading light level which does not cause such action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> In this way, data at and subsequent to the 87<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>bytes in the second sync frame <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>S, as indicated by solid lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>H, within the output data of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> are fetched into the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and recorded on the disc <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The output data of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> indicated by dotted lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7H</cross-reference> indicate that they are not reflected to the output of the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> even though they have been transferred to the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, since the reading mode has been set. It should be noted that the light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is continuously set at reproducing power even when no data is written into the disc because reflected light for tracking servo control is required to track an information recording track (groove track) on the disc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Consequently, after the writing of new data has been started, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> determines whether or not the new data to be essentially transferred to the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> have been terminated (step S<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>). If not terminated, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> continues to still record the new data. Conversely, if terminated, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> stores dummy data <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> corresponding to all data in a first sync frame and 86 bytes of data in a second sync frame in the top recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the ECC block <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to be located next to the last ECC block <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the just recorded data, subsequent to that data together with sync information SY and ID information <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> corresponding thereto (step S<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), as the final processing required at the end of the recording. This processing is similar to the processing performed when the aforementioned old data has been recorded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> When the writing operations associated with all the new data including the additional recording operation at the end of recording have been completed at step S<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> controls the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> such that the intensity of the light irradiated from the pickup <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the disc <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is changed to a constant reading light level, without responding to input data from the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, to switch to the reading mode (step S<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>). The processing for additionally recording the new data is terminated in this way. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> As described above, the loop control signal is raised and the S/H timing signal is generated immediately before new data is written. The S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> operates to perform sampling, i.e., to fetch an error signal from the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and transmits the error signal to the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> while the S/H timing signal is at high level. In this event, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> raises the loop control signal to control the switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to relay the output of the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> to the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, so that the amount of phase shift corresponding to the error signal is specified for the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> over a high-level period of the S/H timing signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Thus, while the S/H timing signal is at high level, a feedback control is performed for the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, in a direction in which an output error level of the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> is reduced in the feedback loop, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7G</cross-reference>. As a result, the feedback loop performs a so-called phase pull-in operation. As the phase pull-in operation advances, the feedback loop proceeds to a lock range to maintain a phase lock state in which the error signal is converged in the vicinity of a target value determined by an offset value. Consequently, the phase of the writing clock WCK is matched with a target phase which is the sum of the phase of the reproduced clock RCK and an offset in the high-level period of the S/H timing signal immediately before the new data is written. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, responsive to a falling edge of the S/H timing signal, holds the value of the error signal sampled immediately before the S/H timing signal falls, and subsequently outputs the held value to the adder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is continuously specified the amount of phase shift corresponding to an addition value of the held value and the offset value even after the high-level period of the S/H timing signal has passed, so that the writing clock WCK is adjusted in phase by the amount of phase shift continuously specified after the lapse of the high-level period of the S/H timing signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7C and 7D</cross-reference> generally and schematically show how the phases of the writing clock WCK and the reproduced clock RCK are controlled. Specifically, a hatched portion in the writing clock WCK indicates that its phase is determined by the amount of phase shift corresponding to the reference value V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> without subjected to phase matching; a cross-hatched portion in the writing clock WCK indicates that its phase is forcibly matched with the phase of the reproduced clock RCK; and a stripe portion in the writing clock WCK indicates that its phase is maintained to substantially match the phase of the reproduced clock RCK. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> According to the operation of the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> as described, the phase of the writing clock WCK is adjusted to align with the phase of the reproduced clock from the written data which has been read a predetermined period before new data is written, so that the new data can be written into the disc while maintaining the continuity of the phase of a bit clock associated with the written data. With the disc on which the new data has been written as mentioned, the previously written data and the new data can be continuously reproduced in a smooth manner without any hindrance in the reproduction of the bit clock and the detection of the synchronization signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Next, another embodiment according to the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a general configuration of an information recording apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention, where parts equivalent to those in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> are designated the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> The information recording apparatus illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> are basically similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> except that the phase shifter <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, the offset generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, and the S/H circuit <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are omitted. For this reason, a PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&prime; is modified such that an adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A is connected between an LPF <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and a VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, receives an output signal of the LPF <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> at one input thereof, and supplies an addition output signal to the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Also, in a modified phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime;, an output signal of the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is directly supplied to an input of a phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, and derived as a writing clock signal WCK. Further, in the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime;, an output signal of an LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> is supplied to an input of a loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> through an amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime;, and an output signal of the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is supplied to the other input of the adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A in the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&prime; through an LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight>Then, a loop control signal supplied to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> is generated by a timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; which has a similar configuration and signal generating principle to the aforementioned S/H timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> In the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime;, the phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> compares the output signal of the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> (writing clock WCK) in the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&prime; with a reproduced clock signal RCK from a clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to generate a signal corresponding to a phase difference between the two signals which is supplied to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> through the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> and the amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime;. The loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> selectively outputs either an output amplified error signal from the amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime; or a reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>. The signal passing through the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>is added to an input control signal to the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> in the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> In the configuration as described above, when a CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> generates a loop control signal to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to select the output of the amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime; (for closing the loop), a phase error between the writing clock signal WCK and the reproduced clock signal RCK is produced by the phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, and a feedback signal corresponding to this phase error is supplied to the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> through the switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and the adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A. Here, the feedback signal supplied to the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> sets in the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> the amount of phase shift corresponding to the phase error, more specifically, such an amount of phase shift (instantaneous frequency) that converges the phase error to zero. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Thus, with a feedback control preformed by a loop formed by the foregoing phase comparator <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime;, loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>and adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A, the writing clock WCK is brought to gradually match the phase of the reproduced clock signal RCK from the clock reproducing circuit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> from the time the loop is closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> generates a loop control signal to the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> to select the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (for opening the loop), the amount of phase shift (instantaneous frequency) corresponding to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is set in the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> which shifts the phase of the writing clock signal WCK by the thus set amount of phase shift (in other words, the instantaneous frequency is changed). Therefore, when the loop is open, the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime; is controlled to generate the writing clock WCK which has the phase adjusted as determined by the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> independent of the reproduced clock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> However, the action of the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>should be noted. The LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>serves to supply the VCO <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> with a feedback signal which is smoothly changed from the value of the output signal of the amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>&prime; to the value of the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> when the loop switch <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> switches its selection from the output signal of the amplifier <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. With this action of the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f, </italic></highlight>the phase of the writing clock signal WCK is gradually changed from its locked phase to a phase corresponding to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> after the loop is open subsequent to its phase lock state, and is eventually returned to the phase (frequency) corresponding to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> after a while. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> The operation of the information recording apparatus according to this embodiment is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>I. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>E, the loop control signal rises at the timing of the first count value N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to close the phase matching loop, and falls at the timing of the second count value N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to open the phase matching loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Therefore, while the loop control signal is at high level, a feedback control is executed for the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime;, in a direction in which an output error level of the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> in the feedback loop is reduced, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12F</cross-reference>. As a result, the feedback loop performs a so-called phase pull-in operation. As the phase pull-in operation advances, the feedback loop proceeds to a lock range to maintain a phase lock state in which the error signal is converged in the vicinity of a target value. Consequently, the writing clock WCK is matched in phase with the reproduced clock RCK in the high-level period of the loop control signal immediately before the new data is written. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> When the loop control signal falls, the phase matching loop is opened to supply the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to the adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A through the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f. </italic></highlight>Here, the LPF <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>has a predetermined time constant, so that it does not immediately transmit the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> as it is, even if the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is supplied thereto, but instead transmits to the adder <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A a signal which exponentially approaches the value indicated by the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Consequently, the output of the LPF <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> after the loop is closed exhibits a slow change as indicated by T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>F and reaches a level corresponding to the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Thus, the writing clock WCK is returned to have a frequency and a phase (i.e., a center frequency determined by the reference signal V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>) inherent to the PLL circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>&prime; serving as a writing clock generating means some time after additional recording is started, so that the writing clock signal WCK is synchronized with the reproduced clock RCK only at a location near the junction of the new data to the old data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12C and 12D</cross-reference> also show generally and schematically how the phases of the writing clock WCK and the reproduced clock RCK are controlled. Specifically, a hatched portion in the writing clock WCK indicates that its phase is determined by the amount of phase shift corresponding to the reference value V<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> without subjected to phase matching; and a cross-hatched portion in the writing clock WCK indicates that its phase is forcibly matched with the phase of the reproduced clock RCK. It should be noted that for a while after time t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12C</cross-reference> representing the writing clock WCK is drawn in such a manner that the cross-hatching pattern is gradually toned down and merges into the original hatching, thus indicating how the phase of the writing clock WCK transitions from the phase of the reproduced clock RCK to its own phase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> According to the operation of the phase matching circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>&prime; as described, the phase of the writing clock WCK is likewise adjusted to align with the phase of the reproduced clock from the written data which has been read a predetermined period before new data is written, so that the new data can be written into the disc while maintaining the continuity of the phase of a bit clock associated with the written data, whereby the previously written data and the new data can be continuously reproduced in a smooth manner without disturbing the synchronization operation for the read data during reproduction of information. In addition, the second embodiment is advantageous in terms of cost because the configuration can be made relatively simple. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> The processing of the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> for performing the foregoing operation is illustrated in flow charts of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> According to the flow charts, it can be seen that when a second sync frame is detected at step S<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> permits the timing generating circuit <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>&prime; to generate a loop control signal at subsequent step S<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>&prime; and proceeds to step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. It can be also seen that after step S<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> determines whether or not a count value has reached the second count value at step S<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, while steps S<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference> are omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Next, a further embodiment according to the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates a general configuration of an information recording apparatus according to a third embodiment, wherein parts equivalent to those in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> are designated the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, an information recording system is improved over the configuration illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Specifically, an encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A comprises two outputs, i.e., an inverting output and a non-inverting output as its encoded outputs. The two encoded outputs are supplied to a switch circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>S. The switch circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>S selectively supplies a power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> with either the one encoded output or the other encoded output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> A buffer circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>B fetches a read signal from a reproducing amplifier <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and supplies the fetched read signal to a comparator circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C with a predetermined delay time (for example, corresponding to 3T which is equal to a minimum pit length Tmin, by way of example). The comparator circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C, responsive to a comparison determining trigger signal supplied thereto from the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, compares the value of the output of the buffer circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>B with the value of the non-inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A, and supplies a control signal to the switch circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>S to select the inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A when the two values are coincident. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> According to the configuration as described above, it is possible to avoid a data pattern that may cause an inconvenience due to a combination of the end of previously written data and the top of new data upon additional recording. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> Advantageous effects unique to the third embodiment as above can be described in detail with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> Written data shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16A</cross-reference> is delayed by the buffer circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>B by a time period corresponding to 3T as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16B</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>C, the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> begins fetching data from the non-inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A at time t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in a manner similar to the aforementioned embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> While the written data is interrupted after time t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the comparator circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C is supplied from the CPU <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with a comparison determining trigger which rises at time t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and has a pulse width corresponding to 3T, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>D, and the written data output from the buffer circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>B with a delay corresponding to 3T, so that the comparator circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C compares the input data with the data from the non-inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A. In other words, the final 3T portion of the written data is compared with the first 3T portion of the data from the non-inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> The comparator <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C, when determining that the values of the two data are coincident, forces the switch circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>S to transfer the data from the inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A to the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, and subsequently the recording operation is continued with data from the inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A. Data after the additional recording shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16E</cross-reference> represents this recording operation. Conversely, when determining that the values of the two data are not coincident, the comparator <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>C forces the switch circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>S to continue to transfer data from the non-inverting output of the encoder <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>A to the power control circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> In this way, it is possible to prevent an end portion of the written data from having the same value as a top portion of new data which is combined thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> Assuming for example that logical values &ldquo;0&rdquo; continue over 7T at the end of written data and logical values &ldquo;0&rdquo; also continue over 7T at the beginning of new data, the resulting data pattern would have logical values &ldquo;0&rdquo; successively over <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>T if both the data are simply combined. This pattern including successive logical values &ldquo;0&rdquo; over 14T is coincident with a pattern which should be given only to the synchronization signal SY in this embodiment. In other words, the same data pattern as the synchronization signal SY is unintentionally formed at the junction of the two data, causing the sync detecting circuit to erroneously detect this data pattern as the synchronization signal SY during subsequent reproduction of information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, since the third embodiment forcibly inverts new data in such a case to prevent the formation of a pattern unintentionally identical to the synchronization signal SY, thereby making it possible to avoid erroneous detection of the synchronization signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> While in the third embodiment, logical values of new data are inverted when a portion at the end of written data is the same as a portion at the beginning of the new data, the values may be changed in such a manner that the contents of the data are not substantially changed as is the case of the foregoing inverting processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> While in the foregoing description, each sync frame of the top recording sector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>T, in which data is additionally recorded, stores new data, dummy data may be stored therein instead of the new data, as described in Laid-open Japanese Patent Application No. 9-270171. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Also, while the foregoing embodiments have been described mainly for the DVD-R as a recording medium, the present invention is applicable to any other additionally recordable recording medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> Further, while the sync frame synchronization signal SY has been taken as an example of the particular synchronization signal, the present invention may also be realized by specifying as the particular synchronization signal another synchronization signal which is provided in each predetermined data block having the amount of information different from the sync frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the foregoing embodiments have been described for the case where new data is additionally recorded on a disc on which the end of recorded old data is followed by old dummy data as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>J. The present invention however can be realized even without providing such intervention as the old dummy data between the old data and the new data. Specifically, significant effects can also be produced when the phase matching is performed in a sync frame which stores old data to synchronize a writing clock for new data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> While in the foregoing embodiments, a variety of means have been described in a rather limitative manner, they may be otherwise modified as appropriate within a scope in which those skilled in the art can design. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> As described above in detail, according to the information recording apparatus of the present invention, it is possible to employ a recording scheme for a recording medium which can smoothly reproduce previously written data and additional data subsequent thereto in succession without disturbing the synchronization operation for read data during reproduction of information. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus capable of additionally recording new data subsequent to previously written data on a recording medium, comprising: 
<claim-text>writing clock generating means for generating a writing clock signal for writing the new data into said recording medium while establishing synchronization with the new data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>clock reproducing means for reading said written data from said recording medium, and reproducing a synchronization clock signal of said written data to generate a reproduced clock signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>phase adjusting means for synchronizing the phase of said writing clock signal to the phase of said reproduced clock signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>said written data is data including a particular synchronization signal for every predetermined data block, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said information recording apparatus further comprises: 
<claim-text>synchronization signal detecting means for detecting said particular synchronization signal from said written data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>counting means responsive to detection timing of said particular synchronization signal by said synchronization signal detecting means to start a counting operation based on said reproduced clock signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>control means for determining a writing start time at which said new data is written into said recording medium, based on a count value presented by said counting means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means synchronizes the phase of said writing clock to the phase of a reproduced clock signal derived from said written data in a predetermined period before an additional recording start position for said new data on said recording medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means synchronizes the phase of said writing clock to the phase of a reproduced clock signal derived from said written data in a predetermined period before an additional recording start position for said new data on said recording medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means, after synchronizing the phase of said writing clock signal to the phase of said reproduced clock signal, gradually returns frequency and phase of said writing clock signal to a frequency and a phase inherent to said writing clock generating means with a predetermined time constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means, after synchronizing the phase of said writing clock signal to the phase of said reproduced clock signal, gradually returns frequency and phase of said writing clock signal to a frequency and a phase inherent to said writing clock generating means with a predetermined time constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means, after synchronizing the phase of said writing clock signal to the phase of said reproduced clock signal, gradually returns frequency and phase of said writing clock signal to a frequency and a phase inherent to said writing clock generating means with a predetermined time constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said phase adjusting means, after synchronizing the phase of said writing clock signal to the phase of said reproduced clock signal, gradually returns frequency and phase of said writing clock signal to a frequency and a phase inherent to said writing clock generating means with a predetermined time constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An information recording apparatus capable of additionally recording new data subsequent to previously written data on a recording medium, comprising: 
<claim-text>comparing means for comparing, in terms of value, an end data portion corresponding to a predetermined amount of data located at the end of said written data with a top data portion corresponding to said predetermined amount of data located at the beginning of said new data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>control means for changing values in said new data when said comparing means determines that values in said end data portion are coincident with values in said top data portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030002408A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
