<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000085A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000085A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000085A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000085A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000085A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000085A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000085A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000085A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000085</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896087</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B21K001/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B21D053/84</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>888100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>METHOD FOR MANUFACTURING A CAMSHAFT HAVING ADDED WEAR RESISTANCE OF THE LOBE</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<family-name>Majewski</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Groveland</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Pollard</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>East Peoria</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Caterpilar Inc.</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Dept. AB6490</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 N.E. Adams Street</address-1>
<city>Peoria</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>61629-6490</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method of manufacturing a camshaft used in an internal combustion engine. The method of manufacturing the camshaft produces a camshaft which has reduced weight and added wear resistance at a lobe of the camshaft. The camshaft is manufactured to provide increased efficiency of the internal combustion engine. The method of making the camshaft includes mixing wear resistant material with a base material and metering the mixture into a rotating die. The rotating die rotates at a predetermined speed and forces the wear resistant material to the outer surface of the lobes. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to a method for manufacturing a camshaft and more particularly to a method for manufacturing a camshaft having added wear resistance at a lobe area of the camshaft. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Manufacturing processes for components of an internal combustion engine have evolved through the years so that such engine components can meet ever increasing performance requirements, e.g., increased stress tolerances and the like. These manufacturing processes have made the internal combustion engine more reliable and efficient; however, current manufacturing processes require additional steps or processes to add wear resistance properties to specific components of the internal combustion engine such as, for example, the camshaft of the internal combustion engine and more specifically the lobe regions of the camshaft. By providing added wear resistant properties to the camshaft, the internal combustion engine would be even more efficient than which is currently possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Being more specific, the lobe regions of the camshaft are subject to metal fatigue due to extensive contact between the lobes of the camshaft and respective rocker arms of the intake and exhaust valves. This contact wears down the lobe regions of the camshaft thus resulting in poor engine performance. However, current manufacturing processes do not address these problems and, in particular, do not provide a means for providing wear resistance properties at a particular region, e.g., lobes, of the camshaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> By way of example, current casting processes do not provide adequate wear resistance properties at the lobe region of the camshaft. For example, in green sand casting processes a pattern which conforms to the external shape of the camshaft is formed. The pattern is then used to form a green sand mold which is made in an open frame or flask such that both the flask and the pattern are capable of being parted to facilitate removal of the pattern from the sand. A molten metal such as iron is then poured into the formed sand mold and, after solidifing, the cast iron is removed from the mold. Depending on the particular application of the camshaft, hardening materials may be added to the iron. The hardening materials, however, migrate to the bottom of the mold resulting in an uneven distribution of the hardening materials within the iron. By adding the hardening material, the integrity of the camshaft may be negatively impacted due to the uneven distribution of materials within the camshaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In another method of manufacturing camshafts, a camshaft is forged using known forging techniques. In particular, in known forging techniques a die is first formed, and a forging material such as alloys, aluminum or steel is heated to a desired temperature. The heated material is placed under pressure within the die until the forging material conforms to the shape of the die. The forging process is unable to provide added wear resistance properties to specific regions of the forged component such as the lobe regions of the camshaft. This is mainly due to the fact that the forging process cannot precisely place wear resistant material in specific locations which would correspond to the lobes of the camshaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,004,370 to Swars issued on Apr. 2, 1991 discloses a hollow shaft having drive elements (e.g., cams) with axially varied properties. The drive elements are secured on the hollow shaft by expansion of the hollow shaft, and includes a separate outside layer produced by an induction-hardened process. This outside layer, however, is not distributed throughout the drive elements, nor is it distributed within the hollow shaft. Accordingly, the apparatus of Swars has a tendency to wear during the use of the internal combustion engine, and does not appear to adequately withstand high torsional stresses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to overcoming one or more of the problems as set forth above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the present invention a method for manufacturing a camshaft is provided. The method includes forming an integrated mixture of a base material having a first density and a wear resistant material having a second density. The method has the steps of metering the integrated mixture into a die having an interior shape corresponding to a shape of the camshaft, and rotating the die. The rotation of the die forces the wear resistant material to migrate toward the outside of the lobe. After the rotating step, the camshaft is removed from the rotating die when the integrated mixture is solidified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the present invention, the method of manufacturing a crankshaft having a wear resistant lobe uses a rotating assembly having a rotating die. The rotating die has an interior shape corresponding to the camshaft. The method of making the crankshaft mixes a base material and a wear resistant material to form an integrated mixture. The wear resistant material is harder than the base material. The integrated mixture is metered into the rotating die, and the rotating die is then rotated so that the wear resistant material is forced toward an outer surface of the lobe. After the integrated mixture is solidified, the camshaft is removed from the rotating die.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>shows a diagrammatic view of a camshaft manufactured in accordance with the method of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows a cut-away view along line <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the camshaft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a diagrammatic view of an apparatus used to manufacture the camshaft in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a flow diagram depicting the manufacturing steps for manufacturing the camshaft in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>a diagrammatic view of a camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> manufactured in accordance with the method of the present invention is shown. The camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes a camshaft body or shaft <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a plurality of cams <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> extending along the length of the shaft <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> extends from each cam <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may also include other features such as camshaft journal bearings <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> spaced apart in an alternating pattern with the cams <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The specific dimensions of these features are not discussed herein and are not critical to the understanding of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>shows a cut-away view along line <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes an axially oriented hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The components of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are composed of a base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> such as steel or cast iron in combination with wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is distributed throughout the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and more preferably within and on an outer surface of each lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may also be distributed in the journal bearings <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and, to an extent, throughout the shaft <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring still to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is incorporated into the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is approximately 20% to 40% of volume in relation to the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on the surface of the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The percentage volume of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> gradually decreases to zero on the inside of shaft <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>; that is, a surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is preferably devoid of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an apparatus used to manufacture the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. In particular, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a horizontal centrifugal casting apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having a rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> positioned on a drive arrangement <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which rotates the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has an interior shape corresponding to the features of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> including the cams <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the lobes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The interior shape of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also correspond with other camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> features such as the journal bearings <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the like. A funnel <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is positioned at a first end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and an end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is positioned at a second end <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are poured into the funnel <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and are further retained within the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the end cap <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be steel or iron or other similar material. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be a carbide material such as tungsten carbide having particles approximately 50 microns in size. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may also be ferro-tungsten/titanium carbide approximately 5 microns in size. When using the carbide based materials, it is preferable to use iron for the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the camshaft due to the high content of carbon within the iron. (The carbons within the carbide material are not sacrificed due to the high content of carbon in the cast iron thus allowing the carbide wear resistant material to retain its integrity during the casting process.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It should be recognized by those of skill in the art that other base materials <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and wear resistant materials <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (including other particle sizes) may also be used with the present invention, depending on the particular application of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. These other wear resistant materials <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be ceramic or diamond material or any material that has a higher density (or harder) than that of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> should also have a higher melting point than the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a flow diagram depicting the manufacturing steps in accordance with the present invention. In step S<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is rotated via the use of the drive assembly <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The specific rotation speed of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> depends on many variables, some of which are the specific materials and proportions of materials used to form the camshaft <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as well as the dimensions of the camshaft <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> being manufactured in accordance with the method of the present invention. However and by way of example, the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be rotated at a predetermined speed, preferably about 60G or about 1200 revolutions per minute (RPM), but may also be in the range of 40-100G or between about 1000-1600 RPM. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In step S<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are mixed together to form an integrated mixture. The ratio of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may vary depending on which base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is used to form the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. By way of example, the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> should be in a ratio with the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> such that the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is approximately 20% to 40% of volume in relation to the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on the surface of the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In step S<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the mixture of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is metered into the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The volume of the integrated mixture of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> should be less than the volume of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In step S<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> continues to rotate at a predetermined speed. The rotation of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> creates centrifugal forces within the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which, in combination with the reduced volume of the integrated mixture, creates the axially oriented hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In step S<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, a determination is made as to whether the integrated mixture of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has solidified. The solidification rate will depend on many variables such as, for example, the specific materials used to form the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> as well as the initial temperature of the materials, etc. If the integrated mixture is not solidified, steps S<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are repeated. Once the mixture of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is solidified, the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is stopped in step S<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In step S<highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the solidified camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is then removed from the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is machined. In step S<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the process ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Furthermore from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, several stages of the manufacturing process of the camshaft using the method of the present invention can be projected. For example, the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotating in a clockwise direction. During the rotation, the impurities <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>remain near the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is forced outwards towards the walls of the rotating die <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (e.g., towards the lobes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>). The concentration of the impurities <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> after the integrated mixture of the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> have solidified in step S<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Also, the concentration of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> collects at the walls of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. And, the impurities <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>can be removed from the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> after the machining step of S<highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Industrial Applicability </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a method of manufacturing the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> having added wear resistance at the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. During the method of making the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the rotation of the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> creates centrifugal forces within the rotating die <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which, in combination with the reduced volume of the integrated mixture, creates the axially oriented hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is preferably devoid of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> so that the impurities <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be machined from the surface of the hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> without damaging the tooling used for the machining process. The hollow interior portion <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also reduces the weight of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which increases the efficiency of the internal combustion engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> During the rotation process, the denser wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> migrates to the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The wear resistant material <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> within the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> ensures that the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, in particular, does not wear due to metal fatigue from extensive contact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> It is noted that the higher density of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> allows the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to migrate to the outer surface of the lobe <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> during the rotation process. Also, the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> should also have a higher melting point than the base material <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to ensure the integrity of the wear resistant material <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> during the manufacturing process of the camshaft <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Other aspects, objects and advantages of this invention can be obtained from a study of the drawings, the disclosure and the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for manufacturing a camshaft, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming an integrated mixture of a base material having a first density and a wear resistant material having a second density, the second density being more dense than the first density; </claim-text>
<claim-text>metering the integrated mixture into a die, the die having an interior shape corresponding to a shape of the camshaft including a cam and a lobe extending from the cam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the die at a predetermined speed, the predetermined speed forcing the wear resistant material to migrate toward the outside of the lobe; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing a formed camshaft from the rotating die when the integrated mixture is solidified. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotating step forces approximately 20% to 40% of volume of the wear resistant material in relation to the base material to a surface of the lobe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the interior shape of the die includes a shaft and the cam extends from the shaft; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the percentage volume of the wear resistant material decreases to zero in the shaft during the rotating step. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotating step forms a hollow interior portion in the shaft of the camshaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein impurities of the integrated mixture remain near the hollow interior portion of the shaft during the rotating step. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, including machining the impurities from the hollow interior portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>determining whether the integrated mixture is solidified prior to the removing step; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>continuing the rotation of the die at the predetermined speed when it is determined in the determining step that the integrated mixture is not solidified. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the wear resistant material includes a carbide based material; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the base material includes steel or iron. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the carbide material is one of tungsten carbide and ferro-tungsten/titanium carbide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wear resistant material has a higher melting point temperature than the base material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wear resistant material is one of ceramic and diamond material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the metering step includes metering a volume of the integrated mixture into the die which is less than a volume of the die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a camshaft having a wear resistant lobe, the method using a rotating assembly having a rotating die having an interior shape corresponding to the camshaft, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>mixing a base material and a wear resistant material to form an integrated mixture, the wear resistant material being harder than the base material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>metering the integrated mixture into the rotating die; </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the rotating die at a predetermined speed, the predetermined speed forces the wear resistant material toward an outer surface of the lobe; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing a formed camshaft from the rotating die when the integrated mixture is solidified. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotating step forces approximately 20% to 40% of volume of the wear resistant material in relation to the base material to a surface of the lobe of the camshaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the percentage volume of the wear resistant material decreases to zero in an inner portion of the camshaft during the rotating step. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rotating step forms a hollow interior portion in the camshaft and impurities of the integrated mixture remain near the hollow interior portion during the rotating step. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, including machining the impurities from the hollow interior portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, including: 
<claim-text>determining whether the integrated mixture is solidified prior to the removing step; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>continuing the rotation of the rotating die at the predetermined speed when it is determined in the determining step that the integrated mixture is not solidified. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wear resistant material has a first density and the base material has a second density, the first density being more dense than the second density such that the rotating step forces the wear resistant material having the first density toward the lobe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wear resistant material has a higher melting point temperature than the base material.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000085A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000085A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000085A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000085A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
