<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002284</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10113209</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020328</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0104542</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010330</filing-date>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F21V007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>362</class>
<subclass>341000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>362</class>
<subclass>346000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Dipped headlight with small size for a motor vehicle</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Herve</given-name>
<family-name>Perrin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bobigny Cedex</city>
<country-code>FR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MORGAN &amp; FINNEGAN, L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>345 PARK AVENUE</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10154</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention relates to a dipped headlight for a motor vehicle, comprising a light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) cooperating with a mirror (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) in order to form an illuminating beam with a V-shaped cut-off, the mirror comprising four regions (<highlight><bold>32, 31, 33, 34</bold></highlight>) arranged side by side, a first region (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its width, a second region (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range under the horizontal part of the cut-off, a third region (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range under the inclined part of the cut-off, and a fourth part (<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range along the longitudinal axis of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">According to the invention, each region (<highlight><bold>31, 32, 33</bold></highlight>) is joined to the adjacent region without a step, the first region (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) of the mirror has a reflecting surface which strongly spreads the light in the lateral direction, and the second and third regions (<highlight><bold>31, 33</bold></highlight>) are located on the same side of the light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates in general to headlights for motor vehicles, and in particular to dipped headlights. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Dipped headlights for motor vehicles conventionally consist of a reflecting mirror sending light rays emitted by a light source towards the front of a vehicle and a glass possibly altering the path of these rays, in order to obtain a light beam having a predetermined photometry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In a known manner, it is necessary to use a reflecting mirror of relatively large dimensions, particularly in width, in order to obtain a dipped headlight which complies both with the regulations in force and which is of high performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> These large dimensions of the reflecting mirror are necessary in order, on the one hand, to recover a sufficient amount of the light flux emitted by the source and, on the other hand, to generate, in some regions of the mirror, images of the source which are small enough to form, in the dipped beam, a spot the concentration of which is intense enough to improve the range of the headlight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Conventionally, the larger the mirror, for a given basic focal length, the larger the solid angle covered by the mirror seen by the source, and therefore the better the rate of recovery of the light flux coming from the source. However, the two objectives mentioned above are contradictory: the smaller the basic focal length of the mirror, that is to say the more the mirror is closed around the source, for a given height and width, the better the flux recovery, but the images of the source are all enlarged, and the range is insufficient. In contrast, if a longer basic focal length is used, the range is improved but the overall intensity of the beam is decreased in an undesirable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> This then results in the provision of mirrors comprising regions with different focal lengths, so as to improve both the range and the intensity of the beam, by combining the advantages of regions with short and with long focal lengths. The surface of mirrors designed in this way then has discontinuities and steps, which make the manufacture of such mirrors, their metallization and their final laquering difficult. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is set in this context and aims to overcome these drawbacks of the prior art, by providing a headlight which, while having an extremely small size as much in width as in height and in depth, is capable of generating a beam, especially a dipped beam, and more particularly a European dipped beam, having both a suitable range, a suitable width and good uniformity, the surface of the mirror not having steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The subject of the invention is therefore a dipped headlight for a motor vehicle, comprising a light source cooperating with a mirror in order to form an illuminating beam with a V-shaped cut-off, the mirror comprising at least three regions arranged side by side, a first region giving the beam its width, a second region giving the beam its range under the horizontal part of the cut-off, and a third region giving the beam its range under the inclined part of the cut-off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, each region is joined to the adjacent region without a step, the first region of the mirror has a reflecting surface which strongly spreads the light in the lateral direction, and the second and third regions are located on the same side of the light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to other characteristics of the invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> the second region, giving the beam its range under the horizontal part of the cut-off, is closer to the light source than the third region, giving the beam its range under the inclined part of the cut-off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> the mirror furthermore comprises a fourth region giving the beam its range along the longitudinal axis of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> the fourth region is located adjacent to the third region, while at the same time being further away from the light source than this third region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> the third and fourth regions are joined without a step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> at least some regions of the mirror which spread the light produce a slightly divergent spread.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Other aims, characteristics and advantages of the present invention will become better apparent on reading the following description of a preferred embodiment thereof, given by way of non-limiting example and made with reference to the appended drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic back view of a mirror for a European dipped headlight for the left side of a vehicle, according to a known design; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic back view of a mirror for a European dipped headlight for the left side of a vehicle, according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic view in axial horizontal section of the mirror of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, and of the source with which it cooperates; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, illustrating the paths of some light rays reflected by the various regions of the mirror, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C illustrate, by sets of isolux curves on a projection screen, the appearance of various parts of a beam generated by the source/mirror assembly of FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the prior art, intended to cooperate with a light source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as a filament, oriented axially, of an incandescent lamp such as a standardized &ldquo;H1&rdquo; or &ldquo;H7&rdquo; lamp, or else such as the electric arc of a discharge lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> By convention, an orthonormal coordinate system Oxyz centred on the light source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is defined, the axis Oy being horizontal and parallel to the longitudinal axis of the vehicle, the axis Ox being horizontal and perpendicular to the axis Oz, and the axis Oz being vertical and perpendicular to the first two axes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is intended to generate by itself a dipped beam, without there being any need to use another optical component, such as, for example, striations or prisms formed on a closure glass placed in front of the mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This glass may then be plain or slightly deflecting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The mirror <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is subdivided into three regions <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, separated by substantially vertical planes parallel to the median plane yOz passing through the source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, these three regions having spreads and geometries which are different one from the other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The central region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is intended to provide considerable spreading of the light, in order to give the light beam its width. It may, for example, be of the type described in Patents FR-B-2 760 067 and FR-B-2 760 068 in the name of the Applicant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> located to the right in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is intended mainly to give to the beam to be generated (in this case a standard European dipped beam, with a &ldquo;V&rdquo;-shaped cut-off) its range, that is to say, a substantial portion of the region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is intended to generate light along the axis of the road or in the vicinity of this axis, below the horizontal cut-off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> located to the left in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is capable of generating, by means of its upper part, a beam part with a horizontal cut-off, and has rows of slightly deflecting vertical striations or prisms, while the lower part of the region <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is capable, by simply tilting the surface by, for example, 15&deg;, of generating a beam part inclined at 15&deg;, in order to define the inclined half cut-off of the European dipped beam, and has rows of slightly deflecting striations or prisms inclined at 15&deg; with respect to the vertical. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A mirror design of this sort, although completely satisfactory, is difficult to apply when it is necessary to produce mirrors of small dimensions, which then entails that the region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has only a small lateral spread in the direction Ox. The problem, in this case, is that the horizontal cut-off can no longer be clean. The result of this is, on the one hand, a sharp deterioration of the photometric performance of the beam, which can no longer comply with the regulations, and, on the other hand, greater difficulty in adjusting the beam in terms of elevation, since the adjustment systems are based on detecting the position of the horizontal cut-off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a solution to this problem of obtaining a European dipped beam, having both a suitable range, a suitable width and good uniformity with a small-sized headlight, of which the mirror itself has small dimensions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a mirror <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, intended to cooperate with an axial light source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as the filament of a standardized &ldquo;H1&rdquo; or &ldquo;H7&rdquo; incandescent lamp, or else the electric arc of a discharge lamp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The mirror <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is subdivided into four regions <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, identified as such by their intersection with the horizontal plane xOy. These three regions have spreads and geometries which are different one from the other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, similar to the region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the headlight of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, is capable of generating considerable spreads of the light, thus giving the light beam its width. It comprises a series of regions <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>, whose parameters, especially in terms of horizontal generatrix, may be set in a way similar to that carried out for a mirror of the usual dimensions. In the present example, the region <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has regions constituting striations capable of giving the reflected light a predetermined degree of spread, with lateral limits <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>G </subscript></highlight>and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>(<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) which are preferably blurred in order to prevent beam uniformity defects, and capable of completely locating this light below the standardized horizontal cut-off. In order to produce these striations, the teachings of the aforementioned documents FR-A-2 760 067 or FR-A-2 760 068 in the name of the Applicant can advantageously be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, located to the left of the region <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is capable of generating the part of the beam with a horizontal cut-off, in order to give it its range under this horizontal cut-off. The region <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is thus shaped so as to reflect the light rays emitted by the source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> only in slightly divergent directions, for example between the rays <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>G </subscript></highlight>and <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. This region <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, taken alone, thus gives a contribution to the beam, which contribution is shown by the isolux curves of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, located to the left of the region <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is capable of generating the part of the beam located under the 15&deg; cut-off of the dipped beam. It is constructed from a parabolic basic surface, while automatically generating the cut-off of the beam according, for example, to the teachings of document FR-A-2 536 502, in the name of the Applicant, it being possible for striations and/or prisms, according to the teachings of document FR-A-2 710 393, also in the name of the Applicant, to be applied to this basic surface, there being inclined at 15&deg; to the horizontal. The region <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is therefore shaped so as to reflect light rays emitted by the source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> only in slightly divergent directions, for example between the rays <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>G </subscript></highlight>and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The region <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> thus contributes to forming the beam part shown by the isolux curves in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The region <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, located to the left of the region <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is capable of generating the light rays giving the beam its range along the longitudinal axis of the vehicle, and it is shaped so as to reflect the light rays emitted by the source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> only in slightly divergent directions, for example between the rays <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>G </subscript></highlight>and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>D </subscript></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, and contributing to forming the beam part shown by the isolux curves in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference>. It is understood that a surface of this sort, in its part furthest away from the source <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, will thus generate images of this source which are small enough to give the beam a satisfactory range. Furthermore, the beam generated by the region <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, being superimposed on those which are generated by the regions <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, contributes to making the connection between these two beams and to giving the beam greater uniformity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Because the regions <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the mirror are substantially more closed around the source than its region <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, provision is made for the mirror to be strongly asymmetric in terms of spread on either side of the lamp, as is shown clearly in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> This therefore makes it possible to produce a mirror of small width, which generates a beam which is quite satisfactory in terms of range, width, overall flux and uniformity. The height of the mirror is advantageously close to its width. A mirror whose width and height are very small, and which has no step, is thus produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> This has the advantage that the mirror emits no unwanted radiation which could be generated by such steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> It is understood from the above description that, when the extinguished lamp/mirror unit is observed from the outside, through a glass which will typically be plain, the observer notices that the lamp is strongly offset laterally with respect to the middle of the mirror. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In order to retain a symmetry in appearance of the vehicle, it is therefore advantageous to design the lamp/mirror assembly intended to be used in the right headlight in such a way that the lateral offset of the lamp in the mirror is reversed with respect to the offset in the left headlight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Of course, the present invention is in no way limited to the embodiments described and shown, and a person skilled in the art will know how to provide many variants or modifications thereof. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Dipped headlight for a motor vehicle, comprising a light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) cooperating with a mirror (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) in order to form an illuminating beam with a V-shaped cut-off, the mirror comprising at least three regions (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) arranged side by side, a first region (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its width, a second region (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range under the horizontal part of the cut-off, a third region (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range under the inclined part of the cut-off, characterized in that each region (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) is joined to the adjacent region without a step, in that the first region (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) of the mirror has a reflecting surface which strongly spreads the light in the lateral direction, and in that the second and third regions (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) are located on the same side of the light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Headlight according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the second region (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>), giving the beam its range under the horizontal part of the cut-off, is closer to the light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) than the third region (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>), giving the beam its range under the inclined part of the cut-off. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Headlight according to either of claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, characterized in that it furthermore comprises a fourth region (<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) giving the beam its range along the longitudinal axis of the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Headlight according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the fourth region is adjacent to the third region (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>), while at the same time being further away from the light source (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) than this third region (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Headlight according to either of claims <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the third and fourth regions (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) are joined without a step. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Headlight according to one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that at least some regions of the mirror (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) which spread the light produce a slightly divergent spread.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002284A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002284A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002284A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002284A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
