<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000733A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000733A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000733</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10203324</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020806</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0003146.8</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20000212</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01B017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>14900B</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Bus bar assembly</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>John</middle-name>
<family-name>Mohan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Lytham St Annes</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>Francis</middle-name>
<family-name>Smith</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Fulwood</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MYERS BIGEL SIBLEY &amp; SAJOVEC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO BOX 37428</address-1>
<city>RALEIGH</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>27627</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/GB01/00545</doc-number>
<document-date>20010209</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Busbar assembly having a support member (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) with internal strengthening means (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) and/or spacers (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) with shoulders (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) adapted to prevent over-penetration of the spacers into receiving apertures (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) of the support member (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) and/or resilient rings (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) arranged for compression between support members (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) and spacers (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a busbar assembly, and includes a support member for a busbar assembly, a method of making a support member for a busbar assembly, a busbar assembly, and a support member and a spacer member for a busbar assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> For many years, busbar assemblies have been used in a wide variety of domestic and industrial installations to provide a convenient means to supply relatively high electric currents, such assemblies not only being convenient from an electrical point of view, but also being relatively compact and easily accessible for maintenance purposes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In view of the relatively high currents (up to 5000 amps, for example) which may be carried by the busbars, various electrical and safety considerations must be taken into account when designing and constructing supports for the current carrying conductors, to prevent cross induction, for example, and to ensure that the overall assembly is sufficiently robust to withstand large thermal and mechanical stresses which may be generated, for example, when short circuit faults occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Typically, a number of busbars are aligned generally parallel to each other, with the busbars being held in position by a number of busbar support members extending generally transverse to the axes of the busbars, with the support members being arranged in pairs, such that the busbars are in effect clamped between the upper and lower halves of each pair. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To avoid any risk of short circuits occurring, the supports are typically formed from a non-conductive material such as a thermo-plastics resin, and whilst such materials exhibit good insulating properties, their mechanical strength is often insufficient to withstand the thermal and mechanical stresses referred to above, and separate strengthening devices, typically in the form of metallic cross-braces, are required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> From a purely mechanical viewpoint, such devices operate satisfactorily, but it is necessary to position them extremely carefully to ensure that a safe minimum clearance is maintained between them and the live/earth inlet terminals to avoid any undesired electromagnetic inductance which can be detrimental to the operation of electrical devices to which power is supplied by the busbar assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Moreover, this type of construction can be relatively time consuming in assembly and the need to manufacture specially configured metallic strengthening devices results in undesired increases in production costs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to a first aspect of the present invention, there is provided a support member for a busbar assembly, having a body and a receiving formation adapted to receive part of an electrical conductor, characterised in that the support member is provided with strengthening means formed from a material different from that of the body, and wherein part at least of the strengthening means is located within the body of the support member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Preferably, substantially the whole of the strengthening means is located within the body of the support member, whereby to maintain the strengthening means insulated from the exterior of the support body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Thus whilst the body may be formed from a non-electrically conductive material, the strengthening means may be of conductive material, being electrically insulated from the conductor by the body of the support member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Thus, the body may comprise a plastics moulding and the strengthening means may be enveloped by the plastics material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Whilst it will be appreciated that a variety of suitable non-electrically conductive plastics materials may be utilised, two particularly suitable materials have been found to be glass fibre filled nylon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and glass fibre filled PBT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The strengthening means is preferably metallic, and conveniently is provided by metallic strip material. The metallic material is preferably non-magnetic, and stainless steel has been found to be a particularly suitable material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> By enveloping the strengthening means within the body of the support member, not only is the support member internally reinforced, thus obviating the requirement of a separate strengthening device, but the amount of thermoplastics material required to mould the body is reduced, thus reducing the associated production costs. Furthermore, by maintaining the metallic strengthening means insulated from the exterior of the support member body, the risk of cross induction occurring between the live conductors is substantially reduced, and thus that the positioning of the support member may be less critical than has previously been the case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a busbar assembly having a plurality of electrical conductors and a plurality of associated support members, the support members being substantially in accordance with one or more of the preceding paragraphs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to a second aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of making a support member for a busbar assembly by moulding a body of the support member from a first material, characterised in that strengthening means formed from a second, different, material is first located within the mould such that part at least of the strengthening means becomes enveloped by the first material upon moulding of the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the strengthening means is wholly enveloped by the first material upon moulding of the body. Desirably, the body of the support member is moulded from a plastics material, and the strengthening means is preferably provided by a section of metallic strip material. Conveniently, the strengthening means is provided with one or more apertures therein for passage of the moulding material therethrough, whereby the strengthening means becomes securely moulded within the body of the support member. Preferably, the plastics material is glass fibre filled nylon 66 or glass fibre filled PBT, with the strengthening means preferably being provided by a section of stainless steel strip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> A further problem which is encountered with known busbar assemblies is that during their construction, a possibility exists that the nut and bolt arrangements which hold the busbars and support members together will be over-tightened, which can result in excessive stresses being imparted to the assembly, and in particular to the relatively weak thermoplastics supports. As discussed above, such stresses can impair the reliability of the components to which the excessive load has been applied, giving rise to serious safety concerns. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the present invention, there is provided a busbar assembly comprising an electrical conductor and support members therefor, the support members extending generally transversely to the longitudinal axis of the conductor, spacer members being provided between adjacent support members, characterised in that compressible means are located between the spacer members and support members to provide a cushioning effect during attachment of the spacer members and support members to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the compressible means are resilient, such that on removal of a load, the compressible means may return exactly or substantially to their pre-loaded condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The compressible means may be generally ring-shaped, and are conveniently provided by resilient plastics material, such as neoprene rings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The spacer members may be provided, adjacent an end thereof, with a shoulder, and the compressible means is located, in use, between the shoulder and the associated support member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The support members may also be provided with a shoulder, such that the compressible means, in use, are located between the respective shoulders of the spacer members and the support members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to a fourth aspect of the present invention, there is provided, in combination, a support member and a spacer member for a busbar assembly, the support member having a body with a passage extending therethrough, the spacer member having a main part and an engagement part, the engagement part being adapted to extend through the passage in the support member, characterised in that the engagement part has a smaller cross-sectional area than the main part such that the main part cannot pass through the passage in the support member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the support member and spacer member are provided with shoulders which face towards each other during attachment of the support member and spacer member to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Conveniently, the shoulders define a space between the support member and spacer member, the space being effective to receive compressible means to provide a cushioning effect during attachment of the support member and spacer member to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The compressible means may be resilient, preferably having a shore hardness in the range 40 to 60, although materials having a shore hardness in the range 20 to 90 may be used. Thus a resilient plastics material may be utilised, conveniently in the form of an annular member such as a butyl rubber ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Part of the spacer member may be internally threaded, with the thread preferably extending only part-way along the engagement part.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be described by way of example only by reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective, exploded view of a busbar assembly, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view of part of a busbar assembly, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an end-on view of the assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in assembled form, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a close-up view of the right hand side of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, showing the inter-engagement of various components, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a close-up view of the support member and spacer member of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of the support member and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a section along the line VII-VII of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown, in part-exploded form, a busbar assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having three live current carrying busbars <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a neutral busbar <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and a number of support members <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> disposed above and below the busbars <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The busbars are conventional, in that they are provided by apertured metallic strips, with the support members <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> each having a body <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a plurality of receiving formations <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in the form of an arrangement of channels, in which the busbar conductors may rest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Whilst in this example, four busbars are shown, each support member is provided with eight channels <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, to enable the support members (see <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) to engage with pairs of additional conductors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, of which <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>carry the inbound three phase current, with conductor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>acting as the return neutral conductor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In generally conventional manner, the conductors <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are attached to the busbars <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by means of nut and bolt arrangements generally indicated at <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, with the bolts <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> passing through apertures <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> provided in the busbars <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The support members <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are moulded in thermo-plastics insulative material such as glass fibre filled nylon <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, and, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, comprise an internal strengthening means in the form of a stainless steel strip insert <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which is provided with a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (in this case four) for passage of the moulding material therethrough, to enable the strengthening means to become surely moulded within the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The assembly further comprises a number of steel spacer members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, each of which has a generally cylindrical main part <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and tubular end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> having a smaller diameter than the main parts <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are internally threaded, to allow engagement with bolts <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> which attach metal frame members <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> to the assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The spacer members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which are provided on their main parts <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> with one or more &ldquo;flats&rdquo; <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to facilitate engagement with a tool such as a spanner, are slidably engageable within passages <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> extending through widened ends of the support members <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> being just long enough to extend through the apertures <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, on compression of resilient rings <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which in use rest on shoulders <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the spacer members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As can been seen especially from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, whilst the end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may slide within apertures <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> provided in the support members <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the diameter of the end parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is too great to allow passage through apertures <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the frame members <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Thus, contact of the distal parts <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the tubular parts <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> with the facing surface <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the frame member <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> limits the degree of tightening of the bolt <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, and prevents any undue clamping force being imparted to the relatively weak thermoplastics support member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> This tightening limit is shown in close up in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, from which it can been seen that at the limit of travel of the bolt <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> (i.e. when the distal end <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the tubular end part <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> bears upon the facing surface <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the frame member <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>) the ring <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is partially compressed in a space <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> defined by shoulder <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the spacer member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and opposing shoulder <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> provided by the stepped passage <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> provided in the support member <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Conveniently used for the resilient ring <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are relatively soft materials such as polypropylene, butyl rubber or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Thus, whilst the maximum tightening which may be effected is limited by the engagement of the tubular end part <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the metallic frame member <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, the later stages of tightening are cushioned to some extent by the compressible ring <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which is located in the path of the spacer member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Thus, any excessive shock or damage to the frame member <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, which might occur, for example, if a powered tool were used to rotate the bolt <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, is avoided or at least substantially reduced, meaning that potentially dangerous over tightening (and hence stresses and distortions in the overall assembly) is far less likely to occur. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Bores <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> which are provided in the support body are in consequence of the use of location elements provided in the moulds, which locate the reinforcing insert <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the mould cavity prior to injection of plastics materials. Whilst such bores inevitably expose parts of the insert <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, these are in positions having no consequence to the functioning of the insert, or maintenance of adequate insulation thereof from the busbars. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> In the present specification &ldquo;comprise&rdquo; means &ldquo;includes or consists of&rdquo; and &ldquo;comprising&rdquo; means &ldquo;including or consisting of&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The features disclosed in the foregoing description, or the following claims, or the accompanying drawings, expressed in their specific forms or in terms of a means for performing the disclosed function, or a method or process for attaining the disclosed result, as appropriate, may, separately, or in any combination of such features, be utilised for realising the invention in diverse forms thereof. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A support member for a busbar assembly, the support member having a body and a receiving formation adapted to receive part of an electrical conductor, characterised in that the support member is provided with strengthening means formed from a material different from that of the body and wherein substantially the whole of the strengthening mean is located within the body of the support member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A support member according to claims wherein the body is formed from a non-electrically conductive material and the strengthening means is of electrically conductive material, the strengthening means being electrically insulated from the conductor by the body of the support member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A support member according to any one of the proceeding claims wherein the body comprises a plastics moulding and wherein the strengthening means is enveloped by the plastics material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A support member according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the strengthening means comprises metallic strip material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A support member according, to any of the preceding claims wherein the strengthening means is non-magnetic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly having a plurality of electrical conductors and a plurality of support members, the support members being substantially in accordance with any one of the preceding claims. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A support member substantially as hereinbefore described and/or as shown in the accompanying drawings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly substantially as hereinbefore described and/or as shown in the accompanying drawings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of making a support member for a busbar assembly by moulding a body of the support member from a first material, characterised in that strengthening means formed from a second, different, material is first located within the mould such that pan of the strengthening means becomes enveloped by the first material upon moulding of the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein substantially the whole of the strengthening means is enveloped by the first material upon moulding of the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the body is moulded from a plastics material and wherein the strengthening means comprises metallic strip material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the strengthening means is non-magnetic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly comprising an electrical conductor and support members therefor, the support members extending generally transverse to the longitudinal axis of the conductor, spacer members being provided between adjacent support members, characterised in that compressible means are located between the spacer members and support members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the compressible means are resilient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the compressible means are generally ring-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly according to any one of claims <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> wherein the compressible means is of a material having a shore hardness lying in the range 20 to 90, preferably 40 to 60. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly according to any one of claims <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> wherein the spacer members are provided adjacent an end thereof with a shoulder, and wherein the compressible means are located, in use, between the shoulder and the associated support member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A busbar assembly according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the support members are also provided with a shoulder and wherein the compressible means are located, in use, between the respective shoulders of the spacer members and the support members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. In combination, a support member d a spacer member for a busbar assembly, the support member having a body with a passage extending therethrough, the spacer member having a main part and an engagement park the engagement part being adapted to extend through the passage in the support member, the engagement part having a smaller cross-sectional area than the main part such that the main part is not able to extend through the passage in the support member, the support member and spacer member are provided with shoulders which face towards each other during attachment of the support member and spacer member to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The combination of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the shoulders define a space which in use is effective to receive compressible means to provide a cushioning effect during attachment of the spacer member and support member to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The combination of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the compressible means is resilient. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The combination of any one of claims <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> wherein part of the spacer member is internally threaded. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The combination of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the internal thread extends only part-way along the engagement part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Any novel feature or novel combination of features described herein and/or in the accompanying drawings.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000733A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
