<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003291A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003291A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003291A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003291A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003291A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003291A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003291A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003291A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003291</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10173377</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B28B013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B29C031/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B29C063/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B32B005/20</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B32B003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B29C044/42</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>317900</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>425</class>
<subclass>00400R</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>425</class>
<subclass>130000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>425</class>
<subclass>256000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>314800</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>315700</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>318600</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>318800</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>428</class>
<subclass>319700</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Foamed thermoplastic resin having fiber reinforcing and apparatuses for making</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302471</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Suresh</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Shah</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Edward</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Wenzel</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mike</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Jary</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Farmington Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chad</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bengry</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rochester Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CHUCK VEENSTRA, ESQ.</name-1>
<name-2>DELPHI TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 5052</address-1>
<address-2>Mail Code: 480-414-420</address-2>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48007-5052</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part is provided. The part comprises a member formed of thermoplastic resin, a plurality of cells and a plurality of reinforcing fibers dispersed within the member, and a skin formed on at least one exterior surface of the member. The skin is substantially devoid of cells. Here, the reinforcing fibers have a length of about 25 mm in an amount of about 10% by weight of the foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part. At least one of a cell density and a cell size of the plurality of cells is inversely proportional to the amount of the reinforcing fibers dispersed within the member. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of provisional application serial number 60/302,471 filed on Jul. 2, 2001, the contents of which are incorporated herein in their entirety. This application is also related to commonly owned and assigned U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/473,279 entitled &ldquo;An In-Line Compounding Extrusion Deposition And Molding Apparatus And Method Of Using The Same&rdquo; filed on Dec. 28, 1999, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference thereto.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This disclosure relates generally to a part of foamed thermoplastic resin having fiber reinforcing, as well as apparatuses for making such parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> It is common to reinforce thermoplastic resin structures with fibrous materials. The fibers typically have mechanical properties that are superior to properties of the thermoplastic resin. Thus, such fiber reinforcing is beneficial because it increases the strength of the resulting structure or part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Thermoplastic resin structures reinforced with fibers have been manufactured using several different methods. For example, such parts have been made using the so-called pultrusion method. Here, a thermoplastic resin is impregnated into a continuous reinforcement fiber bundle. The bundle is subsequently passed through a crosshead extrusion die. After undergoing the pultrusion method, the structures are cut to a desired size. Alternately, such parts have been made by melting thermoplastic resin in a single screw extruder. The melted resin is fed to a second single screw extruder where chopped fibers are fed into the melt. This reinforced melt is pumped into an accumulator after which the required log size is cut and fed into a vertical molding press. However, these prior methods do not employ a desired a single-step process of reinforcing the long fibers and molding the part in the same step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Single-steps methods have also been used to produce fiber reinforced structures. However, these methods require the fiber to be incorporated into the resin pellets. Thus, the length of the reinforcing agents is limited by the size of the pellet. Further, introduction of reinforcing agents is known to increase the viscosity of the melt. Thus, introduction of the reinforcing agents as part of the resin pellets reduces the volume of reinforcing agents that can be added, which limits the overall strength increases that can be achieved from the resultant thermoplastic resin parts. Thus, the single step methods do not provide structures having the desired strength to weight characteristics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> One method of reducing the weight of thermoplastic resin structures is to form the structure of foamed polymer. Such foamed polymer parts include a plurality of cells or voids formed therein. By replacing solid polymer parts with foamed polymer parts, less raw material is necessary for identical parts of a given volume. However, the overall strength of the foamed polymer parts is somewhat less than that of identical solid polymer parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is desired to provide parts having reinforcing fibers of long length in a foamed polymer. However, prior apparatus and methods are not fully effective at producing thermoplastic resins parts having both a foamed structure and long fiber reinforcements. Further, prior apparatus and methods are not fully effective in employing a single-step process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It has been determined that thermoplastic resins parts having both a foamed structure and long fiber reinforcements can be produced using the exemplary apparatuses of the present disclosure. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part is provided. The part comprises a member formed of thermoplastic resin, a plurality of cells and a plurality of reinforcing fibers dispersed within the member, and a skin formed on at least one exterior surface of the member. The skin is substantially devoid of cells. Here, the reinforcing fibers have a length of at least about 25 millimeters (mm) in an amount of at least about 10% by weight of the foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part. At least one of a cell density and a cell size of the plurality of cells is inversely proportional to the amount of the reinforcing fibers dispersed within the member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An apparatus for producing a foamed fiber reinforced part is provided. The apparatus comprises a barrel, three inlets, and a screw. The first inlet feeds a thermoplastic material into the barrel. The second inlet is downstream of the first inlet, and feeds reinforcing fibers into the barrel. The second inlet has a tensioning reel for feeding the reinforcing fibers under a constant tension. The third inlet is downstream of the second inlet, and injects a blowing agent into the barrel. The screw is rotatably disposed within the barrel such that a first zone, a second zone, and a third zone of said barrel are defined. The first zone melts the thermoplastic material, the second zone shears the reinforcing fibers to a predetermined length to form a first melt from the thermoplastic material and the reinforcing fibers. The third zone forms a second melt from the first melt and the blowing agent. The third zone maintains the second melt under a first condition sufficient to maintain the blowing agent in a desired form. The conditions on the second melt are changed to a second condition sufficient to cause the blowing agent to form cells in the second melt when it is forced from the barrel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> An apparatus for producing a foamed fiber reinforced part is also provided. The apparatus comprises an extrusion machine, an injection machine, and a mold in fluid communication with one another. The extrusion machine has twin-screw extruder in fluid communication with a first inlet, a second inlet, and a third inlet. The first inlet introduces a thermoplastic resin to the twin-screw extruder. The second inlet introduces reinforcing fibers to the twin-screw extruder so that the twin-screw extruder forms a first melt. The third inlet injects a blowing agent into the sealed section. A sealed section is defined at the third inlet. The twin-screw extruder forms a second melt from the first melt at a first condition. The injection machine receives the second melt from the sealed section and injects the second melt into the mold. The injection machine changes the first conditions to second conditions that are sufficient to cause the blowing agent to form a plurality of cells in the second melt when the second melt is injected into the mold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The above described and other features are exemplified by the following figures, detailed description, and claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Referring now to the figures, which are exemplary embodiments, and wherein the like elements are numbered alike: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a sectional view of an exemplary embodiment of a foamed fiber reinforced part; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic depiction of an exemplary embodiment of an apparatus for producing the foamed fiber reinforced part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is cross-sectional view of an alternate embodiment of an apparatus for producing the foamed fiber reinforced part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in a first position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in a second position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an exemplary embodiment of a foamed polymer fiber reinforced part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> made in accordance with the present disclosure is shown. The part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a plurality of reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> dispersed in a thermoplastic resin material. Preferably, the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are closed cells. In an alternate exemplary embodiment, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises a skin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> formed on at least one of the exterior surfaces of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The skin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is substantially devoid of cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the skin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is formed on all of the exterior surfaces of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The incorporation of fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> increases the strength of the part. The fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> increase the strength of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> when dispersed in or wetted by the thermoplastic resin. The fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that are dispersed in the thermoplastic resin are referred to herein as wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The incorporation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> into the part decreases the density of the part, which in turn reduces the amount of thermoplastic resin material necessary to make a part of a given size. The cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are voids in the thermoplastic resin of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Thus, these cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can reduce the number of wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> present. Namely, un-wetted fibers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are formed in the areas where the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are disposed in and/or across a portion of a cell <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the present disclosure, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is manufactured to ensure that the number of wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is maximized, while the number of un-wetted fibers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is minimized. Namely, the agents used to form the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> help to maximize the number of wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The agents used to form the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> reduce the viscosity of the polymer during the manufacture of the part. By reducing the viscosity, the fibers are more easily wetted by the polymer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> When it is desired to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a high number of the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the density and/or size of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> dispersed therein can be reduced. Conversely, when it is desired to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a high density of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and/or cells of larger size dispersed therein, the number of fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> dispersed therein can be reduced. In this manner, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is further configured to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a maximum number of wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a minimum number of un-wetted fibers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for purposes of clarity only as including the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> aligned with the axis of the part. Of course, the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> being randomly dispersed in the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> finds use in all applications where thermoplastic resin parts having a high strength-to-weight ratio are found. For example, automotive, aerospace, commercial or military aircraft industries, locomotive industries, and the like. Particularly, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> finds use is automotive uses such as instrument panels, glove boxes, semi-structural instrument panel retainers, interior trim, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Generally, polymeric foams have been formed through the incorporation of physical blowing agents, chemical blowing agents, supercritical fluids, combinations of any of the foregoing and others into a polymer matrix. The blowing agent is mixed with a polymer to form a substantially homogeneous mixture of the blowing agent in the melt. The blowing agent can be introduced into molten polymer in a molding machine, can be introduced with the resin in the hopper of the molding machine, can be incorporated as part of the resin, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> By way of example only, chemical blowing agents can be an inert agent, such as CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, or other inert gas. The agent and the melt are mixed at first conditions (usually high pressures) so that the agent mixes with melt. In some instances, the blowing agent can be a supercritical fluid that is solublized in the polymer melt at the first conditions (e.g., high pressure and temperature) in order to create a substantially homogeneous single-phase solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The first conditions are maintained until the formation of the cells is desired. Foaming, in turn, can be accomplished by changing the first conditions to second conditions (usually ambient pressures). The change from the first to the second conditions causes the agent to expand, forming bubbles in the melt. This change in conditions (from the first to the second) can be a change in temperature, a change in pressure, or combinations thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The melt is injected into a mold while at the second conditions or while the conditions are being changed to the second conditions. The mold is cooled to return the melt to a solid state, which forms the cover. The bubbles formed by the agent in the melt result in the cells or hollows being formed in the cover. It is known to form foamed polymers having cells of less than about 10 microns in diameter, known as micro cellular materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As the mold is cooled, the heat removed from the portion of the melt in contact with the mold causes the agent in that portion to contract such that a skin is formed on the surface of the finished part. The skin is substantially free of the cells or hollows. The thickness of the skin is dependent upon how rapidly the heat is removed from the surfaces of the melt that are in contact with the mold. During normal molding cycle times and temperatures, the skin is formed having a minimum thickness of about 0.0002 inches. However, the thickness of the skin can be increased by removing the heat from the melt more rapidly. Alternately, the thickness of the skin can be decreased by slowing the removal of heat from the melt. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Of course, it should be recognized that the process for forming a foamed polymer is described above by way of example only. Other methods of forming a foamed polymer are contemplated. Accordingly, any method for forming the cells. Turning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, exemplary embodiments of molding apparatus for the manufacture of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are illustrated. Of course, it should be recognized that alternate molding apparatus for the manufacture of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are illustrated. For example, part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be injection molded, injection compression molded, extrusion compression molded, extrusion deposition compression molded, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> first exemplary embodiment of an apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is illustrated. The apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is configured to form the foamed fiber reinforced part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> comprises an extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, an injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and a mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a raw material inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a reinforcing fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and a blowing agent inlet <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Of course, it should be recognized that in alternate embodiments, the raw material inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can is also configured to have the blowing agent introduced at the raw material inlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The raw material inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce a thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Here, the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is in contact with the twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is configured to melt the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is any thermoplastic material suitable for the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. For example, thermoplastic resins <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> comprising polypropylene, engineering thermoplastics such as polyester, nylon, polycarbonate, and TPV and TPE based elastomers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. In the event the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is hygroscopic, a dryer can be used to remove moisture before the resin enters the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The reinforcing fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the molten or semi-molten thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is configured to mix the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to form a fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are any fiber material suitable for the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as but not limited to glass fibers, natural fibers, polyaramid fibers (e.g., Kevlar fibers commercially available from DuPont), carbon fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, prior methods of making reinforced fiber parts introduced the fibers to the extrusion machine by incorporating the fibers into the resin, which limits the maximum length of the fibers to about 8 millimeters (mm) because of the pellet size. It has been determined that feeding the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (e.g., downstream of the inlet <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) allows for fibers having a longer length than previously possible to be incorporated into the part. For example, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is configured to provide the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having of a length of at least about 25 mm, and up to about 100 mm. Accordingly, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> enables the manufacture of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that are significantly longer than possible from prior machines/methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In a first exemplary embodiment, the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are fed into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as chopped fibers. Here, the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are individual fibers, bundles of fibers, and/or combinations thereof. By introducing chopped fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> aids in the dispersion of the fibers in the resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> as randomly oriented reinforcing fibers. Parts <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having randomly oriented reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be formed, depending on gating and part design, having isotropic properties. Namely, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> exhibits equal strength when measured along all axes of the part. It has also been determined that the foaming of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can aid in the isotropic dispersion of fibers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In an alternate exemplary embodiment, the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are fed into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as continuous elongated fibers. Here, the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are drawn into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as individual fibers, bundles of fibers, and/or combinations thereof. By drawing the continuous fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, the fibers are dispersed in the resin such that they are substantially oriented along the axis of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be preheated and/or pre-stretched to open up the bundle for improved wetting. Parts <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having such substantially oriented reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> exhibit non-isotropic properties. Namely, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> exhibits unequal strength when measured along the different axes of the part. In sum, the non-isotropic part exhibits greater strength in the direction of the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> as compared to the direction normal to the fibers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The agent inlet <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce a blowing agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> into the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is configured to admix the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the blowing agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to form a fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In an exemplary embodiment, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a sealing element <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, an inlet valve <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and an outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The sealing element <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is disposed about the twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> between the fiber inlet <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and the agent inlet <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The inlet valve <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> seals the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at the agent inlet <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> seals the outlet of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Thus, a sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is defined by the sealing element <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and the valves <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The blowing agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is introduced into the sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at the agent inlet <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by opening the inlet valve <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, while the outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is open. The sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is maintained at first or supercritical conditions (e.g., elevated pressure and appropriate temperatures) where the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is in a liquid form. The sealing element <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is configured to permit the flow of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into the sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. However, the sealing element <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> prevents the flow of the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> back towards the inlets <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is maintained at first conditions sufficient to maintain the blowing agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in a liquid form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> After the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is injected into the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the inlet valve <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is closed. The twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> admixes the liquid blowing agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> such that the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is a substantially homogeneous mixture of the blowing agent in the melt. The fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is maintained at the first conditions until the formation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is opened to transfer the melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. With the outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> open, the twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> advances the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> until a shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of a desired quantity accumulates therein. The injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes a plunger <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> that is movable disposed within the injection machine. Initially, the plunger is in a first or retracted position (e.g., remote from the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). Once the shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> has accumulated in the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the inlet valve <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and the outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are closed and the twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> stops. The injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> moves the plunger <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> from the first position to a second position (e.g., proximate to the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) to inject the shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> into the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> where the mold forms the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the desired shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When the formation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is desired, the first conditions will be adjusted to second conditions. As will be described in more detail below, the change from the first to the second conditions can occur at several different points in the process. The second conditions are sufficient to convert the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> from the liquid form to a gaseous form. For example, the pressure is reduced from the first conditions to the second conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The gaseous agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> expands and forms bubbles in the melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, which forms the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This change in conditions (from the first to the second condition) changes the blowing agent to a gas by subjecting the mixture to for example, a rapid change in temperature, a rapid change in pressure, or combinations thereof. It is known to form foamed polymers having cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of less than about 10 microns in diameter (e.g., micro cellular materials). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is initially in a closed position. The injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> injects the shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> into the closed mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> by moving the plunger <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> from the first to the second position. The mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is cooled, and the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is ejected. Meanwhile, the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> retracts the plunger <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> as the outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is re-opened and the twin-screw extruder <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> re-starts to repeat the process. At this time, the shut off valve is closed and outlet valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is open. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is cooled to return the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to a solid or non-molten state prior to being removed from the mold. As the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is cooled, the heat removed from the portion of the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in contact with the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. This causes the gaseous agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the portion of the resin <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in contact with the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to contract such that substantially no cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are formed on the surface of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Namely, the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is formed having the skin <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> on its surfaces in contact with the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, wherein the skin does not include cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> While in the sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and combinations thereof, the first conditions on the melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>/shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are changed to the second conditions to allow the liquid agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to convert to a gas and expand to form the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the first conditions are changed to the second conditions during the injection of the shot <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> from the injection machine <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the mold <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, the addition of the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> increases the viscosity of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> typically has a maximum viscosity level beyond which it can no longer function effectively. This maximum viscosity level sets a limit on the total amount of fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that can be introduced to the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Thus, this maximum viscosity level sets a limit on the total amount of fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that can be used to form the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> However, the addition of the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> reduces the viscosity of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Namely, the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is less viscous than the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> has a viscosity that can be about 60% lower than that of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Also in an exemplary embodiment, the viscosity of the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> can be about 10% lower than that of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Of course, higher and lower viscosity reductions are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The reduction in viscosity is advantageously used by the present disclosure to provide additional fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Specifically, it has been determined that the viscosity increase caused by the addition of the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be offset by introducing the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (which reduces viscosity) downstream of the fibers. Thus, apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce higher volumes of fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> than previously possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In prior methods/machines, where the reinforcing agents were part of the resin pellets, the maximum viscosity level of prior extrusion machines was reached at about 30% by weight of the reinforcing agent. Thus, prior extrusion machines are capable of producing parts having about 30% by weight of the reinforcing agent. However, by introducing the fiber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> as described above, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is particularly adapted to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having at least about 10% by weight of the part, with up to about 70% by weight of the fibers preferred and minimum degradation of the fibers. Accordingly, not only does the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> produce part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having longer fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> than previously possible, but it also produces parts having significantly more fibers by weight incorporated in the part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is particularly adapted to produce parts <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a maximum number of wetted fibers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and a minimum number of un-wetted fibers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This is accomplished by controlling the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to adjust, for example, the amount of the fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> fed into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the amount of the agent <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> injected into the sealed section <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the type of the agent injected into the sealed section, the pressure within the sealed section, the temperature within the sealed section, the pressure drop between the first and second conditions, and combinations of any or all of the foregoing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> By way of example, the apparatus <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is particularly adapted to produce a part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having: a part density of at least about 95% of a non-foamed part, up to about 75%, with about 5% to about 40% preferred; having a cell size of at least about 10 microns, up to about 200 microns; fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having a length of at least about 25 mm, with up to about 100 mm preferred; and fibers <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in an amount of at least about 10% by weight of the part, with up to about 70% by weight preferred. In an exemplary embodiment of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the part has a density of about 0.7 to 0.8 grams per cubic centimeter (g/cc). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> An alternate exemplary embodiment of an apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for forming the fiber reinforced part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As will be described in detail below, the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is configured for the in-line compounding/extrusion followed by deposition and compression molding of the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises an extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and a tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is adapted to produce a fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is configured for movement with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to deposit the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> on the tool. For example, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> can be configured to move between a first position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) and a second position (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). Of course, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> can also be configured to evenly deposit the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> on the tool, such as by moving with respect to the tool in an x-direction, a y-direction and a z-direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> comprises a press <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> with a mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is configured to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the desired shape and size. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is further configured to distribute the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> on the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is adapted to move with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to evenly distribute the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> in the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. For example, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is configured to move in at least tow directions with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, preferably three directions, to evenly distribute the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> in the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The press <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is adapted to compress the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> about the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> such that the mold forms the desired part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by a compression molding technique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> comprises a barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> having an internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> extending along a longitudinal axis thereof. The internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is generally divided into three zones, namely a first zone <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, a second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and a third zone <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Each of the zones <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> performs an operation useful in the compounding/extrusion process as will be described in greater detail hereinafter. It should be understood that the relative size of each of the zones <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> has been illustrated for purpose of illustration and clarity only and it is contemplated that the lengths of these zones <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> differ depending upon the application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> extends from the first end <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Here, the first zone <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> starts at the first end <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> transitions from the first zone <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> to the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> down stream of the first end <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> transitions to the third zone <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, which ends proximate the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Located at the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is a die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> including a blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is illustrated at the exit of the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to minimize gas pre-expansion in the die. The blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> opens (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) and closes (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) during operation of the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to allow the melt to exit the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is in fluid communication with the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> at the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is designed to provide the selective fluid communication between the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. In the closed position, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is prevented from advancing material from the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). As a result, material disposed within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is prevented from freely exiting the die or communicating with the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Thus, when the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is closed, the rotation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> advances and mixes the melt, fiber, and agent so that the melt accumulates in the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> before the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. In the open position, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is allowed to advance material from the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is preferably cylindrical in shape and has a diameter great enough to permit a screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to be disposed therein. Preferably, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is sized to fit in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> so as to be rotatably disposed therein. Namely, the widest diameter of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is slightly less than the inner diameter of the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is configured to receive the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> in a manner which allows the screw to rotate therein. The screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, a first end <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, a second end <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, and a head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> are designed to advance the material through the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> as the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> rotates. Namely, the flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> at the first end <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> are larger (e.g., deeper) than the flights at the second end <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is provided at the second end <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. When the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is inserted into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> is inserted into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> at the first end <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and is advanced therein towards the opposing second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> comprises a first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and a third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> disposed at its outer surface. The first, second and third inlets are in fluid communication with the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises a bore extending from the outer surface of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and is substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the barrel. The first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce a thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> into the first zone <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary illustrated embodiment, the first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is preferably cylindrical in shape. Of course, the first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having other cross-sectional shapes is contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The diameter of the first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is of a sufficient dimension to permit the inlet of thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to be introduced there through into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. As the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> enters the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, it enters into the first zone <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The compression ratio is generally defined as a comparison of the channel depth of the last flight of the first zone and the channel depth of the first flight in the third zone. The channel depth (flight depth) is the distance from the outer edge of a flight <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to the outer surface of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Increasing the compression ratio also increases the heat on the resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Thus, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is designed so that as the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> enters the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> through the first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the depth of the plurality of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is decreased. By decreasing the depth of the plurality of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, the compression ratio is increased. For example, between the first and second inlets <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> the depth of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> transition quickly from a deep flight depth to a shallow flight depth. The flight depth should be deep enough to create a compression ratio greater than about 3.5:1 in the first zone. In an exemplary embodiment, the compression ratio is preferably about 8:1 to aid in the rapid melting of the incoming thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> before it reaches the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In exemplary embodiments, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> can include double flights or high shear elements to aid in the rapid melting of the incoming thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> before it reaches the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Thus, as the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is introduced into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, it contacts the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and is disposed there around and between the plurality of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> which serves to advance and melt the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> towards the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> as the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is rotated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is precisely sized to fit the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and allow a very narrow gap <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to exist between the outer diameter of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> (e.g., the flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>) and the diameter of the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> has a preselected diameter (D) and length (L) such that the L/D is large. Preferably, the L/D is greater than or equal to about 16:1, with greater than or equal to about 35:1 more preferred. It is generally known that the higher the L/D ratio, the higher will be the surface available for shearing, mixing, and melting the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Higher L/D ratios also allow for gentle mixing of the fibers and polymer, without degradation of glass fiber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is designed to receive a hopper <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The hopper <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> comprises a funnel-like holder capable of holding the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes but is not limited to any thermoplastic material suitable for the desired part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. For example, the thermoplastic material can include polypropylene, engineering thermoplastics such as polyester, nylon, polycarbonate, and TPV and TPE based elastomers, with polypropylene being preferred. In one exemplary embodiment, the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> comprises a quantity of polypropylene pellets that are fed through the hopper <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The melting is accomplished by maintaining a predetermined compression ratio of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> as the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, e.g., plastic pellets, is advanced forward within the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> by the plurality of flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, similar to the first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, comprises a bore extending from the outer surface of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The second inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> into the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> opens into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> so that the fibers may be introduced thereto from outside of the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary illustrated embodiment, the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is preferably cylindrical in shape. However, as can be appreciated, other shapes are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of the cavity is configured to shear and impregnate the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with the resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> design in this second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> has a deep flight depth however the flight depth throughout the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> remains constant so that there is zero compression in the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. In other words, the compression ratio is zero because there is no change in the depth of the flights <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in the second zone <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Again, the fiber feed area has deeper flight depths as mentioned above. The actual screw flight depth depends on the number of fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> drawn into the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and the type of the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> used. A deep flight depth is necessary in the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to accommodate a larger volume of fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The flight depth should be as high as possible based on the structural integrity of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, which is dependant on the screw diameter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> preferably includes a reinforcing fiber guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> comprises any number of guides designed to separate individual reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> from one another so that the individual reinforcing fibers do not become entangled with one another as they are drawn into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. In this example, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are individual fibers, bundles of fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. In the example where fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are bundles of fibers, each bundle is comprised of multiple fibers. Hereinafter, individual fibers and bundles of fibers are collectively referred to as &ldquo;fibers&rdquo;. The fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are formed of any suitable fiber material including but not limited to glass fibers, natural fibers, polyaramid fibers (e.g., Kevlar fibers commercially available from DuPont), carbon fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> For example, the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may be formed so that the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> comprises at least one bore formed in and extending through the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, wherein one fiber <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is received within one bore. Each fiber <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is drawn into the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> from at least one winding/unwinding reel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, three reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are provided. Here, each reel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> feeds a fiber <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> into the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Of courser; more or less than three reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> feeding more than one fiber <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is useful in directing the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> into the proper location in the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and works in conjunction with the winding/unwinding reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to keep the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in a constant taut state. In the exemplary embodiment shown, the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> comprises a rotatable member having a plurality of grooves formed therein for separating individual fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> from one another so that the individual fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> do not become entangled during the feeding process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are preferably located above the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and are drawn from an equal number of spools <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> containing the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. While the exemplary embodiment shows the spools <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> as having a round shape, it is understood that the other shapes may be used. There is one spool <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> feeding each reel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The movement of the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> sets in motion the winding and unwinding of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> on the reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> For example, the rotation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> draws the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> from the reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, through the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The unwinding of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> from the reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> results in the accompanying unwinding from the associated spools <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the movement of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> with respect to the reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> (e.g., movement of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> towards the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) also results in the accompanying unwinding from the associated spools <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. However, when this movement is reversed (e.g., movement of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> away from the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>) the reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> wind the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so as not to allow for any slack in the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Thus, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are consistently under tension regardless of the positioning of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The movement of the winding/unwinding reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> can be generated by a servo-driven motor (not shown) or by pre-tension created by spring loading the reel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> or any other mechanical means. For example, the servo-driven motor is controlled to unwind or wind the reinforcing fiber bundles <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> depending upon the relative position of the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> with respect to the reel <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> As the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> pass from the guide <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are opened for proper melt impregnation. Specifically, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are opened by the guide for better wetting so that each fiber can be wetted or coated with the melted thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. It is also understood that pre-heating the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> after the fiber pass the winding/unwinding reels <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> but prior to entrance into the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is contemplated. This results in increased wetability of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> with the melted thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The fibers can also be pretreated (heat and/or tension) as discussed earlier for improved wetting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are sheared or broken to a desirable length. The shearing is accomplished as the tensile load on the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is increased so that each of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> shears in approximately the same length. As the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> move through the second zone <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, the resistance on the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> increases so that when the resistance becomes too great, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are sheared or broken forming individual sheared reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. This is achieved by proper design of the screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> By drawing the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> into the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are provided at a greater length than previously possible. For example in a first exemplary embodiment, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is configured to provide fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> having a length of at least 25 mm. In an alternate embodiment, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is configured to provide fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> having a length up to about 100 mm. By way of comparison, prior methods of feeding reinforcing fibers incorporated into the resin pellets provided fibers having a maximum length of about 8 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are mixed with the molten and/or semi-molten thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> such that the fibers are dispersed in the molten resin to form a fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Due to the tension on the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> as they are drawn into the thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the reinforcing fibers are axially oriented along a common direction (e.g., along the axis of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>). Thus, the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can be configured to produce part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having the fibers substantially aligned in one direction (e.g., non-isotropic parts). Namely, the geometry of the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> can be configured such that non-isotropic parts are produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce a blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> into the third zone <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Similar to the first and second inlets, the third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> comprises a bore extending from the outer surface of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is substantially perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, preferably on the top of the barrel. The third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> opens into the internal cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> so that the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be introduced thereto from outside of the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Thus, the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is a closed system where the agent is added therein. In the exemplary illustrated embodiment, the third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is preferably cylindrical in shape. The third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is positioned down stream of the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The first inlet <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is thus closer to the first end <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> than the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, while the third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is closer to the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> than the second inlet <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> further comprises a sealing element <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and an inlet valve <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The sealing element <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> seals the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> prior to the third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the inlet valve <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> seals the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> at the third inlet <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> seals the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> provide selective fluid communication with the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Thus, a sealed section <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is introduced into the sealed section <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> by opening the inlet valve <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. The sealing element <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is configured to permit the flow of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> into the sealed section <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. However, the element <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is also configured to prevent the flow of the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> back towards the first and second inlets <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is configured to admix the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> with the blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to form a fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The sealed section <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> is maintained at first conditions sufficient to maintain the blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in a liquid form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> After the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is injected into the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the inlet valve <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is closed. The screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> admixes the liquid blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> such that the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is a substantially homogeneous mixture of the blowing agent in the melt. The fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is maintained at the first conditions until the formation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The continued rotation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> advances the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> towards the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> of the screw. In addition to being rotatable, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> can also be configured to reciprocate within the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Namely, the continued rotation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> advances the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> until a shot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> accumulates in the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> between the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. The accumulation of the shot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> causes the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to retract or move the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> away from the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In order to force the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> from the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is opened and the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is moved forward until the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> of the screw abuts a beveled portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> of the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The beveled portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> has a shape complementary to the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> so that the beveled portion acts as a stop for the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> as the screw is driven in a direction towards the second end <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The beveled portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> includes and defines a central opening <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> in fluid communication with the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. Thus, the shot <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is forced from the barrel <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> by opening the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and moving the blade <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> forward until the head <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> abuts the beveled portion <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In this manner, the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> urges the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> through the die <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and out of the die at its exit port <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>. As discussed above, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is configured to move with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> moves with respect to the tool <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> so that the exit port <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> evenly distributes the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> on the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The reciprocation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> allows for the deposition of the melt on the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Not shown is the means by which the rotation and reciprocation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is accomplished. Any conventional means can be utilized. Here, the speed of rotation of the screw <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is dependant on the type of thermoplastic resin <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the amount of the cut reinforcing fibers <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, and blowing agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Once the formation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is desired, the first conditions will be adjusted to second conditions. The second conditions are sufficient to convert the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> from the liquid form a gas (e.g., the pressure is reduced). The gaseous agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> expands and forms bubbles in the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to form the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. This change in conditions (from the first to the second condition) changes the blowing agent to a gas by subjecting the mixture to for example, a rapid change in temperature, a rapid change in pressure, or combinations thereof. The change from the first to the second conditions can occur at a desired location in the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, the change from the first to the second conditions occurs as the melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is urged from the cavity <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> onto the mold <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Namely, the first conditions are be adjusted to second conditions in the third zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The addition of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> increases the viscosity of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> typically has a maximum viscosity level beyond which it can no longer function effectively. This maximum viscosity level sets a limit on the total amount of fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> that can be introduced to the extrusion machine <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. Thus, this maximum viscosity level sets a limit on the total amount of fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> that can be used to form the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> However, the addition of the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> reduces the viscosity of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Namely, the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> has a viscosity that is lower than that of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, the viscosity of the fiber/resin/agent melt <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is lower than that of the fiber/resin melt <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> by preferably greater than or equal to about 10%, with about 60% more preferred. Of course, higher and lower viscosity reductions are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The reduction in viscosity is advantageously used by the present disclosure to provide additional fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Specifically, it has been determined that the viscosity increase caused by the addition of the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> can be offset by introducing the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> (which reduces viscosity) downstream of the fibers. Thus, apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is configured to introduce higher volumes of fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> into the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> than previously possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> When the reinforcing agents were introduced as part of the resin pellets, the maximum viscosity level of prior extrusion machines was reached at about 30% by weight of the reinforcing agent. Thus, prior extrusion machines are capable of producing parts having about 30% by weight of the reinforcing agent. However, by introducing the fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and the agent <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> as described above, the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is particularly adapted to produce the part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having at least about 10% by weight of the part, up to about 70% by weight of the fibers. Accordingly, not only does the apparatus <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> produce part <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having longer fibers <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> than previously possible, but it also produces parts having significantly more fibers by weight incorporated in the part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> It should be recognized that apparatuses <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are illustrated above by way of example only, other extrusion machines capable of in line compounding of thermoplastic resins with fibers, followed by formation of the cells <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are contemplated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to an exemplary embodiment, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part, comprising: 
<claim-text>a member formed of thermoplastic resin; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of cells and a plurality of reinforcing fibers dispersed within said member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a skin formed on at least one exterior surface of said member, said skin being substantially devoid of said cells, said reinforcing fibers having a length of at least about 25 mm, said reinforcing fibers comprising an amount of at least about 10% by weight of said foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part, wherein at least one of a cell density and a cell size of said plurality of cells is inversely proportional to said amount of said reinforcing fibers dispersed within said member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers have a length of less than about 100 mm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said amount is less than about 70% by weight of said foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers are selected from the group consisting of glass fibers, natural fibers, polyaramid fibers, carbon fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers comprise individual fibers, bundles of fibers, continuous fibers, chopped fibers, and combinations of one or more of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a portion of said reinforcing fibers are randomly oriented within said member to impart isotropic properties to said foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a portion of said reinforcing fibers are oriented within said member to impart non-isotropic properties to said foamed thermoplastic resin fiber reinforced part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cell density is about is about 5 percent to about 40 percent of a non-foamed part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cell size is about 10 microns to about 200 microns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The part as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said thermoplastic resin is selected from the group consisting of polypropylene, engineering thermoplastics, polyester, nylon, polycarbonate, TPV based elastomers, TPE based elastomers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for producing a foamed fiber reinforced part, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a barrel having an internal cavity formed therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inlet for feeding a thermoplastic material into said internal cavity; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second inlet downstream of said first inlet, said second inlet feeding reinforcing fibers into said internal cavity, said second inlet having at least one tensioning reel for feeding said reinforcing fibers under a constant tension; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third inlet downstream of said second inlet, said third inlet for selectively injecting a blowing agent into said internal cavity; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a screw rotatably disposed within said internal cavity of said barrel such that a first zone, a second zone, and a third zone of said barrel are defined, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first zone being configured for melting of said thermoplastic material, said second zone being configured for shearing said reinforcing fibers to a predetermined length, said second zone being configured to form a first melt from said thermoplastic material and said reinforcing fibers, and said third zone forming a second melt from said first melt and said blowing agent, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said third zone being configured to maintain said second melt at a first condition sufficient to maintain said blowing agent in a desired form, said second melt being exposed to a second condition sufficient to cause said blowing agent to form cells in said second melt when said second melt is forced from said internal cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said blowing agent reduces a viscosity of said second melt as compared to said first melt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said screw is retractable by a shot of said second melt as said shot accumulates at a head of said screw, and said screw being extendable to force said shot from said barrel into a mold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a sealing element seals said third zone such that said blowing agent is sealed from said second zone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said screw is accumulates a shot of said second melt in a plunger, said plunger being extendable to force said shot into a mold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein rotation of said screw draws said reinforcing fibers into said second zone under said constant tension. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second zone is configured to shear said reinforcing fibers to a length of about 25 mm to about 100 mm, and being configured to introduce said reinforcing fibers in said amount of about 10% by weight to about 70% by weight. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers are selected from the group consisting of glass fibers, natural fibers, polyaramid fibers, carbon fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers comprise individual fibers, bundles of fibers, continuous fibers, chopped fibers, and combinations of one or more of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said blowing agent is selected from the group consisting of physical blowing agents, chemical blowing agents, supercritical fluids, and combinations of any of the foregoing </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for producing a foamed fiber reinforced part, comprising: 
<claim-text>an extrusion machine comprising a twin-screw extruder, said twin-screw extruder being in fluid communication with a first inlet, a second inlet, and a third inlet, said second inlet being intermediate said first and third inlets, said first inlet being configured to introduce a thermoplastic resin to said twin-screw extruder, said second inlet being configured to introduce reinforcing fibers to said twin-screw extruder, said twin-screw extruder being configured to form a first melt from said thermoplastic resin and said reinforcing fibers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sealed section defined in said extrusion machine, said sealed section being defined at said third inlet, said third inlet being configured to inject a blowing agent into said sealed section, said twin-screw extruder being configured to form a second melt from said first melt and said blowing agent, said sealed section maintaining said blowing agent at a first condition; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an injection machine in fluid communication with an output of said extrusion machine, said injection machine being configured to receive said second melt from said sealed section, said injection machine being configured to inject said second melt into a mold, said injection machine being configured to change said first conditions to second conditions when said second melt is injected into said mold, said second conditions being sufficient to cause said blowing agent to form a plurality of cells in said second melt, and said mold being configured to form said second melt into a part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second inlet is configured to introduce said reinforcing fibers to said twin-screw extruder having a length of about 25 mm to about 100 mm, and being configured to introduce said reinforcing fibers in said amount of about 10% by weight of said part to about 70% by weight of said part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers are selected from the group consisting of glass fibers, natural fibers, polyaramid fibers, carbon fibers, and combinations of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said reinforcing fibers comprise individual fibers, bundles of fibers, continuous fibers, chopped fibers, and combinations of one or more of any of the foregoing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said extrusion machine is configured such that at least a portion of said reinforcing fibers are randomly oriented within said part to impart isotropic properties to said part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said extrusion machine is configured such that at least a portion of said reinforcing fibers are oriented within said part to impart non-isotropic properties to said part. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said blowing agent is selected from the group consisting of physical blowing agents, chemical blowing agents, supercritical fluids, and combinations of any of the foregoing.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003291A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003291A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003291A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003291A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
