<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002356A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002356A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002356</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10152267</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020521</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-38019</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>194000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Signal delay control circuit in a semiconductor memory device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jae</given-name>
<middle-name>Jin</middle-name>
<family-name>Lee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Ichon-shi</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MARSHALL, GERSTEIN &amp; BORUN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>6300 SEARS TOWER</address-1>
<address-2>233 SOUTH WACKER</address-2>
<city>CHICAGO</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606-6357</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A signal delay control circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device is disclosed. The circuit includes a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to drive input and output operations of internal circuits; and an impedance circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages to be applied to the internal circuits wherein the reference voltages are set in accordance with a distance between the control signal generating unit and the respective one of the internal circuits. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to semiconductor memory devices and, more specifically, to a signal delay control circuit for use in a memory device to improve the delay difference of signals resulting from components or circuits spaced a different distance from a transmission device such as a control circuit. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In a general semiconductor memory device, signal delays proportional to the propagation distances occur when a signal is transmitted from a specific position to circuit elements or devices at various positions. A typical configuration of a semiconductor memory device wherein signal delays are dependent on propagation distance of signals is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> control signal such as a clock signal is generated from a control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is positioned at the center area of a chip. An output pin DQm of a data pin array is located relatively near to the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> while an output pin DQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is relatively far away from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. When data bits are output from the output pins DQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DQm in response to the clock signal generated from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a data bit from DQm outputs earlier than that from DQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Also, an address pin A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is relatively near to the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> while an address pin An is relatively far away from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Thus, when address bits are input into the chip through the address pins A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to An in response to the clock signal generated from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the input of the address bit through address pin A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is faster than that through address address pin An. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> clock signal A is applied to a data input/output circuit which is near to the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> while a clock signal B is applied to another data input/output circuit which is far away from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The slopes at the rising edges of the clock signals A and B are different from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Briefly, a delay difference between pins based on input positions of the clock signal, is usually more than 1 ns (nanosecond) in a semiconductor memory chip having a chip size of 1 cm by 2 cm and having data output pins disposed at the side region stretching over 1 cm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As aforementioned, a device which outputs data signals synchronized with the clock signal (e.g., SDRAM (synchronous DRAM)), has various output times due to the difference of the slope of the rising edge (or a rising time of the clock signal) in accordance with the distance between the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the data input/output circuits. A data output circuit adjacent to the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> outputs a data bit quickly, while another data output circuit located away from the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> outputs a data bit slowly. Such a difference in data output time causes a valid data window to be narrower and acts as an obstacle for high frequency operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In order to minimize the difference in data output time, transmission lines of clock signals are conventionally arranged with a tree shape in order to unify the distance between a clock driver (e.g., the control signal generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and data output buffers. However, there is a problem in the conventional approach in that an excessive increase of circuit area is required for adjusting minute delay times. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an aspect of the invention, a signal delay control circuit is provided for use in a semiconductor memory device. The signal delay control circuit comprises a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to drive an operation of internal circuits; and an impedance circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages to be applied to respective ones of the internal circuits. Each of the reference voltages is set in accordance with a distance between the control signal generating unit and the respective one of the internal circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, a signal delay control circuit is provided for use in a semiconductor memory device. The signal delay control circuit comprises: a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control input and output operations for data bits; a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and a plurality of data output units for outputting data bits from the semiconductor memory device in response to a respective one of the reference voltages. Each of the reference voltages corresponds to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the data output units. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, a signal delay control circuit is provided for use in a semiconductor memory device. The signal delay control circuit comprises: a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control input operations for address bits; a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and a plurality of address input circuits for controlling strobe operations in response to a respective one of the reference voltages. Each of the reference voltages corresponds to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the address input circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with still another aspect of the invention, a signal delay control circuit is provided for use in a semiconductor memory device. The signal delay control circuit comprises: a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control operations of sense amplifiers; a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and a plurality of sense amplifier drive circuits for controlling operations of sense amplifiers in response to a respective one of the reference voltages. Each of the reference voltages corresponds to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the address input circuits.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating an arrangement of pins on a conventional semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a waveform diagram explaining a signal delay in the conventional semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic circuit diagram illustrating an exemplary signal delay control circuit of a semiconductor memory circuit constructed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram of an exemplary data output circuit employed in the signal delay circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> are schematic diagrams explaining a characteristic of the data output circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of another exemplary signal delay control circuit constructed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of still another signal delay control circuit constructed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EXAMPLES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a signal delay control circuit. The signal delay control circuit includes first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a resistor circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The resistor circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, connected between output terminals of the first and second reference voltages, outputs different reference voltages to each data unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> generates a clock signal and a control signal to control an operation of transmitting data. The data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> respectively output data in response to the clock signal supplied from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of data output units. Four data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are shown in this example, but other numbers are possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> connected between a power supply voltage terminal and an output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. It also includes NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> connected in series between the output terminal <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a ground voltage terminal. The PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a gate coupled to the ground voltage terminal and is used as a load element. The gates and drains of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are connected in common. The NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are used as a diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> connected between the power supply voltage terminal and an output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. It also includes NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> connected in series between the output terminal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the ground voltage terminal. The PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has a gate coupled to the ground voltage terminal and is used as a load element. The gates and drains of the NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are connected in common. The transistors N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are used as a diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are connected through the resistor circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The resistor circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed of PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected in series between the reference output terminals <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The gates of the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are coupled to the ground voltage terminal so that the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are always turned on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the resistor circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are provided to respective data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Also, a clock signal CLK supplied from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is applied to enable operations of the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are established at nodes between the PMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, between the first voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and between transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the second voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are established to correspond to distances between the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Each reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is assigned to one of the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A data bit DATA is applied to the data output units in common. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a detailed illustration of an exemplary data output unit (e.g., the first data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). The structures of the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are preferably the same. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the first data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistors N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, which are connected in series between the power supply voltage terminal and the ground voltage terminal. An inverted clock signal (CLKB) of a clock signal (CLK) is generated at a common drain node of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Gates of the PMOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, are commonly coupled to the clock signal CLK from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A gate of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is coupled to the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A data bit DATA applied to the first data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is transferred to a transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through an inverter IV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. One electrode of the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is directly coupled to the inverted clock signal CLKB, and another electrode of the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is coupled to CLKB through an inverter IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The data bit DATA passing through the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is transferred to a transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> through a latch L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> formed of inverters IV<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and IV<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> One electrode of the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is directly coupled to the inverted clock signal CLKB, and another electrode of the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is coupled to CLKB through an inverter IV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The data bit DATA passing through the transmission gate TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is applied through an inverter IV<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to a common gate node of PMOS and NMOS transistors, P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, which are connected between the power supply voltage terminal and the ground voltage terminal. The data bit DATA is generated at the output pin DQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through a common drain node of the PMOS and NMOS transistors P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The first data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, is the one that is furthest from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> supplying the clock signal CLK. The nearest data output unit is DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In the convention used herein, the data output units are referenced as &ldquo;Dum&rdquo;, where m is a number indicating the relative distance from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in decreasing order. In the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the nomenclature indicates that, of the data output units DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is closest, DU<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is next closest, DU<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is next closest, and DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is farthest relative to the unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> When the clock signal CLK is applied to the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in common, the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> corresponding to the distances between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the respective data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are applied to their corresponding data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the clock signal CLK can be applied to the transmission gates TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> when the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is turned on by the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. As a result, an arrival time of the clock signal CLK (or CLKB) at the transmission gates TG<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and TG<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is controlled by the turn-on time of the NMOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in responding to the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Though the clock signal CLK is applied to the data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> with a small value of a rising slope due to a time delay through a path between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the first data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a voltage level regarding the time delay and can, therefore, compensate for the physical time delay. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> An operation of the signal delay control circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> will now be explained. It is assumed that the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is established at 3V by the first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the reference voltage Vrefm (i.e., node <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) is established at 2V by the second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> When the clock signal CLK is commonly applied to the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> (which are located different distances from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>), the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> receive the clock signal CLK with different rising slopes. A rising time of the clock signal CLK applied to the data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is fastest, while a rising time of the clock signal CLK is slowest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, in an example where: (1) a plurality of reference voltages (e.g., Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vrefm; where m is an integer) are provided corresponding to a plurality of data output units (e.g., DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DUm); and (2) each of the data output units has a different distance (e.g., X<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to Xm) from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vrefm are established such that their magnitudes decrease in relation to their corresponding positions Xm (the nearest position from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>) to X<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (the farthest position from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>), along a linear plot C representing an increasing rate of the reference voltages. That is, the lowest reference voltage Vrefm (i.e., Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), (e.g., 2V), is applied to the nearest data output unit DUm while the highest reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (e.g., 3V), is applied to the farthest data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The data output circuit located at the intermediate distance from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> will receive the intermediate reference voltage (e.g., 2.5V). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As a result, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the farthest data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> responds to the clock signal having the slowest rising edge E but receives the highest reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, the nearest data output unit DUm responds to the clock signal having the fastest rising edge D and receives the lowest reference voltage Vrefm (i.e., Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The difference between the rising edges D and E is caused from the difference of distance between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, due to physical delays on the clock signal paths between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the data output block <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The lowest reference voltage Vrefm (i.e., Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) makes the clock signal with the fastest rising edge D be introduced into the nearest data output unit DUm more slowly than any of the other reference voltages, assuming that the other data output circuits associated with the other reference voltages receive the clock signal CLK relatively later than the data output unit DUm. The highest reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> makes the clock signal with the fastest rising edge D be introduced into the farthest data output unit DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> faster than any of the other reference voltages, assuming that the other data output circuits associated with the other reference voltages receive the clock signal CLK relatively earlier than the data output unit DUm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Thus, the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to Vrefm, which correspond to the distances between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the data output units DU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to DUm, can compensate the difference of the rising slopes of the clock signal applied thereto, thereby offsetting the difference of delay times of the clock signal CLK, as shown at waveform F of a clock signal CLKB in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Data output times of the data output units are, thus, substantially equalized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> While the reference voltages are generated from the first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, one of the reference voltages can be assigned to the power supply voltage or the ground voltage supplied from the external voltage source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Further, it is possible not only to maintain the potentials of the reference voltages during all operation periods of the semiconductor memory chip, but also to use the reference voltages exclusively in a specific operation period. Such exclusive use in a specific operation mode would reduce current which flows between the output terminals of the first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> due to a voltage difference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The disclosed technique is available for use with other internal circuits, such as address input circuits and sense amplifier drive circuits, which respond to the clock signal in a synchronous semiconductor memory device, as well as to the data output circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows another exemplary signal delay control circuit applied to address input circuits. In general, the address input circuits, like the data output circuits, experience a problem resulting from differences in distance between the address input circuits and the device transmitting a drive signal. The problem is induced by discordance between setup time and hold time of input signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of a synchronous memory device are arranged to overcome the problems with the setup and hold times. The address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> make address strobe times of all the address input circuits be synchronized to a predetermined time by applying reference voltages corresponding to the distances between a control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the corresponding address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The number of the address input circuits is an example. Other numbers of the address input circuits could alternatively be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the signal delay control circuit for address input includes first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, a resistor circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, a control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AUn (where n is a positive integer). The first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> (which are located at both ends of an address input circuit block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> including the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AUn), generate reference voltages with different levels. A resistor circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> provides the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; to the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AUn. A control unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> generates a strobe clock signal SCLK to control input operations at the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AUn. The address input circuits receive address signals and control address strobe in response to the strobe clock signal SCLK. The resistor circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, which include resistors R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> connected in series between the first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, establishes the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; at nodes between the resistors R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, at a node between the first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and a resistor RI, and at a node between the second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&prime; are inversely proportional to the distances between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Each of the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> includes an input circuit <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, a delay circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, and a strobe circuit <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. The input circuits receive an address bit. The delay circuits provide a delay path for the input address bit in order to compensate the physical delays of the strobe clock signal SCLK in response to the reference voltage having a voltage level corresponding to the physical delay of the strobe clock signal SCLK. The strobe circuits hold the strobe clock signal SCLK by an internal clock signal and transfer the address bit into a decoder as an internal address bit IADD. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Since the distances of transmitting the strobe clock signal SCLK from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to the respective address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are different from each other, a lower reference voltage is applied to a delay circuit of an address input circuit which is nearer to the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, while a higher reference voltage is applied to a delay circuit of an address input circuit which is more distant from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Thus, a delay time of the delay circuit <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in an address input circuit (e.g., AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) which is nearer to the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is longer than that in an address input circuit (e.g., AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) which is more distant from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Namely, the delay times in the address input circuits AU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to AU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are differentiated from each other in accordance with their differences of distance from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As a result, the signal delay control structure for the address input circuits can compensate discordance of the setup and hold times due to the differences of the distance between the address input circuit block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> generating a control signal for address strobe operations thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The disclosed techniques are also applicable to sense amplifier drive circuits as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The number of the sense amplifier drive circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is exemplary in nature. Other numbers of sense amplifier drive circuits could alternatively be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the illustrated signal delay control circuit for the sense amplifier drive circuits includes a first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, a resistor circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, a control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and the sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The first and second reference voltage generating units <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (which are located at both ends of a sense amplifier drive block <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> including the sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), generate reference voltages with different levels. A resistor circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> provides corresponding ones of the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&Prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&Prime; to the sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> generates a signal RTO to control the sense amplifiers. The sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> receive the signal RTO. The second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> employs a ground voltage GND as the second reference voltage source. The resistor circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, (which is formed of resistors R<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> which are connected in series between the first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and the second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>), establishes the reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&Prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&Prime; at nodes between the resistors R<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, at a node between the first reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and at a node between the second reference voltage generating unit <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The reference voltages Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&Prime; to Vref<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>&Prime; are inversely proportional to the distances between the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and the sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Each of the sense amplifier drive circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is composed of: (a) a sense amplifier array (e.g., <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>) receiving the signal RTO from the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and (b) a sense amplifier driver (e.g., <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight>) activating the sense amplifier array in response to its corresponding reference voltage appropriately set by the resistor circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In an operation of the circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the sense amplifier drivers activate the sense amplifier arrays in response to their corresponding reference voltages provided from the resistor circuit <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The ground voltage GND is the lowest reference voltage and is applied to the driver <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> of the sense amplifier drive circuit SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which is nearest to the control signal generating unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> generating the signal RTO. The ground voltage GND makes the driver <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> conductive at a slow rate so as to reduce drivability of the sense amplifier array <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> of the nearest sense amplifier drive circuit SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, the reference voltage Vref<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&Prime; is the highest reference voltage and is applied to the sense amplifier array <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the sense amplifier drive circuit SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that is most distant from the control unit <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. As a result, drivability of the sense amplifier array <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the most distant sense amplifier drive circuit SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is enhanced relative to the others. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The adjustment of the different reference voltages in accordance with the transmission distances of the signal RTO minimizes timing discordance between the sense amplifier operations over the circuits SU<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to SU<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> even when there is transmission skew of the signal RTO. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> While the ground voltage GND is utilized as the second reference voltage, it is also possible to employ other circuits such as the second reference circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 8</cross-reference>. Similarly, the power supply voltage may be also used for the first reference voltage source. The teachings of the present invention are applicable to a general semiconductor memory device which experiences a transmission skew of a control signal that is applied to a plurality of internal circuits such as the data output circuits, address input circuits, or the sense amplifier drive circuits, as well as to the synchronous semiconductor memory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As described above, the disclosed devices produce improved operation timings of drive circuits by compensating or offsetting differences of transmission delays of a control signal that is applied to the drive circuits from a control unit. This technique is advantageous in minimizing discordance of data output times by discriminately activating data output circuits in accordance with the distances between the respective data output circuits and a control unit generating a control signal that is applied to the data output circuits. Moreover, this technique is helpful to synchronize address input times by minimizing differences of setup and hold times in address input circuits, and to stabilize operations of sense amplifiers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing, persons of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that a signal delay circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device has been provided which is capable of driving internal circuits without time differences of signal delay in the input and output operations. It will further be appreciated that a circuit has been provided which is capable of minimizing difference of output time at multiple output terminals by applying various voltages in accordance with the distance between a control signal source and the respective output terminals. It will further be appreciated that a circuit has been provided which is capable of synchronizing address input times by minimizing a time difference between a setup time and a hold time of an address input circuit. It will further be appreciated that a circuit has been provided which is capable of stabilizing operation states of sense amplifiers by synchronizing the conduction times of the sense amplifiers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Although certain apparatus constructed in accordance with the teachings of the invention have been described herein, the scope of coverage of this patent is not limited thereto. On the contrary, this patent covers all embodiments of the teachings of the invention fairly falling within the scope of the appended claims either literally or under the doctrine of equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A signal delay control circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device, the signal delay control circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to drive an operation of internal circuits; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an impedance circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages to be applied to respective ones of the internal circuits, wherein each of the reference voltages is set in accordance with a distance between the control signal generating unit and the respective one of the internal circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the internal circuits are one of the group comprising data output circuits, address input circuits, and sense amplifier drive circuits. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A signal delay control circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device, the signal delay control circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control input and output operations for data bits; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of data output units for outputting data bits from the semiconductor memory device in response to a respective one of the reference voltages, each of the reference voltages corresponding to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the data output units. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first reference voltage generating unit comprises: 
<claim-text>a load element connected between a power supply voltage terminal and an output terminal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of diode elements connected in series between the output terminal and a ground voltage terminal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second reference voltage generating unit comprises: 
<claim-text>a load element connected between a power supply voltage terminal and an output terminal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of diode elements connected in series between the output terminal and a ground voltage terminal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the load element is a PMOS transistor whose gate is grounded. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the resistive circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a plurality of resistors connected between the first and second reference voltage generating units; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of nodes, each of the nodes being connected to a respective one of the data output units. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the respective reference voltage of each of the data output units is proportional to the distance between the control signal generating unit and the respective data output unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the data output units comprises: 
<claim-text>a clock driver for outputting the clock signal provided from the control signal generating unit in response to the respective reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission circuit for latching and transferring a data bit in response to the clock signal provided from the clock driver; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a data driver for outputting the data bit from the transmission circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the clock driver comprises: 
<claim-text>an inverter for converting the clock signal supplied from the control signal generating unit into an inverted clock signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switch for controlling an output of the inverted clock signal in response to the reference voltage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the clock driver operates in accordance with a turn-on resistance of the switch in order to compensate a slope of a rising edge of the clock signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A signal delay control circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device, the signal delay control circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control input operations for address bits; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of address input circuits for controlling strobe operations in response to a respective one of the reference voltages, each of the reference voltages corresponding to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the address input circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the address input circuits receives the respective reference voltage that is inversely proportional to the distance between the control signal generating unit and the address input circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the address input circuits comprises: 
<claim-text>an input circuit for receiving an address bit supplied; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay circuit for delaying the address bit by a predetermined time in response to the respective reference voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a strobe circuit for admitting the address bit supplied from the delay circuit to an internal circuit of the semiconductor memory device in response to the clock signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the resistive circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a plurality of resistors connected between the first and second reference voltage generating units; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of nodes, each of the nodes being connected to a respective one of the address input circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A signal delay control circuit for use in a semiconductor memory device, the signal delay control circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a first reference voltage generating unit for generating a first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference voltage generating unit for generating a second reference voltage that is lower than the first reference voltage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control signal generating unit for generating a clock signal to control operations of sense amplifiers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive circuit in circuit with the first and second reference voltage generating units for generating a plurality of reference voltages; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of sense amplifier drive circuits for controlling operations of respective ones of sense amplifiers in response to a respective one of the reference voltages, each of the reference voltages corresponding to a distance between the control signal generating unit and a respective one of the address input circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the sense amplifiers drive circuits receives the respective reference voltage that is proportional to the distance between the control signal generating unit and the sense amplifier drive circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sense amplifier drive circuits comprises: 
<claim-text>a sense amplifier array for receiving the clock signal supplied from the control signal generating unit; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sense amplifier driver for activating the sense amplifier array in response to the respective reference voltage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the resistive circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>a plurality of resistors connected between the first and second reference voltage generating units; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of nodes, each of the nodes being connected to a respective one of the sense amplifier drive circuits. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The signal delay control circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second reference voltage generating unit comprises a ground voltage terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002356A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
