<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001148A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001148A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001148</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894005</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B66D005/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>254</class>
<subclass>378000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>BRAKING DEVICE FOR MOTIVE WINCH</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shih</given-name>
<middle-name>Jyi</middle-name>
<family-name>Huang</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BACON &amp; THOMAS, PLLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>625 SLATERS LANE</address-1>
<address-2>FOURTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention discloses a braking device for a motive winch, mainly having a sectional axle, an elastic member, two engraved chunks, and a clutch base in a retardation compartment of the motive winch; wherein said first engraved chunk is coupled to the sectional axle, having a braking plate being contacted with the frictional surface in the retardation compartment; the elastic member has an appropriate whirling force with respect to the first engraved chuck such that the braking plate of the first engraved chuck tends to press against the frictional surface of the retardation compartment; the second engraved trunk is coupled to the sectional axle and rotates synchronously, such that the first and second engraved chucks are capable of being attached to each other to push the brake plate of the first engraved trunk to generate the braking action on an inclined surface and the clutch base brings a protruded member to rotate, and the protruded members on the two engraved chunks is pushed by the protruded trunk at the inner side of the clutch base, and the axle of the motor brings the mechanical force for the clutch base. Such arrangement can stop the braking action by bringing the two engraved trucks to rotate simultaneously in the clutch base when the motor is operating. When the motive force is stopped, the pulling force due to the reaction of heavy substance comes from the cable wire reel makes the inclined plane of the second engraved trunk to push the inclined plane of the first engraved trunk such that the brake plate and the frictional surface contact with each other tightly, and hence attains the braking effect. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a braking device for a motive winch, more particularly to a highly reliable and safe innovative structural design of a braking device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In General, the braking device used for industrial applications was disclosed in the inventor&apos;s R.O.C. Patent Application No. 85212474 entitled &ldquo;Braking device without motive force for crane elevator&rdquo; filed on Aug. 15, 1996, which was published in the patent bulletin on May 21, 1997 with Publication No. 306588 (which is shown in the attachment). However, the present inventor further improves such device with another innovative design for the braking mechanism. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The primary objective of the present invention is to provide a braking device for a motive winch, which has a reliable and safe protective design to ensure the operating safety of the users and the equipment in addition to its innovative structural design. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> To make it easier for our examiner to understand the objective of the invention, structure, innovative features, and performance, we use a preferred embodiment together with the attached drawings for the detailed description of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the braking device of the present invention is in use, it definitely has a safe braking effect because once the motive force disappears, the device will immediately produce a braking effect due to the reaction in the reverse gravitation of the heavy load of the substance on the wheel. Therefore, it is absolutely safe to use such device. When the device according to the present invention is not in use, it is always in the braking status, which the device is a safe mechanical brake and a safe operating environment for a motive force winch. It enhances the traditional braking device and improves the shorting comings of the prior art.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other objects, features, and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of the preferred but non-limiting embodiment. The description is made with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows the disassembled parts of a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the cross-sectional diagram of the assembled parts of a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the enlarged cross-sectional diagram of the assembled parts of a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the relative positions of the clutch base and the engraved trunks according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the cross-sectional diagram of the motor according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is moving forward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the movement of the clutch base and the engraved trunks of a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is moving forward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows the cross-sectional diagram of a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is stopped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows the movement of the clutch base and the engraved trunks a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is stopped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows the cross-sectional diagram of a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is reversing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows the movement of the clutch base and the engraved trunks a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the motor is reversing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows cross-sectional diagram of a preferred embodiment of the present invention when the cable wire is placed manually by pulling up the clutch mechanism. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Please refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, which respectively show the cross-sectional diagrams for the disassembled parts of the braking device for a winch and the assembled structure according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention. The structure comprises: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, being disposed on the motive winch and having a penetrating hole <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the middle for allowing the inner side of the motor and a sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to pass through, and a bearing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is disposed at the inner side of the penetrating hole <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and after the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> passes through the bearing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the retardation gear set D is engaged, its extending end and the C-shape buckle <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are latched to fix to the bearing <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> an elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (which could be a volute spring), being sleeved into predetermined hole <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for the positioning, and the other end of the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> presses against the flange B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the first engraved trunk B and has a pushing reaction force, and the end section is inserted into a hole B<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on the flange B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for positioning (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> a sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, being extended into the penetrating hole <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the sidewall facing the penetrating hole <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is serrated as teeth <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A which are engaged with the retardation gear set D as a moving parts, and the other end of the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is facing the first engraved trunk B and the second engraved trunk A, and the sidewall of such end has teeth <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> which are engaged with the teeth A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the hole edge of the inner side of the second engraved trunk A as a simultaneous moving parts, and the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is sleeved into the outer surface of the motor axle S, and there is no connection of direct movement with each other. The end of the motor axle S is a non-circular latching end S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (the latching end S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of this embodiment of the present invention is set to be a hexagonal tooth, however the shape is not limited to hexagonal only); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> a first engraved trunk B, having a hole B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> facing the center of the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which can be sleeved onto the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the inner edge of the hole B<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is a smooth surface, therefore it has no direct movement connection with the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the external edge of the flange B<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the engraved trunk B is in frictional contact with the preset frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> on the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or is detached from the brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In addition, a ringed base B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> at the top surface having a plurality of up and down (with different inclinations) inclined planes B<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is protruded from an end surface of the engraved trunk A that faces the engraved trunk B; on the corresponding outside wall of the ringed base B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> it has a protruded latching member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> a second engraved trunk A, inner teeth A<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are set on the inner edge of the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> facing the center which are engaged corresponding to the teeth <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> on the end side of the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, therefore the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the second engraved trunk A have direct movement connection with each other, and a set of C-shape buckle <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A latches the second engraved trunk A to the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for the positioning in order to restrict and prevent the engraved trunk A from being displaced. Further, an inclined plane A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and a protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are disposed at the position corresponding to the ringed base B<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> on the first engraved trunk B that faces the second engraved trunk A. However, there is a slight angle difference between the corresponding inclined plane B<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at the position of the inclined plane B<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the protruded latching member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> a clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a latching hole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> corresponsive to the latching end S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the motor axle, which faces the middle of the latching end S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the motor axle S, such that the clutch base being sleeved onto the latching end S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the motor axles by means of the latching hole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and being rotated by the motor axle. Further, the protruded latching members A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the corresponding engraved trunks A, B in the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the inner side of the clutch base has a corresponding protruded trunk <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> such that when the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is rotated by means of the motor axle S (no matter forward or reverse rotation), the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is pushed by the protruded member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> at the inner side of the clutch base, the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> will rotate accordingly, and the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> will also rotate. The clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will immediately uses its protruded trunk <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to push the protruded latching member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the engraved trunk B, such that the engraved trunk B will also rotate accordingly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> a bushing <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, being inserted onto the corresponding bushing base <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the external side of the busing <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is restricted by the protruded member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> at the inner side of the rear casing <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the retardation compartment, and the rear casing <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the retardation compartment is coupled to the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for the positioning such that the rotation of the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> attains the effect of stable transmission. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> By means of the assembly of the foregoing components, the elastic member <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is pressed, therefore it will exist a reaction force and a tendency for the plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on the first engraved trunk B being pushed away from the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, but when the components are stalled, an appropriated whirling force device (i.e. after inserting an end of the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> into the preset hole <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the other end will be rotated and pressed slightly, and then is inserted into the hole B<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the engraved trunk B for the positioning) can be installed between the first engraved trunk B and the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> such that a reverse whirling torque exists on the first engraved member B with respect to the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a tendency to push the brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the first engraved trunk B towards the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and the reverse whirling torque is larger than the pushing force. Therefore, when it sits still, the brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the first engraved member B is always near the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and generates the friction. Under normal still condition, it is always in the braking status, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, there is an angle difference between the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the engraved member A and the protruded latching member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the engraved member B due to their alignments, and the protruded trunk <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> does not press against the protruded latching members A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. Therefore there is no pushing against each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> When the user is loading heavy stuff, the user presses the forward button in order to let the motor rotate and bring its axle S into rotation, and then it will immediately bring the clutch base into rotation as well. In a split second, the protruded member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> pushes against the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the engraved member A and the protruded member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the engraved member B such that both engraved members A and B are rotated simultaneously (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). Then the engraved member A is rotated synchronously with the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and the sectional axle will be engaged with the retardation gear set D. Therefore, it can transmit the rotation to the wire cable reel to collect the wire cable and lift heavy substance. In the meantime, the first engraved trunk B is also brought into rotation such that the angle difference between by the engraved trunks A, B disappears, and the less-inclined surface of the engraved trunk B will be proximate to the less-inclined surface of the engraved trunk A (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>), and the rotation force is larger than the reverse torque exerted on the engraved trunk B. In addition, the reverse pushing force of the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> makes the first engraved trunk to be proximate to the right side (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>), therefore the brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> detaching from the contact of the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can successfully lift the heavy substance. When the motive force stops, the motor axle S and the clutch base will stop immediately, and thus the protruded member <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will stop pushing the protruded latching members A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. However, the torque generated by the gravitational force of the heavy substance will bring the wire of the wire cable reel back into position, and the transmission by the retardation gear set D on the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the second engraved trunk A will rotate back in position. Actually, the second engraved trunk A rotates back in position for a very short distance, and then it will stop. In a split second, the angle difference between engraved trunks B and A will be produced again (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). In such a short time, the more-inclined plane A<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the second engraved member A is pushed to the more-inclined plane B<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the first engraved trunk A. In addition, a reverse torque is exerted on the first engraved member B by the elastic member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and thus the first engraved trunk B has to shift to the left (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>), and spontaneously it produces a braking effect such that the brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> tightly attach to each other. The larger the torque of the heavy substance, the larger is the force pushed by the second engraved member A onto the first engraved member B, and hence the larger is the braking force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The above-mentioned situation shows the braking action from the user lifts the heavy substance until it stops. Another commonly used situation is when the heavy substance is unloaded from the high position until it stops at a low position. In such process, when the user lifts the heavy substance on the hook at the end of a wire to suspend the heavy substance, it will produce the braking effects as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, and the user operates the motor to rotate the motor axle S and the clutch base in reverse direction. In a split second, the protruded trunk <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the clutch base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will push the protruded latching member B<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the first engraved trunk B and then push the protruded latching member A<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the second engraved member A (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) and it eliminates the angle difference between the first and second engraved members A and B, and the less-inclined surface of the engraved trunk B will be proximate to that of the engraved trunk A (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>). The brake plate B<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the first engraved trunk B will detach from the contact of the frictional surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and successfully unload the heavy substance from a high position. Please compare the figures of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 9</cross-reference> for the lifting or unloading a heavy substance, the engraved trunk B slightly shift to the right, and when the braking effect stops, it will immediately produce the braking effect as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. Furthermore, it has a braking effect even when there is no suspending heavy substance on the wire or no motive force as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> It is known from the above description, the braking effect exists once the device is assembled, and once the motor is started (regardless of the forward rotation or the reverse rotation), the braking effect is stopped. When the motive force is stopped suddenly or during power failure, the brake will be in effect immediately. The heavier the substance, the larger is the braking effect. It ensures the safety and convenience of using such device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In addition, we can install a manually operated clutch mechanism <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment of the invention (please refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 12</cross-reference>). When the user desires to operate the wire manually (i.e. the user does not rely on the motor for releasing the wire cable), the operator can use such manual clutch mechanism <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> for the control to pull the handle of the clutch for the positioning and disable the inner gear mechanism between the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) such that the gear mechanism in the retardation compartment <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> will be idle rotation and the rotary force will not be transmitted to the sectional axle <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the wire cable reel will not be controlled by the braking device, and can easily pull the wire cable out to attain the purpose of releasing the wire cable manually. When the wire cable is to be rotated back into the reel (when lifting heavy substance), the user only needs to release the handle of the clutch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In summation of the above description, when the braking device of the present invention is in use, it definitely has a safe braking effect because once the motive force disappears (such as pressing the stop button for the motor or during power failure), the device will immediately produce a braking effect (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>) due to the reaction in the reverse gravitation of the heavy load of the substance on the wheel. Therefore, it is absolutely safe to use such device. When the device according to the present invention is not in use, it is always in the braking status, which the device is a safe mechanical brake and a safe operating environment for a motive force winch. It enhances the traditional braking device and improves the shorting comings of the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described by way of example and in terms of a preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited thereto. To the contrary, it is intended to cover various modifications and similar arrangements and procedures, and the scope of the appended claims therefore should be accorded the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and similar arrangements and procedures. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A braking device for a motive winch, comprising: 
<claim-text>a retardation compartment, being disposed on the motive winch, and having a penetrating hole in the middle for allowing a motor axle to pass through, and a sectional axle to extend into it: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sectional axle, extending into the penetrating hole of the retardation compartment, and the sidewall at the end facing the penetrating hole has teeth and retardation gear set for the engagement of a transmission device, and the sidewall on the other end of the sectional axle has teeth which can be engaged with the inner teeth of a second engraved trunk for the transmission device; an elastic member, being sleeved into the sectional axle, and a hole is disposed on the sectional axle for receiving the insertion of an end section of the elastic member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first engraved trunk, having a hole on the sectional axle facing the elastic member, and the side of the first engraved trunk facing the elastic member has a hole for receiving the insertion of an end of the elastic member for the positioning; when it is installed, the first engraved trunk slightly rotates and presses with respect to the elastic member such that the first engraved trunk with respect to the elastic member can have an appropriate whirling force, and the external edge of the first engraved trunk has a brake plate as a contract to the frictional surface being preset on the retardation compartment and a ringed base being disposed on a top surface with a plurality of up and down inclined planes outwardly protruded from the end of the elastic member facing backward to the first engraved trunk, and the external wall of the ringed base has a pair of outwardly protruded latching members; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second engraved trunk, having a hole in its middle and inner teeth being engaged with the corresponding teeth of the sectional axle, the inclined plane and the protruded latching member of the first engraved member facing the second engraved member also have a corresponding inclined surface and protruded latching member, and there is an angle difference between these two devices; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a clutch base, a latching hole corresponsive to the latching end of the motor axle, which is disposed in and faces the middle of the latching end of the motor axle, and the inner side of the clutch base has a pair of protruded trunks to push the protruded latching members of the first and second engraved trunks; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bushing, being inserted onto a corresponding bushing base of the clutch base, and the external side of the busing is restricted by the protruded member at the inner side of the rear casing of the retardation compartment, and the rear casing of the retardation compartment is coupled to the retardation compartment for the positioning; </claim-text>
<claim-text>such that when the motor rotates, the motor axle brings clutch base and the second engraved trunk and the first engraved trunk into rotation, and the brake plate of the first engraved trunk detaches from the frictional surface of the retardation compartment, which stops the braking effect and in turn starts the rotation of the wire cable reel by the indirect transmission of the motor; when the motive force is stopped, the load of the heavy substance suspended on the wire cable produces a reverse pulling force, such that the first engraved trunk produces a reverse pushing force to push the brake plate of the first engraved trunk to press against the frictional surface of the retardation compartment, and produce a prompt braking effect.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001148A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
