<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004534</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10162144</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020603</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61M029/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>191000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Balloon transporter</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60295307</doc-number>
<document-date>20010601</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephanie</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>George</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>St. Louis Park</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jeffrey</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lechner-Riehle</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Burnsville</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kimberly</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Anderson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Eagan</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Patricia</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Derus</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rogers</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Steven</given-name>
<middle-name>T.</middle-name>
<family-name>Deininger</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Savage</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Oppenheimer Wolff &amp; Donnelly LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>45 South Seventh Street, Suite 3300</address-1>
<city>Minneapolis</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>55402-1609</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A balloon transporter device, system and method for its use in deploying a detachable balloon at a target site in a patient is disclosed. The device includes an elongated tube having an inner lumen, an outer circumference and at least one opened end. The inner lumen is sized to receive a detachable balloon, and a proximal end adapted to retractably associate with a balloon delivery device. Alternatively, the device includes a housing configured as a truncated cone, the housing having an inner channel with decreasing diameters sized to accommodate a deflated balloon at its largest diameter and a catheter tip at its narrowest diameter. The balloon transporter protects the detachable balloon as well as aids in the application or loading of the detachable balloon onto a catheter tip. The balloon transporter further includes properties that increase the ease of use and stability of the device so as to reduce the effort required by the user during loading of a detachable balloon onto a delivery device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a balloon transporter for protection and delivery of a detachable balloon in medical procedures. The present invention particularly relates to a balloon transporter to be used with a balloon delivery system when deploying detachable, inflatable balloons in medical procedures involving blood vessels, body cavities, treatment of vesicle ureteral reflux, fecal incontinence, gastrointestinal reflux, urinary incontinence, and the like. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Detachable balloons are used for a wide variety of medical procedures where occlusion of a vessel or duct, or compression at a target tissue site is desired. One specific example is in the treatment of urinary incontinence. In patients suffering from this condition, detachable balloons have been used to successfully treat the intrinsic sphincter deficiency. One or more detachable balloons are implanted into the tissue adjacent to the neck of the bladder of a patient. The inflated balloons aid in the ability of the sphincter muscles to occlude, which improves or resolves the condition. This method of treatment is preferred as it is minimally invasive, safe and less traumatic to the patient. As such, various systems have been developed for the delivery of balloon catheters to a desired target site. See, for example, U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,411,475; 4,802,479; and 4,686,962. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> An example of such a system may be found in U.S. Pat. No. 5,830,228, which describes a device for delivering a detachable, inflatable balloon at a target site. The system includes a holder, a protective sheath configured for insertion through the holder and a catheter device for carrying a balloon. Use of the device requires loading of the balloon directly onto the catheter device by the user immediately prior to insertion of the balloon/catheter through the protective sheath. Once loaded, the balloon is exposed by retraction of the sheath portion of the delivery device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It has been discovered that an obstacle or disadvantage to such systems is that the user himself/herself loads the balloon &ldquo;naked&rdquo; or bare onto the catheter. This requires handling of a small balloon as well as manipulation and positioning of the balloon valve onto the small catheter tip. Therefore, the risk of damage to the balloon during loading, or separation of the balloon from the catheter tip due to user misalignment is a limitation of these systems. Further, balloons manufactured for uses with such systems are often shipped with limited protection. This further increases the risk of delivering a damaged balloon to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In view of the above, it is apparent that there is a need to provide a balloon transporter for protection and delivery of a balloon. Such a transporter can be used with a balloon delivery system with a more reliable and stable transport of inflatable, detachable balloons. There is also a need to provide a balloon transporter that is efficient, easy to use, reliable and functions as a holder. This would reduce the overall procedure time required and therefore reduce patient discomfort. Such a balloon transport device protects the balloon during shipping as well as reduces the preparation time required by the physician or clinician prior to a procedure. This reduces the overall medical procedure time, thus minimizing patient discomfort and trauma, as well as physician frustration. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, it is an object of the present invention to provide a balloon transport device that protects and reduces the risk of damage to a balloon intended for delivery to a patient target site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide a balloon transporter that is efficient, requires minimal effort by the user, is easy to use and is reliable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A further aspect of the invention is to provide a balloon transporter that enhances the delivery or loading of a balloon onto a delivery device. Such an aspect can include a balloon transporter having a window for visual verification of correct loading of a balloon onto a delivery catheter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the invention, a balloon transporter for use with a balloon delivery system for deploying a detachable, inflatable balloon to a target site in a patient is disclosed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An additional aspect of the invention provides a method of using a balloon protector with a balloon delivery system for deploying a detachable, inflatable balloon at a target site in a patient in vivo. The system includes a balloon transporter configured for insertion through the lumen of the sheath assembly of a delivery device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and other objects not specifically enumerated herein are believed to be addressed by the present invention which contemplates a balloon transporter for protection and delivery of a balloon for inflation at a target site, the balloon transporter including a housing having a passageway sized so as to fit at least a portion of a detachable balloon.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a linear delivery system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a detailed view of a balloon transporter in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an assembly view of a balloon transporter including a delivery device in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of the distal end region of a balloon transporter system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view of a balloon transporter during loading of a balloon in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of the distal end region of a balloon transporter during loading of a balloon in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a transporter in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an enlarged side assembly view of a balloon transporter as inserted into a balloon delivery device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of the proximal end region of a balloon transporter as assembled within the base portion of a sheath assembly in accordance with one embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a balloon transporter engaged with a delivery catheter in accordance with an alternative embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an enlarged side assembly view of a balloon transporter inserted into a balloon delivery system in accordance with one aspect of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional enlarged view of a balloon transporter housing a balloon in accordance with one aspect of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12B</cross-reference> is a planar view of a base support engaged with a balloon transporter in accordance with one aspect of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12C</cross-reference> is a planar view of an alternative base support engaged with a balloon transporter in accordance with another aspect of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a balloon housed within the balloon transporter in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The present invention is a device for enhanced transport of a balloon usable with a balloon delivery system. The balloon transporter functions to protect the balloon prior to its use, including protecting the balloon during shipment of the device to a user. In addition, the transporter operates as a holder and an alignment tool during the step of loading the balloon onto a balloon delivery device. Therefore, the present invention can be used with a variety of balloon delivery devices. For example, a balloon transporter can be used to load a balloon onto the catheter element described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,830,228, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference. Alternatively, a balloon transporter may be used with available delivery devices such as used with the &ldquo;UroVive&rdquo; delivery device (available from American Medical Systems, Inc. Minnetonka, Minn., the current assignee of the present invention). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In particular, the transporter of the present invention may also be used with a linear delivery device, such as described in Applicant&apos;s co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/547,952 filed on Apr. 12, 2000, entitled &ldquo;Linear Delivery System For Deployment of a Detachable Balloon at a Target Site In Vivo,&rdquo; the entire disclosure of which is incorporated by reference herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and as described in the above-referenced co-pending Application, such a linear delivery system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes a balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. When a linear delivery system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is used without a balloon transporter, the balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with a balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> attached at its distal end <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, is inserted into the sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the proximal end lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> until the balloon is positioned within the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. During such movement, the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is exposed to the inside surfaces of the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, when the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is retracted (through rearward movement of the retracting tab <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>), the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> becomes exposed to the target site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The present invention therefore provides enhanced transport of a balloon into the sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, one embodiment of a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for use with a balloon delivery device or other similar device includes an elongated tube, sheath or sleeve <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> having an inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that is continuous between a proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the elongated tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is configured so as to mate with structure in the balloon delivery device (discussed below). The detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is located or placed toward the distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the elongated tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Also, toward the distal end of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is an aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in the wall of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. This aperture allows for visual observation of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as located in the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 &amp; 3</cross-reference>, a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a tube or sleeve <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> which is elongated so as to fit over the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of a delivery system. Contained within the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for deployment at a target site in a patient. In use, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted on the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and slid along the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> until the catheter tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> engages and receives the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The resulting connection is shown in enlarged view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Depending upon user preference, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be supplied preloaded, where the balloon is loaded into the transporter during manufacture, or can be manufactured &ldquo;empty,&rdquo; thus allowing the user to select a desired balloon for loading onto the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 &amp; 6</cross-reference>, the loading of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> into the transport <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is now described. A stop member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is first inserted at the end of the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> nearest the distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is then sealed with the stop member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in place. A vacuum is applied (not shown) at the proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6, a</cross-reference> detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (shown in phantom) lubricated with fluoro-silicone oil <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is then introduced into the lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the transport <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The suction from the vacuum source (not shown) causes the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to move along the lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> until it is prohibited from further movement by the stop member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Upon the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> arriving adjacent the stop member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the vacuum is discontinued and the seal and stop member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are removed from the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). In this state, the transporter is considered fully loaded and ready to transport the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Returning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 &amp; 3</cross-reference>, the tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) should be of a length sufficient to adequately expose the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> when the proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is withdrawn into the base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> during deployment in vivo. The balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> should also be sized so that its inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> passageway fits snuggly or closely over the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This close fit ensures that the catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> travels directly down the central axis or middle of the balloon valve and aids in aligning the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> onto the tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, in one embodiment, the diameter D of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is approximately 0.063 inches and the wall thickness T is approximately 0.0045 inches. In such an embodiment, the inner lumen diameter of the catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (not shown) is approximately 0.060 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, when used with a delivery device as described in Applicant&apos;s co-pending U.S. Patent Application (supra), the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has an inner lumen diameter D that provides a slight compression fit for the detachable balloon. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the cross-sectional diameter D of the inner surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is smaller than the outer diameter of the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Therefore, in an embodiment where the detachable balloon has an outer diameter of about 0.07 inches (1.788 mm), the inner diameter D of the tube is about 0.063 inches (1.6 mm). This results in a balloon fit that is neither too loose nor too tight and serves to hold the balloon in place. An inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that provides a loose fit can cause the balloon contained within the tube to slide away from the tip of the catheter device during loading. A fit that is too tight can result in a balloon that does not easily move within the lumen and thus fails to properly deploy upon retraction of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 8</cross-reference>, the sleeve <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has an inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or passageway that extends axially and is continuous between its proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 &amp; 9</cross-reference>, the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contains a flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> that extends radially outward from the longitudinal axis of the proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> mates with the internal geometry of the sheath assembly unit shaft hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the delivery device when the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is inserted through the lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The proximal end <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is integrally coupled to the shaft hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the delivery device. Movement of the retraction tab <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) in the rearward direction causes the shaft hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, coupled to the proximal end <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, to retract into base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This also causes retraction of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by engaging the flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The simultaneous pulling or withdrawing of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> away from the target site exposes the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> mounted on the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which was previously contained within the lumen of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Returning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is also advantageous in that the flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> aids the user in aligning the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> over the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by operating as a centering surface edge. In other words, the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is &ldquo;funneled&rdquo; into the lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the transporter by the flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. This decreases the time and effort that would otherwise be required by the user when inserting the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to load the balloon onto the catheter. Once placed over the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the balloon transport <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> serves to guide the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the base or valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> until the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is fully mounted onto the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The fully mounted configuration is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, as discussed previously, a preferred embodiment of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes an aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for viewing the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or at least the base or valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> contained within the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The location of the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> on the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> depends upon the shaft length of the balloon delivery structure. In a preferred embodiment, when used with a linear delivery device as disclosed in the previously identified co-pending patent application, the distal edge <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is about 0.34 inch or 8.636 mm from the distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the transporter. The proximal edge <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is about 0.54 inch or 13.716 mm from the distal end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the transporter. Therefore, the axial dimension of the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is about 0.2 inch or 5.08 mm in length. These dimensions allow the user to see the base or valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The ability to visualize the balloon provides an added level of assurance to the user when loading the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> onto the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In addition, where a transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is provided that is not preloaded with a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may serve as an opening through which a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be loaded into the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In this latter case, the aperture should be of a size sufficient to allow insertion of a balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> without causing damage to the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> When provided as a verification mechanism, the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> should preferably be of a size that allows the user to visually see at least the base valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> contained therein, yet still provides protection to the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The aperture can be sized so as to have a width dimension <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> in the range of about 10% to 50%, or 25% 35%, or approximately one third, of the circumference of the tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the aperture <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will have a width of about 0.053 inch or 1.346 cm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can also include an inner surface that is lubricated so as to allow easy insertion of the balloon into the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> during manufacture as well as easy deployment of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at a target site. The lubricant <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can be applied either to the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or to the inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the lubricant material is a coating such as a fluoro-silicone oil, acetone, alcohol, or PEG solution with water. A fluoro-silicone oil is particularly advantageous when used with a silicone balloon insofar as the fluoro-silicone also prevents balloon adherence to the inner surface of the transporter tube <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Without a fluoro-silicone lubricant, the silicone material of the detachable balloon <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, over time, can begin to adhere or stick to the inner surface of the transporter tube <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a fluoro-silicone oil helps to increase the shelf life of a balloon transporter/detachable balloon device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As described above and shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 &amp; 8</cross-reference>, the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> mounted therein is placed within the catheter shaft of a sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, such as a linear delivery device (supra). As used with a linear delivery device, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> containing a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is first mounted over and onto the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> until the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> pierces the pre-pierced valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The transporter/balloon/catheter assembly is then inserted into the lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>). As the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>/transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pushed down through the lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> protects the balloon. The hub <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) then snaps into the sheath assembly base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) when the correct position is reached. To expose the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the tab <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> disposed on the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (which is connected to the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) is retracted. This also retracts the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> due to the flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the proximal end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the transporter <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> engaging the shaft hub <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. This exposes the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the target site in vivo and the balloon is inflated. Once the balloon is deployed, the entire assembly (sheath, catheter and transporter) is removed from the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 13</cross-reference>, in another embodiment of the present invention, the balloon transport system includes a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be affixed to the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is comprised of structure that operates to temporarily control and restrict the distance that the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extends into transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. It is preferred that such an element be temporarily controlling and/or restrictive so that after the stop has ensured correct alignment of the catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (with the catheter tip engaging the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>), the transport <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be urged or retracted beyond the stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> as is necessary during use to expose the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> located on the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In this fashion, the stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> controls relative movement of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> between a first position and a second position, the first position being that location where the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is restricted from further insertion into the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the second position being that location beyond the stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> upon deployment of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> can be constructed of a piece of tubing that is disposed on the outer surface of the catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. For example, a piece of Teflon&reg; or tygon tubing can be heat-sealed to the outer surface of the catheter shaft. Upon sealing, a force of about 3 lb. (1.361 kg) on the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is required to break the seal around the catheter shaft. This seal provides the temporary restriction preventing further movement of the catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> into the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The sealing force of 3 lb. (1.361 kg) is generally equivalent to the force applied when inserting the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>/catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> into the base portion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of a sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the Teflon tubing functions as a releasable barrier which, when engaged by the transport <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, indicates to the user that the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> contained within the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has been properly aligned onto the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, once inserted into the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the user pushes the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>/transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> assembly into position in the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This requires a force of about 3 lb (1.361 kg) which leads to the breakage of the Teflon seal. The Teflon seal now being broken, there is freedom for withdrawal movement of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> over the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to expose the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, in another embodiment of the present invention balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may include groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> that seats stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>&prime;. Stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>&prime; generally comprises an O-ring. Groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extends circumferentially around shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> Groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may include a beveled or chamfered edge <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> or, alternatively, a straight cut edge (not shown). Groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> ensures that the balloon delivery device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; of the present invention is correctly positioned on balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> so that balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> remains intact until it is delivered to the base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>&prime; allow the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to engage the valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; maintaining the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; in position in channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> or alternatively the inner lumen <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of elongated tube <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. As the catheter/balloon transporter/balloon assembly is advanced into the shaft hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and through the sheath lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the stop element <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>&prime; slides out of groove <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and is pushed along the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of balloon delivery catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; until balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is delivered to the distal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of sheath assembly unit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is now in position for deployment at the target site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Examples of balloon types useful in the present invention are disclosed in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,304,123, 5,411,475 and 4,311,146. Other balloons made of silicone or other elastomeric material may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of the present invention for use with a periurethral linear delivery system as described in Applicants&apos; co-pending Application (supra), the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a manufacturing specification of 2.750 inches (69.85 mm) in total length. The internal diameter of the shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is 0.077 inches (1.956 mm), or a size sufficient to allow passage of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will preferably have a total length of about 2.760-inch (70.104 cm) with a flared portion <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> dimension of about 0.085 inch (2.159 mm) in diameter. The balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; in accordance with the present invention, may be made of a rigid material to protect the balloon during passage through the lumen of the sheath assembly. Alternatively, a flexible material that has sufficient rigidity so as to protect the balloon during passage through the lumen of the sheath assembly may be used. Representative examples of suitable materials include, nickel titanium, stainless steel, certain grades of nitinol, urethane, polycarbonate, acetyl, nylon, PTFE/teflon, polyimides, polyamides, polyethylene, polypropylenes and mixtures thereof. In a preferred embodiment, balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; is made from any thermoplastic material that may be injection molded such as those thermoplastics enumerated previously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment of a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for use with a transurethral system for delivery of a detachable balloon, the length of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be adapted to correspond appropriately with the increased catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> length of the balloon delivery device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In such uses, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will preferably be fabricated of a more flexible materials such as polycarbonate, acetyl, nylon, urethane, silicone, teflon, polyimides, polyamides, polypropylene and nitinol in order to facilitate transport through the lumen of a cytoscope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 through 13</cross-reference>, an alternative embodiment of the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; in accordance with the present invention is shown. Balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; includes housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, distal tip <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, and base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has the general configuration of a trapezoid or truncated cone. Channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extends along the longitudinal axis of housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> from the distal tip <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> includes two or more continuous sections of decreasing diameters. The largest diameter section <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is located at the distal tip <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and is dimensioned to accommodate the diameter of a deflated balloon. The middle section (not shown) of channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is dimensioned to accommodate the diameter of the balloon valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and approximate the inside diameter of sheath <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The narrowest section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of channel <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> at the base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is dimensioned to accommodate the diameter of distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The continuous decreasing diameters of channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> allow balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; to be correctly positioned without folding or buckling as may happen in a channel of uniform diameter. In addition, the junction of the narrowest section <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and the middle section creates a ledge or platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> on which the valve <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; sits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12B and 12C</cross-reference>, housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may also include base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. Base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> includes a central portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> including an aperture <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> located therewithin, and two or more flanges <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> integrally attached to central portion <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The flanges <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> extend radially from base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and are received in mating relationship with corresponding grooves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> on base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> snaps into mating relationship with grooves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, grooves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> on base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> may receive base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> in an interference fit relationship or base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> may be solvent bonded in grooves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> or directly to base <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Aperture <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is aligned with pre-pierced valve <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; and functions to additionally guide catheter tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> into valve <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The two piece design of housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> facilitates placement of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; within channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> during manufacture and prior to use. Base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> also functions to restrain the balloon from dislodging from channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> during transport and prior to or while in use by the physician. Base support <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> may also include plug <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> which functions as an additional stop or restraint so that balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; does not become dislodged after placement during manufacture or during use prior to being placed at the target site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; includes a window or notch <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> that extends approximately 0.125 inches along the length of housing <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and parallel to channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Notch <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is cut close to channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> leaving a thickness of approximately 0.010 to 0.012 inches. Notch <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> provides visualization of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; and distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and insures that during placement there are not any folds or twists in the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;. The ability to visualize the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; provides an added level of assurance to the user when loading the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; onto the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As noted previously, if balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is pre-loaded into the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; during manufacture, the tip of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is dipped into a lubricant and passed through channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. Valve <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is also dipped into a lubricant. The use of a lubricant maintains balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; aligned in channel <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> without any deleterious breaks, twists or folds in balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;. Alternatively, the inner surface of balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; may be lubricated to allow easy insertion of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; into transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. The lubricant material may comprise fluorosilicone oil, acetone, alcohol, or polyethylene glycol solution with water and mixtures thereof. A suitable lubricant for use in accordance with the present invention is fluorosilicone oil because it prevents balloon surface adherence to the inner surface of the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; thus increasing the shelf life of a pre-loaded balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> One aspect of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; may include balloon feet <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. Balloon feet <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> aid in the manufacture of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; by providing a mechanism for the quick release of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; from the manufacturing mold without damaging the fragile balloon<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; and be used for positioning balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; within transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. Additionally, balloon feet <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> firmly seat balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; within transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. Upon deployment of balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; by catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, balloon feet <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> are sheared off by the cutting motion between edge <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and sharp edge <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of ledge <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> in transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The in use operation of balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; and the balloon delivery system of the present invention is substantially as described above for balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and delivery system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; with the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> mounted therein is placed within the catheter shaft of a sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, such as a linear delivery device (supra). As used with a linear delivery device, the balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; containing a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is first mounted over and onto the catheter device <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> until the distal tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> pierces the pre-pierced valve region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;. The transporter/balloon/catheter assembly is then inserted into the lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>). The catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> plus transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; including balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is pushed through lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; engages the conically-shaped portion <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of lumen <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and is prevented from moving forward as the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and attached balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; continue advancing toward distal end of shaft portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The hub <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of the catheter <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>) then engagingly snaps into the sheath assembly base <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) at the same time the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; reaches the distal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. To expose the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime;, the tab <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> disposed on the sheath assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (which is connected to the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) is retracted&rsquo;. As balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; is advanced, transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; retracts along the length of catheter shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This exposes the balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; at the target site in vivo and the balloon is inflated. Once the balloon is deployed, the entire assembly (sheath, catheter and transporter) is removed from the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The present invention can be used for a variety of medical treatments where implantation of a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; in a patient is desirable. For example, in the treatment of urinary incontinence, a detachable balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; can be placed in the tissue immediately adjacent to the urethra. The inflated balloon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; provides pressure external to the urethra, which causes partial closure of the urethra and reduces unwanted fluid leakage from the bladder through the urethra. Use of a balloon transporter <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> increases the efficiency and ease of use of such medical devices. Alternatively, the present invention can be used with other types of delivery devices or systems used to deliver a balloon to a patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The methods and systems of the present invention provide simple, accurate and stable transport of a balloon to a delivery system and a target site. The invention, as described herein with reference to preferred embodiments, provides a balloon transporter that protects and enhances the use of a detachable balloon in a medical procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Although the invention has been described in terms of particular embodiments and applications, one of ordinary skill in the art, in light of this teaching, can generate additional embodiments and modifications without departing from the spirit of or exceeding the scope of the claimed invention. Accordingly, it is to be understood that the drawings and descriptions herein are proffered by way of example to facilitate comprehension of the invention and should not be construed to limit the scope thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> All publications and patent applications in this specification are herein incorporated by reference to the same extent as if each individual publication or patent application was specifically and individually indicated by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A transporter for a balloon comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a proximal and distal end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lumen extending axially substantially along the length of said housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said lumen being sized to engage at least an external surface of said balloon and thereby retain said balloon in said lumen until said balloon is exposed for inflation at an intended target site. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing is an elongated tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a proximal end of said tube is shaped to have a diameter which is larger than an external diameter at substantially all other locations along said elongated tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said proximal end of said tube is flared. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an aperture disposed in a distal region of said elongated tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said aperture is sized to expose at least a base portion of said balloon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a lubricant interposed between said external surface of said balloon and said lumen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing has a diameter sized to receive a catheter for engaging said balloon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said transporter comprises a rigid material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said transporter comprises a flexible material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing is configured in the shape of a truncated cone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lumen comprises a uniform diameter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The transporter as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lumen comprises varying diameters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The transporter of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing further includes a base support, said base support having two or more flanges matingly coupled with said proximal end of said housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of transporting a balloon intended for use in treating a medical condition comprising: 
<claim-text>placing said balloon into a housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mounting said balloon onto an inflation catheter by inserting said inflation catheter into said housing until a distal end of said catheter engages said balloon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting said housing and said inflation catheter into a balloon delivery sheath; </claim-text>
<claim-text>moving said housing relative to said inflation catheter and thereby exposing said balloon; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detaching said balloon from said inflation catheter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing is an elongated tube. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein moving said elongated tube includes moving said delivery sheath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said balloon is inflated through said inflation catheter prior to detaching said balloon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein placement of said balloon into said elongated tube includes holding said balloon in said elongated tube by frictional engagement between said tube and said balloon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising viewing said balloon in said elongated tube prior to inserting said elongated tube and said inflation catheter into said balloon delivery sheath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said inflation catheter is insertable into said housing a predetermined distance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said predetermined distance is controlled by a restrictive structure located on said inflation catheter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein insertion of said inflation catheter and housing into said delivery sheath requires a force to overcome any resistive force caused by said restrictive structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said force results in breakage of said restrictive structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A balloon delivery system for treatment of a medical condition comprising: 
<claim-text>a balloon delivery assembly having a base and sheath, said sheath being movable relative to a balloon transporter containing a detachable balloon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an inflation catheter insertable into said balloon transporter for attachment of said inflation catheter to said balloon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said sheath having a diameter sized to receive said balloon transporter; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said inflation catheter being fixedly mountable to said balloon delivery assembly; and, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said sheath having a length so as to expose said inflation catheter upon movement of said sheath relative to said base. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The balloon delivery system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said balloon transporter is shaped to engageably mate with one end of said sheath such that movement of said sheath relative to said base in at least one direction causes movement of said balloon transporter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The balloon delivery system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said balloon transporter comprises an elongated tube having a flared shape at one end to engageably mate with said one end of said sheath. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The balloon delivery system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said balloon transporter includes an aperture at a location to at least partially reveal said balloon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The balloon delivery system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said balloon transporter comprises a housing configured in the shape of a truncated cone.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004534A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
