<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000757</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10151995</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020522</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-196790</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60R021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>180</class>
<subclass>271000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Seat load measuring system with zero point-adjusting capability</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shoichi</given-name>
<family-name>Ishida</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Oobu-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tadashi</given-name>
<family-name>Ozaki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gamagoori-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Denso Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Kariya-city</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OLIFF &amp; BERRIDGE, PLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 19928</address-1>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22320</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A seat load measuring system for use in a vehicle occupant protection device for a vehicle seat has a zero point adjusting capability. The seat load measuring system comprises four weight sensor assemblies; a hub assembly for collecting the weight sensor outputs and providing an output determined by the weight sensor outputs; and means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment to each weight sensor assembly. Each weight sensor assembly includes a zero point adjusting section, which receives an output from the communication means for executing a zero point adjusting operation. If a zero point of a weight sensor assembly is not within a predetermined range, the zero point adjusting section may providing an alert. A zero point adjusting command may be entered by a command input device and passed to the zero point adjusting section. Alternatively, the zero point adjustment may be initiated through a momentary switch provided in the hub assembly. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a seat load measuring system for use in a vehicle occupant protection device for securing the safety of a vehicle occupant and for measuring a seat load a vehicle seat bears or the weight of the occupant of a vehicle seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Vehicles have become equipped with seat belt systems and air bag systems as vehicle occupant protection devices. In order to enhance the performance of such devices, attempts are being made to control the operation of each vehicle occupant protection device in response to the weight of the occupant of a vehicle seat equipped with the vehicle occupant protection device as well as a detection of the occurrence of a vehicle crash. For example, the quantity of air bag deploying gas, the deploying speed of air bags and/or the pretension of seat belts are controlled in response to the occupant&apos;s weight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to vehicle seat load or occupant&apos;s weight measuring systems used in vehicle occupant protection devices as mentioned above. For example, three of such seat load measuring systems are disclosed in European Patent EP0990565 and U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,039,344 and 5,971,432. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Generally, a seat load measuring system provided for a vehicle seat comprises four weight sensor assemblies and a hub assembly for collecting the weight sensor assembly outputs and providing an output signal determined by the weight of the occupant of the vehicle seat. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a conventional way of determining the seat load component W<highlight><subscript>LD </subscript></highlight>posed on each of the weight sensors from the output W of the weight sensor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the horizontal axis indicates time and the vertical axis indicates the output W of the weight sensor. It is assumed in this figure that the used sensors are capable of measuring not only the pressure (i.e., the positive pressing force forward the sensor) but also the negative pressure or the tension. The least upper bound and the greatest lower bound of the weight sensor output are indicated by dotted lines Wmax and Wmin, respectively. A weight level W0 indicates the output level of a weight sensor assembly measured without applying any load thereto. After installing a seat assembly that includes the seat load measuring system in a vehicle under manufacturing, the output W0&plus;W1 of each weight sensor assembly that includes a seat weight component W1 applied to the weight sensor assembly, is stored as a zero-point in the weight measuring hub assembly. Thereafter, the seat load (i.e., the load applied to a seat) is obtained by summing up seat load components given by the four weight sensor assemblies used for the seat. The seat load component for each weight sensor assembly is calculated as W&minus;(W0&plus;W1) from the output W of the sensor assembly and the stored zero-point W0&plus;W1 for the sensor assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> However, the zero point of one or more weight sensor assembly may deviate far from the stored value W0&plus;W1 to a value W0&plus;W2 due to any cause such as a minor crash or distortion of any rigid member of the seat that is caused by the lowering of durability. In such a case, the inability to adjust the zero-point in conventional seat load measuring system results in the seat load component being still determined by the expression W(W0&plus;W1) using the old correction value W1. Further, if the deviation W2 is too large, which means that the positive dynamic range (PDR) is narrower than a necessary range, then the output of the weight sensor may be saturated for a large load. In this case, the seat assembly needs a disassembly and adjustment or the substitution of a new one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Therefore, what is needed is a seat load measuring system that provides an accurate seat load measurement by adjusting its zero point even when the zero point has significantly deviated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> What is further needed is a seat load measuring system that alerts the user if the zero point deviation exceeds a predetermined value. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the invention, a seat load measuring system which is for use in a vehicle occupant protection device for a vehicle seat and which has a zero point adjusting capability is provided. The seat load measuring system comprises a plurality of weight sensor assemblies each for providing a first output indicative of a weight component of an occupant of the vehicle seat which component is applied to the weight sensor assembly; a hub assembly for collecting the first outputs and providing a second output determined by the first outputs; and means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment to each of the weight sensor assemblies. Each weight sensor assembly includes a zero point adjusting section, which receives an output from the communication means for executing a zero point adjusting operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The predetermined zero adjusting operation includes providing an alert if a zero point of the weight sensor assembly is not within a predetermined range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment may be communicated to the zero point adjusting section by using an input device for permitting the user to enter a predetermined command; and portions distributed in the hub assembly and each weight sensor assembly for transferring the predetermined command to the means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment may be communicated to the zero point adjusting section by using a momentary switch provided in the hub assembly; and portions distributed in the hub assembly and each weight sensor assembly for transferring the operation state of the momentary switch to the zero point adjusting section.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Further objects and advantages of the present invention will be apparent from the following description of the preferred embodiments of the invention as illustrated in the accompanying drawing, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a conventional way of determining the seat load component W<highlight><subscript>LD </subscript></highlight>posed on each of the weight sensors from the output W of the weight sensor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a first exemplary zero point adjusting arrangement using a seat load measuring system capable of adjusting its zero point in accordance with a first illustrative embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagram for illustrating the principles of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flowchart showing a zero point adjusting operation executed by CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of a seat load measuring hub <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in response to a predetermined instruction by a service person; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a second exemplary zero point adjusting arrangement including an air bag system using a seat load measuring system capable of adjusting its zero point in accordance with a second illustrative embodiment of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing an exemplary modification of the seat load measuring hub assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 5</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Throughout the drawing, the same elements when shown in more than one figure are designated by the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a first exemplary zero point adjusting arrangement I using a seat load measuring system (10&plus;20) which is capable of adjusting its zero point in accordance with a first illustrative embodiment of the invention. In the zero point adjusting arrangement <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> from which a service person enters a zero point-adjustment command is connected with a seat load measuring system which comprises four weight sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and seat load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is preferably a microprocessor-based maintenance service tool with data input and output portions. Weight sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are attached to a seat assembly (not shown), while seat load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is provided within the vehicle chamber: e.g., on the not-shown seat assembly or a vehicle floor (not shown) in a well-known manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Each weight sensor assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for generating an output voltage depending on the pressure or tension applied thereto; amplifier (AMP.) <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> for amplifying the output voltage from weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to an appropriate level W; memory <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> for storing a sign-inverted correction value (&minus;Wc) for use in the correction of the sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> output voltage; adder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for adding the sign-inverted correction value &minus;Wc to the sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> output voltage; amplifier (AMP.) <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> for amplifying the adder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> output; controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for performing a zero point adjustment as detailed below; and communication interface (IF) <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for communicating with seat load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises a bridge circuit of four strain gages with two opposing nodes supplied with a constant voltage. An output voltage is given by the other two opposing nodes of the bridge circuit. The strain gages may be any of semiconductor strain gages, Cu&mdash;Ni strain gages, etc. Applying a pressure to a weight sensor causes the resistances of the strain gages (i.e., the balance of the bridge circuit) to vary, resulting in a change in the output of the weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Since the sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> output voltage is vary small, amplifier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is preferably inserted just after weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which enhances the signal-to-noise ratio of the amplifier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> output W. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The correction value Wc is equal to no-load weight sensor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> output W0 plus seat weight component W1, i.e., W0&plus;W1. It should be noted that adder <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be replaced with a subtracter and the correction value Wc instead of the sign-inverted correction value &minus;Wc may be stored in the memory <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Seat load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises communication interface (IF) <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for communicating with four weight sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or their communication interfaces <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>; CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for providing an output signal based on the weight of the seat load; and interface <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> for communicating with command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> collects the output signals from the four weight sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via interface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and provides a piece of information determined on the basis of the sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> output signals. The piece of information may be indicative of the seat load status, which is, for example, one of adult, child and unoccupancy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagram for illustrating the principles of the invention. When installing a seat assembly (not shown) that includes the seat load measuring system in a vehicle under manufacturing is completed, an initial setting of the correction value W0&plus;W1 is executed in each weight sensor assembly. Specifically, an attendant enters a zero point adjusting command from command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The zero adjustment command is received by CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, which in turn transfers the zero point adjusting command to each weight sensor assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In response to a reception of the zero point adjusting command, controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of each weight sensor assemblies <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> executes a zero point adjusting operation as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> measures the amplifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> output W&minus;Wc&equals;W1 (memory <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> contains &minus;W0 as &minus;Wc at this initial setting stage) without applying a load to the seat in step <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> and stores an initial correction value &minus;(W0&plus;W1) in memory <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in step <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> If a vehicle should experience a minor crash, which can cause the zero point to deviate from the current value W0&plus;W1 to a new value W0&plus;W2, then the user will take the vehicle to an auto repair shop. The attendant or repairman connects the command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to enter the zero point adjusting command. Responsively, the zero point adjusting operation is executed in the above-described manner. In this case, since the no-load amplifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> output W2 is measured in step <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> stores the new value &minus;(W0&plus;W2) in memory <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, even if the zero point of a weight sensor <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> should deviate from the current value W0&plus;W1 to the new value W0&plus;W2, once the zero point is adjusted at the auto repair shop as described above, the amplifier <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> output W is corrected with the new value W0&plus;W2, resulting in each weight sensor assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> yielding a correct output W&minus;(W0&plus;W2)&equals;(W0&plus;W2&plus;W<highlight><subscript>LD</subscript></highlight>)&minus;(W0&plus;W2)&equals;W<highlight><subscript>LD</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Further, controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be so arranged as to output an alert signal or message if the no-load amplifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> output W2 in step <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> exceeds a predetermined allowable maximum zero point value W0max. In this case, the alert signal or message is passed to CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and then to command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, which in turn displays a message to the effect that the correction value W0&plus;W2 exceeds the predetermined allowable maximum value while providing a predetermined alert sound. The alert message preferably includes an ID of the alerting weight sensor assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which enables command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to display which of the four weight sensor assemblies is alerting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiment, load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and air bag controller <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are separately implemented. However, they are embodied as a single module by incorporating the functions of CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> into the controller <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. In this case, communication interfaces <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> can be eliminated. This enables reductions in the size, the weight and the price of the seat load measuring system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a second exemplary zero point adjusting arrangement including an air bag system using a seat load measuring system capable of adjusting its zero point in accordance with a second illustrative embodiment of the invention. In other words, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows an example in which seat load measuring system <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is used for an air bag system. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the Zero point adjusting arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises an air bag system <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>; two seat load measuring systems <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which are connected to air bag system <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which are installed into the driver&apos;s seat (not shown) and the assistant driver&apos;s seat (not shown) for example; and maintenance service tool <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> which serves as a command input device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Air bag system <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> comprises crash sensors <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> for detecting a crash; air bag controller <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for controlling the deployment of the air bags; and front and side air bags <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> for the not-shown driver&apos;s seat and front and side air bags <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> for the not-shown assistant driver&apos;s seat. Air bag controller <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises accelerometer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for measuring the acceleration; CPU-based controller <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>; communication interface <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> to which two seat load measuring systems <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected; and service tool interface <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to which maintenance service tool <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is connected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The zero point adjusting operation of zero point adjusting arrangement <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is identical to that of zero point adjusting arrangement <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> except for the route of the zero point adjusting command. Specifically, a zero point adjusting command entered by the attendant through service tool <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is passed to controller <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> via interface <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, to CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> via interfaces <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and then to controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via interfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The operation of controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is identical to that described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. If controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> issues the above-mentioned alert message, then the alert message is transmitted along the opposite route. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In order to enable the above operation, air bag controller <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has to be so arranged that if controller <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> receives first data indicative of a zero point adjusting request, then controller <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> passes second data of the zero point adjusting request to controller <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The first and second data may be either identical to or different from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiments, command input device <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> or maintenance service tool <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> is used as command input means. Alternatively, load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be provided with a kind of switch as zero point adjusting command input means as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is identical to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> except that CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has been replaced with CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and momentary switch <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> having the terminals connected to CPU <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and opening <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> provided in the enclosure of load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>have been added. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, if the attendant desires to cause a set of four weight sensor assemblies to execute zero point adjusting operation, he or she has only to make switch <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> on, for example, by pushing the switch <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> button (not shown) through opening <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> with a rod. This embodiment needs any other input means for the zero point adjustment. As long as this type of hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is used, an occupant protection system configured as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> can have any configuration. In other words, air bag system controller <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has no longer to be specially arranged in order to relay the zero point adjusting command from service tool <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to load measuring hub assembly <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Many widely different embodiments of the present invention may be constructed without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. It should be understood that the present invention is not limited to the specific embodiments described in the specification, except as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system which is for use in a vehicle occupant protection device for a vehicle seat and which has a zero point adjusting capability, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of weight sensor assemblies each for providing a first output indicative of a weight component of an occupant of the vehicle seat which component is applied to the weight sensor assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>hub means for collecting said first outputs and providing a second output determined by said first outputs, wherein each weight sensor assembly; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment to each of said plurality of weight sensor assemblies, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each weight sensor assembly includes means responsive to a reception of an output from said communication means for executing a predetermined zero point adjusting operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation includes means for providing an alert if a zero point of said weight sensor assembly is not within a predetermined range. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment comprises: 
<claim-text>means for permitting the user to enter a predetermined command; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means distributed in said hub means and each weight sensor assembly for transferring said predetermined command to said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment comprises: 
<claim-text>a momentary switch provided in said hub means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means distributed in said hub means and each weight sensor assembly for transferring an operation state of said momentary switch to said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An occupant protection system of a vehicle including: 
<claim-text>a seat load measuring subsystem for providing information determined by a weight of an occupant of a vehicle seat, said seat load measuring subsystem comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of weight sensor assemblies each for providing a first output indicative of a weight component of said occupant which is applied to the weight sensor assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>hub means for collecting said first outputs and providing said information, wherein each weight sensor assembly; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment of each weight sensor assembly to each weight sensor assembly, and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control means for controlling an operation of the occupant protection system on the basis of said information, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each weight sensor assembly includes means responsive to a reception of an output from said communication means for executing a predetermined zero point adjusting operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An occupant protection system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation includes means for providing an alert if a zero point of said weight sensor assembly is not within a predetermined range. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment comprises: 
<claim-text>means for permitting the user to enter a predetermined command; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means distributed in said hub means and each weight sensor assembly for transferring said predetermined command to said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A seat load measuring system as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said means for communicating a user&apos;s desire for a zero point adjustment comprises: 
<claim-text>a momentary switch provided in said hub means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means distributed in said hub means and each weight sensor assembly for transferring an operation state of said momentary switch to said means for executing a predetermined zero adjusting operation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
