<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003892A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003892A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003892A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003892A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003892A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003892A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003892A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003892A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003892</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10184403</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>20011415</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>FI</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04J003/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04B001/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H05K011/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04M001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04B001/38</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>345000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>455</class>
<subclass>569000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Wireless user interface extension</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Rauno</given-name>
<family-name>Makinen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tampere</city>
<country-code>FI</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Nokia Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARRINGTON &amp; SMITH, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4 RESEARCH DRIVE</address-1>
<city>SHELTON</city>
<state>CT</state>
<postalcode>06484-6212</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A car hands-free unit (HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>) with a Low-Power Radio-Frequency (LPRF) module <highlight><bold>141 </bold></highlight>(typically a Bluetooth module) configured to receive an identifier <highlight><bold>134 </bold></highlight>from a car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. Different drivers are provided with different car keys <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. When receiving the identifier <highlight><bold>134 </bold></highlight>first time, the HFU stores trusted data to pair with a driver&apos;s phone. Thereafter, the HFU automatically connects to the driver&apos;s phone when the same car key <highlight><bold>133 </bold></highlight>is used. The hands-free unit typically comprises a microphone and a loudspeaker, and can also have a display and/or a camera. In operation the HFU provides automatic link <highlight><bold>160 </bold></highlight>with a compliant LPRF enabled mobile phone without need to touch the mobile phone, allowing its use even when the mobile phone is placed in a boot of a car <highlight><bold>101. </bold></highlight></paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to wireless hands-free (HF) equipment of mobile telephones. It relates particularly, but not exclusively, to vehicle-installable wireless HF equipment for mobile telephones. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Various accessories have been developed for mobile telephones to improve their usability. One of these is an HF set for a car that has a cradle for receiving a mobile telephone. The cradle comprises an interface for charging the mobile telephone and another interface for coupling an external speaker and microphone (HF equipment) to the mobile telephone when placed in the cradle. This enables the HF operation and easy charging of the mobile telephone. More recently, the talk and standby times of mobile telephones have increased so that charging is not usually required during a car journey. Therefore, many individuals have considered HF sets to be unnecessary in car. However, if a mobile telephone is kept in a pocket or attached to a belt, answering mobile telephone calls can be inconvenient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Wireless Bluetooth HF-sets have been developed to provide an easy connection of a mobile telephone with the HF-set. A mobile telephone brought into a car can connect to the HF-set from a pocket or a briefcase by means of Low-Power Radio Frequency (LPRF) waves. For example, Parrot has presented in their press release a Bluetooth enabled car HF set Parrot CK3000. According to the press release, this kit is based on Parrot&apos;s technology and powered by Parrot&apos;s Chip &ldquo;Parrot3&rdquo;, which provides voice recognition. The user can place a call with his phone in his pocket or briefcase. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> According to a first aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of extending a user interface of a mobile communication device by means of a user interface extension device which is configured for vehicle use, the mobile communication device and the user interface extension device communicating over a wireless link, the method comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> characterised by the method further comprising the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> obtaining an authorisation code to use a vehicle; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> obtaining an identifier having a common source as the authorisation code; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> identifying by the identifier a particular mobile communication device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> using the identifier to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> It is advantage of the invention that trusted relationship information can be stored and later used easily so as to make use of a presently available mobile communication device automatically without necessarily requiring user interaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the trusted relationship information corresponds to the identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises the step of using the trusted relationship information corresponding to the identifier to connect the user interface extension device with the mobile communication device selected. This allows forming of a relatively secure link with the mobile communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the identifier is derived from the authorisation code. Alternatively, the identifier is identical to the authorisation code. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the authorisation code is a code derived from a physical entity. Preferably, the physical entity is a mechanical key, an electronic key, a retinal pattern of the user, a finger print of the user, or the voice of the user. Alternatively, the authorisation code is a code known by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device is connected with the particular mobile communication device in response to obtaining the identifier. This may provide the user interface extension device available to the particular mobile communication device without perceivable delays. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the user interface extension device is connected with the particular mobile communication device on an on-demand basis, for example on receiving a telephone call by the particular mobile communication device. This may provide the user interface extension device available to the particular mobile communication device without perceivable delays and without unnecessarily communicating radio signals and spares energy of the particular mobile communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises associating the trusted relationship information with the identifier by the user interface extension device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises the step of detecting a pairing request from a mobile communication device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the associating comprises a sub-step of storing the trusted relationship information in a memory of the user interface extension device. This allows automatic connection of the user interface extension device to an associated mobile telephone without necessarily performing the association again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device repeatedly broadcasts messages to indicate to any mobile communication device within its coverage that a user interface service is available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said storing trusted relationship information comprises a sub-step of storing the trusted relationship information in a memory of the mobile communication device. This helps in the forming of the trusted link. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Preferably, said storing trusted relationship information is suitable for use in a pairing process conforming to the Bluetooth standard. This provides conformance with a forthcoming extensive base of Bluetooth enabled mobile telephones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device comprises a loudspeaker. This allows hands-free conversations using the mobile communication device where the user interface extension device provides an audio signal to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device comprises a microphone. This allows hands-free conversations using the mobile communication device where the external user interface extension device captures an audio signal from the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device comprises a speech synthesiser. This allows the user interface extension device to convert written information into speech to the user. This helps receiving written messages such as short messages known from the short message service in GSM. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device comprises a display. This allows the user interface extension device to provide an external display for displaying information to the user, for example, maps, pictures, traffic signs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the user interface extension device comprises an electronic image capturing device. This allows hands-free video mobile telephone conversations where the user interface extension device captures images by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the image capturing device is manually controllable such that the user may determine the object of the capturing device. This allows the user to take electronic images of the environment, for example to help rescue people to determine which rescuing units are required in case of a traffic accident, or to ask advice for navigation, or just collect pictures from beautiful scenes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises the step of detecting the authorisation code. Preferably, this detecting is based on checking the user&apos;s key. Even more preferably, at least two different keys are provided for different users so that those different users have an access to use the vehicle with different keys that provide different identifiers. This allows association of different mobile communication devices with different identifiers by the user interface extension device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the identifier is used to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and the particular mobile communication devices among at least two mobile communication devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises the step of keeping a database of identifiers and corresponding mobile communication devices. Preferably, the database is kept by the user interface extension device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises the steps of obtaining a signal when the authorisation code becomes inaccessible to the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises removing the wireless link between the user interface extension device and the particular mobile communication device in response to detecting the authorisation code becoming inaccessible to the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the method further comprises automatic transfer of user interface operation from the user interface extension device to the particular mobile communication device in response to detecting the authorisation code becoming inaccessible to the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> According to a second aspect of the present invention, there is provided a user interface extension device for extending a user interface of a mobile communication device, comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> a memory for storing trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link. characterised by </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> the user interface extension device further comprising a port for receiving an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, and for receiving an identifier having a common source as the authorisation code, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> the wireless transceiver being configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the present invention, there is provided a system comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> a mobile communication device comprising a wireless transceiver for forming a wireless link; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> a user interface extension device comprising a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device and at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> a memory for storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting the user interface extension device to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; characterised by </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> the system further comprising a port for receiving an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> the wireless transceiver being configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> According to a fourth aspect of the present invention, there is provided a vehicle for a user having a mobile communication device and an authorisation code to use the vehicle, the vehicle comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> a user interface extension device configured for vehicle use; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and a mobile communication device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> a memory for storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting the user interface extension device to the mobile communication device over the wireless link. characterised by </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> the vehicle further comprising an authentication code verification means for checking validity of an authentication code to restrain unauthorised use of the vehicle without a valid authentication code; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> means for providing the user interface extension device with an identifier having a common source as the authorisation code; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> the wireless transceiver being configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device, by using the identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the vehicle is a car. Even more preferably, the vehicle is a passenger car. Alternatively, the vehicle may be a boat or an aircraft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> According to a fifth aspect of the present invention, there is provided a computer executable program to control a user interface extension device configured for vehicle use, for extending a user interface of a mobile communication device, comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to provide a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to provide the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to store trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; characterised by the program further comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to receive an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The embodiments of one aspect also apply to various other aspects of the invention. In sake of briefness, the embodiments have not been repeated in connection with every aspect of the invention. A skilled reader will appreciate the advantages of the various aspects based on the advantages of the first aspect of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a system according to a preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a flow chart of the operation of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the association process <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> in more detail; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a correlation matrix of the preferred embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to a preferred embodiment of the invention. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is installed in a car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The system comprises a black box, or car controller <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, a Controller Area Network (CAN) <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> connected to the car controller <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of devices connected to the controller area network, including a lock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight>, a lock radio <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> for receiving remote locking and unlocking commands, a hands free (HF) extension Unit HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and a mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> comprises a Bluetooth (BT) module <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> for Low-Power Radio Frequency co-operation with Bluetooth enabled mobile telephones, a memory <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, a speaker <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>, a microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and a port <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> for communicating with the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The speaker <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> and the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are user interface elements mounted on or embedded in an inner surface of the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> as is typical in the art of car HF sets for mobile telephones. In alternative embodiments, either or both of the speaker <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> and the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> may be integrated into an HF-set accessory that can be plugged into a cigarette lighter socket. The mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> comprises a Bluetooth module <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> compliant with the Bluetooth module <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> of the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> When the driver comes to the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> when stopped and parked, he takes the key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, opens a door (not shown) with the key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, and switches an ignition voltage on using the key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is installed such that it receives the car&apos;s battery voltage and is operable when ignition voltage is switched on. This connection provides clear logic that is easy to understand by a user (that is, a driver). the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is on when the ignition voltage is switched on, and off when the ignition voltage is switched off. In an alternative embodiment, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> becomes switched off with a delay if, upon switching the ignition voltage off, an HF conversation is going on. In yet another alternative embodiment, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is continuously operable and can be switched on and off separately from the ignition voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is configured so that the doors (not shown) of the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> can be locked either with a car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> or with a remote controller (not shown), using the lock radio <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. On opening a door or unlocking the steering lock, the lock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> is configured to read the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> and an identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> associated to the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> and to provide the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> to the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Although the lock is drawn as a single unit, it typically has at least three different access elements, one for each front door and one for steering or gear-box locking. The car key is mechanical or electronic such as in Renault Laguna&trade; model (2001 version). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is configured to pass to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> information specific to the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. This information may be the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> associated to the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>, or a derivative thereof. In this embodiment, the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> passes the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> associated with the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> itself to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The operation of the system is described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In brief, when in operation, the HFU outputs and inputs electrical signals to and from the speaker <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> and the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The Bluetooth module <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> allows remote use of the HFU by the Bluetooth enabled mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> located, for example, in a boot of the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a flow chart of the operation of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The operation starts from step <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, in which the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is in a passive state (for example, parked and locked). Next, the driver arrives at the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, and unlocks it using the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. In step <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> is used to switch ignition voltage on and the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> becomes operative. In step <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, the driver&apos;s ID, or the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> related to the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> of the driver, is passed from the lock <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> via the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> next checks (step <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>) whether it has already associated any mobile device such as the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> with the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. If it has, the procedure skips steps up to <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. If it has not, in step <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> attempts to associate one or more mobile telephones with the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. This association process is further described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> then searches among the associated mobile telephones for available mobile telephones associated with the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. A correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) is stored and maintained in the memory <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> for determining the mobile telephone or mobile telephones associated with the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. The searching has two possible results. As a first result, there is only one such mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> attempts to connect with this mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. As a second result, there are more than one available associated mobile telephones and the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> attempts to connect with one of them. In this case, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> attempts to connect with each of the available associated mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> in a predetermined order, until it succeeds in connecting with one mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> or all attempts have failed. This predetermined order is typically the order of recent usage of the mobile telephones with the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Although the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is physically independent of the mobile communication device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, that is it is kept in the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> and is not even accessible to the mobile communication device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, the mobile communication device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is identified by the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, because the driver at least temporarily is in possession of the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. Therefore, common control by the driver creates an association between the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and the mobile communication device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> checks whether an HF service has been or is being requested. If no HF service has been or is being requested, the operation jumps to step <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Assuming an HF service has been or is being requested, in step <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> provides the service requested. It forms the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> with an associated mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to provide the HF service requested, for example, by providing a loudspeaker and microphone service over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> using the Bluetooth module <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, the operation proceeds and cycles repeatedly through steps <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> during the providing the service requested. The service is thus started in step <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> and the process continues during the providing the service. In an alternative embodiment, the service requested is first provided entirely before proceeding to step <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In this preferred embodiment, the mobile communication device <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> has a voice recognition capability. Otherwise, in an alternative embodiment, steps <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> are omitted and the operation returns to step <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> checks whether it has been ordered to receive a voice command from the driver. Such an order can be given by a voice command, for example, by pronouncing &ldquo;HF command&rdquo; if the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has voice recognition functionality. In alternative embodiments, the order can be given by pressing a particular button (not shown) or by using the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> (for example, using a menu command). If the order for receiving a voice command has been given, the operation proceeds to step <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> If no order for receiving a voice command has been given, the operation returns to step <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. There the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> checks again for mobile telephones that are available, because the number of mobile telephones available may change during a journey, for example, due to switching a mobile telephone on or off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, voice commanding is performed. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> captures speech (or at least one word or phoneme) by the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and transmits it over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> then performs voice recognition to recognise what the driver has commanded. After step <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, the operation resumes to step <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the voice recognition has two phases, firstly initiating voice recognition by a first voice recognition command (the order) and secondly actually performing voice recognition of the actual message. These phases are next explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In the first phase, only an oral order for receiving a voice command is recognised by the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. For example, if the driver desires to call a friend &ldquo;Laura&rdquo;, he or she first says &ldquo;HF command&rdquo;. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> recognises this order. It then starts preparing the mobile telephone for the second phase of the voice recognition by messaging over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> that oral signal will be captured by the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and transmitted to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In the second phase, the mobile telephone carries out voice recognition on the oral signal which is transmitted to it over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. In this case, the driver says &ldquo;call Laura&rdquo;. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> captures this oral signal and forwards it to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, which recognises as a command that a call should be made. The mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> further recognises the recipient or number to which the call should be made, in this case the name Laura. It then looks for its own phone book for this name, picks the corresponding telephone number and initiates a mobile telephone call to Laura&apos;s number. It also connects to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> for an HF phone call and the driver can hear through the speaker <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> when the call is answered. At this point, if the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is able to detect answering of the phone call, the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> commands the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to silence through the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> a car radio (not shown) if such is installed. Correspondingly, when the telephone call is terminated, the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> informs the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> that the telephone call has been terminated and the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> stops transmitting signals received by the microphone <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and returns the car radio to its previous playing mode through the CAN <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment of the invention, voice recognition can be further used for inputting text messages spoken by the driver for transmission in a text form. Correspondingly, received text messages can be synthesised (back) to speech with a recipient&apos;s mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The two-phase operation described in the foregoing necessitates only limited voice recognition functionality from the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, as the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> performs recognition of the actual command. Furthermore, different interpretation of commands is enabled depending on which mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> has been connected to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, because the different mobile telephones have different phone books and may also have different capabilities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the association process <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with more detail. The process starts from step <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, wherein the correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) is empty, that is, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> does not initially have any associations. Next, in step <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> checks if it has received a pairing request from a mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. If no pairing request has been received, the association process <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> jumps to step <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> and ends there. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, if a pairing request has been received, a code (such as a 4-digit code known by the driver if he is a legitimate user of the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>) is requested from the driver as an indication that his or her mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> should be trusted and paired with the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment this code is presented by the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> so that only the people within the car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> should have access to the code. Next, the code is inputted by the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> from the driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>, the code received in step <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is transferred from the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> over the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are paired with each other, by using the code transferred in step <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>, in a pairing process known from Bluetooth technology. This process involves steps in which the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> generates a code that can later be used to form session keys for securing the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> between the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> stores in its memory <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, in a record <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of the correlation matrix, the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and the code (typically in a non-volatile manner) and other data for later forming Bluetooth links <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> with the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Typically, radio traffic between the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is encrypted using a session key that is derived from trusted relationship information stored as part of the pairing made in step <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight>, the association process <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the invention. The correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is a dynamically sizeable matrix that is able to contain a plurality of records <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Each record comprises the following data fields: an identifier field <highlight><bold>411</bold></highlight>, a pairing data field <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> and a priority field <highlight><bold>413</bold></highlight>. The identifier field <highlight><bold>411</bold></highlight> comprises an identifier (such as the identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>). The pairing data field comprises the pairing data for one mobile telephone (such as the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>). The priority field comprises data for selecting an order in which to select one mobile telephone if different mobile telephones are associated with the same identifier, that is, if the correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> comprises two records having the same data in the identifier data field <highlight><bold>411</bold></highlight>. Typically, the priority data field comprises a time stamp showing the time when the use of the mobile telephone ended. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The use of the correlation matrix is next briefly explained. For example, if the correlation matrix <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> comprises more than one data field with the same identifier field <highlight><bold>411</bold></highlight> content (that is, more than one mobile telephone is associated with the same car key), the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> determines which record <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to use by looking for the most recent time stamp in the priority field <highlight><bold>413</bold></highlight>. The pairing data of that record <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> will then be used in selecting the mobile telephone associated with this most recent time stamp and a connection is attempted to this mobile telephone if it is available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> To summarise the foregoing description of the preferred embodiment of the invention, the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> provides automatic reconfiguration of the system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Some of the system&apos;s functional elements are chosen among different alternatives (mobile telephones). The system helps the driver to more easily access his or her mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, even if the same car <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> accommodates other mobile telephones that also earlier have been connected to the same HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. This particularly applies when the mobile telephones are each associated with different car keys <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> allows performing various operations (by using voice recognition and the Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>) with the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> associated with the driver&apos;s identifier <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> without the driver needing to physically access it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> The invention may further be enhanced by providing an automatic user interface control resuming to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> when the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> is removed from the lock, or key reader in general. This allows automatic recognising when the driver leaves the car and consecutive moving of any active call from the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to the mobile telephone <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Using this embodiment, a user may step out his or her car and continue a mobile telephone call using the mobile telephone. By removing the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> from the lock user simultaneously immobilises the car and indicates termination of the user of the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Technically, this is typically implemented by sending an indication of the removal of the car key <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> over a bus in the car (e.g. CAN) and detecting this indication by the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Using this information, the HFU can smoothly disconnect the current Bluetooth link <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> according to the BT protocol. When the link is disconnected, the radio telephone <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> will automatically re-route the call to its own user interface. For user feedback, an indication of the re-routing of the call is advantageously provided by the HFU <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, for example, by speech synthesis or displayed message. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Particular implementations and embodiments of the invention have been described. It is clear to a person skilled in the art that the invention is not restricted to details of the embodiments presented above, but that it can be implemented in other embodiments using equivalent means without deviating from the characteristics of the invention. The scope of the invention is only restricted by the attached patent claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of extending a user interface of a mobile communication device by means of a user interface extension device which is configured for vehicle use, the mobile communication device and the user interface extension device communicating over a wireless link, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining an authorisation code to use a vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining an identifier having a common source as the authorisation code; </claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying by the identifier a particular mobile communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>using the identifier to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the trusted relationship information corresponding to the identifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of using the trusted relationship information corresponding to the identifier to connect the user interface extension device with the particular mobile communication device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising keeping a database comprising the trusted relationship information and the corresponding identifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of detecting a pairing request from the mobile communication device within the radio coverage of the user interface extension device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the user interface extension device further comprises a memory and said associating the trusted relationship information with the identifier further comprising a sub-step of storing trusted relationship information in the memory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said trusted relationship information is suitable for use in a pairing process conforming to the Bluetooth standard. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the user interface extension device further comprises at least one of a loudspeaker, a microphone, a display, an electronic image capturing device and a speech synthesising device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising deriving the authorisation code from a physical entity, the physical entity being selected from a group consisting of: mechanical key, an electronic key, a retinal pattern of a user, a finger print of a user, and the voice of a user. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>.A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising automatically transferring user interface operation from the user interface extension device to the particular mobile communication device in response to detecting the authorisation code becoming inaccessible to the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A user interface extension device for extending a user interface of a mobile communication device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory for storing trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a port for receiving an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the wireless transceiver has been configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A system comprising: 
<claim-text>a mobile communication device comprising a wireless transceiver for forming a wireless link; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a user interface extension device comprising a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device and at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory for storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting the user interface extension device to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a port for receiving an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the wireless transceiver has been configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>a user interface extension device configured for vehicle use; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wireless transceiver for providing a wireless link between the user interface extension device and a mobile communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one user interface element for providing the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a memory for storing, accessible to the user interface extension device, trusted relationship information for connecting the user interface extension device to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an authentication code verification means for checking validity of an authentication code to restrain unauthorised use of the vehicle without a valid authentication code; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for providing the user interface extension device with an identifier having a common source as the authorisation code; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the wireless transceiver has been configured to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device, by using the identifier. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>.A computer executable program to control a user interface extension device configured for vehicle use, for extending a user interface of a mobile communication device, comprising: 
<claim-text>computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to provide a wireless link between the user interface extension device and the mobile communication device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to provide the mobile communication device with an extended user interface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to store trusted relationship information for connecting to the mobile communication device over the wireless link; </claim-text>
<claim-text>computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to receive an identifier having a common source as an authorisation code to use a vehicle, the identifier identifying a particular mobile communication device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>computer executable program code for causing the user interface extension device to establish the wireless link between the user interface extension device and a particular mobile communication device by using the identifier.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003892A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003892A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003892A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003892A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
