<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002386</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896077</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010630</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B01F007/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>366</class>
<subclass>153300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>366</class>
<subclass>156100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>366</class>
<subclass>603000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Combined chassis and mixer apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>William</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Knight</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Brodhead</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DAVID J. ARCHER</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>9790 FOREST PRESERVE RD.</address-1>
<city>DURAND</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>61024</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A combined chassis and mixer apparatus is disclosed for mixing livestock feed. The apparatus includes a chassis having a front and a rearward end. The chassis includes an operator station, a motor and a gearbox driven by the motor. The chassis also includes at least one pair of drive wheels for moving the chassis. The drive wheels are connected to the gearbox for selectively moving the chassis in a first direction from the rearward end towards the front end and in a second direction from the front end towards the rearward end of the chassis. An extension framework has a first and a second end, the first end of the extension extending from the chassis in the second direction. A mixer container is supported by the extension such that the container is disposed between the chassis and the second end of the extension. Additionally, at least one steerable wheel is rotatably connected to the second end of the extension so that the second end of the extension is disposed between the container and the steerable wheel such that location and positioning of the mixer container for dispensing the livestock feed is enhanced. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a combined chassis and mixer apparatus for mixing livestock feed. More specifically, the present invention relates to a combined chassis and mixer apparatus for mixing livestock feed in which location and positioning of the mixer container for dispensing the livestock feed is enhanced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Information Disclosure Statement </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Mixers are primarily used for mixing various foods for subsequent distribution to animal feed troughs. However, prior art mixers include a drawbar and hitch for connection to a tractor The tractor includes a power take off (PTO) and a driveline must be connected between the tractor and the mixer in order to rotate a mixing auger within the mixer container. When the feed has been mixed, the tractor tows the mixer to the animal trough where a portion of the feed is discharged through an outlet in the mixer container for feeding the cattle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Although U.S. Pat. No. 5,782,559 to Neier et al teaches a self-propelled material mixer, the prior art arrangements suffer from the following drawbacks: In the Neier et al arrangement described in the &apos;559 patent, the operator is located at the back which is a disadvantage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The combined tractor and mixer according to the present invention has the following advantages over the more conventional mixers towed by a tractor. First, the combined tractor and mixer of the present invention is shorter. Second, the combined tractor and mixer is easier to maneuver. Third, the combined tractor and mixer according to the present invention is easier to backup. Fourth, the combined tractor and mixer has better traction when compared with the mixers towed by a tractor. Also, with the towed mixers, the mixer must be hitched and unhitched to the tractor when mixing is to be carried out. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The combined chassis and mixer of the present invention overcomes all of the aforementioned problems associated with the prior art arrangements by the provision of a combined apparatus which enables an operator thereof to accurately locate the outlet of the mixer in close proximity to the animal feed trough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is a primary feature of the present invention to provide a combined chassis and mixer which overcomes the problems associated with the prior art proposals and which makes a considerable contribution to the art of mixing and distributing animal feed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another feature of the present invention is the provision of a combined chassis and mixer apparatus in which the mixer is permanently connected in driven relationship with the chassis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the present invention will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art by a consideration of the detailed description of a preferred embodiment of the present invention contained herein. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a combined chassis and mixer apparatus for mixing livestock feed. The apparatus includes a chassis having a front and a rearward end. The chassis includes an operator station, a motor and a gearbox driven by the motor. The chassis also includes at least one pair of drive wheels for moving the chassis. The drive wheels are connected to the gearbox for selectively moving the chassis in a first direction from the rearward end towards the front end and in a second direction from the front end towards the rearward end of the chassis. An extension framework has a first and a second end, the first end of the extension extending from the chassis in the second direction. A mixer container is supported by the extension such that the container is disposed between the chassis and the second end of the extension. Additionally, a steerable wheel is rotatably connected to the second end of the extension so that the second end of the extension is disposed between the container and the steerable wheel such that location and positioning of the mixer container for dispensing the livestock feed is enhanced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In a more specific embodiment of the present invention, the drive wheels have a diameter which is greater than a diameter of the steerable wheel. Also, the first end of the extension is rigidly secured to the rearward end of the chassis and the mixer container is secured to the extension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the mixer container includes a base which defines a peripheral edge. A wall extends away from the peripheral edge, the base and the wall defining therebetween an enclosure for the reception therein of the livestock feed. An auger is rotatably disposed within the enclosure such that when the feed is disposed within the enclosure, rotation of the auger mixes the livestock feed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Also, a power take off extends between the gearbox and the auger for rotating the auger and the wall defines a discharge outlet for the discharge therethrough of mixed livestock feed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Many modifications and variations of the present invention will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art by a consideration of the detailed description contained hereinafter taken in conjunction with the annexed drawings showing a preferred embodiment of the present invention. However, such modifications and variations fall within the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined by the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a combined chassis and mixer apparatus according to the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Similar reference characters refer to similar parts throughout the views of the drawings. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a combined chassis and mixer apparatus generally designated <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the present invention for mixing livestock feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> having a front and a rearward end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> respectively. The chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes an operator station <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, a motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a gearbox <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> driven by the motor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> also includes at least one pair of drive wheels <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for moving the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The drive wheels <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are connected to the gearbox <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for selectively moving the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in a first direction as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the rearward end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> towards the front end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and in a second direction as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from the front end <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> towards the rearward end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An extension framework <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a first and a second end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> respectively, the first end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending from the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in the second direction <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A mixer container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is supported by the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> such that the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is disposed between the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the second end <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Additionally, a steerable wheel <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is rotatably connected to the second end <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> so that the second end <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is disposed between the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the steerable wheel <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> such that location and positioning of the mixer container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for dispensing the livestock feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is enhanced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In a more specific embodiment of the present invention, the drive wheels <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> have a diameter D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is greater than a diameter D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the steerable wheel <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Also, the first end <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is rigidly secured to the rearward end <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the chassis <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the mixer container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is secured to the extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the mixer container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> which defines a peripheral edge <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A wall <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> extends away from the peripheral edge <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the base <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the wall <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> defining therebetween an enclosure <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> for the reception therein of the livestock feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An auger <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is rotatably disposed within the enclosure <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> such that when the feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is disposed within the enclosure <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, rotation of the auger <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> mixes the livestock feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Also, a power take off (PTO) and driveline <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extends between the gearbox <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the auger <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for rotating the auger <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and the wall <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> defines a discharge outlet <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> for the discharge therethrough of mixed livestock feed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Also as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a self loader arrangement generally designated <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for collecting and conveying material to the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for mixing thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the self loader <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> includes a bucket <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and a first and second auger <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> respectively. The augers are arranged so that the material is fed in the direction of the arrows <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> by the augers <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> respectively. The material is thereafter conveyed by a conveyor belt <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> in a direction as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> so that the material is fed into the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The conveyor belt <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> has a first end <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> disposed adjacent to the bucket <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and a second end <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> disposed above the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the conveyor <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> is pivoted about an axis <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> disposed between the first and second ends <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> respectively of the conveyor <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the axis <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is a pivotal bearing supported by a column <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In operation of the apparatus according to the present invention, in order to position the outlet <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> adjacent to an animal feed trough, the gearbox <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is positioned in reverse gear and the combined apparatus is reversed to the desired location. Drivers towing a trailer know that reversing a towed trailer into a parking space requires considerably more driving skill than reversing an automobile without a trailer into the same parking space. Also, parking an automobile forwardly with or without a trailer is relatively easy. Similarly, in the present invention, the combined chassis and mixer is analogous to driving an automobile without trailer forwardly for parking thereof. Therefore, the unique combined apparatus according to the present invention enhances the ease with which an outlet of the mixer may be located adjacent to an animal feeding trough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Also, the operator is able alter the elevation of the bucket <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> as indicated by the arrow <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, so that material can be selectively fed into the container <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by means of the augers <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and by the conveyor <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The apparatus according to the present invention provides a compact and maneuverable machine for mixing feed and the like and conveying such mixed feed for distribution thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus for mixing livestock feed, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a chassis having a front and a rearward end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said chassis including: 
<claim-text>an operator station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gearbox driven by said motor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of drive wheels for moving said chassis, said drive wheels being connected to said gearbox for selectively moving said chassis in a first direction from said rearward end towards said front end and in a second direction from said front end towards said rearward end of said chassis; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extension framework extending from said chassis, said extension framework having a first and a second end, said extension extending from said chassis in said second direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mixer container supported by said extension such that said container is disposed between said chassis and said second end of said extension; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one steerable wheel rotatably connected to said extension such that location and positioning of said mixer container for dispensing the livestock feed is enhanced. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said drive wheels have a diameter which is greater than a diameter of said steerable wheel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said chassis is a tractor that has had a front steering axle removed therefrom; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first end of said extension being rigidly secured to said tractor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said mixer container is secured to said extension. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said mixer container includes: 
<claim-text>a base which defines a peripheral edge; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wall extending away from said peripheral edge, said base and said wall defining therebetween an enclosure for the reception therein of the livestock feed; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an auger rotatably disposed within said enclosure such that when the feed is disposed within said enclosure, rotation of said auger mixes the livestock feed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> further including: 
<claim-text>a power take off driveline extending between said gearbox and said auger for rotating said auger. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said wall defines a discharge outlet for the discharge therethrough of mixed livestock feed. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said steerable wheel is a multiple wheel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> further including: 
<claim-text>a power take off driveline extending between said gearbox and said auger for rotating said auger. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus for mixing livestock feed, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a chassis having a front and a rearward end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said chassis including: 
<claim-text>an operator station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gearbox driven by said motor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of drive wheels for moving said chassis, said drive wheels being connected to said gearbox for selectively moving said chassis in a first direction from said rearward end towards said front end and in a second direction from said front end towards said rearward end of said chassis; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>an extension framework having a first and a second end, said extension extending from said chassis in said second direction; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mixer container supported by said extension such that said container is disposed between said chassis and said second end of said extension; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one steerable wheel rotatably connected to said extension such that location and positioning of said mixer container for dispensing the livestock feed is enhanced; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said apparatus further including: 
<claim-text>a self loader arrangement for collecting and conveying material to said container. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said self loader arrangement includes: 
<claim-text>a bucket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first and a second auger disposed within said bucket for collecting the material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveyor having a first and a second end, said first end being disposed adjacent to said bucket, said second end of said conveyor being disposed above said container for conveying the material from said augers to said container. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said conveyor is pivotally mounted about a pivotal axis disposed between said first and second ends of said conveyor for permitting an operator to alter the elevation of said bucket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said steerable wheel includes: 
<claim-text>a first and a second wheel. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A combined chassis and mixer apparatus as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein 
<claim-text>said steerable wheel includes: 
<claim-text>a single wheel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tire mounted on said wheel, said tire having a narrow steer wheel tread.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002386A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002386A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
