<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002167A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002167A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002167A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002167A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002167A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002167A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002167A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002167A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002167A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002167A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002167</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09472890</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>19991228</filing-date>
<continued-prosecution-application>This is a publication of a continued prosecution application (CPA) filed under 37 CFR 1.53(d).</continued-prosecution-application>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>10-377638</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19981230</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B027/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>633000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>631000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>727000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>730000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>OPTICAL ELEMENT AND OPTICAL DEVICE HAVING IT</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>HIROAKI</given-name>
<family-name>HOSHI</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>KANAGAWA-KEN</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>HIROSHI</given-name>
<family-name>SARUWATARI</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>KAWASAKI-SHI</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FITZPATRICK CELLA HARPER &amp; SCINTO</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>30 ROCKEFELLER PLAZA</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10112</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical element of a transparent body has two refracting surfaces formed in surfaces of the transparent body, and a plurality of reflecting surfaces formed in surfaces of the transparent body. Light incident through one refracting surface into the transparent body is reflected successively by the plurality of reflecting surfaces to be guided to the other refracting surface. At least one of the two refracting surfaces and reflecting surfaces has an optical low pass filter. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an optical element used in silver-film cameras, video cameras, still video cameras, copiers, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> There have been proposals made heretofore for a variety of optical systems utilizing reflecting surfaces of concave mirrors and convex mirrors, and U.S. Pat. No. 4,775,217 discloses the structure of an eyepiece in an observation optical system. This patent discloses the optical system that permits a viewer to observe a display image displayed on an information display medium and also to observe a scenery image of the outside as superimposed thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2-297516 (corresponding to U.S. Pat. No. 5,453,877) also discloses the structure of the eyepiece in the observation optical system, and the whole optical system is made thinner by making use of total reflection of light between planes arranged in parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> These conventional examples disclose the technology of the so-called seethrough function by which the outside scenery image is superimposed on the display image in the information display medium by use of a semi-transparent film. The use of the semitransparent film inevitably decreases the amount of transmitted light of the display image, but, in order to prevent it, the conventional examples employ the combination utilizing the total reflection to minimize loss of light amount at each reflecting surface. In many cases employing the total reflection at each reflecting surface, only planes are used as totally reflecting surfaces in order to simplify the structure. It is, however, more desirable to effect correction for aberration by each reflecting surface while optimizing the surface shape of each reflecting surface, rather than the structure in which the totally reflecting surfaces are only planes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> If an attempt is made to satisfy the total reflection condition for all beams incident to the reflecting surfaces degrees of freedom of the surface shape will decrease, so as to bring about the disadvantage that efficient aberration correction cannot be made at the reflecting surfaces, however. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In order to solve these problems, the applicant of the basic application filed Japanese Patent Applications Laid-Open No. 8-292368 and Laid-Open No. 8-292371 to propose a reflection type optical system, wherein the whole optical system was compactified by use of an optical element in which reflecting surfaces of curved surfaces and planes were formed integrally, and wherein accuracy of placement of each reflecting surface was relaxed in the reflecting optical system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In general, the video cameras etc. using solid state image sensors having the discrete pixel structure are designed to obtain an output image by optical space sampling of image information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> However, if on this occasion an object includes high spatial frequency components there will appear a false signal. It is thus necessary to optically limit the high frequency components of image to below the Nyquist frequency. Optical filters having such function, i.e., low pass filters are classified into those making use of the birefringence effect of such a substance as quartz or the like and those making use of refraction and diffraction by the surface shape like a phase grating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Normally, in cases wherein a birefringent plate is used as a low pass filter, the birefringent plate is placed near the image plane. This imparts constraints on design of optical system and design of mechanism in the designing process which is demanded to compactify the system. Further, the interposition of the flat plate near the image plane will give rise to ghost and flare, so as to bring about the disadvantage of degrading the quality of image, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> When a phase grating type low pass filter is used, the constraints on the design of mechanism can be relaxed by determining the grating pattern according to the distance from the image plane and a desired image separation amount. It is, however, necessary to pay attention to the point that the interposition of the transparent member should not degrade the optical performance including spherical aberration, curvature of field, and so on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Further, when the optical system and the phase grating low pass filter are constructed as respective separate members, highly accurate alignment is required between them and improvement is necessary in the cost and production technology. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In view of the problems discussed above, an object of the present invention is to provide an optical element that can readily achieve the desired optical low pass filter effect while accomplishing compactification and simplification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In order to accomplish the above object, an optical element according to the present invention is an optical element comprising an entrance refracting surface to which light is incident, a plurality of reflecting surfaces, and an exit refracting surface from which the light successively reflected by the reflecting surfaces emerges, in surfaces of a transparent body, wherein at least one of the two refracting surfaces and reflecting surfaces has the function of a low pass filter.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of an optical element according to an embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the optical element illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a phase grating type low pass filter of a domed shape; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> are schematic diagrams of phase grating type low pass filters of a triangular prism shape; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a forming mold; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> are schematic diagrams of amplitude grating type low pass filters.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be described in detail, based on the illustrated embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> having a plurality of reflecting surfaces of rotationally asymmetric shape (having no rotation symmetry axis) integrally formed, in the first embodiment, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of this optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is composed of an entrance surface of a concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, reflecting surfaces of a concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and a concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and an exit surface of a convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, these surfaces being arranged in the stated order from the direction of incidence of light L from the object. At least one of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> also functions as a low pass filter. Further, a stop <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is placed on the object side of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and an image pickup element surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of an image pickup device such as a two-dimensional CCD or the like is placed in the direction of emergence from the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is made of an optical glass or an optical plastic or the like which is optically transparent. The three reflecting surfaces of the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as the first reflecting surface formed opposite to the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> as the third reflecting surface, and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> as the fifth reflecting surface are arranged adjacent to each other and compose a first reflecting surface group. The convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the second reflecting surface and the convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the fourth reflecting surface formed opposite to the first reflecting surface group are arranged adjacent to each other and compose a second reflecting surface group. Further, a reference axis L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is indicated by a chain line, on the side of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the entrance surface of the light L passes through the center of the stop <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a reference axis L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which is indicated by a chain line, on the side of the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the exit surface arrives at the center of the image pickup element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the reference axes L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> being approximately parallel or antiparallel to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The light L from the object side is limited to a fixed amount of incident light by the stop <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and thereafter is incident to the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to become divergent light because of the power of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. After that, the light is reflected by the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to form a primary object image on an intermediate image plane IP by the power of the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. By forming the object image on the intermediate image plane IP in the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the early reflection stage in this way, increase in the optical effective area can be restrained in each surface placed on the intermediate image side of the stop <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The light L from the primary image formed on the intermediate image plane IP is reflected repeatedly by the convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to be affected by the powers of the respective reflecting surfaces and reach the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The light L is refracted by the power of the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to form an object image on the image pickup element surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As described above, the optical element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> functions as a lens unit having desired optical performance and a positive power as a whole by the repetitive refractions at the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and reflections at the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a phase grating type low pass filter, in which microscopic domes arranged in the two-dimensional directions of X and Y are formed on the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and by which phase variation is achieved in the two-dimensional directions of X and Y, thereby accomplishing the beam separation effect as a result. The pitch and the slope shape of the microscopic domes are determined so as to gain an optimal value of an output ratio of low-order diffracted light to high-order diffracted light by diffraction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> It is also possible to achieve the two-dimensional filter effect in plural directions in the frequency space, by forming a low pass filter (phase grating) of triangular prisms arranged in the Y-direction, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, on the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and forming another low pass filter (phase grating) of triangular prisms arranged in the X-direction, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, on the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. It is noted that the directions of arrangement of the triangular prisms, i.e., the directions of occurrence of the phase variation do not always have to agree with the X-direction and the Y-direction and that angles between the arrangement directions are determined by the array configuration of pixels of the image pickup element and are not always 90&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Further, there is no need for provision of the low pass filter placed immediately before the image pickup element surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the conventional optical systems, and a color correcting glass such as an infrared cut filter or the like, which used to be placed in the optical system, can be excluded from the optical path, by evaporating an interference film with wavelength selectivity on a refracting surface or a reflecting surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment the low pass filters were illustrated as to those of the domed shape and the triangular prism shape, but the cross-sectional shape thereof can be determined arbitrarily according to the desired low pass filter effect. The present embodiment showed the example in which the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> adjacent to the pupil had the low pass filter effect, but the same effect can also be expected in a configuration wherein the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> has the low pass filter effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Generally speaking, the accuracy of the phase grating and the like can be relaxed by generating the diffracted light near the pupil. However, it is better to generate the diffracted light of the zero order and the &plusmn;first orders at the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> than to propagate it inside the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the following respects; the former can suppress increase of the optical effective area in each reflecting surface and is effective in terms of flare and ghost. Therefore, a preferred one can be selected according to the specifications required of the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the optical system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In the low pass filters of the triangular prism shape illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the phase pattern is formed so as to yield the low pass filter effect using the two surfaces of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, but it can also be contemplated that the other surfaces than the aforementioned surfaces are shaped so as to bring about the phase variation in the transmitted or reflected light and the desired low pass filter effect is achieved by the effect of composition thereof. Also, not only combination of two surfaces but also three surfaces are selected to be combined as the need arises and the phase pattern is formed on each surface of the selected three surfaces so as to yield the low pass filter effect. For example, in order to decrease the X-directional dimension, the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> close to the pupil is formed in the triangular prism shape as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> so as to cause diffraction only in the Y-direction, which possibly enlarges the Y-directional, optical, effective area of each surface because of propagation of the diffracted light in the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> but which does not expand the optical effective area in the X-direction. Therefore, this is advantageous in decrease of the thickness in the X-direction. The triangular prism shape as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is formed in either of the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> close thereto so as to cause diffraction only in the X-direction, thereby forming the phase grating that induces diffraction in the X-direction. This achieves the decrease of the thickness. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Further, when the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> described in the present embodiment is applied to optical systems having the zoom function with arrangement of plural optical elements as disclosed in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 8-292368, the optical system can be constructed with high transmittance and in compactified and simplified structure. This structure increases degrees of freedom of the surfaces with the low pass filter placed therein and also increases degrees of freedom of the combination of plural surfaces, thus the optimum combination of surfaces can be selected out of those of the plural optical elements according to the specifications of the zoom lens. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of a forming mold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for molding of the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The forming mold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is composed of a pair of die units <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in order to integrally mold the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The die unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is composed of dies <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> corresponding to the respective surfaces of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The die unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is composed of three dies <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> corresponding to the respective surfaces of the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Since the dies <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> corresponding to the respective surfaces of plural curvatures forming the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are unified in the die units <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the shape of the forming mold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be determined freely even in the structure in which the reflecting surfaces and refracting surfaces are eccentric to each other. This enables the integral molding of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, convex mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, convex mirror <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, concave mirror <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The mold of the asymmetric and aspherical surfaces as in the present embodiment can be produced by cutting into the shape, using a cutting machine with high degrees of freedom of axis. The phase grating of the dome shape as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> can be produced with accuracy by optimizing the tip curvature and turning curvature of a cutting tool, and the cutting pitch in the cutting machine. Namely, an ideal case is to finish the asymmetric and aspherical surfaces into mirror-finished surfaces without the phase grating. In contrast, the present embodiment has the advantage that the mold <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the two-dimensional phase grating can be produced without extra load on the process, because the phase grating is made by positively utilizing patterns corresponding to cutting traces left by the cutting tool of the cutting machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It is also possible to form the one-dimensional phase grating filters of the triangular prism shape in the two asymmetric and aspherical surfaces, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>, and this configuration is also advantageous in cost and in accuracy of alignment between the optical system and the phase gratings, when compared with the optical system using the conventional phase type low pass filter, because the entrance surface and reflecting surface having the function of the low pass filter can be produced at the same time as the molding of the optical element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> are schematic diagrams of low pass filters in the second embodiment. In the first embodiment each of the surfaces was shaped so as to have the effect of the phase type filter, but in the present embodiment the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is formed so that transmittances are constant in the Y-direction and vary at regular intervals in the X-direction on the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Further, a reflecting surface is formed so that reflectances are constant in the X-direction but vary at regular intervals in the Y-direction on the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The low pass filters in the first embodiment were the phase type low pass filters, whereas those in the present embodiment are the amplitude type low pass filters. As for the effect thereof, the low pass filter effect can also be achieved two-dimensionally, as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>. The combination of the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in this way can halve the decrease of total transmittance caused by the formation of the low pass filters of only the reflecting surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> It is a matter of course that an amplitude type low pass filter can also be formed by making the two-dimensional grating in the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or in the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Generally speaking, with use of the amplitude type grating having lower diffraction efficiency than the phase type grating, the effect is greater in suppressing the decrease of total transmittance due to formation of the two-dimensional grating in the concave refracting surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or in the convex refracting surface <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. One can freely choose either of these combinations according to desired specifications of the optical element <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or the optical system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment it is considered to be preferable in terms of formation of image that the low pass filter is formed near a plane on which variations of the low pass filter effect on on-axis light and off-axis light are as equal to each other as possible on the occasion of variation in the diameter of the stop <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> according to the amount of incident light, i.e., near the pupil plane in which the sectional area of beams subjected to the low pass filter effect is constant. In cases wherein the low pass filter is formed in the reflecting surface close to the intermediate image plane IP, the pitch of the phase grating or the microscopic prisms to be formed in this reflecting surface, or the period of reflectances can be increased by designing the optical element so as to make the image magnification small after the intermediate image plane IP, which is preferable in terms of the production technology. In such cases, the image or the pattern on the intermediate image plane IP is imaged again on the image pickup element and it is thus desirable to design the intermediate image plane IP and the surface with the low pass filter function so as to space them a fixed distance apart from each other in order to avoid imaging of the phase grating pattern on the image pickup element surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In the optical elements of the embodiments as described above, the optically acting surface (the refracting surface or the reflecting surface) also serves as a low pass filter and thus there is no need for provision of a separate low pass filter. Therefore, the desired low pass filter effect can be achieved readily while accomplishing compactification and simplification of the optical system. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An optical element of a transparent body comprising: 
<claim-text>two refracting surfaces formed in surfaces of said transparent body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of reflecting surfaces formed in surfaces of said transparent body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein light incident through one refracting surface into said transparent body is reflected successively by said plurality of reflecting surfaces to be guided to the other refracting surface, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one of said two refracting surfaces and reflecting surfaces comprises an optical low pass filter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of said plurality of reflecting surfaces has an optical power. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one of said plurality of reflecting surfaces has a rotationally asymmetric shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said optical low pass filter is a phase type low pass filter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said optical low pass filter is an amplitude type low pass filter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said optical low pass filter is formed in at least one of said two refracting surfaces and reflecting surfaces at the same time as molding of said optical element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one of said two refracting surfaces comprises an optical low pass filter and one of said plurality of reflecting surfaces comprises an optical low pass filter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said refracting surface comprising the optical low pass filter is a phase grating whose grating pattern extends in a predetermined direction and said reflecting surface comprising the optical low pass filter is a phase grating whose grating pattern extends in a direction different from said predetermined direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The optical element according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an interference film with wavelength selectivity, said interference film being formed on at least one surface of said two refracting surfaces and reflecting surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An optical device comprising: 
<claim-text>the optical element as set forth in either one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">9</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The optical device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an image pickup element, wherein light having passed through said optical element is incident onto an image pickup surface of said image pickup element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002167A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002167A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002167A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002167A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002167A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
