<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002558</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09305097</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>19990504</filing-date>
<continued-prosecution-application>This is a publication of a continued prosecution application (CPA) filed under 37 CFR 1.53(d).</continued-prosecution-application>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01S003/097</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>372</class>
<subclass>094000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>CORROSIVE RESISTANT PLATED ELECTRODES FOR A RLG</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>STEVEN C.</given-name>
<family-name>ALBERS</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>COON RAPIDS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HONEYWELL INTERNATIONAL INC.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>101 COLUMBIA ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>P O BOX 2245</address-2>
<city>MORRISTOWN</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>07962-2245</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A ring laser gyro uses electrodes plated with a high corrosive resistant material to extend the life of the ring laser gyro. The material creates an environment that will prevent degradation of the ring laser gyro cathode and the mirrors which in turn will lengthen the life of a ring laser gyro. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> In ring laser gyros it is important for obvious reasons to have a gyro with a long lifetime. Presently, ring laser gyros have a ring laser gyro block with two anodes, a cathode and mirrors placed at the ends of the ring laser gyro block. A laser cavity exists for lasing to operate the ring laser gyro. In the past, electrodes were made with a corrosive material such as Invar. In oxidation process of the corrosive material, the material would continuously remove oxygen in the ring laser gyro which degraded the cathode and mirror environment and in turn degraded the cathode and the mirrors. As a result of the shortened life of the cathode or the mirrors, the life of the ring laser gyro was shortened as well. It would be beneficial to create a cathode and mirror environment that did not degrade the cathode or the mirrors so that the life of the gyro could be extended. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A ring laser gyro uses electrodes plated with a high corrosive resistant material to extend the life of the ring laser gyro. The material creates an environment in the ring laser gyro that will prevent degradation of the ring laser gyro cathode and the mirrors which in turn will lengthen the life of a ring laser gyro.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a cut away top view of a ring laser gyro of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a cut away top view of another embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The ring laser gyro <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has a ring laser gyro block <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, anodes <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Also, the laser cavity <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is shown where lasing occurs to create laser beams <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the ring laser gyro <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Before, as described in the background of the invention, the corrosive material of the electrodes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> would act as an oxygen sink taking oxygen away from the cathode and mirror environment. It has been discovered that this environment degraded the cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> actually require a small amount of oxygen to react with the environment which will result in a longer life for the cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and thus, the ring laser gyro <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a small amount of oxygen is required in the environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention uses the old corrosive electrode material and plates it with a high corrosive resistant material. The plating covers the entire electrode. This plating could cover the entire surface of the electrode or only the entire interior of the electrode as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Covering the entire surface or only the interior depends on available resources or other requirements that may be desirable. The plating is a thin layer of material ranging in thickness from 0.00001 to 0.0015 inches. The process to plate the material onto the electrodes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is well known in this area of technology and will not be discussed in any further detail. The material used in the present invention could be gold or aluminum, but any high corrosive resistant material could be used. This material does not take away all the oxygen in the environment and allows the oxygen to diffuse in the laser cavity <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Oxygen in the laser cavity <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> now reacts with the cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> instead of the electrodes <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and this reaction with oxygen will extend the life of the cathode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and the mirrors <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and thus, the life of the ring laser gyro <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention has been described herein in considerable detail in order to comply with the Patent Statutes and to provide those skilled in the art with the information needed to apply the novel principles and to construct and use such specialized materials and components as are required. However, it is to be understood that the invention can be carried out by specifically different materials and components, and that various modifications, both as to the processing details and operating procedures, can be accomplished without departing from the scope of the invention itself. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or right is claimed are defined as follows: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A ring laser gyro, comprising: 
<claim-text>a ring laser gyro block having a plurality of sides; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>plurality of electrodes, having an external surface and an internal surface, placed on the sides external of the ring laser gyro block wherein the electrodes are made with a first material covered with at least one other material wherein the other material covers entire internal surface of the electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is a high corrosive resistant material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the plurality of electrodes is two. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the plurality of electrodes are anodes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the electrodes are placed in the middle of the sides of the ring laser gyro block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is gold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first material is Invar. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The ring laser gyro of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is aluminum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An electrode, having an internal surface and an external surface, for use with a ring laser gyro, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first material that the electrode is made of; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one other material that covers the first material wherein the other material covers entire internal surface of the electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The electrode of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first material is Invar. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The electrode of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is a high corrosive resistant material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The electrode of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is gold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The electrode of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the other material is aluminum.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002558A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002558A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002558A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
