<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-P00900.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004902A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004902A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004902</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10179374</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-194077</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F015/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>706</class>
<subclass>001000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Outlier determination rule generation device and outlier detection device, and outlier determination rule generation method and outlier detection method thereof</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kenji</given-name>
<family-name>Yamanishi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jun-ichi</given-name>
<family-name>Takeuchi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>NEC CORPORATION</organization-name>
<address>
<city>TOKYO</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Paul J. Esatto, Jr.</name-1>
<name-2>Scully, Scott, Murphy &amp; Presser</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>400 Garden City Plaza</address-1>
<city>Garden City</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>11530</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The outlier detection device for detecting abnormal data in a data set includes an outlier rule preservation unit for holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, a filtering unit for determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the rules held in the outlier rule preservation unit, a degree of outlier calculation unit for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering unit, a sampling unit for sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by the degree of outlier calculation unit based on the calculated degree of outlier to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and a supervised learning unit for generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied and adding the new rule to the set of rules held in the outlier rule preservation unit to update the rules. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an outlier determination rule generation device and an outlier detection device for conducting statistical outlier detection, unfairness detection and fraud detection, and an outlier determination rule generation method and an outlier detection method thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Unfairness detection (abnormality detection, fraud detection) using machine learning techniques is roughly classified into two systems, a system based on supervised learning and a system based on unsupervised learning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Among well-known systems based on supervised learning are that proposed by T. Fawcett and F. Provost (&ldquo;Combining Data Mining and Machine Learning for Effective Fraud Detection&rdquo;, Proceedings of AI Approaches to Fraud Detection and Risk Management, pp. 14-19, 1997) and that proposed by J. Ryan, M. Lin and R. Miikkulainen (&ldquo;Intrusion Detection with Neural Networks&rdquo;, Proceedings of AI Approaches to Fraud Detection and Risk Management, pp. 72-77, 1997). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Supervised learning needs &ldquo;labeled data&rdquo;, data with a label (supervisor information) attached thereto in advance which indicates that data is abnormal (unfair) or not. In supervised learning, based on such past data, features of abnormal data are learned for use in the detection of abnormal data. Unfairness detection, for example, is conducted by collating data of past unfairness with data to be examined and is therefore incapable of coping with detection of unfairness having new features. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, unsupervised learning detects abnormal data (unfair data) without requiring such labeled data. Systems based on unsupervised learning make use of the idea of statistical outlier detection, among which well-known are the system proposed by P. Burge and J. Shawe-Taylor (&ldquo;Detecting Cellular Fraud Using Adaptive Prototypes&rdquo;, Proceedings of AI Approaches to Fraud Detection and Risk Management, pp. 9-13, 1997) and the system proposed by K. Yamanishi et al. (&ldquo;On-line Unsupervised Outlier Detection Using Finite Mixtures with Discounting Learning Algorithms&rdquo;, Proceedings of the Sixth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, ACM Press, pp. 320-324, 2000). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Statistical outlier detection here denotes a technique of considering data outside a probability distribution which the majority of data follow (data whose generation is less likely) in a data set, as &ldquo;statistical outlier&rdquo; and identifying the data as being abnormal (unfair). The above-referenced system, in particular, is characterized in that for each data in a data set, a score indicating how much the data falls outside is calculated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The above-described conventional techniques, however, have the following problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> First, although the conventional systems based on supervised learning are characterized in that features of unfairness and abnormality can be presented, it is in practice so difficult to prepare sufficient labeled data in advance as described above that highly precise learning can not be conducted to deteriorate efficiency of unfairness detection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Secondly, although the conventional systems based on unsupervised learning are characterized in being capable of coping with unknown abnormality and unfairness, they have a problem that the reason why detected abnormal data is determined to be abnormal is not indicated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Moreover, when structural abnormality occurs or when unfairness is made organizationally, abnormal data will be generated in the lump and in such a case, conventional unsupervised-learning-based systems fail to detect the abnormality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Here, even when abnormal data is generated in the lump, if the features of the generating abnormality can be implicitly seized and automatically ruled to detect abnormal data using the rules, efficiency of abnormal data detection can be drastically improved. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to solve the above-described shortcomings of the conventional techniques and provide an outliner determination rule generation device for automatically generating a rule which characterizes abnormal data based on data (unlabeled data) which is not known to be abnormal (unfair) or not, an outlier detection device for detecting abnormal data efficiently using the rule obtained by the function of the outlier determination rule generation device, and an outlier determination rule generation method and an outlier detection method thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> According to the first aspect of the invention, an outlier rule generation device for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set, comprises means for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on the degree of outlier to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective labeled data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the preferred construction, the outlier rule generation device may comprise a degree of outlier calculation unit for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data in the data set, a sampling unit for sampling each the data based on the degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and a supervised learning unit for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to the second aspect of the invention, an outlier detection device for detecting abnormal data in a data set, comprises means for holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on the degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In the preferred construction, the outlier detection device may comprise an outlier rule preservation unit for holding the set of rules characterizing abnormal data, a filtering unit for determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, a degree of outlier calculation unit for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering unit, a sampling unit for sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by the degree of outlier calculation unit based on the degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and a supervised learning unit for generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied and adding the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, after repeatedly executing a predetermined number of times a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in the data set based on the held rules, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each the data determined not to be abnormal and updating the held rules, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> determination is made whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules to output the determination result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in the data set based on the held rules, outputting data determined to be abnormal, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each the data determined not to be abnormal and updating the held rules is repeatedly executed a predetermined number of times with respect only to data determined not to be abnormal in preceding processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, a sequentially applied data string is the set of data from which abnormal data is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, the filtering unit determines whether the sequentially applied data string to be examined is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> the degree of outlier calculation unit calculates a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering unit, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> the sampling unit accumulates data whose degree of outlier is calculated by the degree of outlier calculation unit and when the data is accumulated in a volume of more than a predetermined value, samples the data based on the degree of outlier calculated and applies a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> the supervised learning unit generates a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied and adds the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, the outlier detection device may comprise an outlier rule editing unit for editing the held rules by user&apos;s operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to the third aspect of the invention, an outlier rule generation method of generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set, comprising </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> a supervised learning step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on the degree of outlier to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective labeled data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In the preferred construction, the outlier rule generation method may comprise a degree of outlier calculation step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data in the data set, a sampling step of sampling each the data based on the degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether the data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and a supervised learning step of generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, an outlier detection method of detecting abnormal data in a data set, comprises a supervised learning step of holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on the degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In the preferred construction, the outlier detection method may comprise an outlier rule preservation step of holding the set of rules characterizing abnormal data, a filtering step of determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, a degree of outlier calculation step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering step, a sampling step of sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by the degree of outlier calculation step based on the degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and a supervised learning step of generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied and adding the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, after repeatedly executing a predetermined number of times a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in the data set based on the held rules, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each the data determined not to be abnormal and updating the held rules, determination is made whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules to output the determination result. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in the data set based on the held rules, outputting data determined to be abnormal, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each the data determined not to be abnormal and updating the held rules is repeatedly executed a predetermined number of times with respect only to data determined not to be abnormal in preceding processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, a sequentially applied data string is the set of data from which abnormal data is detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, at the filtering step, determination is made whether the sequentially applied data string to be examined is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> at the degree of outlier calculation step, a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal is calculated with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering step, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> at the sampling step, the data whose degree of outlier is calculated is accumulated and when the data is accumulated in a volume of more than a predetermined value, the data is sampled based on the degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> at the supervised learning step, a new rule characterizing abnormal data is generated by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which the label is applied and the new rule is added to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In another preferred construction, the outlier detection method may comprise an outlier rule editing step of editing the held rules by user&apos;s operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> According to a further aspect of the invention, an outlier rule generation program for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set by controlling a computer, wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> a supervised learning function is executed of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on the degree of outlier to generate a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> According to a still further aspect of the invention, an outlier detection program for detecting abnormal data in a data set by controlling a computer, wherein </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> a supervised learning function is executed of holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of the data set is abnormal data or not based on the held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on the degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to the held set of rules to update the rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become clear from the detailed description given herebelow.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be understood more fully from the detailed description given herebelow and from the accompanying drawings of the preferred embodiment of the invention, which, however, should not be taken to be limitative to the invention, but are for explanation and understanding only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In the drawings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier rule generation device according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier rule generation in the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier detection in the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation as another embodiment of the outlier detection according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device according to a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier detection in the third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation as another embodiment of the outlier detection according to the third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier detection in the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier detection in the fifth embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The preferred embodiment of the present invention will be discussed hereinafter in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. It will be obvious, however, to those skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. In other instance, well-known structures are not shown in detail in order to unnecessary obscure the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In the following description, one data in a data set is represented as x&equals;(x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , x<highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>)&isin;D&equals;X<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>x . . . X<highlight><subscript>d</subscript></highlight>. D is referred to as a domain. Each x<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>(i&equals;1, 2, . . . , d) is assumed, for example, to be a continuous value or a discrete value of a text etc. A set U of the data, that is, U&equals;&lcub;x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , x<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub;, is referred to as a data set. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing an outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to a first embodiment of the present invention. The outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment is a device for generating, for a data set applied, a rule characterizing abnormal data within the data set. Rules generated here can be used in other device for detecting abnormality of data in order to detect abnormal data in a data set or to examine a tendency of abnormal data or for other purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment includes a degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for calculating, with respect to each data in a data set to be examined, a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of abnormality of the data, a sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> for sampling each data based on a calculated degree of outliner to apply to each data a label indicating whether it is abnormal data or not, and a supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of labeled data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> calculates and outputs a degree of outliner indicative of a degree of unfairness (abnormality) of each data. More specifically, while sequentially reading data from a data set, the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> calculates a degree s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>of outlier of each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>and outputs the degree as V&equals;&lcub;y<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , y<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub; (y<highlight><subscript>t</subscript></highlight>&equals;x<highlight><subscript>t</subscript></highlight>, s<highlight><subscript>t</subscript></highlight>)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Next, the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> will be described. Based on a degree of outlier of each data output by the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> applies to each data a label indicating whether the data is abnormal (unfair) or not to generate a set of data with supervisor information. More specifically, the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> generates a data set with supervisor information from a scored (whose degree of outlier is calculated) data set V&equals;&lcub;y<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , y<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub; and at that time, data whose score is high (having high degree of unfairness) is labeled &ldquo;positive&rdquo; and data whose score is not high is labeled &ldquo;negative&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Specific example of labeling processing conducted by the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> will be shown in the following. First, take out q % higher score data from the data set V&equals;&lcub;y<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , y<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub; to attach the label &ldquo;positive&rdquo; to the data and conduct random sampling of data which is not included in the q % higher score data to take out k*q % of the whole data (k: positive number, e.g. k&equals;3) and attach the label &ldquo;negative&rdquo; to the taken out data. Newly generated data is written as z<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>&equals;(x<highlight><subscript>t(i)</subscript></highlight>, 1<highlight><subscript>t(i)</subscript></highlight>), in which 1<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>denotes a label and t(i) denotes a one-to-one function from an integer i (1&lE;i&lE;m&lE;n) to &lcub;1, 2, . . . n&rcub;. New data set obtained here is expressed as W&equals;&lcub;z<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, z<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , z<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>&rcub;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Another possible method, not a method of taking out &ldquo;q % higher score data&rdquo;, is, for example, labeling data having a higher score than a provided certain threshold value as &ldquo;positive&rdquo; and taking out data whose score is lower than the threshold value by random sampling to label the data as &ldquo;negative&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Next, the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> will be described. The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> generates a rule from data with supervisor information output by the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Here, supervised learning (processing that the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> executes) represents outputting a function f:D&rarr;&lcub;positive, negative&rcub; with a data set with supervisor information W&equals;&lcub;z<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, z<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , z<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>&rcub; as input or represents outputting a conditional probability distribution f of 1&isin;&lcub;positive, negative&rcub; with a data set with supervisor information W&equals;&lcub;z<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, z<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , z<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>&rcub; as input when data x is applied. Here, W is referred to as training data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Consideration will be here given to a case, for example, where with x<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>representing data indicative of a height (cm), with respect to data in W, data having x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&gE;300 in W is labeled positive because it is highly probable that it is unfair and the remaining data is labeled negative. In this case, to the input of W, a function f should be output which indicates that If x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&gE;300, then positive is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In practice, because regularity hidden in training data is more complicated or because a data set contains noise, learning is not that simple. Various manners have been proposed for conducting learning efficiently under such complicated conditions. According to these manners, a method of representing a rule varies such as a method using such a logical expression as described above or a method using a neural network. The learning system using a probability decision list which is proposed by K. Yamanishi (K . Yamanishi, &ldquo;A Learning Criterion for Stochastic Rules&rdquo;, Machine Learning, vol. 9, pp. 165-203, 1992), for example, employs the following expressions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> If x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&gE;300, then positive with probability 0.9, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Else if x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&equals;male, then positive with probability 0.8, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Else negative with probability 0.2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Such representation system, which is referred to as a probability decision list, specifies a conditional probability distribution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> In the following, making determination whether applied data x&isin;D is positive or negative will be referred to as &ldquo;filtering&rdquo; (filtering of data x). When the corresponding f:D<custom-character file="US20030004902A1-20030102-P00900.TIF" wi="20" he="20" id="custom-character-00001"/>x&rarr;&lcub;positive, negative&rcub; is a function whose value is unitarily determined, the function f itself can be used for filtering and when f is a conditional probability distribution, the following determination criterion is used: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> If f(positive&verbar;x)&gE;p<highlight><subscript>th</subscript></highlight>, then x is positive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Here, p<highlight><subscript>th</subscript></highlight>, which denotes a threshold value given by a user, is ordinarily designated to be 0.5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier rule generation according to the present embodiment. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment operates in the following order. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> First, transfer an input U&equals;&lcub;x<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, x<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , x<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub; to the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> calculates, for each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>of the input, a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>of a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of unfairness (abnormality) of each data to generate data with score V&equals;&lcub;y<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, y<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , y<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&rcub; and output the same to the sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> takes out higher score data at a predetermined rate from the data V with scores and applies a label of positive to the data to make the same positive data. Furthermore, the unit <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> takes out a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data from V by random sampling and applies a label of negative to the data to make the same negative data. By thus applying positive and negative labels to the data, data W&equals;&lcub;z<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, z<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, . . . , z<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>&rcub; with supervisor information is generated and applied to the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> obtains and outputs a rule characterizing abnormal data based on the applied data W with supervisor information (Step <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, according to the outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment, a rule characterizing abnormal data can be automatically generated with high efficiency based on data (unsupervised data) which is not known to be abnormal (unfair) or not. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to a second embodiment of the present invention. The outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment is a device for detecting abnormal data in a data set. The outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment is characterized in having the function of the outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> described in the first embodiment to automatically generate a rule which characterizes abnormal data within an applied data set and execute detection of abnormal data based on the rule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment includes, in addition to a degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and a supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> provided as the components of the outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment, an outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for preserving a set of rules which characterize abnormal data and a filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> for determining whether each data of an applied data set is abnormal data or not based on the preserved rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment, the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> calculates a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of abnormality of each data which is determined not to be abnormal data by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Then, the sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> samples each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> based on the calculated degree of outlier to apply to the sampled data a label indicating whether the data is abnormal or not. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Then, the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> generates a new rule which characterizes abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of labeled data. Then, the unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> adds the newly generated rule to a set of rules characterizing abnormal data which are preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and stores the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> As a result, the rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> will be appropriately updated, and using the updated rules, abnormal data can be detected with higher precision. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> This also enables the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment to realize highly efficient detection of abnormal data with high precision by, after, for example, repeatedly executing the above-described processing with respect to a data set to be examined a predetermined number of times to update the rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to those enabling abnormal data to be detected with high precision, the detection of abnormal data in the data set to be examined based on the rule by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Next, description will be made of operation of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to the present embodiment. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining one embodiment of operation of the outlier detection according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, first, repeatedly execute the processing of Steps <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> with respect to a data set to be examined a predetermined number of times to repeatedly update rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> operates in the following order in an i-th iteration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> An input U is transferred to the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> by an external input or from the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>). The filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> makes determination of the input data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to output data determined to be an outlier as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and sends a data set U&prime; determined not to be an outlier to the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>determined not to be an outlier by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, generates a set V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of data with scores and applies the set to the sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight>). At the same time, the unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> outputs data whose degree of outlier is not less than a predetermined threshold value as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo; and holds a set of-data determined to be otherwise as U&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> takes out higher score data at a predetermined rate from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>to take the same as positive data and takes out a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data W<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>with supervisor information to apply the same to the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the applied data with supervisor information and selects or gives up a rule from the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>405</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> By repeatedly executing the foregoing processing of Steps <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> a predetermined number of times in the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, the rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are repeatedly updated to those enabling abnormal data to be detected with high precision (Step <highlight><bold>407</bold></highlight>) and using the updated rules, final filtering is executed to detect abnormal data (Step <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in a system which repeatedly executes the above-described series of rule generation and updating, it is also effective, for example, to exclude data whose abnormality is detected by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the preceding processing from targets of the following processing. In this case, assuming that data whose abnormality is detected by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is output at a time point of detection of the abnormality each time, rule generation and updating processing and a series of following processing will be conducted based on the remaining data-from which abnormality is not detected so far. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation as the above-described embodiment of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, first, repeatedly execute the processing of Steps <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> with respect to a data set to be examined a predetermined number of times. More specifically, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> operates in the following order in an i-th iteration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> An input U<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>is transferred to the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> by an external input or from the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>501</bold></highlight>). The filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> makes determination of the input data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to output data determined to be an outlier as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and sends a data set U<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; determined not to be an outlier to the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (Steps <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>503</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Here, if the predetermined number of times of iteration is completed, end the processing and otherwise proceed to the processing at Step <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> and the following steps (Step <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>determined not to be an outlier by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, generates a set V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of data with scores and applies the set to the sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. At the same time, the unit <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> outputs data whose degree of outlier is not less than a predetermined threshold value as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo; and holds a set of data determined to be otherwise as U<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>(Step <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> takes out higher score data at a predetermined rate from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>to take the same as positive data and takes out a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data W<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>with supervisor information to apply the same to the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the applied data with supervisor information and selects or gives up a rule among the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>507</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> By repeatedly executing the foregoing processing of Steps <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> a predetermined number of times in the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, abnormal data can be sequentially taken out and detected from the data U<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>to be processed and the preserved rules R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>can be updated to better rules every time processing is repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, according to the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment, rules characterizing abnormal data can be automatically generated based on data which is not known to be abnormal or not and using the automatically generated rules, abnormal data can be efficiently detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>according to a third embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment is further provided, in addition to the components of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to the second embodiment, with an outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> for a user to operate to edit outlier rules preserved in an outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, by using the outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, users are allowed to freely edit the outlier rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> as necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Next, operation of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment will be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining one embodiment of operation of outlier detection according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, first, in the same way as the second embodiment, repeatedly execute the processing of Steps <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight> with respect to a data set to be examined a predetermined number of times to repeatedly update the rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. In other words, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>operates in the following order in an i-th iteration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> An input U is transferred to a filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> by an external input or from a degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>601</bold></highlight>). The filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> makes determination of the input data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to output data determined to be an outlier as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and send a data set U&prime; determined not to be an outlier to the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>determined not to be an outlier by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, generates a set V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of data with scores and applies the set to a sampling unit <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>603</bold></highlight>). At the same time, the unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> outputs data whose degree of outlier is not less than a predetermined threshold value as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo; and holds a set of data determined to be otherwise as U&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> takes out higher score data at a predetermined rate from Vi to take the same as positive data and takes out a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data W<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>with supervisor information to apply the same to a supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the applied data with supervisor information and selects or gives up a rule from the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>605</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>). In addition, when necessary, the user is allowed to edit the outlier rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> by using the outer rule editing unit <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> By repeatedly executing the foregoing processing of Steps <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight> a predetermined number of times in the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> can be repeatedly updated to those enabling detection of abnormal data with higher precision (Step <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>). Then, using the updated (or further edited by the user) rules, execute final filtering to detect abnormal data (Step <highlight><bold>609</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Although in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> here, it is assumed that the processing conducted by a user to edit rules is Step <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight> which is the final step of the repetitional processing of Steps <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight>, processing of outlier detection according to the present embodiment is not limited thereto. It is similarly possible, for example, to execute the processing conducted by a user to edit the rules at the end of the repetitional processing of Steps <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>607</bold></highlight> or between Steps <highlight><bold>605</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> in the loop of the repetitional processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> It is also effective in the system where the above-described series of processing of rule generation and updating, for example, to exclude data whose abnormality is detected by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the preceding processing from targets of following processing. In this case, assuming that data whose abnormality is detected by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is output at the time of detection of the abnormality each time, using the remaining data whose abnormality is not detected so far, the processing of rule generation and updating and a series of processing to follow will be executed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation as the above-described embodiment of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, first, repeatedly execute the processing of Steps <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> with respect to a data set to be examined a predetermined number of times. More specifically, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>operates in the following order in an i-th iteration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> An input U<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>is transferred to the filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> by an external input or from the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>701</bold></highlight>). The filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> makes determination of the input data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to output data determined to be an outlier as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and send a data set U<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&prime; determined not to be an outlier to the degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (Steps <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>703</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Here, if the predetermined number of iteration is completed, end the processing and otherwise proceed to the processing at Step <highlight><bold>705</bold></highlight> and the following steps (Step <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for each data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>determined not to be an outlier by the filtering unit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, generates a set V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of data with scores and applies the set to the sampling unit <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. At the same time, the unit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> outputs data whose degree of outlier is not less than a predetermined threshold value as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo; and holds a set of data determined to be otherwise as U<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>(Step <highlight><bold>705</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> takes out higher score data at a predetermined rate from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>to take the same as positive data and takes out a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data from V<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data W<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>with supervisor information to apply the same to the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>706</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> The supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the applied data with supervisor information and selects or gives up a rule from the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>707</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight>). When necessary, the user is allowed to edit the outlier rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> by using the outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>709</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> By repeatedly executing the foregoing processing of Steps <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>709</bold></highlight> a predetermined number of times in the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, abnormal data can be sequentially taken out and detected from the data U<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>to be processed and the preserved rules R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>can be updated to better rules every time the processing is repeated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Although in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> here, it is assumed that the processing conducted by a user to edit the rules is the final Step <highlight><bold>709</bold></highlight> of the repetitional processing of Steps <highlight><bold>702</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>709</bold></highlight>, processing of outlier detection according to the present embodiment is not limited thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, the present embodiment has an effect, in addition to that attained by the second embodiment, of allowing a user to freely edit rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, so that it is possible, for example, to modify inappropriate rules which are automatically determined or designate appropriate rules by a user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention. While in the second and third embodiments, the outlier detection devices are designed to receive input of all the data sets to be examined to detect abnormal data, the device according to the present embodiment is designed, with sequentially applied data as a target of examination, to sequentially accept input of the data to detect abnormal data. In addition, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment executes abnormal data detection processing, while determining and updating rules for detecting abnormal data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining operation of outlier detection according to the present embodiment. Function of each component of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>according to the present embodiment is the same as that of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to the first embodiment with the only difference being that sequentially applied data is a target of examination, in which the following operation is conducted every time one data is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Here, description will be given to a case where t-th data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>is transferred to a filtering unit <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>801</bold></highlight>). More specifically, when the t-th data V<highlight><subscript>xt </subscript></highlight>is transferred to the filtering unit <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the filtering unit <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> make determination of the applied data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in an outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and when determining that the data is an outlier, outputs the same as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and when determining that the data is not an outlier, sends the same to a degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>802</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for the applied data x<highlight><subscript>t</subscript></highlight>, generates data y<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>with a score and applies the same to a sampling unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>803</bold></highlight>). At the same time, when the score is not less than a predetermined threshold value, the unit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> outputs the data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> preserves the applied data and when the number of the preserved data reaches a predetermined number, takes high score data at a predetermined rate from the set of these data to take the same as positive data and further takes a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data W<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>with supervisor information and applying the generated data to a supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to erase all the accumulated data (Steps <highlight><bold>804</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>805</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> When receiving input of the labeled data W<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>, the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the received data and selects or gives up a rule from the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>806</bold></highlight>). The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>807</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment enables rules characterizing abnormal data to be automatically generated and sequentially and appropriately updated based on sequentially applied data which is not known to be abnormal or not, thereby efficiently detecting abnormal data from thereafter applied data by using the automatically generated latest rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a structure of an outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment is further provided with, in addition to the components of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the fourth embodiment, an outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for a user to operate to edit outlier rules preserved in an outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> In the present embodiment, by using the outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, a user is allowed to freely edit the outlier rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> as necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> Next, operation of the outlier detection device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the present embodiment will be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a flow chart for use in explaining one embodiment of operation of outlier detection according to the present embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Here, description will be given to a case where t-th data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>is transferred to a filtering unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>1001</bold></highlight>). More specifically, when the t-th data V<highlight><subscript>xt </subscript></highlight>is transferred to the filtering unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the filtering unit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> make determination of the applied data based on a set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of outlier rules accumulated in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and when determining that the data is an outlier, outputs the same as &ldquo;outlier 1&rdquo; and when determining that the data is not an outlier, sends the same to a degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>1002</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> The degree of outlier calculation unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> calculates a score s<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>for the applied data x<highlight><subscript>t</subscript></highlight>, generates data y<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>with a score and applies the same to a sampling unit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>1003</bold></highlight>). At the same time, when the score is not less than a predetermined threshold value, the unit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> outputs the data x<highlight><subscript>t </subscript></highlight>as &ldquo;outlier 2&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> The sampling unit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> preserves the applied data and when the number of the preserved data reaches a predetermined number, takes high score data at a predetermined rate from the set of these data to take the same as positive data and further takes a predetermined number of data starting with the lowest score data by random sampling to take the same as negative data, thereby generating data Wi with supervisor information and applying the generated data to a supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to erase all the accumulated data (Steps <highlight><bold>1004</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>1005</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> When receiving input of the labeled data W<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>, the supervised learning unit <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> obtains a group of rules characterizing abnormal data based on the received data and selects or gives up a rule from the group by conforming to a predetermined criterion or by user&apos;s choice to send in the selected rule to the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> (Step <highlight><bold>1006</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> adds the sent-in rule to the set R<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of rules to generate and preserve a new set R<highlight><subscript>i&plus;1 </subscript></highlight>of rules (Step <highlight><bold>1007</bold></highlight>). In addition, the user is allowed to edit the outlier rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> by using the outlier rule editing unit <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> when necessary (Step <highlight><bold>1008</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> Although in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the processing of editing the rules by a user is conducted after the preserved rules are updated (Step <highlight><bold>1007</bold></highlight>), the processing of outlier detection according to the present embodiment is not limited thereto. It is similarly possible to execute the processing of editing the rules by a user between the other steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, the present embodiment has an effect, in addition to the effect achieved by the fourth embodiment, of enabling rules preserved in the outlier rule preservation unit <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to be freely edited by a user, thereby, for example, enabling automatically determined inappropriate rules to be modified or enabling users to designate an appropriate rule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> The outlier rule generation device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the outlier detection devices <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the above-described respective embodiments allow the functions of the filtering units <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the degree of outlier calculation units <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the sampling units <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, the supervised learning units <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the outlier rule preservation units <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and the outlier rule editing units <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and other functions to be realized not only by hardware but also by loading an outlier rule generation program and an outlier detection program which are computer programs having the respective functions into a memory of a computer processing device. The outlier rule generation program and the outlier detection program are stored in such recording media <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> as a magnetic disc and a semiconductor memory. Then, loading the programs from the recording media to the computer processing device to control operation of the computer processing device realizes each of the above-described functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> As described in the foregoing, the outlier rule generation device and the outlier detection device of the present invention enable rules characterizing abnormal data to be automatically generated based on data (unsupervised data) which is not known to be abnormal (unfair) or not and further enable abnormal data to be efficiently detected using the generated rules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Although the invention has been illustrated and described with respect to exemplary embodiment thereof, it should be understood by those skilled in the art that the foregoing and various other changes, omissions and additions may be made therein and thereto, without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. Therefore, the present invention should not be understood as limited to the specific embodiment set out above but to include all possible embodiments which can be embodies within a scope encompassed and equivalents thereof with respect to the feature set out in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An outlier rule generation device for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set, comprising 
<claim-text>means for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on said degree of outlier to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective labeled data. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The outlier rule generation device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising: 
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculation unit for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data in said data set, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling unit for sampling each said data based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning unit for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. An outlier detection device for detecting abnormal data in a data set, comprising 
<claim-text>means for holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on said degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising: 
<claim-text>an outlier rule preservation unit for holding said set of rules characterizing abnormal data, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filtering unit for determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculation unit for calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by said filtering unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling unit for sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by said degree of outlier calculation unit based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning unit for generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>after repeatedly executing a predetermined number of times a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determination is made whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules to output the determination result. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, outputting data determined to be abnormal, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules is repeatedly executed a predetermined number of times with respect only to data determined not to be abnormal in preceding processing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a sequentially applied data string is said set of data from which abnormal data is detected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said filtering unit </claim-text>
<claim-text>determines whether said sequentially applied data string to be examined is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said degree of outlier calculation unit </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculates a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by said filtering unit, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said sampling unit </claim-text>
<claim-text>accumulates data whose degree of outlier is calculated by said degree of outlier calculation unit and when the data is accumulated in a volume of more than a predetermined value, samples the data based on said degree of outlier calculated and applies a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said supervised learning unit </claim-text>
<claim-text>generates a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied and adds the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection device as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising 
<claim-text>an outlier rule editing unit for editing said held rules by user&apos;s operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An outlier rule generation method of generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set, comprising 
<claim-text>a supervised learning step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on said degree of outlier to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective labeled data. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The outlier rule generation method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising: 
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculation step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data in said data set, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling step of sampling each said data based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether the data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning step of generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An outlier detection method of detecting abnormal data in a data set, comprising 
<claim-text>a supervised learning step of holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on said degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising: 
<claim-text>an outlier rule preservation step of holding said set of rules characterizing abnormal data, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filtering step of determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculation step of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by said filtering step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling step of sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by said degree of outlier calculation step based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning step of generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>after repeatedly executing a predetermined number of times a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determination is made whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules to output the determination result. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, outputting data determined to be abnormal, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules is repeatedly executed a predetermined number of times with respect only to data determined not to be abnormal in preceding processing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a sequentially applied data string is said set of data from which abnormal data is detected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>at said filtering step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>determination is made whether said sequentially applied data string to be examined is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>at said degree of outlier calculation step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal is calculated with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by said filtering step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>at said sampling step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>said data whose degree of outlier is calculated is accumulated and when the data is accumulated in a volume of more than a predetermined value, the data is sampled based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at said supervised learning step, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a new rule characterizing abnormal data is generated by supervised learning based on a set-of said respective data to which said label is applied and the new rule is added to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising 
<claim-text>an outlier rule editing step of editing said held rules by user&apos;s operation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An outlier rule generation program for generating a rule characterizing abnormal data in a data set by controlling a computer, wherein 
<claim-text>a supervised learning function is executed of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal and sampling data based on said degree of outlier to generate a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of the respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The outlier rule generation program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein executed are: 
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculating function of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data in said data set, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling function of sampling each said data based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether the data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning function of generating a rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data too which said label is applied </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An outlier detection program for detecting abnormal data in a data set by controlling a computer, wherein 
<claim-text>a supervised learning function is executed of holding a set of rules characterizing abnormal data, determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data, sampling the data based on said degree of outlier calculated, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein executed are: 
<claim-text>an outlier rule preservation function of holding said set of rules characterizing abnormal data, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a filtering function of determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a degree of outlier calculating function of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data by said filtering function, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sampling function of sampling each data whose degree of outlier is calculated by said degree of outlier calculation function based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a supervised learning function of generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>after repeatedly executing a predetermined number of times a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing is executed of determining whether each data of said data set is abnormal data or not based on said held rules to output the determination result. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a series of processing of making determination of abnormal data in said data set based on said held rules, outputting data determined to be abnormal, generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data based on each said data determined not to be abnormal and updating said held rules is repeatedly executed a predetermined number of times with respect only to data determined not to be abnormal in preceding processing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>a sequentially applied data string is said set of data from which abnormal data is detected. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>in said filtering function, </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing is executed of determining whether said sequentially applied data string to be examined is abnormal data or not based on said held rules, </claim-text>
<claim-text>in said degree of outlier calculating function, </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing is executed of calculating a degree of outlier indicative of a degree of being abnormal with respect to each data determined not to be abnormal data in said filtering processing, </claim-text>
<claim-text>in said sampling function, </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing is executed of accumulating said data whose degree of outlier is calculated and when the data is accumulated in a volume of more than a predetermined value, sampling the data based on said degree of outlier calculated to apply a label indicating whether data is abnormal data or not to the sampled data, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>in said supervised learning function, </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing is executed of generating a new rule characterizing abnormal data by supervised learning based on a set of said respective data to which said label is applied and adding the new rule to said held set of rules to update the rules. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The outlier detection program as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>an outlier rule editing function is executed of editing said held rules by user&apos;s operation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004902A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
