<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003417A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003417A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003417A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003417A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003417A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003417A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003417</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10171763</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020617</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47L005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A47L009/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A61C017/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>433</class>
<subclass>092000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>347000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>301000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>015</class>
<subclass>319000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Dental vacuum system assembly and process incorporating an amalgam separation chamber</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60300105</doc-number>
<document-date>20010625</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Henry</given-name>
<family-name>Hubner</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Amityville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frederick</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fischer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Farmingdale</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CLIFFORD G. FRAYNE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 7A</address-1>
<address-2>136 Drum Point Road</address-2>
<city>Brick</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>08723</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A dental vacuum system for use in dental operatories wherein a dental aspirator tip and in the dental operatory is in fluid communication with a vacuum means for providing suction to the system, there being interposed between the aspirator tip and the vacuum means a separation chamber for the separation of effluent, and solids, including amalgam and other particulate matter from the air stream, the separation chamber being in communication with a collection chamber for the separation collection of solids, amalgam and other particulate matter, from the effluent which is discharged, the collection chamber being removably replaceable from the system for the recycling of the contents. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Applicant claims the benefit of provisional application No. 60/300,105, filed Jun. 25, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to dental care facilities and in particular to a central vacuum system for dental care operatories incorporating an integrated amalgam separation system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Modern dental facilities usually include multiple operatories and a central vacuum system. Dental aspirator tips are provided at each operatory for disposition in the patient&apos;s oral cavity to remove aerosols, liquids, solid debris and odors from the patient&apos;s mouth. Typical conventional dental vacuum systems have been far from ideal from the standpoints of noise output, vacuum intensity and flow rate characteristics, efficiency, reliability and recovery of amalgam metals, and particulate matter used or generated in the dental process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Additionally, environmental laws at some locations now have incorporated mandatory amalgam separation in the dental suction system. The dental vacuum system of the present invention as described herein incorporates an air/liquid separation tank having an integral sedimentation amalgam separator and collector insuring capatability of the system with the current state of the law. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide for a novel dental vacuum system for the efficient evacuation of aerosols, liquids, solid debris and odors from the patient&apos;s mouth in a dental operatory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel dental vacuum system having a novel air/liquid/solids separation tank which incorporates an integral amalgam separation and collection capability which is removably replaceable from the system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A dental vacuum system for use in dental operatories in which a dental aspirator tip in the dental operatory is in fluid communication with a vacuum means for providing suction to the system, there being interposed between the dental aspirator tip and the vacuum means, a separation chamber for the separation of effluent and solids including amalgam from the air stream. Solids including amalgam and liquids are collected in the separation chamber while air is passed through for eventual venting to the atmosphere. When no vacuum is required in the operatories, a sensor turns off the vacuum means and a timer relay allows for sedimentation to occur in the chamber. Thereafter, contaminated water and solids including amalgam are drawn out to an amalgam separation and collection chamber. Contaminated water is drawn off to the drain and the process repeats itself until the amalgam collection chamber has accumulated its maximum amount of solids, including amalgam. It is then prepped for recycle and replaced with an empty amalgam collection chamber and the full chamber is sent out for recovery of precious metals and proper disposal of hazardous material.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of a typical dental vacuum system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic illustration of a dental vacuum system of the present invention including an amalgam separator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view illustrating the removal of a spent amalgam collection chamber.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a prior art dental vacuum system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. During the course of a dental procedure, gases, liquids and solids are removed from each dental operatory <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, by means of a dental aspirator tip <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which are disposed within the patient&apos;s oral cavity. Gases, liquids, and solids, including amalgam under vacuum or suction are transported via conduit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> to a separation tank <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Disposed in conduit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> before the separation tank <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be a solids collector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which allows gas and liquids to pass through, but interrupts the flow of large particulate solids and causes them to fall into the collector under the influence of gravity for later collection and disposal. The gas and liquids are introduced into the separator tank through inlet port <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> wherein the liquids and small particulate matter accumulate in the bottom of the tank and are subsequently drained through drain outlet <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> through conduit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to a sewer drain <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A check valve <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is positioned in conduit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to prevent any back flow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The gas introduced into separation tank <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> exits separation tank <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> through a gas or air outlet port <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to exit conduit <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> which is in communication with the vacuum pump <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which provides the vacuum and suction to the overall system. The gas thus drawn through the system is then evacuated to the atmosphere through conduit <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. There is positioned between separator tank <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a vacuum pump <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> a vacuum relief valve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The solids collector <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and its location in the flow plan oftentimes presents problems in that not all solids are collected and as a result of environmental codes operatories must insure that no amalgam or metals are discharged into the sewer system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a dental vacuum system of the present invention with the separation chamber of the present invention further incorporating an amalgam collection chamber. The system consists of a separation/sedimentation tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, an amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the necessary control valves and a timer relay and vacuum sensor <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In operation, liquids, solids and gases enter the separation/sedimentation tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> through conduit <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> from the operatories when the vacuum system is in operation. The solids and liquids are collected and the gases are removed via conduit <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> by a vacuum pump in accordance with previous description. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> When a vacuum is no longer required, the vacuum pump is turned off. The vacuum sensor <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> detects that the pump is off and starts a timer relay. The timer relay is set for a period of time which permits sedimentation <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to occur within the separation/sedimentation tank of any solids which have been introduced therein. This results in the formation of layers or levels within tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, solid sedimentation <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, and a layer of contaminated water <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A control valve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is opened to permit the sedimentation/solids <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and contaminated liquids <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to enter a solids/amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> via conduit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The control valve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are then closed and a vacuum may be reinitiated to the dental operatory. The preferred amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is of the type described in International Application PCT/SE98/00685 as published on Oct. 22, 1998, publication number WO98/46324 and the teachings thereof are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The solid sedimentation <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and contaminated liquids <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> are allowed to further separate in the amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The contaminated water is then drawn off via conduit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to the sewer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, there being positioned in conduit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> a back flow valve <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The aforesaid cycle is repeated when no vacuum is required in the operatories and there is the presence of water and solids in separation tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> until the amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> becomes fully charged with particulate matter or solid sedimentation <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is then replaced with a duplicate, and the fully charged chamber is sent to be recycled and processed for the recovery of the amalgam and other metals found therein, and proper disposal of hazardous materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the manner of removal of an exhausted or spent amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> so as to permit replacement and recycle the exhausted amalgam collection chamber. The process requires the power to the vacuum pump <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> be turned off and separation tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> be allowed to drain completely, or in the alternative the shut off valve <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> located between the separation tank <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> would be closed. The inlet conduit <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> to amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is disengaged from the adaptor <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and O ring <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> on the inlet port <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of the collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Using a funnel assembly <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> attached to the collection container inlet port <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, two liters of disinfectant solution is introduced into the amalgam collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Once the two liters of disinfectant solution have been introduced, the funnel assembly <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is removed, as is the adaptor assembly <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and O ring <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight>. A shipping cap (not shown) is then placed on the inlet port <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. At this time, the outlet conduit <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the outlet adaptor and the outlet restrictor plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> with O ring <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are removed. A second shipping cap (not shown) is placed on the outlet port <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The spent collection chamber <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is then placed in a zip lock bag and styrofoam container for shipping for recycling. The replacement container is positioned and the associated adaptors, O rings and restrictor plates are secured to the respective inlet and outlet ports. Power can then be returned to the system and respective valves returned to their proper settings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The assembly and process disclosed insures that solids, amalgam and particulate matter from the dental operatory are collected prior to the discharge of any liquids or effluents into the sewer. Thus the possibilities of hazardous materials entering into the sewer system and water system is minimized, if not eliminated. The assembly and process insures that there is no interruption to the dental technician&apos;s work and that only air is drawn from the separation chamber and not deleterious liquids or solids which could damage the vacuum means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described with respect to the exemplary embodiment thereof, it will be recognized by those of ordinary skill in the art that many modifications and changes may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Therefore it is manifestly intended that the invention be limited only by the claims and the equivalence thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An assembly for collection and removal of solids, amalgam and particulate matter from a dental operatory air stream created by a vacuum means comprising: 
<claim-text>a first separation chamber positioned between a vacuum means and a dental operatory, said first separation means having an inlet means for the introduction of air, effluent, solids, amalgam and particulate matter from said dental operatory, a first outlet means in communication with said vacuum source for the exhaust of air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second outlet means in communication with a second chamber for the exhaust of effluent, solids, amalgam and particulate matter to said second chamber for the separation of effluent from solids, amalgam and particulate matter and collection of solids, amalgam and particulate matter by sedimentation means in the said second chamber, said fluid discharged to a sewer, said second chamber removably replaceable allowing for the recycling and recovery of solids, amalgam and particulate matter collected therein. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The assembly in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first separation chamber is fitted with a vacuum sensor and timer relay for sensing the absence of a vacuum and transferring said effluent, solids, amalgam and particulate matter from said first separation chamber to said second chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method for the collection and removal of effluent, solids, amalgam and particulate matter from a dental operatory air stream created by a vacuum means comprising: 
<claim-text>a) establishing conduit communication between a vacuum means and a dental operatory; </claim-text>
<claim-text>b) positioning a first separation chamber in said conduit communication between said vacuum means and said dental operatory; </claim-text>
<claim-text>c) drawing a vacuum by means of said vacuum means from said dental operatory through said first separation chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>d) collecting effluent, solids, amalgam and particulate matter in said first separation chamber and permitting said residual air stream to exit to said vacuum means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>e) positioning a second separation chamber in communication with said first separation chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>f) exhausting said fluid, solids, amalgam and particulate matter from said first separation chamber to said second separation chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>g) collecting said solids, amalgam and particulate matter in said second separation chamber by means of sedimentation; </claim-text>
<claim-text>h) exhausting said fluid from said second separation chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>i) replacing said second separation chamber when full; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>j) recycling said replaced second separation chamber for recovery of said solids, amalgam and particulate matter. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a vacuum sensor and timer relay automatically control step f. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein steps f through j are repeated as required by step i.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003417A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003417A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003417A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
