<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001882A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001882A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001882A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001882A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001882A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001882A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001882A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001882A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001882A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001882A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001882</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894917</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F015/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G09G005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>733000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>709</class>
<subclass>217000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>747000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Portable entertainment machines</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Macer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bristol</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>Thomas Edward</middle-name>
<family-name>McDonnell</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Bristol</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LOWE HAUPTMAN GILMAN AND BERNER, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1700 DIAGONAL ROAD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 300 /310</address-2>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22314</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A portable entertainment machine (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is used for storing, displaying and swapping digital objects such as virtual swap cards or tokens, video clips, or game features relating to a game that can be played on the machine. The machine has a selected article window display (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) in which the user can display digital objects, or icons (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>) corresponding to digital objects, that have been selected by the machine user as being potentially available for swapping with another machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">The machine is provided with a short-range wireless transceiver (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>) and when the machine comes within range of another such machine, the possibility arises of a digital object swap transaction. Articles offered for swap by the second machine (<highlight><bold>1&prime;</bold></highlight>), FIG. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, are displayed in a reciprocal display portion (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) of the display <highlight><bold>3 </bold></highlight>of the first machine, and the content of the selected article display (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) of the first machine is displayed to the user of the second machine in the reciprocal display portion (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) of the second machine (<highlight><bold>1&prime;</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="0">The user of the first machine can indicate a proposed swap in the linking indicator display portion (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). If both machine users agree on a proposed swap then the swap is executed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0004" lvl="0">Additional digital objects may be acquired by purchase from a static digital object vending machine, FIG. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, by means of short-range wireless communication. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to portable entertainment machines, and particularly to portable entertainment machines provided with a short-range wireless communication facility which enables the machines to communicate one with another when the machines are within range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The term &lsquo;entertainment machine&rsquo; is used herein to include machines on which one or more games may be played, but also to include machines which are adapted to collect digital objects such as a virtual card or computer-generated character which can be viewed on a display of the machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The entertainment machine may provide other functions which may be the primary function of the machine, such as a telephone function. The machine may be an enhanced version of a PDA (portable digital assistant) for example. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND TO THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Some aspects of the invention are based on our realisation that it may be attractive to users to provide entertainment machines that are capable of swapping digital objects by means of a short-range wireless link. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARIES OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the invention a portable entertainment machine comprises a digital object store adapted to store digital objects, a short-range wireless transceiver device capable of transmitting and receiving signals that are representative of a digital object to and from the transceiver of another portable entertainment device, and a manually operable control adapted to permit the user of the entertainment machine to exercise at least some control over swapping of digital objects between the digital object stores of two or more such entertainment machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> By &lsquo;transceiver&rsquo; we mean a device or devices capable of transmitting and receiving, but we do not intend the term to be restricted to devices which transmit and receive alternately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The use of a short-range wireless link, such as a Bluetooth&trade; network or an IrDA (Infra Red Data Association) network provides interest associated with the fact that swapping of digital objects is generally only possible when two machines are within range of each other. This provides an additional interest factor especially when the machine users are on the move, since the ability to swap will depend upon what other machines come into range of the user&apos;s machine. Also, it is generally likely to be difficult to collect a comprehensive collection of available data objects since the opportunities to swap may be limited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The machine preferably comprises an electronic display capable of being used to display to the machine user one or more of any digital objects currently held in the digital object store of the machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The electronic display will usually be a visual display but it may in some cases be an audible display and it may be an audio-visual display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> When the display is a visual display the display may be arranged to display the entire contents of the digital object store, or it may be adapted to display a list of the objects held in the store and may be capable of displaying a more detailed representation of a digital object when that object is selected from the list. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The displayed object may, for example, take the form of a decorative card or token when amusement is to be derived by collecting such cards or tokens. The cards may be sport cards, such as football player cards. Such cards or tokens may have an aesthetically pleasing appearance, to increase their desirability, but in some cases, for example in science fiction war games, the displayed objects may portray a frightening element such as an evil alien. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> When the display is a visual display this may be in the form of a liquid crystal display, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The manually operable control could be a voice-activated control but preferably comprises a touch-sensitive device such as one or more control buttons or a touch-sensitive display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The entertainment machine preferably comprises a casing of a size that is suitable for putting in a pocket, the casing preferably housing a battery for powering the machine, but if desired power could be supplied by a lead connected to a separate battery pack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The data object may comprise a static image or a moving image such as a video-clip or an animation, and the image may have associated textual information which may be displayed on the display, or associated audio information which may be played by an audio playback component of the machine if the machine is so equipped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The machine is preferably adapted to provide to the user information on data objects that become potentially available to be acquired from a similar machine that comes within range of the machine, to enable the user to take a decision on whether or not to proceed with a potential swapping transaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The machine may, however, be capable of being provided by the user with a standing instruction to swap a certain data object or category of data objects in the data object store for another specified data object or category of data objects if such a required object or object category becomes available for swap, and any conditions imposed on the swap by the user are complied with. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The digital object store may comprise a retained object portion for storing data objects for which the machine user has taken a decision to retain at least for the time being, or for data objects for which the user has not yet taken a decision on whether to retain or swap, and a selected article window portion of the data store in which data objects are placed for which the user has taken at least a preliminary decision to dispose of provided that an acceptable swap deal can be arranged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The significance of the selected article window portion of the data store is that when the user&apos;s machine comes within range of another similar machine it is preferably arranged that information is transmitted to the other machine to inform the other machine of the content of the selected article window store. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Desirably both machines will comprise a selected article window store, and the contents of the selected article window stores are made available to the other machine, and the machines are adapted to display to their respective users, in a reciprocal display portion, information on the content of the selected article window store of the other machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the machine is provided with an alert device for alerting the user to the availability of a potential swap, such as an audible alert device or a vibration producing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Of course, since the aim is to facilitate a possible swap of a data object it will not usually be desirable to transmit the full digital data object to the other machine until a swap deal has been agreed, unless some restrictive conditions are intimately associated with the initial transfer. For example the restrictive condition may be a time limit on the use of the digital object. Such an arrangement would have the advantage that the potential recipient of the data object could display the data object for a limited length of time to facilitate a decision being made as to whether or not the data object is to be acquired by proceeding with a swap transaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> When the data object is a game program, the current owner of the game may allow the user of the other machine to sample playing of the game by exercising game control over the wireless connection, the game being run on the machine of the current game owner, or the user of the second machine may merely be permitted to watch the game being played. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The machine preferably comprises manually operable selection means to enable the user of the machine to select which data objects are transferred from the retention portion of the store to the selected article window portion of the store and vice-versa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The machine preferably comprises a swap proposal indicator means for indicating to another, similar machine the swap transaction being proposed, and preferably this comprises a linking indicator function adapted to link the representations of the digital data objects held by the two machines in their selected article window stores, and to communicate that link indicator to the other machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Preferably the machine comprises a swap approval indicator means which is adapted to respond to transmit a response to the other machine in answer to the output of the linking indicator function of the machine which first suggests a swap proposal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A swap control function is arranged to be initiated on acceptance of the proposed swap by the other machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Once both machines have indicated acceptance of the proposed swap a swap procedure is initiated, preferably by the machine that first proposed the possible swap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Preferably swap control procedures are implemented to reduce or eliminate the possibility of one machine user cheating during the swapping procedure by accepting a digital object without providing a digital object in return. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> For example, a swap protocol may be utilised which ensures that the data objects that have been agreed to be swapped are transmitted simultaneously by the two machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, or in addition, each machine may comprise an escrow store adapted to receive a digital object and an escrow store inspection means adapted to test the authenticity of a digital object held in the escrow store. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The swap procedure preferably then comprises the initiating machine transmitting the data object to the escrow store of the other machine, and the other machine transmitting the other data object to the escrow store of the first machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Preferably the transmitted data objects have accompanying signed certificates which provide evidence to the recipient escrow store of the authenticity of the transmitted data objects, and on confirmation by both machines that the machines have both verified the authenticity of the data objects held in the escrow stores, an exchange of authenticity verification signals enables the data objects to be released from the escrow stores to be deposited in the respective retention stores of the machines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The machine preferably comprises a data object input means to enable data objects to be loaded into the machine by a purchasing transaction from a data object vendor rather than by a data object swapping transaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The data object input means may comprise a reader adapted to read a physical storage medium such as a compact flashcard, the reader being arranged to load purchased data objects into the machine store, (and preferably the storage medium is arranged to be disabled following reading). Alternatively, or in addition, the data object input means may utilise a short-range wireless network, cellular telephony or a direct connection, such as USB. The user may then acquire data objects when the user&apos;s machine comes within range of a static supplier of data objects. Payment for such data objects can then be made by some wireless electronic payment facility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The nature of the digital data object will now be further discussed in more detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The digital data object may be a game program which when run on the entertainment machine enables the user to play a game. For example, the game program may be a program to implement a single-player treasure seeking adventure game. Alternatively the game implemented may involve an additional player or players who communicate with the said entertainment machine, on which the game is run, by means of a short-range network such as a piconet, the additional players not gaining access to a copy of the game through playing the game. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Such an entertainment machine is enabled to implement different games according to the different game programs held in the store of games. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Swapping of the digital object may not necessarily involve loss of a digital object by either machine, but instead providing a copy (subject to suitable copyright permissions) of a digital object to another user in exchange for receiving a copy of a different digital object. This is a potentially desirable feature particularly when the digital object is a game program. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The digital data objects may comprise a game feature, for example a feature which potentially assists a player to play a game, or achieve a higher score, or reach a higher level of the game such as extra energy, additional player abilities to control a game element, enhancements to the powers of a game piece or character etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The machine may be location aware (eg GPS or from beacons on known sites, or some of the piconet members may be location aware and share their location with other piconet members). This location awareness may be a parameter to playing the game, eg you are in my team if you live in Room 101, the other team if you are in Room 102. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The portable amusement machine may be adapted to perform other functions, for example a mobile telephone, in which case the display may be the display that is used for the telephone functions, and the buttons used for telephone functions may also be used in controlling the swapping of digital objects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The digital object may be an enhancement to the functionality of the existing machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> When the machine has a mobile telephone function the digital object may be a ring tone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The machine in accordance with the first aspect of the invention will generally comprise a processing unit and software adapted to cause the swapping of digital objects in response to user input commands. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> According to a second aspect of the invention we provide software encoded on a data carrier which when loaded into a control processor causes the entertainment machine to operate in accordance with the first aspect of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> According to a third aspect of the invention we provide apparatus to enable a plurality of players to swap digital objects, the apparatus comprising a short-range wireless network, a plurality of portable entertainment machines for carrying by respective players, each machine being in accordance with the first aspect of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The invention will now be further described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic front elevation of a portable entertainment machine in accordance with the invention and shown in a condition just prior to a swap transaction being effected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the digital object store of the machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> schematically shows two machines similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in communication with each other and in the condition just prior to executing a swap transaction, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a modification to the machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> incorporating cellular telephone functions, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the steps involved in setting up and completing a swap transaction, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a digital object vending machine.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the entertainment machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> typically comprises a housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of a size to fit in a pocket (but could be larger if desired), a liquid crystal display <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, CPU, ROM and RAM contained within the housing <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, various control buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and a wireless transceiver <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> such as an IrDA transceiver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In one mode of operation of the display <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, selected by operation of one of the buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the display comprises a user selected article window portion <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a proposed-swap indicator portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, a reciprocal display portion <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> displaying objects offered by another machine for swapping, and a main game display portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The selected article window <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> displays images corresponding to data objects that the machine user has selected from his/her store of data objects to be the subject of a possible swap transaction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> For the purposes of illustration only, the digital object images shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in the selected article window <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and in the offered objects window <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are shown as fruit images, but it will be appreciated that the images can be of any form and could be much more elaborate in design, for example a sci-fi character. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> By operation of one of the control buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> an enlarged image of a data object selected from selected article window <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be displayed on the main game display portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for full appreciation by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> indicates the organisation of the RAM storage, constituting a digital object store, for the digital data objects. The digital data store comprises a retained object store <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and a selected article window store <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, comprising storage locations <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>corresponding to the four elements <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the selected article window display for four digital objects which have been transferred from the retained object store <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> under control of buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The user can inspect the content of the retained object store <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> by requesting, with suitable use of control buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the display of a list of retained objects in the main display portion <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Selected objects can be transferred from the retained object store <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to selected article window storage <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> which can hold four digital objects in locations <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Images or icons representative of the digital objects corresponding to the data objects in the locations <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are displayed in the selected article window display, but not necessarily in corresponding positions, as will be explained. When only an icon is displayed in selected article window display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> a fuller image of the data object may be chosen to be shown in main display <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Button <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> enables the images or icons displayed in the selected article window display to be scrolled, that is such that the image displayed at <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>moves to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, that at <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, that at <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, and that at <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>moves to <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The purpose of scrolling the display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is to enable a proposed swap transaction to be set up on the displays <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the proposed swap being indicated by a linking indicator function in the form of a linking arrow <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>&prime; of display portion <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, which links the image in position <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with the image in position <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of reciprocal display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Button <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> similarly enables the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be scrolled to bring whichever image or icon the user desires to align with the linking arrow <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>&prime;. It will therefore be appreciated that by use of buttons <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> the user can set up a proposed swap based on a selection of any one of the objects/icons in display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> with a selection of any one of the objects/icons in display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows two machines, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; which are in communication with each other by way of transceivers <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. It will be seen that the selected article window display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been transmitted to machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; to appear in the reciprocal display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime;. And the selected article window display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; has been transmitted to machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to appear in the reciprocal display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> When the user of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is happy with the proposed swap indicated by the linking arrow of display <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the user transmits to machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; an approval signal, by suitable operation of a button <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the user of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; can then signify his or her approval of the swap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The overall procedure for the communications is set out in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a multi-purpose embodiment of the invention which is usable both as a cellular telephone and as an entertainment machine. The machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> comprises a cellular telephone transceiver <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, speaker <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and microphone <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. When telephone mode is selected by operation of control buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the main display <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is used to show telephone features such as address book numbers, whereas when a game mode is selected by operation of buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> the display <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is used to display a game such as a treasure-seeking adventure game. It should be noted that for such embodiments of the invention, the device may be a conventional computing device with cellular telephone capability installed with appropriate software. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Speaker <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> may be used to provide an audio element associated with a selected digital object when that object has been selected for display in display <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; can only exchange digital objects when the respective transceivers <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are within range of each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In a further modification to the machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the buttons <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> can be operated to set up a standing instruction for exchange of digital objects. On activation a filter is implemented for filtering digital objects that can be allowed to be displayed in display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as the filter operates in conjunction with an automatic exchange function which operates as follows. The user of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> selects from the retained object store <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> data objects which he or she is prepared to exchange, and places those objects in store <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, (and those objects are consequently displayed in display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>). The filter is set and icons of the objects that the user of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is prepared to accept in exchange for any other items displayed in display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are then displayed in display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In the event that the machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comes into range of another machine that is offering to swap any of the data objects that have been displayed in <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in order to set the filter, then machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> automatically transmits to the other machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; the contents of selected article window display <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of that machine, and a swapping transaction can then proceed, assuming of course that the user of machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; is happy to accept the transaction that has been proposed by machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Of course, if machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; has also been set to automatic exchange mode, then a swap transaction will be effected, providing that the swap criteria set on the two machines are compatible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In a further modification to the machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> the software is configured to allow multi-player games being played on machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to be controlled by remote players, each of which has a similar machine to machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and communicates with machine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by way of a short-range piconet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> schematically shows a digital object vending machine which will desirably be mounted in a fixed location, but could be mounted in a public transport vehicle. Parts of the vending machine which correspond to the parts of the machine of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> have been given corresponding reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The vending machine will allow a machine user who comes within range to purchase digital objects, for example by a charge made to their cellular telephone account, the vending machine owner being reimbursed by the cellular telephone service provider (who may retain a commission). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Preferably exchange of digital objects is carried out in such a way that the creation of digital objects does not lose economic benefit by cost-free copying by others. Mechanisms can be applied to prevent this, or to minimise the risk. One approach to minimising risk could be to require any &ldquo;transaction&rdquo; to include the identity of the provider (which could thus be embedded in the digital object&mdash;an embedded audit trail). If users also had to register with a central service, this approach could render illicit copying detectable. An even more complete (if practically more complex) solution would be to register each transaction with a central service. Further minimisation as prevention of risk could be achieved by locating the digital object exchange application, and possibly the digital objects themselves, within a tamper proof device within the machine logically and physically isolated from tampering&mdash;preferably one with a cryptographic identity. Such a device is discussed in WO 00/48063 (Hewlett-Packard). Transfer of digital objects could thus be constrained to be carried out in a cryptographic exchange under a shared session being in conventional manner. Other known approaches to requiring validation for use of software (dongles, smartcards etc) can also be employed. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A portable entertainment machine comprising a digital object store adapted to store digital objects, having a short-range wireless transceiver device capable of transmitting and receiving signals that are representative of a digital object to and from the transceiver of another portable entertainment device, and a manually operable control adapted to permit the user of the entertainment machine to exercise at least some control over swapping of digital objects between the digital object stores of two or more such entertainment machines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising an electronic display capable of being used to display to the machine user one or more of any digital objects currently held in the digital object store of the machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> in which the electronic display comprises a visual display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> in which the electronic display comprises an audible display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> in which the display is adapted to display the entire contents of the digital object store. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> in which the display is adapted to display a list of the objects held in the store and is capable of displaying a more detailed representation of a digital object when that object is selected from the list. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the manually operable control is a voice-activated control. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the manually operable control comprises a touch-sensitive device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a casing of a size that is suitable for putting in a pocket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> adapted to provide to the user information on data objects that become potentially available to be acquired from a similar machine that comes within range of the machine, to enable the user to take a decision on whether or not to proceed with a potential swapping transaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the machine is capable of being provided by the user with a standing instruction to swap a certain data object or category of data objects in the data object store for another specified data object or category of data objects if such a required object or object category becomes available for swap, and any conditions imposed on the swap by the user are complied with. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the digital object store comprises a retained object portion for storing data objects for which the machine user has taken a decision to retain at least for the time being, or for data objects for which the user has not yet taken a decision on whether to retain or swap, and a selected article window portion of the data store in which data objects are placed for which the user has taken at least a preliminary decision to dispose of provided that an acceptable swap deal can be arranged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> characterised in that when the user&apos;s machine comes within range of another similar machine information is transmitted to the other machine to inform the other machine of the content of the selected article window store. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> in which the display comprises a reciprocal display portion adapted to display the content of the selected article window store of another machine which comes within range. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the machine is provided with an alert device for alerting the user to the availability of a potential swap. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> which is adapted to transmit an incomplete digital object for sampling by the user of another machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> which is adapted to transmit a data object for sampling over a limited length of time to facilitate a decision being made as to whether or not the data object is to be acquired by proceeding with a swap transaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data object is a game program, and the machine is so arranged that the current owner of the game can allow the user of another similar machine within range to sample playing of the game by exercising game control over the wireless connection, the game being run on the machine of the current game owner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> comprising manually operable selection means to enable the user of the machine to select which data objects are transferred from the retention portion of the store to the selected article window portion of the store and vice-versa. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the machine comprises a swap proposal indicator means for indicating to another, similar machine the swap transaction being proposed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> in which the swap proposal indicator means comprises a linking indicator function adapted to link the representations of the digital data objects held by the two machines in their selected article window stores, and to communicate that link indicator to the other machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a swap approval indicator means which is adapted to respond to transmit a response to the other machine in answer to the output of the linking indicator function of the machine which first suggests a swap proposal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising swap control function arranged to be initiated on acceptance of a proposed swap by a similar such machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> in which a swap protocol is utilised which ensures that the data objects that have been agreed to be swapped are transmitted simultaneously by the two machines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a data object input means to enable data objects to be loaded into the machine by a purchasing transaction from a data object vendor rather than by a data object swapping transaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data object input means comprises a reader adapted to read a physical storage medium, the reader being arranged to load purchased data objects into the machine store. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> in which the reader is arranged to disable the storage medium following reading. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data object input means utilises a short-range wireless network. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data input means utilises cellular telephony. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the digital data object is a game program which when run on the entertainment machine enables the user to play a game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> in which the game implemented by the digital data object involves an additional player or players who communicate with the said entertainment machine, on which the game is run, by means of a short-range wireless network, the additional player/s not gaining access to a copy of the game through playing the game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> in which the digital data object comprises a game feature for assisting a player to play a game. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> adapted to be operable as a mobile telephone, said display being used to display the telephone functions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the digital object is an enhancement to the functionality of the existing machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> in the digital object is a ring tone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Software encoded on a data carrier which when loaded into a control processor of a portable entertainment machine causes the machine to operate as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. Apparatus to enable a plurality of players to swap digital objects, the apparatus comprising a short-range wireless network, a plurality of portable entertainment machines for carrying by respective players, each machine being as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> in which the displayed object takes the form of a decorative virtual card or token. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data object comprises a moving image. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> in which the image has associated textual information which is displayed on the display. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A machine as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> in which the image has associated audio information which is suitable for being played by an audio playback component of the machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A computer program product comprising a computer usable medium having computer readable program code embodied therein executable by a portable entertainment machine which comprises a short-range wireless transceiver device capable of transmitting and receiving signals to and from the transceiver of another portable entertainment device, and a manually operable control adapted to permit the user of the entertainment machine to exercise at least some control over the use of the transceiver device: the computer program product comprising code that when loaded into the portable entertainment machine causes the portable entertainment machine to be capable of swapping, by way of the transceiver device, signals that are representative of digital objects for swapping digital objects between digital object stores of two or more such entertainment machines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to be capable of displaying a list of the objects held in the store, and to be capable of displaying a more detailed representation of a digital object when that object is selected by a user from the list. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to be adapted to provide to the user information on data objects that become potentially available to be acquired from a similar machine that comes within range of the machine, to enable the user to take a decision on whether or not to proceed with a potential swapping transaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to be capable of being provided by the user with a standing instruction to swap a certain data object or category of data objects in the data object store for another specified data object or category of data objects if such a required object or object category becomes available for swap, and any conditions imposed on the swap by the user are complied with. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to allocate a retained object portion of the digital object store for storing data objects for which the machine user has taken a decision to retain at least for the time being, or for data objects for which the user has not yet taken a decision on whether to retain or swap, and to allocate a selected article window portion of the data store in which data objects can be placed for which the user has taken at least a preliminary decision to dispose of provided that an acceptable swap deal can be arranged. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> characterised in that the product comprises means which causes the machine to operate such that when the user&apos;s machine comes within range of another similar machine information is transmitted to the other machine to inform the other machine of the content of the selected article window store. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> in which the product comprises code means which causes a display of the machine to comprise a reciprocal display portion adapted to display the content of the selected article window store of another machine which comes within range. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to issue an alert to the user upon the availability of a potential swap. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to be capable of transmitting an incomplete digital object for sampling by the user of another machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which causes the machine to transmit a data object for sampling over a limited length of time to facilitate a decision being made as to whether or not the data object is to be acquired by proceeding with a swap transaction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data object is a game program, the program comprising code means which configures the machine whereby the current owner of the game can allow the user of another similar machine within range to sample playing of the game by exercising game control over the wireless connection, the game being run on the machine of the current game owner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which configures the manually operable control to enable the user of the machine to select which data objects are transferred from the retention portion of the store to the selected article window portion of the store and vice-versa. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which configures the machine to provide a swap proposal indicator means for indicating to another, similar machine the swap transaction being proposed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> in which the swap proposal indicator means comprising a linking indicator function adapted to link the representations of the digital data objects held by the two machines in their selected article window stores, and to communicate that link indicator to the other machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which configures the machine to provide a swap approval indicator means which is arranged to respond to transmit a response to the other machine in answer to the output of the linking indicator function of the machine which first suggests a swap proposal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which configures the machine to provide a swap control function arranged to be initiated on acceptance of a proposed swap by a similar such machine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which provides a swap protocol that ensures that the data objects that have been agreed to be swapped are transmitted simultaneously by the two machines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. A computer program product as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> comprising code means which configures the machine for enabling data objects to be loaded into the machine by purchasing transaction from a data object vendor rather than by a data object swapping transaction.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001882A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001882A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001882A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001882A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001882A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
