<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000641A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000641A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000641A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000641A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000641</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09898633</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B32B031/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>156</class>
<subclass>307300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Adhesive-infused 3-D woven textile preforms for structural joints</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ronald</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schmidt</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>James E. Bradley</name-1>
<name-2>BRACEWELL &amp; PATTERSON, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2900</address-1>
<address-2>711 Louisiana Street</address-2>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77002-2781</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method for using a three-dimensional, woven preform to assemble two components. The woven preform is infused with an adhesive, and at least one surface of the preform is bonded to at least one surface of one of the components using the adhesive within the preform. The other of the components is attached to the preform, and this may occur with fasteners after the adhesive is cured or by bonding the second component to the preform with the adhesive. Use of an adhesive, instead of a resin, creates a stronger joint, especially with fiber-reinforcement of the adhesive. The thickness of the compressible, three-dimensional weave provides for a larger dimensional tolerance at each bond line. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention generally relates to assembly of components using woven preforms and particularly relates to assembly of components into structural joints using adhesive-infused preforms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Typically, laminating resins are used as the matrix material in woven textiles, this also being true for woven preforms used to connect components made of composites or other materials. An example of a commonly-used laminating resin is 977-3, available from Cytec Industries, Inc., of West Paterson, N.J. The laminating resin is infused into a textile product and is cured to form a polymer matrix in the finished composite component. When assembling a joint using a preform, the preform may be co-cured along with uncured composite components or the components may be cured prior to assembly using an uncured preform. Because of the inferior bonding characteristics of laminating resins, an layer of adhesive is placed between the preform and the components. Generally, an adhesive film is used, which is expensive and adds to fabrication time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To achieve proper bonding when using adhesive film between pre-cured components, special attention must be paid to the interface at the adhesive layer. This bond line is critical, and, where two surfaces are brought together, the distance between the surfaces must be within a critical tolerance to ensure a proper bonding layer. The thickness of the adhesives are usually about 0.015&Prime; thick with a bond layer tolerance of &plus;/&minus;0.005&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, a need exists for an improved method that reduces the steps in assembly and provides for a stronger joint when joining components using a woven preform. A further need exists for a method of joining components in a structural joint that provides for a larger dimensional tolerance between components when using an adhesive at the bond line. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A method uses a three-dimensional, woven preform to assemble two components. The woven preform is infused with an adhesive, and at least one surface of the preform is bonded to at least one surface of one of the components using the adhesive within the preform. The other of the components is attached to the preform, and this may occur with fasteners after the adhesive is cured or by bonding the second component to the preform with the adhesive. Use of an adhesive, instead of a resin, creates a stronger joint, especially with fiber-reinforcement of the adhesive. The thickness of the compressible, three-dimensional weave provides for a larger dimensional tolerance at each bond line. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The novel features believed to be characteristic of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. The invention itself however, as well as a preferred mode of use, further objects and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description of an illustrative embodiment when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an assembly using a preform and in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of the preform of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> prior to installation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a front view of a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a front view of a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a front view of a fourth embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides for infusing a resin-free preform with an epoxy-based adhesive to form the matrix. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</cross-reference> illustrate the preferred embodiments of an adhesive-infused, three-dimensional (3-D), woven textile preform used for assembling parts into structural joints. The preferred adhesive is FM&reg; 300, also available from Cytec Industries, Inc., but other adhesives will work, providing the adhesive can be infused in a way that properly &ldquo;wets out,&rdquo; or saturates, the fiber bundles in the preform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Various resin systems are sold under the terms &ldquo;laminating resins&rdquo; and &ldquo;adhesives,&rdquo; though there is no &ldquo;bright-line,&rdquo; industry-standard definition by which to distinguish one from the other. The term &ldquo;adhesive,&rdquo; as used herein, is meant as a resin system that has a lower modulus of elasticity and/or a higher strain-to-failure than the resin forming the matrix of the parts to be adhered. The combination of these characteristics is described as higher toughness, and adhesives have a higher toughness than laminating resins, which tend to be more brittle and have lower crack-formation loads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Results from ASTM tests can be used to distinguish, generally, between laminating resins and adhesives. High-strength, structural laminating resins have a peel strength rating generally ranging from 0-15 pounds per linear inch, whereas the peel strength of adhesives are greater than 15 pounds per linear inch. For example, the Bell Peel test (ASTM D3167 &ldquo;Standard Test Method for Floating Roller Peel Resistance of Adhesives&rdquo;) shows that the peel strength of FM&reg; 300 is 23-29 pounds per linear inch at room temperature, but the peel strength of 977-3, which is used to laminate the parts, is 0-6 pounds per linear inch. In addition, laminating resins generally have a tensile strength greater than 7500 pounds per square inch (psi) as tested using ASTM D638 (&ldquo;Standard Test Method for Tensile Properties of Plastics&rdquo;), with high-strength resins ranging to 12000 psi. Adhesives generally have tensile strengths less than 6500 psi. Thus, in the present application, &ldquo;adhesives&rdquo; also means resin systems with tensile strengths less than 6500 psi and a peel strength greater than 15 pounds per linear inch. &ldquo;Laminating resins&rdquo; is used to mean resin systems having tensile strengths greater than 7500 psi and a peel strength of less than 15 pounds per linear inch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> To provide higher strain-to-failure characteristics, epoxy-based adhesives usually have rubber modifiers added to them. The higher strain capability improves load distribution through the preform, reducing the crack formation at the outer edges of the bond lines and in the weave that can lead to catastrophic failure of the joint at loads less than those which would cause failure of the parts. Also, adhesives usually have a higher viscosity than laminating resins. Laminating resins easily saturate woven components, whereas adhesives require an infusion process to wet-out the fiber bundles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The preforms can be infused with adhesive in many ways, though the preferred method is drawing preforms through a tank containing adhesive dissolved in a solvent, usually acetone or toluene. The preforms are immersed in the solution, then removed from the tank. The solvent is allowed to evaporate, or &ldquo;flash off,&rdquo; leaving the adhesive in the preform. To completely wet-out the preforms, this process may be repeated several times. The preform is saturated with the adhesive and is laid up while uncured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The parts, or components, to be joined may be formed from composites and may be cured or uncured, or the parts may be formed from other materials, e.g., plastics, metals, etc. If joining uncured composite parts, the entire assembly can be co-cured. However, a disadvantage to using uncured parts is that more elaborate and expensive tooling is required to create dimensionally-accurate parts. The preforms can be used as a connector (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 3</cross-reference>) or as a bond ply (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to the figures, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a pi-shaped, 3-D, woven preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> used to connect two pre-cured, composite, detail parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, which may be, for example, a frame member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on its lower portion that has a continuous, flat lower surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A pair of spaced-apart planar legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> extend vertically upward from base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Each leg <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is at a position that is offset from, but near to, the center of base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are parallel to each other and generally perpendicular to base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. In the installed position, inner surfaces <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> face each other for receiving frame member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A small, upward-facing surface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> lies between the lower ends of legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Though it is preferable for the outer surface of legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the upper surface of base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to be tapered at their outer ends, as shown, the ends may also be squared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the method used after infusion and prior to installation to keep legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> from adhering to the base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A non-stick separator film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is laid on the upper surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and each leg <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is laid over on film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The outer surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of each leg <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is in contact with film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, not with upper surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of base <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Separator film <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is removed prior to installation of preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, to connect parts <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, frame member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is placed between inner surfaces <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, lower edge <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of frame member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> contacting upward-facing surface <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Lower surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is placed against upper surface <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in the desired position. The adhesive forms a bonding layer at the interface of inner surfaces <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of legs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and outer surfaces <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> of frame member <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and at the interface of lower surface <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and upper surface <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of skin <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> To ensure consistent bonding at the interfaces, the assembly is placed within a vacuum bag (not shown), from which the air is drawn, allowing outside air pressure to apply force to preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Soft, silicone tooling, such as over-presses <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, is normally used against preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> within the vacuum bag to distribute the forces evenly across preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. If the adhesive is a heat-cured adhesive, the assembly is then placed in an autoclave, or heat is applied through other means, to cause the rapid curing of the adhesive. Alternatively, adhesives used in preform <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be cured by other types of cure mechanisms, for example, electron-beam curing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, </cross-reference>3-D woven preform <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is T-shaped, having a base <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and a single vertical leg <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Preform <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is infused with adhesive, and lower surface <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is placed in contact with upper surface <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of cured piece <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> formed from composites. The assembly is vacuum-bagged, and semi-rigid tooling (not shown) is used to support leg <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> while adhesive is cured. A bond layer forms from the adhesive at the interface of surfaces <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, whereas leg <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is cured in an upright position. A separate member <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can be connected to piece <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> by attaching to leg <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, normally with a fastener <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> passing through the thickness of leg <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> illustrate the larger dimensional tolerance available with the use of 3-D preforms as bond plies. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a connection of two planar pieces <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> in shear using an adhesive-infused, 3-D, woven preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> having a rectangular cross-section and no tapered edges. Upper surface <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> of lower piece <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is in contact with lower surface <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, as is lower surface <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of upper piece <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> with upper surface <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. Bond layers form at these interfaces, connecting pieces <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Because the adhesive is infused in preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> having a selected thickness, the bond layer tolerance is increased, preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> allowing a larger variation in distance between pieces <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Without preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>, the distance between pieces <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> must be within a critical tolerance to ensure a proper bonding layer. Preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> preferably has at least two warp-fiber layers and a thickness of about 0.050&Prime;, or may have more layers, increasing the thickness of preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The thickness of preform <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> may be increased to &frac14;&Prime; or beyond and may involve the use of thicker fibers. However, the weight of the extra adhesive used in a thicker preform would likely mean that thicker preforms would be reserved for applications where minimization of weight is not a primary concern, for example, in construction of boats. Though a vacuum bag can be used when a preform is used as a bond ply, mechanical pressure may provide the necessary force during curing of the adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> metal, T-shaped piece <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is bonded to a cured, planar piece <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> using a 3-D, woven preform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> infused with adhesive. The assembly allows for out-of-plane tension loads to be exerted on piece <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> that are transferred to piece <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. As described above for <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the multi-layered, rectangular cross-section of preform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> allows for a larger dimensional tolerance between pieces <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. Lower surface <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> of piece <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is bonded to upper surface <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, while upper surface <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> of piece <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> is bonded to lower surface <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> of preform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. Use of preform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> allows for some misalignment of pieces <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> when bonding and can accommodate dimensional variations in pieces <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> or surfaces <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. After curing, a second planar piece <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> can be attached to piece <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> using fastener <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. While piece <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is shown as being formed from metal, it may also be formed from composites. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The advantages of the present invention include the increased strength from using an adhesive, rather than a resin, within a 3-D woven preform used to connect components. Another advantage is the reduction of steps needed to complete the assembly. By infusing the adhesive into preforms, pieces can be joined without the need for a separate adhesive film being inserted between a resin-infused connector and the pieces to be joined. Also, the thickness of the preform allows for a larger dimensional tolerance at the bond line, while providing the strength of fiber-reinforced adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown in only some of its forms, it is not thus limited but is susceptible to various changes and modifications without departing from the spirit thereof. For example, a cross-shaped preform may be used, or the preform may have more than two legs extending from the base. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for bonding a first component to a second component, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a preform of woven fabric having a selected thickness; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) infusing the preform with an adhesive; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) adhering at least one surface of the preform to at least one surface of the first component using the adhesive within the preform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) curing the adhesive; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) attaching the second component to the preform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the adhesive has a tensile strength less than 6500 pounds per square inch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the adhesive has a peel strength greater than 15 pounds per linear inch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) comprises adhering the second component to the preform using the adhesive within the preform prior to curing the adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) comprises orienting the second component to be generally perpendicular to the first component after attachment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) comprises orienting the second component to be generally parallel to the first component after attachment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) comprises fastening the other of the components to the preform using fasteners. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the preform contains no resin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the preform has a base and two legs extending from a surface of the base. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the preform has a thickness of at least two textile layers. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (d) further comprises enclosing the preform and portions of the components in contact with the preform within a collapsible container and drawing air from within the container, air pressure outside of the container collapsing the container and applying forces to the preform and portions of the components during curing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for bonding two components orthogonally relative to each other, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a resin-free woven preform with a base and a pair of legs extending from the base generally parallel to each other; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) infusing the woven preform with an adhesive; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) adhering opposing surfaces of one of the components to the inner surfaces of the legs of the preform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) adhering a surface of the base of the preform to a surface of the other of the components and positioning the components orthogonal relative to each other; then </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) curing the adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the adhesive has a tensile strength less than 6500 pounds per square inch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the adhesive has a peel strength greater than 15 pounds per linear inch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) further comprises enclosing the preform and portions of the components in contact with the preform within a collapsible container and drawing air from within the container, air pressure outside of the container collapsing the container and applying forces to the preform and portions of the components during curing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) further comprises distributing inward forces across outer surfaces of the preform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method for assembling two components, one of the components being planar, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a resin-free, woven, T-shaped preform with a single leg extending from a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) infusing the preform with an adhesive, the adhesive having a tensile strength of less than 6500 pounds per square inch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) adhering a lower surface of the preform to a surface of the planar component; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) supporting the leg of the preform in an upright orientation; then </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) curing the adhesive; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) securing the other of the components to the leg of the preform with a fastener. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (d) further comprises using tooling to support the leg of the preform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (e) further comprises using tooling to distribute inward force across outer surfaces of the preform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the adhesive has a peel strength greater than 15 pounds per linear inch.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000641A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000641A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
