<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000686A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000686A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000686</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180852</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F28D001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>F28D001/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B21D053/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>165</class>
<subclass>151000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>165</class>
<subclass>150000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>890030</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>High-V plate fin for a heat exchanger and method of manufacturing</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301140</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Douglas</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kester</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>York</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>York International Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>York</city>
<state>PA</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MCNEES, WALLACE &amp; NURICK</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 PINE STREET</address-1>
<address-2>P.O. BOX 1166</address-2>
<city>HARRISBURG</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>17108-1166</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A fin for a heat exchanger coil assembly and a method of manufacturing the fin is provided. The fin includes a heat transfer enhancement pattern which appears sinusoidal in shape. The base wavy pattern of the enhancement pattern includes two wavelengths within each tube row and includes seven discrete segments. Six of the seven segments are circular arc segments. The seventh segment comprises two linear segments which form a condensate channel. The segments are arranged in a particular order at specific distances offset (above and below) from a leading edge nominal air streamline (LENAS) by a fraction of a nominal fin pitch P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. The LENAS is related to the &ldquo;normal&rdquo; base wavy pattern used in other fins. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/301,140 filed Jun. 28, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a heat exchanger fin. More specifically, the present invention relates to an enhanced pattern for a plate fin used in a plate fin/tube heat exchanger that maximizes heat transfer in all areas of the fin and a corresponding method of manufacturing the fin to have the enhanced pattern. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Finned heat exchanger coil assemblies are widely used in a number of applications in fields such as air conditioning and refrigeration. A finned heat exchanger coil assembly generally includes a plurality of spaced parallel tubes through which a heat transfer fluid such as water or refrigerant flows. A second heat transfer fluid, usually air, is directed across the tubes. A plurality of fins is usually employed to improve the heat transfer capabilities of the heat exchanger coil assembly. Each fin is a thin metal plate, made of copper or aluminum, which may or may not include a hydrophilic coating. Each fin also acts as a tubesheet and includes a plurality of apertures for receiving the spaced parallel tubes, such that the tubes generally pass through the plurality of fins at right angles to the fins. The fins are arranged in a parallel, closely spaced relationship to one another along the tubes to form multiple paths for the air or other heat transfer fluid to flow across the fins and around the tubes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In heat exchanger coil assemblies, it is desirable to maximize the amount of heat transfer within a given coil. Once way to increase heat transfer is to increase the size of the fin. However, increasing the size of the fin leads to a larger device and to a higher, air-side pressure drop, both of which are undesirable. &ldquo;Pressure Drop&rdquo; is the air pressure difference required to maintain air flow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. High pressure drop is undesirable since the energy required to keep air flowing through the coil assembly is proportional to the pressure drop across the coil assembly. Higher coil pressure drop leads to higher energy (typically electrical) usage, for a given building HVAC system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In a heat exchanger coil assembly for dehumidifying air, relatively warm and humid air flows into the coil, and as the air becomes cooler, it becomes saturated with water. At some point, the cooled air reaches its dew point and is unable to hold moisture as it is cooled further, resulting in condensation on the fin plate. The resulting condensate on the fin inhibits heat transfer between the fin and the air. The condensate is typically removed from the fin plate by one of two mechanisms. The first mechanism is gravity-induced drainage along the fin surface into a pan located under the coil assembly. This mechanism of condensate removal is desirable, and results in plate fins being oriented vertically in dehumidification coils. The second mechanism for condensate removal is entrainment of condensate droplets by the airflow exiting the coil. This mechanism of condensate removal is typically undesirable, since it can lead to problematic biologic activity on downstream surfaces of the equipment housing the coil assembly. Thus, it is desirable to provide the fin with a structure that minimizes the condensate inventory residing on the fin surface, facilitates and maximizes gravity-induced drainage of condensate from the coil assembly, and inhibits entrainment of condensate droplets into the exiting airflow. To solve these problems, some fins are produced or manufactured having complex geometries which are difficult and expensive to manufacture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, what is needed is a fin geometry that is simple and inexpensive to manufacture while maximizing the heat transfer capabilities of the fin. In addition, a fin geometry is needed that can remove moisture from the air passing over the fin and reduce the amount of condensation that is permitted to reside on the fins. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, a heat exchanger coil assembly is provided. The heat exchanger coil assembly includes a plurality of fins and a plurality of heat transfer tubes. Each fin has a heat transfer enhancement pattern, which is made up of seven discrete segments within each tube row. The shape and placement of these segments forces the over-tube fluid streamlines to tend toward a sinusoid-like pattern having two wavelengths within each tube row. The sinusoid-like pattern passing through the leading edge of the fin is termed the Leading Edge Nominal Air Streamline, and it is represented by the acronym &ldquo;LENAS.&rdquo; The segments are offset, perpendicular to a mean airflow direction, from the LENAS by a fraction of a nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the present invention, in a finned heat exchanger coil assembly configured for heat transfer to take place between a first fluid flowing through a plurality of spaced apart finned heat transfer tubes and a second fluid flowing outside of the tubes, a fin comprises a heat transfer enhancement pattern. The heat transfer enhancement pattern of each fin includes seven discrete segments within each tube row. The shape and placement of these segments forces the over-tube fluid streamlines to tend toward a sinusoid-like pattern having two wavelengths within each tube row. The segments are offset, perpendicular to a mean airflow direction, from the LENAS by a fraction of a nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In still another embodiment of the present invention, a heat exchanger coil assembly includes a plurality of heat transfer tubes. The plurality of heat transfer tubes are positioned into at least one row and are disposed substantially parallel to one another. The coil assembly also includes a plurality of fins. The plurality of fins are disposed substantially perpendicular to the plurality of heat transfer tubes and substantially parallel to one another and are separated from each other by a preselected distance. Each fin of the plurality of fins has a predetermined pattern for each row of heat transfer tubes. The predetermined pattern of each fin has a substantially sinusoidal shape and seven discrete segments. Each segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed with respect to a predefined reference shape. Finally, at least one segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset of a first distance from the predefined reference shape and at least one other segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset of a second distance greater than the first distance from the predefined reference shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment of the present invention, a fin plate for a heat exchanger coil assembly has a predetermined fin pitch and a plurality of tubes arranged into a plurality of rows. The fin plate includes a predetermined pattern for each row of tubes. The predetermined pattern has a substantially sinusoidal or sinusoid-like shape and seven discrete segments. Each segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed with respect to a predefined reference shape. At least one segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the predefined reference shape by a first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch and at least one other segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the predefined reference shape by a second fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the present invention is directed to a method of manufacturing a fin plate for a heat exchanger coil assembly having a predefined fin pitch and a plurality of tubes arranged into a plurality of rows. The method includes the step of defining a reference shape for the fin plate. The reference shape has a substantially sinusoidal shape and corresponds to a nominal air streamline. Another step is providing a first die to form a first predetermined pattern into the fin plate. The first predetermined pattern is formed with respect to the reference shape. Still another step is forming the reference shape in the fin plate with the first die. Yet another step is raising a section of the fin plate above the reference shape by a first distance with the first die to form the first predetermined pattern into the fin plate. A further step is providing a second die to form a second predetermined pattern into the fin plate. The second predetermined pattern has a plurality of segments and at least one segment of the plurality of segments is offset from the first predetermined pattern by a first distance and at least one other segment of the plurality of segments is offset from the first predetermined pattern by a second distance. The method also includes the steps of: slitting the fin plate with the second die to define the plurality of segments; offsetting the at least one segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the first distance with the second die; and offsetting the at least one other segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the second distance with the second die to form the second predetermined pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the present invention is the production of a high, air-side, convective heat transfer coefficient and a relatively low air-side pressure drop. The positioning and size of the fin enhancement segments prevent the wake of any one segment from interfering with the heat transfer capabilities of at least the next two downstream segments. The impact of each segment&apos;s thermal wake on the heat transfer capability of downstream segments is therefore minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another advantage of the present invention is that it minimizes the deleterious impact of fin-surface condensate on heat transfer by promoting gravity-induced drainage of condensate along the fin surface. The first fin segment of each tube row forms a relatively sharp crease, or condensate channel, that spans the entire height of the fin without interruption. Surface tension forms a relatively thick condensate film on the concave side of the crease, where the condensate also happens to be shielded from the viscous drag of the airflow, resulting in relatively large condensate drainage velocities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A further advantage of the present invention is that it provides a relatively high airflow face velocity with respect to incipient condensate carryover. If condensate droplets are entrained by the airflow, the sinusoidal shape of the air streamline and the positioning of the fin enhancement segments can redeposit the condensate droplets back on the fin surface within a short airflow travel distance of a fraction of a tube row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Still another advantage of the present invention is that it minimizes the pressure drop penalty typically produced by sinusoidal fin enhancement shapes. The division of the fin enhancement into discrete segments that are offset from the LENAS kinematically blocks the development of the secondary flow patterns that tend to form adjacent to curved fluid flow boundaries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the present invention will be apparent from the following more detailed description of the preferred embodiment, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings which illustrate, by way of example, the principles of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a small portion of a staggered tube pattern heat exchanger fin having an enhanced heat transfer pattern of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of the heat exchanger fin of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional side view of the heat exchanger fin taken along line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of a portion of a fin having an enhanced base wavy pattern of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a heat exchanger coil assembly incorporating the fin of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top view of a fin from one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a enlarged view of the collar portion surrounding apertures of the fin of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a side view of a portion of an enhanced fin according the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a sectional side view of an enhanced base wavy pattern corresponding to the enhanced heat transfer pattern illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a sectional side view of the fin taken along line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> showing the enhanced heat transfer pattern of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an isometric view of a in-line tube pattern heat exchanger fin having the enhanced heat transfer pattern of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a sectional side view of a collar portion and fin taken along line <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> illustrate one embodiment of a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is preferably incorporated into a heat exchanger, and more preferably a heat exchanger coil assembly, to enhance the heat transfer capabilities of the heat exchanger. The enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is configured to maximize heat transfer in all areas of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> has seven distinct and discrete segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, which segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will be described in greater detail below. The segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are substantially parallel to each row of tubes and can be repeated along the width of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> an additional number of times, as necessary to correspond to the number of tube rows. The width of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is measured in a direction parallel to the direction of airflow through the heat exchanger. The number of times the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is repeated along the width of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is dependent on the particular heat exchanger into which the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is incorporated. The heat exchanger includes a plurality of tubes for the passage of a heat transfer fluid, which operation of the heat exchanger will be described in greater detail below. The fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of apertures or openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> to receive the plurality of tubes of the heat exchanger. The positioning of the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> on the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is dependent upon the particular configuration of the tubes of the heat exchanger. For example, in one embodiment of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are arranged or positioned in four rows, with the apertures in adjacent rows being offset from one another and apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in alternate rows being aligned with one another in a staggered tube pattern. In another embodiment of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are positioned and arranged in two rows with the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in adjacent rows being aligned with one another in an in-line tube pattern. It is to be understood that the above examples of the positioning and arrangement of the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are not intended to be limiting, with other arrangements being possible, and a specific positioning and arrangement of the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is dependent on the particular heat exchanger application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 8</cross-reference> illustrate a side view of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention. As discussed above, the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes seven discrete segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is based on an enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and will be described in greater detail below. The enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> has a substantially sinusoidal shape and is designed and used to simplify the manufacturing of a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> from base fin plate or stock. The manufacturing process of a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> will be described in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The dimensions of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are derived from the specific fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, and longitudinal tube pitch, P<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>, of the optimal heat exchanger application of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. While only one fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, is used to define the enhancement geometry, the resulting fin can be applied to coil assemblies having a different fin pitch. However, the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is preferably most effective when applied to a coil assembly having the fin pitch used as the basis for the enhancement design. The fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, is a measurement of the spacing of two adjacent fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the heat exchanger application, measured in a direction parallel to the tubes&apos; centerlines or is a preselected distance between adjacent fins. The longitudinal tube pitch, P<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>, is a measurement of the distance between the aperture center points of two adjacent rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, measured in a direction perpendicular to a plane including the centerlines of the tubes when installed within a given row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A Leading Edge Nominal Air Streamline (&ldquo;LENAS&rdquo;) is an imaginary reference curve that is made up of congruent, circular arc segments joined together at their points of tangency, forming a pattern that resembles a sine wave. The LENAS preferably corresponds to a &ldquo;normal&rdquo; base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> used in prior heat exchanger fins. The &ldquo;normal&rdquo; base wavy pattern or LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is used to define the shape of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the present invention. The LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> has a wavelength of about P<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>/2, a maximum inclination from the mean airflow direction of about 40 degrees, and a phase that positions half of its peaks (or troughs, depending on an arbitrary 180 degree flip of the fin) on planes including the centerlines of the tubes when installed within a given row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The placement of the seven discrete segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is obtained by offsetting portions of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern can be considered to be lances or louvers of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> repeats throughout the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> depending on the specific heat exchanger application and the number of rows of tubes in the heat exchanger application. Six of the seven segments <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are circular arc segments or parabolic segments. The seventh segment <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has two substantially linear portions that form a condensate channel. The segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are arranged in a particular order at specific distances offset, above and below, the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The positioning of the segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is described relative to the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> shown with a dashed line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. As discussed above, there are two wavelengths of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> included in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> corresponding to a row of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, and the seven discrete portions or segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, which for ease in identification will be referenced as segments &ldquo;A&rdquo;-&ldquo;G&rdquo;, extend over or across the two wavelengths of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> included in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, begins at a midpoint between two adjacent rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and extends to the first inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> includes two linear portions which form a condensate channel. The first portion <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> is tangent to the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> at the midpoint between the adjacent rows of apertures, and the second portion <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is tangent to the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> at its first inflection point. Segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is placed in its final position in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during manufacturing or application of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the fin stock. In another embodiment of the present invention, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can be used with a fin having a heat transfer pattern with a shape similar to the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. The use of segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in this embodiment, provides the fin with a condensate channel to remove condensate from the fin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first portion <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and the second portion <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> forms an angle of approximately 40 degrees as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, and this angle acts as a condensate channel to transport condensate off the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is continuous across the height of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (the height of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> being measured perpendicular to the direction of the airflow through the heat exchanger application), i.e. segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is not interrupted or broken by the corresponding collar structure or portion for the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> (the collar structure surrounding the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is described in greater detail below with regard to the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 12</cross-reference>), thereby creating a &ldquo;condensate superhighway&rdquo; or condensate channel to transport condensate off the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Since condensate flows by gravity through the condensate channel, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is aligned substantially perpendicular to the ground or with a substantial perpendicular component to the ground, i.e. segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a substantially vertical orientation. Condensate gathers in the sharp angle due to the surface tension of the condensate, forming a thicker than average condensate film on the concave side of the angle. This increased thickness of the condensate film increases the speed at which it flows off the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, due to gravity, relative to a thinner film. In addition, because the condensate gathers on the concave side of the angle, the condensate is shielded from the airflow and is therefore less likely to be re-entrained by the airstream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Three fluid mechanical phenomena explain the operation of the condensate channel. First, a liquid&apos;s surface tension increases the thickness of a thin liquid film on a wettable, solid surface in the immediate vicinity of the concave side of a sharp corner or crease in the surface. Second, thicker liquid films flow down vertical walls under the influence of gravity faster than thinner liquid films. Third, the corner shields the thicker liquid film adjacent to it from cross-flowing air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The first mechanism can be explained by surface tension&apos;s tendency to minimize a liquid&apos;s surface area. Surface tension makes small droplets of water take the shape of spheres, since a sphere has the smallest surface area-to-volume ratio of any three-dimensional body of a given internal volume. In just the same way, surface tension rounds the surface of thin liquid films adhering to wettable surfaces. For example, if the surface contains a crease with a radius of curvature of 0.5 mm, the radius of curvature of an adjacent, 0.1 mm-thick water film will be substantially greater, such as 1 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The second mechanism is an intuitive characteristic of open-channel flow. Just as a river&apos;s water level increases during periods of heavy rain, when it is carrying a greater-than-average flow of water, a thick film of water running down a vertical wall will carry a greater flow of water down the wall than a thin film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Finally, the third mechanism is a well-known fluid-dynamic phenomenon. Two-dimensional flow of an incompressible fluid adjacent to a wall having an angle of less than 180 degrees always produces a stagnation point (point of zero velocity) at the corner. An idealized flow pattern illustrating this phenomenon is named &ldquo;Faulker-Skan Wedge Flow&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> begins at the first inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). Segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset downward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Offset pattern <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> shifted or offset downward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> starts or begins at the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the second inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset upward by &frac12; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. and rotated counterclockwise approximately 4 degrees, and more preferably approximately 3.8 degrees, about its trailing edge as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Offset pattern <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> shifted or offset upward by &frac12; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. The rotational angle of segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is measured between the tangent of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and the tangent of the end of segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Further, the rotational angle of segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is related to the raising of segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, which raising is described in greater detail below. In a preferred embodiment, the nominal fin pitch is {fraction (1/12)} inch, and the fin thickness is 0.006 inch and the performance of the fin is enhanced by an inclination of 3.8 degrees. However, the angle can vary depending on the particular fin pitch and fin thickness of the heat exchanger application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> begins or starts at the second inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the third inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> includes one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset upward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Offset pattern <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> shifted or offset upward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> comprises crest <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is preferably formed in its final position in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during application or manufacturing of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the fin stock. The positioning of segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> results in the contortion or deviation of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> from LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> begins or starts at the third inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). Segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset downward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is substantially similar to segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern starts or begins at the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the fourth inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset upward by &frac12; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, and rotated clockwise approximately 4 degrees, and more preferably approximately 3.8 degrees, about its trailing edge. Segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is substantially similar to segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the preferred embodiment of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> begins or starts at the fourth inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to the midpoint between successive rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; includes a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; is preferably formed in its final position in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during the application or manufacturing of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the fin stock. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are continuous when the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is repeated for successive rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> for the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are joined together by a smooth curve through the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and segments &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are joined together by a smooth curve through the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. The first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is the midpoint between the trailing edge of segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and the leading edge of segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> is the midpoint between the trailing edge of segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and the leading edge of segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> through the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is a parabola. Alternatively, the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> through the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> can be a circular arc segment. In either case, the slope of the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> through the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> does not have to match the slopes of segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> at their points of intersection. Also in the preferred embodiment, the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> through the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> is a parabola. Alternatively, the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> through the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> can be a circular arc segment. Again, in either case, the slope of the smooth curve joining segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> through the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> does not have to match the slopes of segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> at their points of intersection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates one embodiment of a heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that can incorporate the fins and corresponding fin plates having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> extending along the length of the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and arranged in proximity to each other. A plurality of tube connectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connect the ends of a pair of the plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each tube connector <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has a substantially U-shape and connects an adjacent pair of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to provide a serpentine path for fluid flowing through the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and tube connectors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. One tube <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to a fluid inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and another tube <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is connected to a fluid outlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The fluid inlet <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and fluid outlet <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may be located, for example, at the bottom portion of the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, at a side portion of the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or any other suitable location on the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The number of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and their arrangement and positioning in the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can vary depending on the requirements of a specific application. In one embodiment, a row of up to 24 substantially parallel tubes may be provided in the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. More preferably, the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has two or more substantially parallel rows of up to 12 substantially parallel tubes. The tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are preferably made of copper, however, other suitable materials may also be used. The tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> have a preselected cross-sectional shape, preferably a round or an oval cross-section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> During the heat transfer process, a first heat transfer fluid flows through the serpentine path formed by the plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and a second heat transfer fluid flows over the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provide an interface for the transfer of heat between the first and second heat transfer fluids. The first heat transfer fluid flowing through tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is water or a refrigerant fluid such as ammonia, ethyl chloride, Freon&reg;, chlorofluocarbons (CFCs), hydrofluorocarbons (HFCs), and other natural refrigerants. However, it is to be understood that any suitable heat transfer fluid may be used for the first heat transfer fluid. The second heat transfer fluid is preferably air, which is being either warmed or cooled during the heat transfer process depending on the particular application. However, it is to be understood that other suitable heat transfer fluids may be used for the second heat transfer fluid. The airflow is typically forced, such as by a fan, but can be static. Adjacent to the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are a plurality of fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The transfer of heat between the first heat transfer fluid and the second heat transfer fluid occurs as the second heat transfer fluid, which is preferably air, flows over or across the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, while the first heat transfer fluid flows through the plurality of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a plurality of fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to improve the heat transfer capabilities of the heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Each fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is a thin metal plate, preferably made of a high conductivity material such as copper or aluminum, and may include a hydrophilic coating. The fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> include a plurality of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> for receiving each of the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> preferably pass through the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at preferably a right angle to the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The tubes and fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> make intimate contact with one another to permit heat transfer between the two. While the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and tubes can be metallurgically joined such as by brazing or welding, the preferred embodiment of the present invention joins the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and tubes frictionally or mechanically such as by rolling. The fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are preferably arranged and disposed in a substantially parallel, closely spaced relationship that has multiple paths for the second heat transfer fluid, which is preferably air, to flow between the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and across the tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also has end plates <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that are located on either side of the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to provide some structural support to the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and to protect the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from damage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Preferably, all of the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of a single heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> have the same dimensions. The dimensions of the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of a coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can range from less then 1 inch to 40 inches in width and up to 72 inches in height, depending upon the intended use of the heat exchanger coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the number of tubes <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The fins preferably have a minimum thickness of about 0.002 inches, to avoid possible manufacturing problems. However, the fins can have a very large thickness if, for example, the whole coil assembly is scaled-up from dimensions of inches to dimensions of feet. In a preferred embodiment, the thickness of the fins are about 0.006 inches, 0.008 inches, and 0.010 inches. With regard to the spacing of the fins, the distances between fins is preferably not less than about {fraction (1/30)} inch, otherwise there can be manufacturing difficulties. However, the fin pitch could be very large if the whole coil assembly is scaled up as described above. In a preferred embodiment, the fin pitch can range from &frac18; inch to {fraction (1/14)} inch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> A fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having an enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> according to the present invention is readily manufacturable. Because the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is continuous across the midpoint between successive rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, i.e. segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are continuous, the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is able to span a large number of rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, several fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> each spanning a few rows of apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> may be used. In addition, plastic deformation of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> during fabrication is reduced by offsetting segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> upwardly rather than downwardly, as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The present invention is also directed to a method or process of manufacturing a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes applying the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the fin stock with a first die. Next, the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is slit or cut with a second die in a direction perpendicular to the mean airflow direction. Finally, segments of the fin stock are raised or lowered with the second die, or a third die, as appropriate, from the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> into their final positions in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and the collar structure are formed in the fin stock using well known techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The process begins with the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> being applied or formed in the fin stock with a first die. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> after the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> has been formed in the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. After the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> has been formed in the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are positioned in their final position for the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The formation of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in the fin stock, positions segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> at an upward offset of &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, from the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. The positioning of segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> at this upward offset and in its final position in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> simplifies the manufacturing process because segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is positioned in one step and, thus, does not have to be cut and bent into its final position using the second die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is applied to the fin stock with a first die. The enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is configured to position segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in their final position. The enhanced base wavy pattern also positions a continuous segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> across the midpoint of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, permitting easier manufacturing of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, as previously discussed, includes two parabolic regions or circular arc portions forming troughs <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> that are connected by a crest portion <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. The slope of the segments forming the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> do not necessarily have to be continuous. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> After the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is applied to the fin stock, the fin stock is slit or cut with a second die, in a direction perpendicular to the mean airflow direction, to define segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. After the fin stock is slit or cut, segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are offset or &ldquo;raised&rdquo; and &ldquo;lowered&rdquo; from the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> using a different die or in a different embodiment, the same die. During the slitting or cutting and offsetting of segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are not displaced from their positions in the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> each include a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset downward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> begins at the first inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to its first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> begins at the third inflection point of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to its second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> each include a fraction of one circular arc segment of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> offset upward by &frac12; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, and rotated clockwise approximately 4 degrees about its trailing edge. Segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> begins at the first trough <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to its second inflection point and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> begins at the second trough <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> of the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and extends to its fourth inflection point. By offsetting segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in an upward direction, plastic deformation of the fin stock during fabrication of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is reduced, compared to offsetting segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in a downward direction approximately &frac12; nominal fin pitch in an alternate embodiment, which would result in substantially the same enhancement pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, it would be possible to form the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> by applying a normal base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to the fin stock. In such a process, it would be necessary to also offset segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> upward by &frac14; nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. Additionally, it would also be possible to combine the slit and offset steps into a single step which would be performed with a single die. However, such an alternative would increase the possibility of manufacturing difficulties and is therefore a less desirable alternative. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6, 7</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> illustrate one embodiment of a fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is configured for use in a half-inch (&frac12; inch) staggered equilateral tube coil having twelve (12) fins per inch. The fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6, 7</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a nominal fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, of 0.0833 inches and a longitudinal tube pitch, P<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>, of 1.0820 inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top view of a portion of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and shows the staggered tube pattern of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a enlarged view of the fin structure surrounding the apertures <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> for receiving the tubes of the heat exchanger. Some dimensions for the embodiment of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> are provided therein. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates the collar structure surrounding the apertures of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The collar structure of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> supports the tube passing through the aperture <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In addition, there is a small, flat, annular section immediately surrounding the collar structure that acts as a spring to keep the collar structures in physical contact with the tubes. This small disk is part of the &ldquo;base fin plate&rdquo;. The size of the transition region between the small flat disk and the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is kept to a minimum, constrained by material stretching limitations, in order to maximize the area of the fin formed into the enhanced heat transfer pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are continuous about the collar structure. As discussed above, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can operate as a condensate channel, because the continuity of segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is not interrupted by the collar structure. The collar structure has a lip that is raised from the base fin plate a distance approximately equal to the fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the height to the top surface of the raised lip, measured from the bottom surface of the base fin plate, is about 0.0833, which corresponds to the fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, for this embodiment. The height of the lip from the base fin plate will vary based on the particular fin pitch, P<highlight><subscript>f</subscript></highlight>, of the heat exchanger application. For example, the height of the lip for 6 fins per inch (fpi) is about 0.1667 inches, for 8 fpi, the height of the lip is about 0.1250 inches, for 10 fpi, the height of the lip is about 0.1000 inches, and for 14 fpi, the height of the lip is about 0.0714 inches. Preferably, the lip is in contact with an adjacent fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, when the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is arranged in a heat exchanger application. The contact of the lip against the adjacent fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, provides some support for the tubes and increases the rigidity of the fins <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in the heat exchanger application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross-section of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates the fin stock of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> after the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> has been applied, but before segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> have been slit and offset from the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> used to create the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. The enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> includes a first parabolic portion determined by the equation y(x)&equals;0.0101665&minus;1.513209(x)&plus;2.939419(x<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>) and a second parabolic portion determined by the equation y(x)&equals;1.905621&minus;4.847693(x)&plus;2.939419(x<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>), where &ldquo;x&rdquo; is the absolute distance from the datum line labeled &ldquo;X&rdquo; as shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> and &ldquo;y&rdquo; is the absolute distance from the datum line labeled &ldquo;Y&rdquo; as shown on <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The two parabolic portions are connected by a crest or arc portion <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> having a radius of curvature of 0.2104 inches. The above dimensions and equations apply to the embodiment where P<highlight><subscript>f&equals;</subscript></highlight>{fraction (1/12)}&Prime; and P<highlight><subscript>l</subscript></highlight>&equals;1.0820&Prime;. The above dimensions and equations will differ for other embodiments having a different fin pitch and tube pitch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> As discussed in greater detail above, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;D&rdquo; <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;G&rdquo; <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are formed in their final position in the enhanced heat transfer pattern upon the formation of the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in the fin stock. Segment &ldquo;B&rdquo; <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;C&rdquo; <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, segment &ldquo;E&rdquo; <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and segment &ldquo;F&rdquo; <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are offset from the enhanced base wavy pattern <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> into the final positions in the enhanced heat transfer pattern. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention represents a new and highly effective fin geometry for use in plate fin and tube heat exchangers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for heating and cooling applications. A fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> according to the present invention produces a high, air-side, convective heat transfer coefficient and a relatively low air-side pressure drop. The geometry of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> permits the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to maintain thin thermal boundary layers adjacent to the surfaces of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Positioning of the offset fin segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> minimizes the impact of each segment&apos;s thermal wake on heat transfer from down stream segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention, the airflow streamlines tend toward a generally sinusoidal pattern, previously described as the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The seven segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are offset from the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> by varying distances which prevents the wake of any one segment from interfering with heat transfer from at least the next two segments downstream. The distribution of the seven segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> also retards development of secondary flow patterns (Taylor/Goertler vortices), which tend to result from the curvature of the air streamlines and which erode heat transfer coefficient to pressure drop ratio. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> A fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> according to the present invention also has a relatively high face velocity corresponding to incipient condensate carryover. As discussed previously, during cooling or dehumidifying applications the air passing through the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> becomes saturated with moisture, and this moisture can interfere with heat transfer when condensate forms on the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, if the moisture remains in the air, the air dispensed by the coil assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be wet, which is also undesirable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, segment &ldquo;A&rdquo; <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has two portions which preferably form an angle of approximately 40 degrees to act as a condensate channel to transport condensate down off the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Condensation gathers in the channel formed by the angle due to capillary forces. The gathered condensation forms a thicker than average condensable film on the concave side of the angle. The thickness of the condensate film increases the speed at which it flows off of the fin <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, under the influence of gravity, relative to a thinner film. In addition, because the condensate gathers on the concave side of the angle, the condensate is shielded from the airflow and is not likely to be re-entrained into the airstream. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In addition to the condensate channel, the curvilinear shape of the airflow streamlines acts to remove liquid condensate droplets from the air. The curvilinear shape of the airflow streamlines leads to inertial separation of entrained liquid droplets from the bulk airflow onto the surface of the fin. The particular order and distances of the segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> offset from the LENAS <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> in the enhanced heat transfer pattern <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of the present invention positions each segment to catch liquid droplets entrained in the airflow from the trailing edge of an upstream segment. Generally, the curved shaped and positioning of the segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> will not permit liquid entrained from one segment to be carried more than two segments downstream before it is &ldquo;caught&rdquo; and removed from the airflow. This is accomplished using the concept of centrifugal separation of entrained liquid from air, wherein the liquid is more dense than the air and tends to travel straight as the air travels around a curve. This means that any liquid carried by the air flowing over the curved surface of the segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is likely to travel straight, and hit one of the segments <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, removing the liquid from the air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to a preferred embodiment, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof. Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A heat exchanger coil assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of heat transfer tubes, the plurality of heat transfer tubes being positioned into at least one row, and the plurality of heat transfer tubes being disposed substantially parallel to one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of fins in contact with the plurality of heat transfer tubes, the plurality of fins being disposed substantially perpendicular to the plurality of heat transfer tubes and substantially parallel to one another; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each fin of the plurality of fins having a predetermined pattern for each row of heat transfer tubes, the predetermined pattern having a substantially sinusoidal shape, the predetermined pattern comprising seven discrete segments, each segment of the seven discrete segments being disposed with respect to a predefined reference shape; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, at least one segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset of a first distance from the predefined reference shape and at least one other segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset of a second distance greater than the first distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the predetermined pattern has a first end and second end opposite the first end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the seven discrete segments comprises a first segment, the first segment being disposed adjacent to the first end of the predetermined pattern, and the first segment being disposed substantially on the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment comprises a first linear portion and a second linear portion, the first linear portion and the second linear portion being disposed to form an angle of about 40 degrees. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprise a second segment disposed adjacent to the first segment, the second segment being disposed at an offset of the first distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second segment is offset below the predefined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprise a third segment disposed adjacent to the second segment, the third segment being disposed at an offset of the second distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third segment is offset above the predefined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third segment has a first end adjacent the second segment and a second end opposite the first end, the first end of the third segment being displaced about 4 degrees from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprise a fourth segment disposed adjacent to the third segment, the fourth segment being disposed at an offset of the first distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fourth segment is offset above the predefined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprise a fifth segment disposed adjacent to the fourth segment, the fifth segment being disposed at an offset of the first distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fifth segment is offset below the predefined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprise a sixth segment disposed adjacent to the fifth segment, the sixth segment being disposed at an offset of the second distance from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sixth segment is offset above the predefined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seven discrete segments comprises a seventh segment, the seventh segment being disposed adjacent to both the second end of the predetermined pattern and the sixth segment, and the seventh segment being disposed substantially on the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the at least one row of heat transfer tubes comprises a plurality of rows; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the seventh segment of the predetermined pattern of one row of heat transfer tubes is continuous with the first segment of the predetermined pattern of an adjacent row of heat transfer tubes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the plurality of fins having a predetermined fin pitch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the first distance is a first predefined fraction of the predetermined fin pitch; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the second distance is a second predefined fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first predefined fraction is one quarter of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second predefined fraction is one half of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>each fin of the plurality of fins having a height measured substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly and a width measured substantially parallel to the airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one segment of the seven discrete segments extends continuously along the height of the fin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein six segments of the seven discrete segments have a first width and a seventh segment of the seven discrete segments has a second width greater than the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second width is twice the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seventh segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed centrally in the predetermined pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The heat exchanger coil assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the at least one row of heat transfer tubes comprises a plurality of rows; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each fin of the plurality of fins having tube pitch corresponding to the distance between adjacent rows of heat transfer tubes; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the predetermined pattern having a wavelength of one half of the tube pitch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A fin plate for a heat exchanger coil assembly having a predetermined fin pitch and a plurality of tubes arranged into a plurality of rows, the fin plate comprising: 
<claim-text>a predetermined pattern for each row of tubes, the predetermined pattern having a substantially sinusoidal shape, the predetermined pattern comprising seven discrete segments, each segment of the seven discrete segments being disposed with respect to a predefined reference shape; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, at least one segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the predefined reference shape by a first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch and at least one other segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the predefined reference shape by a second fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a plurality of apertures corresponding to the plurality of tubes, the plurality of apertures being arranged into a plurality of rows, and each aperture of the plurality of apertures being configured and disposed to receive a corresponding tube of the plurality of tubes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the predetermined pattern has a first end and second end opposite the first end; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the seven discrete segments comprises a first segment disposed adjacent to the first end of the predetermined pattern, a second segment disposed adjacent to the first segment, a third segment disposed adjacent to the second segment, a fourth segment disposed adjacent to the third segment, a fifth segment disposed adjacent to the fourth segment, a sixth segment disposed adjacent to the fifth segment and a seventh segment disposed adjacent to both the sixth segment and the second end of the predetermined pattern. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment is disposed substantially on the predefined reference shape and comprises a first linear portion and a second linear portion, the first linear portion and the second linear portion being configured and disposed to form a condensate channel for removal of condensate from the fin plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first linear portion and the second linear portion are disposed to form an angle of about 40 degrees. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second segment, the third segment, the fourth segment, the fifth segment and the sixth segment are offset from the predetermined reference shape in a direction substantially perpendicular to airflow through the heat exchanger coil assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second segment is disposed at an offset below the predefined reference shape by the first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third segment is disposed at an offset above the predefined reference shape by the second fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third segment has a first end adjacent the second segment and a second end opposite the first end, the first end of the third segment being displaced about 4 degrees from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fourth segment is disposed at an offset above the predefined reference shape by the first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the fifth segment is disposed at an offset below the predefined reference shape by the first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sixth segment is disposed at an offset above the predefined reference shape by the second fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sixth segment has a first end adjacent the fifth segment and a second end opposite the first end, the first end of the sixth segment being displaced about 4 degrees from the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seventh segment is disposed substantially on the predefined reference shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the seventh segment of the predetermined pattern of one row of tubes is continuous with the first segment of the predetermined pattern of an adjacent row of tubes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first predefined fraction of the predetermined fin pitch is one quarter of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second predefined fraction of the predetermined fin pitch is one half of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment and the seventh segment of the predetermined pattern each extend continuously in a direction substantially parallel to a corresponding row of heat transfer tubes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment, the second segment, the third segment, the fifth segment, the sixth segment and the seventh segment each have a first width and the fourth segment has a second width greater than the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second width is twice the first width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a fin plate for a heat exchanger coil assembly having a predefined fin pitch and a plurality of tubes arranged into a plurality of rows, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>defining a reference shape for the fin plate, the reference shape having a substantially sinusoidal shape and corresponding to a nominal air streamline; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a first die to form a first predetermined pattern into the fin plate, the first predetermined pattern being formed with respect to the reference shape; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the reference shape in the fin plate with the first die; </claim-text>
<claim-text>raising a section of the fin plate above the reference shape by a first distance with the first die to form the first predetermined pattern into the fin plate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a second die to form a second predetermined pattern into the fin plate, the second predetermined pattern having a plurality of segments and at least one segment of the plurality of segments being offset from the first predetermined pattern by a first distance and at least one other segment of the plurality of segments being offset from the first predetermined pattern by a second distance; </claim-text>
<claim-text>slitting the fin plate with the second die to define the plurality of segments; </claim-text>
<claim-text>offsetting the at least one segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the first distance with the second die; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>offsetting the at least one other segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the second distance with the second die to form the second predetermined pattern. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>the plurality of segments comprises a first segment disposed adjacent to a first end of the second predetermined pattern, a second segment disposed adjacent to the first segment, a third segment disposed adjacent to the second segment, a fourth segment disposed adjacent to the third segment, a fifth segment disposed adjacent to the fourth segment, a sixth segment disposed adjacent to the fifth segment and a seventh segment disposed adjacent to the sixth segment; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one segment of the plurality of segments offset from the first predetermined pattern by a first distance comprises the second segment and the fifth segment; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the at least one other segment of the plurality of segments offset from the first predetermined pattern by a second distance comprises the third segment and the sixth segment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first distance is one fourth of the predefined fin pitch and the second distance is one half of the predefined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of offsetting the at least one segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the first distance with the second die further comprises the step of lowering the second segment and the fifth segment the first distance from the first predetermined pattern with the second die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of offsetting the at least one other segment of the plurality of segments from the first predetermined pattern by the second distance with the second die further comprises the step of raising the third segment and the sixth segment the second distance from the first predetermined pattern with the second die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the step of raising a section of the fin plate above the reference shape by a first distance with the first die further comprises the step of raising the fourth segment above the reference shape by the first distance with the first die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. A fin plate for a heat exchanger coil assembly having a predetermined fin pitch and a plurality of tubes arranged into a plurality of rows, the fin plate comprising: 
<claim-text>a predetermined pattern for each row of tubes, the predetermined pattern having a substantially sinusoidal shape, the predetermined pattern having a first end and second end opposite the first end, the predetermined pattern comprising a first segment disposed adjacent to the first end of the predetermined pattern; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, the first segment comprises a first linear portion and a second linear portion, the first linear portion and the second linear portion being configured and disposed to form a condensate channel for removal of condensate from the fin plate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first linear portion and the second linear portion are disposed to form an angle of about 40 degrees. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined pattern is a base wavy pattern based on a leading edge nominal air streamline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the predetermined pattern is an enhanced base wavy pattern based on a leading edge nominal air streamline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the enhanced base wavy pattern comprises seven discrete segments including the first segment, each segment of the seven discrete segments being disposed with respect to the leading edge nominal air streamline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the leading edge nominal air streamline by a first fraction of the predetermined fin pitch and at least one other segment of the seven discrete segments is disposed at an offset from the leading edge nominal air streamline by a second fraction of the predetermined fin pitch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment is disposed substantially on the leading edge nominal air streamline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The fin plate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first segment of the predetermined pattern extends continuously in a direction substantially parallel to a corresponding row of tubes.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030000686A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
