<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000211A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000211A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000211A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000211A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000211A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000211A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000211</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10188262</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0102338-1</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>SE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F02D023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>060</class>
<subclass>602000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for driving an internal-combustion engine and an internal-combustion engine</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hans</given-name>
<family-name>Drangel</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Stockholm</city>
<country-code>SE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hans</given-name>
<family-name>Karlsson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Jarfalla</city>
<country-code>SE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Anders</given-name>
<family-name>Larsen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nykvarn</city>
<country-code>SE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Henrik</given-name>
<family-name>Nordin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sundsvall</city>
<country-code>SE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Saab Automobile AB</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OSTROLENK FABER GERB &amp; SOFFEN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1180 AVENUE OF THE AMERICAS</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>100368403</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In an internal-combustion engine having an exhaust-gas driven supercharger (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) and having at least two exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2, 3</bold></highlight>) per cylinder, a first exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder is connected to a first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>), whilst a second exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder is connected to a second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). The two exhaust manifolds (<highlight><bold>4, 5</bold></highlight>) lead to at least one exhaust-gas turbine in at least one turbo compressor and the first exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) are arranged to be opened at all engine speeds, whilst the second exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) are arranged to be opened only at higher engine speeds. The first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) has a smaller flow area than the second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). By choosing which exhaust-gas valves are to be used, the size of the flow ducts between engine and exhaust-gas turbine can easily be suited to the size of the exhaust-gas flow which is available at the time. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates firstly to a method for driving an internal-combustion engine, according to the preamble of Patent claim 1, and secondly to an internal-combustion engine, according to the preamble of Patent claim 5. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">PRIOR ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In turbo engines having an exhaust-gas-driven turbo compressor, the performance of the engine is largely dependent on the working range of the turbo compressor. The exhaust-gas turbine of the turbo compressor and the exhaust-gas ducts leading thereto are usually dimensioned for the high exhaust-gas flows which are generated at high revs and high engine loads. This means, however, that at lower revs and with smaller exhaust-gas flows, exhaust-gas energy is lost en route to the exhaust-gas turbine, thereby impairing the effectiveness of the turbo compressor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In order to be able to achieve good performance of the turbo compressor at low revs, it is desirable to use a small turbine and small dimensions on the pipes thereto with a view to reducing energy losses. This creates disadvantages, however, in respect of high exhaust-gas flows, since the small dimensions result in a throttling of the exhaust-gas flow and high counter-pressure in the exhaust-gas pipe, with accompanying air-supply problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In four-cylinder turbo engines, in particular, it is known to use exhaust-gas turbines having dual, equal-sized inlets and to connect two cylinders to each inlet, the cylinders being connected in such a way that an intake cylinder is always separated from an exhaust-gas-delivery cylinder. In the case of a four-cylinder in-line engine, the two outer cylinders-are therefore normally connected to the same turbine inlet, whilst the two centremost cylinders are connected to another turbine inlet. In order to obtain the required adjustability, there is a waste gate valve disposed in each inlet, which adds to the complexity of the turbine. The two inlet ducts to the exhaust-gas turbine here have the same sizes, designed for a large exhaust-gas flow, with accompanying loss of efficiency at low revs and small exhaust-gas flows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the light of this, improved solutions are needed in terms of exhaust-gas delivery to the exhaust-gas turbine. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECT OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The object of the invention is to achieve an improved exhaust-gas delivery to the exhaust-gas turbine. Another object is to achieve a simple solution. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">ACCOUNT OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The object of the invention is achieved firstly by the use of a method for driving an internal-combustion engine, having special features according to Patent claim 1, and secondly by the use of an internal-combustion engine having special features according to Patent claim 5. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> By, in each cylinder, splitting the exhaust-gas delivery amongst valves which can be activated differently, it becomes possible, at low revs, to make all delivery to the exhaust-gas turbine occur via only one valve in the cylinders and via narrower pipes than at high revs, whilst at the same time using an exhaust-gas turbine of limited size. At high revs and large exhaust-gas flow, on the other hand, all exhaust-gas valves and larger ducts are used to drive a sufficiently large exhaust-gas turbine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The exhaust-gas turbine can expediently in this case have dual inlets, namely an inlet which is used at all revs and another inlet which is used as a supplement at high revs. Another possibility is to use two separate exhaust-gas turbines, namely a small one which is always connected and a larger one which is connected only at high revs and large exhaust-gas flows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> By thus controlling the exhaust-gas delivery as a function of the engine speed and size of the exhaust-gas flow, it becomes possible to use a size of exhaust-gas turbine and inlet ducts thereof which is better suited to the particular operating situation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Further special features and advantages in respect of solutions according to the invention can be seen from the description and other patent claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The invention is explained in greater detail below with reference to illustrative embodiments shown in the appended drawing.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the drawing: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an internal-combustion engine according to the invention provided with an exhaust-gas-driven supercharger, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> show a section through an embodiment of an exhaust-gas turbine in various working positions, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a section through another embodiment of an exhaust-gas turbine, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a variant of the supercharger shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows in diagrammatic representation an Otto-type multi-cylinder internal-combustion engine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> realized according to the invention. The engine cylinders each have at least two exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, in which a first exhaust-gas valve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in each cylinder is connected to a first exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and in which a second exhaust-gas valve <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in each cylinder is connected to a second exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The two exhaust manifolds <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> emerge via respectively a first exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and a second exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> into a supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, by means of which charge air is fed to the engine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> via an air pipe <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in a known manner (not shown here in greater detail). The supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> driven by exhaust gases from the engine is provided with air via an inlet <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and has an exhaust-gas outlet <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> intended for the exhaust gases, whence the exhaust gases are led away from the engine in the conventional manner via a catalyser <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and other conventional components (not shown here in greater detail) in the engine&apos;s exhaust system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> can be realized in a number of different ways, some of which are described below. In the case of the realization shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is constituted by a single turbo compressor having an exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a compressor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> driven by the latter. The two exhaust-gas pipes <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> here emerge into one and the same exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The more detailed realization of such an exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can be seen from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A first inlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, into which the first exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> emerges, leads to a first duct <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from which exhaust gases can reach the turbine wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the exhaust-gas turbine in order to drive it. Correspondingly, a second inlet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, into which the second exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> emerges, leads to a second duct <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> from which exhaust gases can reach the turbine wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. For regulation of the exhaust-gas flow from the second duct <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the turbine wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, there is a valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, in which a tubular valve body <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is axially displaceable and can thereby alter the opening extent of the valve from a closed position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> to a fully open position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Radially within the valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> there is a waste gate valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, in which a tubular valve body <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is axially displaceable from a closed position represented by continuous lines to an open position represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> by dashed lines, in which a desired proportion of the exhaust gases can pass by the turbine wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> without driving it, thereby serving to regulate the compressor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> an exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is shown of a somewhat different realization than in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. As previously, there is a first inlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> connected to the first exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and a second inlet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> connected to the second exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A conventional-type waste gas valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is here placed in the second, larger inlet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and can be opened in order to reduce the exhaust-gas flow to the turbine wheel <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. This waste gate valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> might instead be placed in the first, smaller inlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> or such a waste gate valve can also be present in each of the two inlets <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The engine <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> functions as follows. The first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are arranged to be constantly in operation, whereas the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are arranged to operate only at high revs and at large exhaust-gas flows. This is achieved by the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> being driven by means of a mechanism in which the valves can be activated and deactivated as desired. A large number of such mechanisms are now commercially available to the person skilled in the art, and therefore a more detailed description of a realization is not provided in this connection. At low revs and small exhaust-gas flows, only the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are therefore operative. In order to limit energy losses in the exhaust gases delivered via the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the pipe dimensions from these valves and up to and into the exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> via its first inlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are relatively small. Once the engine speed and the load have risen to a predefined level, the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the valve <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are also activated in order to provide the exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with more exhaust gases. In order to handle this increased exhaust-gas flow, the pipe dimensions from the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> up to and into the exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> via its second inlet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can be larger than from the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. When required, the charge pressure of the compressor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be adjusted by manoeuvring the waste gate valve <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and thereby causing a desired quantity of exhaust gases to be led past the gas turbine without driving it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The adjustability of the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> also makes it possible to have for these valves a different length of opening than for the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. By causing the second exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to have a longer, and possibly larger retained opening than the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a very effective exhaust-gas delivery at high load and high revs is made possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A variant of a supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The first exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is here connected to a dedicated turbo compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and also the second exhaust-gas pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to a dedicated turbo compressor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, which can be larger than the turbo compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> so as to be able to handle larger exhaust-gas flows. From an exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> in the first turbo compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and an exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the second turbo compressor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the exhaust gases are delivered to the exhaust-gas outlet <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Similarly, air is fed from compressors <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, in which the latter can be larger than the former, to the air pipe <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and from there to the engine. The two turbo compressors <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are here expediently of standard realization, but as has been made clear, possibly of different sizes. The one or both can in a conventional manner have a waste gate valve for regulating the charge pressure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> When a supercharger <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the type shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and in which the exhaust-gas turbine <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> thus has dual inlets is combined with a four-cylinder engine, it becomes possible to utilize the special characteristics of such an engine in order to obtain an advantageous blow-cleaning of the cylinders at low revs and high load. This is achieved by making also the first exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> capable of being activated and deactivated and by, at low revs, causing the two outer cylinders to be connected via their respective first exhaust-gas valve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the first inlet <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, whilst the two middle cylinders are instead connected to the second inlet <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through the closure of the first exhaust-gas valve <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in these cylinders and the opening of the second exhaust-gas valve <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In the event of a change to other operating conditions, the retained opening of the exhaust-gas valves <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the two middle cylinders can subsequently be altered so that it becomes the same as for the two outer cylinders. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As a result of the ability to activate and deactivate different exhaust-gas valves in different ways, the operating conditions for an engine can thus be influenced in a wide variety of ways, according to requirement and wishes. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Method for driving a multi-cylinder internal-combustion engine having an exhaust-gas driven supercharger (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) and having at least two exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) per cylinder, in which exhaust gases are delivered, on the one hand, to a first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) via a first exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder and, on the other hand, to a second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) via a second exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder, characterized in that at low revs only the first exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) are opened, whilst at high revs both the first (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and the second (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) exhaust-gas valves are opened, and in that the exhaust gases are led to at least one exhaust-gas turbine in at least one turbo compressor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that exhaust gases from the first (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the second (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) exhaust manifold are led to different inlets (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) in the same exhaust-gas turbine (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that exhaust gases from the first (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the second (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) exhaust manifold are led to two different exhaust-gas turbines (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) in two different turbo compressors (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Method according to any of claims <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, characterized in that a larger exhaust-gas flow is led through the second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) than through the first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine having an exhaust-gas driven supercharger (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) and having at least two exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) per cylinder, a first exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder being connected to a first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and a second exhaust-gas valve (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) in each cylinder being connected to a second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>), characterized in that the exhaust manifolds (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) are connected to at least one exhaust-gas turbine in at least one turbo compressor and in that the first exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) are arranged to be opened at all engine speeds, whilst the second exhaust-gas valves (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) are arranged to be opened only at higher engine speeds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the second exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) has a larger cross-sectional area than the first exhaust manifold (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) for a larger exhaust-gas flow than the first exhaust manifold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the first (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the second (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) exhaust manifold feed their respective exhaust-gas turbine (<highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) in two separate turbo compressors (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the first (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and the second (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) exhaust manifold are connected to the same exhaust-gas turbine (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) via their respective inlet (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) in this. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that in at least one of the inlets (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) there is a waste gate valve (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) for adjusting the exhaust-gas flow to a turbine wheel (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Internal-combustion engine according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that next to the turbine wheel (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) there is a waste gate valve (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) which is common to two ducts (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) connected to the two inlets (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>).</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000211A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000211A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000211A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
