<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000302A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000302A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000302</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10234748</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020903</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01L005/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>073</class>
<subclass>159000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for testing of sheet material</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10234748</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020903</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09812741</doc-number>
<document-date>20010320</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6443002</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09812741</doc-number>
<document-date>20010320</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09316677</doc-number>
<document-date>19990521</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6202482</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09316677</doc-number>
<document-date>19990521</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09274487</doc-number>
<document-date>19990323</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6205852</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60079058</doc-number>
<document-date>19980323</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Austin</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Blew</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lehighton</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alexander</given-name>
<family-name>Eidukonis</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Stroudsburg</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>DUANE MORRIS, LLP</name-1>
<name-2>ATTN: WILLIAM H. MURRAY</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE LIBERTY PLACE</address-1>
<address-2>1650 MARKET STREET</address-2>
<city>PHILADELPHIA</city>
<state>PA</state>
<postalcode>19103-7396</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus for testing of electrical, mechanical, physical and/or chemical properties of material in sheet form includes a cassette for holding of sheets and sensors rigidly mounted relative to the cassette. The sensors may be mounted adjacent a test location exterior to the cassette. The cassette and the sensors may be so configured and positioned that a suitable end effector may move sheets of material between storage locations in the cassette and test locations adjacent the sensors. A method for testing sheet material includes the steps of placing the sheet material in a cassette, and conducting tests employing one or more sensors rigidly mounted with respect to the cassette. The method may include employing an end effector to remove the sheet from the cassette, to position the sheet stepwise in several positions relative to the sensors, and to replace the sheet in the cassette upon completion of testing. Materials to be tested include flat panels for computer screens and other applications and semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/274,487, filed Mar. 23, 1999, which claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/079,058, filed Mar. 23, 1998, which application is incorporated by reference herein.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This application relates to the field of testing of sheet materials, and in particular testing of thin glass sheets, such as glass sheets for use in computer flat panel displays, or for semiconductor wafers. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Glass sheets or panels are conventionally maintained, after fabrication of the glass sheets, and before assembly into products, such as flat panel displays, in cassettes. Similarly, semiconductor wafers are placed in cassettes. Cassettes are essentially boxes sized to accommodate sheets or cassettes of a selected size. In one existing design of cassettes, there are provided projecting inward from the sides of the cassette panel supports. A defined distance separates the panel supports. The defined distance is selected to permit an end effector of a robot to pass between the panel supports, so as to remove or insert the panel in the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> After fabrication, and after various steps during processing, panels, semiconductor wafers, and other materials in sheet form, are tested for a variety of physical, electrical, mechanical and chemical properties. Typically, upon fabrication, the panels or wafers are placed in the cassette by a robot with an end effector that engages the panel or wafer in such a manner as to minimize damage. When it is desired to test the panel or wafer, an end effector of a robot is inserted into the cassette, engages the panel or wafer, and transports the panel or wafer from the cassette to a testing device. The robot then places the panel or wafer on suitable supports on the testing device. A handler in the testing device moves the panel or wafer relative to test heads that carry out various tests on the panel or wafer. Upon completion of testing, the robot again engages the panel or wafer and removes the panel or wafer from the test equipment and returns it to the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This presents several difficulties. Testing time includes time to remove the panel from the cassette and transport it to the test device, and the time required to remove the panel from the test device and return it to the cassette. Each time the panel or wafer is engaged or disengaged by handling equipment, such as the robot end effector or the handler of the test device, there is a risk of damage. The time required to position the sample or sheet before measurement or testing and replace the sample after measurement or testing is increased by the need to have several devices successively engage and release the wafer or panel. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS AND ADVANTAGES OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the invention to provide a method and apparatus for testing of physical, chemical, electrical and mechanical properties of material in sheet form, such as panels and wafers, that reduces the process time associated with testing the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is a further object of the invention to provide a method and apparatus for testing of material in sheet form that reduces the risk of damage associated with testing of the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is an advantage of the invention that the foregoing objects are achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will become evident from a review of the detailed description which follows. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> An apparatus for testing of material in sheet form includes a cassette adapted to store one or more sheets of material and one or more sensors rigidly mounted with respect to the cassette. The sensors may be mounted adjacent a test location exterior to the cassette. The cassette and the sensors may be so configured and positioned that a suitable end effector may move sheets of material between storage locations in the cassette and test locations adjacent the sensors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A method for testing sheet material includes the steps of placing the sheet material in a cassette, and conducting tests employing one or more sensors rigidly mounted with respect to the cassette. The method may include employing an end effector to remove the sheet from the cassette, to position the sheet stepwise in several positions relative to the sensors, and to replace the sheet in the cassette upon completion of testing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> An apparatus for testing of material in sheet form includes sensors that can be positioned adjacent to a surface of material in sheet form located in a cassette and supports positioned to reduce sag of the material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A method for testing sheet material includes the steps of placing the sheet material in a cassette, and testing the sheet material while in the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A cassette according to the invention includes shelves having defined therein test heads for testing properties of material in sheet form.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic drawing of an apparatus of the invention positioned relative to an exemplary cassette with an exemplary panel in the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partial sectional view along line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of an apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic representation of an alternative embodiment of an apparatus of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a partial plan view of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic representation of an alternative embodiment of an apparatus of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a substrate of the invention of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the substrate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a top view of an alternative embodiment of the substrate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a bottom plan view of the substrate of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a plan view of an alternative design of the upper surface of a substrate of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic representation of an alternative embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a top plan view of an alternative embodiment of a cassette shelf arrangement according to the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a partial front cross-sectional view of the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown an apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the invention. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is an end effector of a robot arm. More broadly, apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a movable unit. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is generally a flattened end effector, relatively thin in height compared to length and width. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is relatively thin in height in this embodiment to permit apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to fit beneath a panel or wafer to be tested and over a lower panel or wafer supported in the cassette with adequate clearance. The height of apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is dictated principally by the need to clear the next lower panel or wafer in the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has three projecting fingers <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Each finger <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> has a sensor or test head <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The number of fingers <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may be varied as desired depending on the test pattern to be achieved. Each sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is suitable for positioning adjacent to a panel or wafer positioned in a cassette. Sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be any one of numerous types of known compact test heads for testing properties of sheet materials. A wide variety of physical, chemical, mechanical and electrical properties of materials may be tested by use of suitable test heads. For example, the test heads may provide for eddy current sheet resistance testing. Photoreflectance testing may be provided. If photoreflectance testing is provided, then optical fibers are provided to the test heads. Suitable circuitry and wiring are provided in the body of apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to permit communication between sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and controllers and data storage and read out devices. Communication may include control signals sent to sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and data signals received from sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Three sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are shown merely as examples. The number of sensors may be selected as desired, depending on the number of locations to be tested at any one time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As an alternative, pairs of coplanar sensors and detectors for eddy current detection may be provided in place of each individual sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Disposed on opposite sides of sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> for engaging a sheet of material. Devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may be small vacuum heads, or vacuum hold downs, as are well known in the art. Devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> serve to prevent relative movement between the panel and sensor <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> while testing is carried out. Air lines (not shown) are provided between vacuum heads <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and electrically controlled valves (not shown). Device <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may also support the panel. As there may be sag in the panel, which is otherwise supported only by the panel supports, devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may serve to reduce sag. This may also serve to reduce stresses in the panel that result from sag. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> also shows a cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having panel or sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> therein. Cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is generally a box, having a planar horizontal bottom, planar vertical parallel sides, a planar horizontal top, and a planar back wall. A front opening is provided opposite the back wall. The term cassette as used herein includes any container for retaining and protecting multiple sheets of material, such as panels or wafers. Panel supports <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> project inward from the two side walls. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows only one set of panel supports <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. For convenience of viewing panel supports <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are shown through panel <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has numerous such supports. Numerous panels are supported in a horizontal position in cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In a method according to the invention, apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted on a robot arm. By robot arm, any device capable of supporting and precisely moving and locating apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is meant. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned relative to a sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Initially, apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned so that testing may be conducted on sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> at the set of locations closest to the opening of the cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, i.e., at locations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Preferably, apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is moved into position beneath sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and then moved upward to contact sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and then moved upward slightly further a distance sufficient to significantly reduce sag in sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. This last step may involve movement upward of about 5 mils, although the precise distance may vary depending on the distance between sheets and the susceptibility of the particular material and thickness to sag. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> remains with sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at locations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> holding sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, to prevent relative movement of sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. After the test is completed, devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> release sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is moved to the next selected set of locations. The process is repeated. Devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> engage sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> carry out testing on sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> at locations <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Devices <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> disengage sheet <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and the process is repeated until all desired locations are tested. Of course, the order of testing of various locations on the sheet may be varied. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> must be sufficiently long to permit sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to contact the desired test location closest to the back wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Fingers <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are shown to provide a certain amount of independent vertical positioning for the three sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be constructed without fingers, and all sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> supported on a single surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The number and relative location of sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be selected as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In summary, in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, there is provided a robot end effector <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having one or more sensors <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or test devices thereon. The end effector <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is dimensioned to fit between sheets of material <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> in a cassette <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for holding numerous flat sheets of material. The end effector&apos;s length is sufficient to provide testing over all or a substantial portion of a sheet fully inserted in the cassette without moving the sheet. Multiple sensors may be provided on the end effector, and devices may be provided to engage the sheet to prevent relative movement of sensors and sheet during testing. The end effector is dimensioned to fit between panel supports projecting from opposite sidewalls of the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In a method of the invention in accordance with the foregoing, an end effector with one or more sensors mounted thereon is inserted in a cassette holding sheets of material, and is moved relative to one of the sheets so that the sensor can test the material at selected locations on many points on the surface of the sheet. This process may be repeated for all sheets in the cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Such an effector may be provided, for example, on a Gencobot 7 or 8 GPR robot, available from Genmark. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, there is shown an alternative end effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> according to the invention. End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> in proximity to cassette <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> which has an exemplary flat panel <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> to be tested located therein and supported on supports <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has an array of sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may be any suitable sensor or test head, as discussed above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are arranged linearly on each finger <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. Vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are provided adjacent to sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Sensors are multiplexed to external control electronics and electronics for detecting and storing readings from sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In operation, end effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is brought into contact with the sheet material by movement of a robot arm (not shown). End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is so positioned relative to the sheet material that sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are positioned adjacent to a substantial portion of the surface of the sheet material. As a result, in a single positioning, sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may conduct appropriate tests on the sheet material. Preferably, end effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is moved vertically to engage the lower surface of the sheet material and move the sheet material slightly upward to reduce, and preferably to eliminate, sag in the sheet material. For example, end effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> may be moved upward about 5 mils after engaging the lower surface of the sheet material. Sag in the sheet material during testing is undesirable as such sag results in anomalous results in various tests. After the vertical movement, the vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are engaged to maintain each sensor <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> stationary relative to the surface of the sheet material. The sensors <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> are then maintained in such proximity to test sites <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> to permit testing. The tests are then carried out. With multiplexing of the sensors, the tests are not necessarily carried out simultaneously, but in series along each finger of end effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Upon completion of the tests, the vacuum is released. End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is moved vertically downward until it is no longer in contact with the sheet material. End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is then moved outward from the opening of cassette <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. End effector <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is then positioned appropriately relative to the next sheet to be tested in cassette <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, and the tests are conducted. The absence of a need for movement of the end effector during testing of a sheet improves throughput and reduces the risk of damage to the surface of the sheet material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5, 6</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, there is shown an alternative embodiment of an apparatus of the invention for in-cassette testing of sheet material. There is shown a cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> according to the invention. Cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is essentially a rectangular box with an open front and walls on its other five sides. The walls may be made from conventionally used materials, for cassettes for use in storage of flat panels and wafers, such as metal or ceramics. Cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> has a plurality of sheet shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> for testing of sheet material. Each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is a planar sheet of a rigid, non-contaminating material. For example, shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be made of one of various ceramics. Shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be of metal, such as aluminum; suitable insulation may be provided between the aluminum of the shelf and the conductors. It may be desirable to use heavier conductors than laminated copper for better shielding; if insulated wires are used, the conductive nature of the aluminum is less of a disadvantage. Each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is rigidly supported on side walls of cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be bonded to the side walls with an adhesive, be supported on projecting wires attached to the side walls, or otherwise be securely and rigidly supported. Each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> has a plurality of test heads or sensors <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> formed therein in an array. The array is preferably selected to be of a size relative to the surface of material to be tested to permit conducting of tests on test points including a substantial portion of the surface of the material. Sensors <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are preferably recessed at the level of the upper, planar surface of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Sensors <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are arranged in several lines, although the patterns of sensor locations may be varied. Vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> are provided in pairs adjacent each sensor <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Vacuum hold downs may be provided in smaller or larger numbers or in different locations as desired. Vacuum hold downs may be in the form of recesses or wells in the body of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, which wells are in physical communication with a tube. Each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> preferably has defined therein one or more cutouts or recesses <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> intermediate rows of sensors <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Recesses <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> are defined to reduce the area of contact between shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and the sheet material. Recesses <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> also reduce the weight of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, particularly intermediate the walls of cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. This reduction in weight tends to reduce sag of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Exemplary wiring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> is shown on the surface of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Wiring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> may be placed on the lower surface of shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, or interior to shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as desired. In fact, each sensor <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may have control and readout lines associated therewith. Exemplary circuit boards <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight>, on which appropriate control and memory electronics may be mounted, are shown immediately below each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. The appropriate functionality to provide control and memory for test data for the sensors may be physically located elsewhere on the cassette, such as on an outer surface of a cassette wall. Alternatively, wiring <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> of shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be electrically connected during testing to electronics mounted externally to cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Suitable connectors may be provided on each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> for rapid connection and removal of connecting wiring. By employing externally mounted electronics, additional space is provided within cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Rather than providing a single board <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> corresponding to each shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, two or more shelves <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be multiplexed to a single board. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As many of the test devices or sensors provide analog data, the boards may include analog-to-digital converters to facilitate the exchange of information with digital devices. Alternatively, the boards may have solely analog electronics. The use of analog devices will reduce the complexity of the boards, although analog-to-digital converters will be required remotely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> If photoreflectance testing is to be provided, in place of wiring to the sensors, optical fibers may be provided. A pair, one for emission of radiation and one for detection of reflected radiation, may be provided at each test head. The optical fibers are preferably placed on the lower surface of the shelf or in cavities defined interior to the shelf. Optical emitters and detectors may be provided on the shelf itself, on an associated board, or remotely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Vacuum hold downs have tubes or pipes leading thereto from electrically operated valves, which in turn are connected to a pump, vacuum manifold or the like. All hold downs on the surface of a shelf are preferably in physical communication with a single valve, so that all vacuum hold downs on a surface engage and disengage the sheet material simultaneously. The valves may be mounted on the cassette, or may be external. Appropriate couplings are provided for tubes or pipes leading from the vacuum hold downs. Couplings for vacuum lines may be provided to permit quick connection and release. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In an apparatus as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the sheet of material is placed in cassette <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> by a suitable robot end effector. The sheet is placed on the surface of the ceramic shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> to provide contact with the vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. If external electronics must be connected with the sheet, the connections are made. The vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, as a result of a valve opening in response to a suitable signal from control board or from external electronics, engage the sheet. The test is then carried out. During the testing, the test heads <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are caused to emit suitable signals by control board <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight> or external electronics, and to sense resulting fields, in accordance with well-known techniques. Upon completion of the testing, any electrical connections can be removed. The sheets remain in the cassette, and the cassette can be transported to the location for the next processing step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, there is shown an alternative embodiment of the shelf shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5, 6</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Shelf <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> is configured for conducting tests that require sensor or emitter devices on opposing sides of a panel or wafer. Shelf <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>, as with shelf <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, includes sensors or test heads <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, and vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> located in recesses in the upper surface of the shelf, and recesses <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, the lower surface of shelf <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> includes test heads or sensors <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> disposed in recesses formed in the lower surface. Test heads <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> are aligned with test heads <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. Suitably designed test heads <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> on a first shelf and test heads <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> on a second shelf may be inductively coupled through a sheet or wafer to test various properties, in accordance with well-known techniques. Test heads <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> and test heads <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> may be designed in other manners to cooperate to achieve testing of various properties. For example, test head <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> may emit radiation, and test head <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> may detect radiation emitted by test head <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, or radiation emitted by the material as a result of exposure to radiation emitted by test head <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. Existing equipment designs need simply be miniaturized appropriately to fit in the recesses defined in the surface of shelf <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. The design of FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be readily incorporated in a cassette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Also shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference> are lines or tubes <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> running to vacuum devices or hold downs. These lines <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> all physically communicate to a single source. Lines <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> do not block sensors <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight>. As noted above, a single valve may control communication with a vacuum manifold or pump. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown in plan view an alternative embodiment of a shelf according to the invention. In this alternative embodiment, each test point <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> on shelf <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> includes two sensors <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> that are positioned in sufficiently close physical proximity to one another to cooperate in testing materials. For example, both test devices <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> may be coils that may be inductively coupled to each other. Such inductive coupling permits measurement of various properties. Exemplary wiring <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> is shown. Each test point <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> also includes pairs of vacuum hold downs or vacuum devices <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, there is shown in a somewhat schematic isometric view a combined cassette and test location unit <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. Cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> is a conventional cassette, in the form of a rectangular box with side walls <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> having sheet supports <highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> projecting horizontally inward therefrom. Front opening <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is defined in cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. Sheet supports <highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight> are so positioned to permit a suitable end effector to fit between vertically adjacent sheets and between the sheet supports <highlight><bold>515</bold></highlight>. Rigidly attached to the lower wall of cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> is testing location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>. Testing location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> is also in the form of a rectangular box with a front opening. Testing location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> includes test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, which are represented schematically. Test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> are preferably contactless sensors for testing physical, mechanical, chemical or electrical properties of sheets placed in test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>. Such test heads are known in the art. For example, test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> may be sheet resistance sensors, which are positioned in vertically aligned pairs at the front opening of test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>. Suitable electrical connections to controllers and to data recording software and hardware are provided in accordance with well-known techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Also along the front opening of test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>, intermediate test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, there are provided vacuum chucks or vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight>. Vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> are positioned to engage sheets and hold the sheets motionless relative to test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> during each testing step. Vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> also minimize sag of the sheets during testing. Suitable vacuum lines are provided in accordance with well-known techniques. Inward of front opening of test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> there are located substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>. The substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> are elevated to support sheets when those sheets are placed in contact with vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight>. The substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> are also sufficiently elevated above the floor of test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> to provide clearance for a suitable end effector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Representative end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> is schematically shown adjacent test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>. End effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> has two fingers <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>. Fingers <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> are so positioned and dimensioned, and test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight>, and substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> are all so positioned and dimensioned to permit fingers <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> to position a sheet on substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> and vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> in a position for testing by test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In a method of testing sheet materials using unit <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight>, or another robot end effector, is employed to load sheets into cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. End effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> then is inserted into cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>, removes a sheet, and moves the sheet into test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight>. When a desired position of the sheet in the horizontal plane relative to test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> is reached, end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> moves downward to cause the sheet to be supported on vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> and substrate supports <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>. If desired, the sheet can be supported on end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> as well. Vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> then engage the sheet, and testing is carried out by test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>. When testing is complete, vacuum chucks <highlight><bold>535</bold></highlight> disengage the sheet, and end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> engages the sheet again. If measurement at additional locations is desired, end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> moves in a suitable direction until the sheet is positioned properly relative to test heads <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, and the above process is repeated. This process is repeated at as many locations as desired. When the testing is complete, end effector <highlight><bold>545</bold></highlight> removes the sheet from test location <highlight><bold>525</bold></highlight> and returns the sheet to a storage location in cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. This process may be repeated for each sheet in cassette <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The upper set of sensors may be mounted on a vertically movable mount. The mount may be guided on a vertical track. The mount in this configuration is moved vertically by a stepper motor. This configuration is desirable if the amount of sag in the sheet before engagement by the vacuum chuck is greater than the desirable separation between upper and lower sensors. If this configuration is employed, the upper set of sensors is in an upper position when insertion of the sheet by the end effector commences. After insertion of the sheet and engagement by the vacuum chucks, the upper set of sensors is lowered to a lower position. In the lower position, the separation between upper and lower sensors is selected such that any effects of the separation are minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, it is also possible to mount sensors so that they are movable in a horizontal direction. As it is not necessarily possible to move the sheet laterally within the test area, lateral movement of sensors will permit additional portions of the sheet surface to be tested. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that the location of the sensors mounted relative to the cassette reduces the distance that sheets must be moved. Also, the use of the end effector, rather than a separate handler, at the test location, reduces the number of pieces of equipment involved and the number of items of equipment that must contact the sheet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, rather than a robot end effector, a handler positioned on an elevator may be employed to provide the required vertical and horizontal movement of the sheet into and out of the cassette, between the cassette and the test area, and to various positions within the test area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, there is provided a top view of an alternative shelf arrangement within a cassette. In this arrangement, there is provided a partial shelf <highlight><bold>605</bold></highlight> at only the opening of the cassette. The positions of sensors <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> and vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> are represented schematically. Suitable electrical connections for sensors <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> and air lines for vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> may be provided. Exemplary sheet supports <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> are also shown in the form of ledges protruding inward from the side and rear walls of the cassette. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a partial front cross-sectional view along line <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> shows corresponding upper sensors <highlight><bold>625</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, an end effector, engaging a sheet, moves the sheet to a desired location relative to sensors <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>625</bold></highlight>. Vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> engage the sheet, and appropriate testing is conducted. Vacuum hold downs <highlight><bold>615</bold></highlight> then release the sheet, and the end effector moves the sheet to a next desired location. The process is repeated until a desired number of measurements have been made. As the sensors and hold downs are located only at the front opening of the cassette in this embodiment, repair and maintenance are simplified. In this embodiment, single sensors may also be employed if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In the embodiments with the sensors in the substrate and in the end effector, either a coil cup, generally of metal foil, such as aluminum, may be used, or individual components may be separately fastened. A coil cup which supports all of the components is useful because it can be constructed so that each sensor may readily be mounted and removed for maintenance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> In any of the embodiments, it will be understood that heads which use microwave radiation to excite the carriers of electric current, induce localized heating, and utilize a thermographic imaging system to measure the physical, chemical, electrical and/or mechanical properties of the sample may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> It will be understood that testing is not confined to testing of wafers and panels merely after initial manufacture, but after any suitable stage in the process of manufacture of products incorporating wafers or panels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> It will be appreciated that the foregoing method and apparatus may be used in connection with testing any material in sheet form, and is not limited to use with the items, such as flat panels and semiconductor wafers, named as examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> While an apparatus and method of the invention have been described with reference to particular embodiments, it will be understood that additional variations are within the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Apparatus for testing of material in sheet form, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cassette adapted to store one or more sheets of material; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more sensors rigidly mounted with respect to said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cassette and said sensors are so configured and located that a suitable end effector may move sheets of material between test locations adjacent said sensors and storage locations in said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are adjacent a test location exterior to said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are mounted below a lower wall of said cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said test location comprises a defined space for receiving a sheet supported on an end effector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein one or more vacuum hold downs are provided adjacent said test location. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Method for testing sheet material, comprising the steps of placing the sheet material in a cassette, and conducting tests employing one or more sensors mounted rigidly with respect to the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the steps of, after placing the sheet material in the cassette and before testing said material, removing the sheet material from the cassette, and placing the sheet material in a test location adjacent one or more sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step further comprises employing an end effector to remove the sheet from the cassette, to position the sheet relative to the test heads, and to replace the sheet in the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step further comprises using said end effector to move the sheet stepwise to a plurality of positions relative to said sensors so as to conduct tests at a plurality of points on the material surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of positioning further comprises engaging the sheet to be fixed relative to the sensors at each of said positions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein during said steps of removing, positioning and replacing, only the end effector moves the sheet. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Apparatus for testing of material in sheet form, comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of sensors adapted to be mounted adjacent to a surface of material in sheet form when the material is located in a cassette; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>supports positioned to reduce sag of the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are mounted on an end effector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are arranged in an array corresponding to a substantial portion of the surface of the material, whereby tests may be conducted on a selection of points covering a substantial portion of the surface of the material without movement of said sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are arranged substantially linearly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sensors are mounted on a substrate mounted in the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate comprises a sheet of rigid, electrically insulating material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate further comprises a vacuum hold down. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein sensors are mounted on upper and lower surfaces of said substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of test devices are mounted in sufficiently close proximity to one another to permit coupling between said test devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate is located only adjacent a front opening of the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Method for testing sheet material, comprising the steps of placing the sheet material in a cassette, and testing the sheet material while in the cassette. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step comprises moving a sensor mounted on an end effector into proximity with said sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step further comprises moving the sensor into proximity with said sheet material successively at two distinct locations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step comprises moving a plurality of sensors mounted on a robot end effector into proximity with said sheet material in a single instance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step comprises providing a plurality of sensors mounted on a substrate in proximity with said sheet material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said substrate comprises a sheet of rigid, electrically-insulating material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said testing step comprises providing a plurality of test devices mounted on a substrate in proximity with said sheet material and in such proximity with one another to permit coupling between said test devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Cassette for sheets of material, said cassette comprising shelves having generally planar upper surfaces, and sensors recessed in said upper surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Cassette of claim <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, wherein said shelves are of an electrically insulating material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Cassette of claim <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, wherein further sensors are mounted in a lower surface of at least one of said shelves.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000302A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
