<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000583A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000583A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000583</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10181645</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020718</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>100-58-515.9</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001124</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16K015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>137</class>
<subclass>536000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Pressure relief valve with a spring-loaded membrane closing body</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Kuhn</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Weinheim</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frank</given-name>
<family-name>Obrist</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Dornbirn</city>
<country-code>AU</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stefan</given-name>
<family-name>Kroess</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Dornbirn</city>
<country-code>AU</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Georg</given-name>
<family-name>Weber</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Offenbach</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Richard P Berg</name-1>
<name-2>Ladas &amp; Parry</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2100</address-1>
<address-2>5670 Wilshire Boulevard</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90036-5679</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/IB01/02158</doc-number>
<document-date>20011113</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The pressure relief valve has a spring pressure-loaded diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), which in the closed position sealingly engages on a centrally positioned valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) surrounding a first valve opening (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>). Its spring pressure loading takes place by means of a counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) positioned centrally over it. The valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) is surrounded by a channel-like valve chamber (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) in the valve housing body (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and on which is provided on the overpressure side at least one second valve opening (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). To be able to dissipate high overpressures, the counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) is surrounded by a diaphragm support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) held on the valve housing (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) and which has a circumferential recess (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), whose depth measured perpendicular to the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) determines the maximum deflection of said body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), so that when the valve is completely opened the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is supported in an area between the valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) and its outer edge. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a pressure relief valve with a spring pressure-loaded diaphragm closing body, which in the closed position sealingly engages on a centrally positioned valve seating surface surrounding a first valve opening and whose spring pressure loading determining the sealing pressure takes place by means of a counterpressure body centrally arranged in the vicinity of and over the valve seating surface, which is surrounded by a channel-like valve chamber covered by the diaphragm closing body and provided in the valve housing body and on which on the overpressure side is provided at least one second valve opening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A pressure relief valve of this type is known from U.S. Pat. No. 5,944,050. This valve is only suitable for relatively low pressures as a result of the nature of the arrangement or mounting of the diaphragm closing body. It also takes up a relatively large construction volume with a correspondingly high thermal inertia, which has a disadvantageous effect e.g. when used in CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>air conditioning systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,413,311 discloses a diaphragm valve, whose counterpressure body operated by a closing piston is surrounded by a ring, which engages on the diaphragm closing body, both in the closed and the opened valve position and by means of which said diaphragm closing body is fixed in the vicinity of its outer circumference. It also forms a stop for the maximum lifting motion of the counterpressure body. Said stop is positioned in such a way that with the valve opened to the maximum the diaphragm closing body has a planar configuration. Consequently when engaged on the valve seating surface it is downwardly outwardly curved in its central area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> FR-A-26 77 425 discloses a diaphragm closing valve, which is intended to have a maximum opening cross-section. For this purpose in the relieved state, the diaphragm closing body is upwardly and outwardly curved away from the plane of its peripheral fixing in plate-like or step-like manner. For closing purposes it is deformed by a closing piston counter to its spring tension in the direction of the valve seating surface. A downward displacement of the valve seating surface away from the fixing plane of the diaphragm closing member increases the spring elastic deformation of the diaphragm closing body necessary for closing purposes. A ring surrounding the closing piston serves both to fix the diaphragm edge and as a boundary casing for the diaphragm closing body, when the latter has its plate-like starting shape in the relieved state with the closing piston raised. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The problem of the invention is to provide a pressure relief valve of the aforementioned type which, in the case of an adequately large opening cross-section and without overloading its diaphragm closing body, is suitable for pressure differences of more than 150&prime; bar between its inflow and outflow sides. According to a preferred embodiment it has a low thermal inertia due to its particularly compact construction and despite the relatively large flow cross-section, so that it can be used with advantage, particularly in areas with pronounced temperature changes, such as e.g. during the cooling and heating operation of a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>air conditioning system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> According to the invention the problem is solved in that the counterpressure body placed over the valve seating surface or a counterpressure plate cooperating therewith is surrounded by a diaphragm support ring held on the valve housing and which extends radially outwards from the counterpressure body over the valve chamber to the outer edge of the diaphragm closing body and above the valve chamber has a circumferential recess, whose depth measured perpendicular to the diaphragm closing body determines the maximum deflection of the diaphragm closing body, so that when the valve is completely opened the diaphragm closing body is supported in an area between the valve seating surface and its outer edge.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the invention are described hereinafter relative to the attached drawings, wherein show: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> not true-to-scale cross-section through a pressure relief valve in the closed position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> second embodiment of a pressure relief valve according to the invention in cross-section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> larger scale detail of the cross-sectional representation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> in the vicinity of the diaphragm closing body when closed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> representation corresponding to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> with a diaphragm closing body, which is curved out and raised from the valve seat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> third embodiment of a pressure relief valve according to the invention in a larger scale cross-sectional representation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> fourth embodiment of a pressure relief valve according to the invention in a larger scale partial cross-section.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The pressure relief valve <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is particularly suitable for the high pressures of a CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>air conditioning system, preferably has a one-piece, compact housing body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with a base part <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> enclosing the connecting grooves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a cylindrical housing wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> connected thereto and which forms a cup-shaped housing area <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, into whose bottom issue a first and a second valve openings <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> of the connecting grooves <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> surrounding the first valve opening <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is outwardly surrounded by a flat valve chamber <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> shaped in channel-like manner into said bottom and which extends outwards to a clamp fit surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which is intended for retaining and sealing the circumferential area of a diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed by at least one planar, preferably metallic diaphragm, which in the closed position rests on a planar valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is maintained there in the closed position by a counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> transferring the closing force of at least one spring element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As a result of the planar-surface sealing contact between the preferably finely ground valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the metallic diaphragm of the closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, associated with the pressure acting in this area through the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, a sealing effect counteracting high pressures and thermal stresses is obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In order to be able to absorb the force suddenly acting on the entire free diaphragm surface and prevent an excessive deformation of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at the time of the opening of the valve under a high overpressure and a corresponding falling back of the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, said body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is supported by the support edge <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of a flat support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> above the channel-like, circumferential valve chamber <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and opposite the second valve opening <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in a radially closely defined area. When the valve is closed, said support edge <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is spaced from the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, so that it only becomes active during the opening movement thereof. It allows the multiple curvature of the diaphragm closing body in its position raised from the valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> preventing local overstressing and illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> With an outer, flat clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> also serves as a clamping ring for retaining the edge of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Between its clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and its support edge <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> consequently has a recess <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> defining said edges <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Starting from the position according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the closing body diaphragm <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can deform into the recess <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, as illustrated by the larger scale representation of the opened valve in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> For the sealing pressing of the support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> with its clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> against the diaphragm edge there is a screw ring <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having an external thread and which engages with an internal thread <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> on the housing wall <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The spring pressure loading of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> via the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> takes place both as a result of its spring characteristic and as a result of the limited installation height thereof, preferably through disk springs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which, in the embodiment according to FIG. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, surround the shaft <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and are fixed between a step of the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and a threaded ring <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> screwed into the housing area <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The transfer of the spring tension from the spring-loaded counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> preferably takes place by means of a counterpressure plate <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> engaging on the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. For a uniform pressing of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> against the valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> contact between the counterpressure plate <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> takes place by means of a curved surface provided on at least one of the two and whose centre of curvature is in the axis of the first valve opening <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is a spherically curved end face <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in pressure-transferring contact with a planar counterpressure plate <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> engaging on the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. However, in the embodiments of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> a counterpressure member <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> guided in the support ring <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is provided at its upper end with a convex, circular symmetrical curvature <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, which is received in a correspondingly curved, concave recess. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> only comprises a counterpressure plate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and two equidirectionally arranged disk springs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are located in a recess <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of a screw body <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> determining the spring pretension. The substantially radially directed inner surface <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of the recess <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is inclined away from the disk springs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, so that the latter can spring from the position corresponding to the valve closing position away from the counterpressure body <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The pressure action of the counterpressure body takes place by means of the inner edge of the disk springs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> engaging thereon. The screw body <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> tensioning the disk springs <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is screwed into the screw ring <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> holding the support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in order to limit the valve height. The minimum height of the counterpressure member <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> projecting only slightly over the support ring <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> contributes to the flat construction of the valve according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> show pressure relief valves according to the invention with measures to avoid tensile stresses in the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> as a result of an inflexible clamping fit on the clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and which leads to a change in the valve response pressure. Such stresses arise because the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is extracted somewhat from its clamping fit on the clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> through its bending out during the first valve opening and due to the frictional forces in the clamping fit cannot completely slide back during the following closing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a first measure for avoiding tensile stresses in the diaphragm closing body and in accordance with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, in the vicinity of the outer diaphragm circumference or the clamping fit surface <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is provided an elastic sealing ring <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> e.g. in the form of an O-ring and which is enclosed in a circumferential slot <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the housing body <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and which engages under pretension on the diaphragm closing body. Such a sealing of the diaphragm closing body makes it possible to considerably reduce the clamping force on the clamping edge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, so that on opening and closing the valve the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can perform an adequate sliding movement in the area of its marginal seal to prevent permanent tensile stresses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As a second, e.g. additional measure for avoiding tensile stresses in the diaphragm closing body, in the embodiment according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> in the latter is provided a circularly circumferential, channel-like bulge <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The valve chamber <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> passing beneath the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> provides a free space for the positioning of such a bulge <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. In place of a channel-like bulge <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> can have a circumferential step in a not shown manner. However, such a step in the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> would prevent the placing of the peripheral clamping fit surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in the same plane as the valve seating surface <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Such circumferential bulges <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> or steps are able to elastically absorb the tensile force resulting from the opening movement of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and arising in the plane thereof, so that an extraction of the diaphragm closing body <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> from its peripheral clamping fit on the clamping fit surface <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is prevented. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve with a spring pressure-loaded diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), which in the closed position sealingly engages on a centrally positioned valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) surrounding a first valve opening (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) and whose spring pressure loading determining the sealing pressure takes place by means of a counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) centrally arranged in the vicinity of and over the valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>), which is surrounded by a channel-like valve chamber (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) covered by the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and provided in the valve housing body (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and on which on the overpressure side is provided at least one second valve opening (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>), characterized in that the counterpressure body placed over the valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) or a counterpressure plate (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) cooperating therewith is surrounded by a diaphragm support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) held on the valve housing (<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) and which extends radially outwards from the counterpressure body (150 over the valve chamber (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) to the outer edge of the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and above the valve chamber (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) has a circumferential recess (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), whose depth measured perpendicular to the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) determines the maximum deflection of the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>), so that when the valve is completely opened the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is supported in an area between the valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) and its outer edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the recess (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) is bounded radially inwards by a downwardly projecting support edge (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is relieved in the closed position and planar and the valve seating surface (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) extends parallel to the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) in the closed position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, characterized in that a counterpressure plate (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) is located between the counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) and the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and the contact between the counterpressure plate (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) and the counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) takes place by means of a circular symmetrical, curved surface (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>) provided on at least one of these and whose centre of curvature is in the axis of the first valve opening (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that on its outer circumference the support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) has a clamping edge (<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>) for the sealing, clamping retention of the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) on a circumferential surface of the housing body (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), the support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>) being kept under pretension by a tensioning element (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) acting towards a clamping fit surface (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the valve chamber (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) is radially outwardly sealed by a sealing ring (<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>), engaging on the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and located in a circumferential slot (<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>) of the housing body (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), so that during the opening or closing movement of the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) the latter performs a compensating movement in its plane in the area of its marginal seal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that in the vicinity of the valve chamber (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), the diaphragm closing body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) has at least one channel-like, circumferential bulge (<highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>) or a step. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claims 1</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">7</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the spring pressure loading of the counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) is provided by at least one disk spring (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that there are one or two equidirectionally engaging disk springs (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>), whose surface is inclined towards the first valve opening (<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) with the valve closed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the counterpressure body (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is in the form of a plate (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) enclosed in the support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claims 8</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00010">10</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the disk springs (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) are located in a recess (<highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) of a screw body (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) determining the spring pretension. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Pressure relief valve according to one of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claims 8</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">11</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the screw body (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) tensioning the disk springs (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is screwed into the screw ring (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) retaining the support ring (<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>).</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000583A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
