<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.NB SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.NB SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.NB SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002424A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002424A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002424</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09885067</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010621</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B007/135</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>369</class>
<subclass>103000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Cylindrical medium for storing holographic data and methods and apparatus for manipulating data using the cylindrical medium</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Doyle</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Temple</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hampton</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hampton University</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Hampton</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MILLEN, WHITE, ZELANO &amp; BRANIGAN, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2200 CLARENDON BLVD.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 1400</address-2>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22201</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Holographic data is stored in a cylindrical crystal by directing a signal beam with data encoded therewith axially through an end face of the crystal, which signal beam interferes with a reference beam directed radially through the cylindrical side surface of the crystal. By rotating the crystal about its axis, numerous holograms are recorded therein an annular layer and by indexing the crystal axially the annular layers are stacked to further increase the storage capacity of the crystal. The holograms are read from the crystal by focusing a reference beam therethrough in a radial director for diffraction with the stored holograms to produce a defracted reference beam which emerges axially from the crystal. The diffracted reference beam is then read with a detector in the form of a CCD camera. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a cylindrical medium for storing holographic data and to methods of and apparatus for manipulating data using the medium. More particularly, the present invention is directed to a cylindrical storage medium in which rotation of the medium and apparatus, one with respect to the other, provides a method of manipulating holographic data. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> There is a constant demand to increase the storage capacity of data systems. As has been set forth in U.S. Pat. No. 6,101,161 issued Aug. 8, 2001, this is especially the case for storing large amounts of data such as, for example, the data required for motion picture images. There are of course a meriad of other needs for data storage, such as storage for library text and other massive amounts of information, which information can for example relate to anything from scientific data to financial data. In the &apos;161 patent, a cylindrical storage medium is indexed rotationally to store holographic image data in the form of pixel arrays generated from a spacial light modulator system (SLM). Multiple holograms are stored in the cylindrical crystal using angular multiplexing by rotating the crystal about its z-axis. Attempts to successfully store and retrieve data from systems such as that of the &apos;161 patent have proved illusive. A primary reason for this is the complicated cylindrical optics for imagery into and out of the cylinder. Another reason for this difficulty is that extraordinarily polarized laser beams appear to be necessary to store holographic gratings in the x,y, plane of cylindrical crystals </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In addition, prior art approaches do not identify a range of angles for angularly positioning each hologram in a cylindrical crystal. Moreover, the prior art does not teach or suggest that a cylindrical crystal may be moved axially in the direction of its c-axis to record holograms at different axial locations in the cylindrical crystal so as to vastly increase the storage capacity of a single cylindrical crystal. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In view of the aforementioned considerations, the present invention is directed to a cylindrical crystal formed around an axis wherein the cylindrical crystal has holograms stored in annular arrays therein about the axis thereof, with the annular arrays being stacked in an axial direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention is also directed to a method of storing holographic data in a cylindrical crystal wherein the cylindrical crystal is formed about an axis and has an axially facing surface and a cylindrical peripherial surface. In accordance with the method, a reference beam is focused through one of the surfaces and a signal beam containing the data to be stored is focused through the other of the surfaces. The signal and reference beams interfere within the crystal to form a hologram therein containing the data. The method further includes rotating the crystal about the axis to form additional angularly spaced holograms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In addition, the method includes translating the cylindrical crystal axially to store additional layers of angularly spaced holograms within the crystal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an apparatus for writing holograms into the cylindrical crystal, the apparatus includes a source of laser light focused through a polarizing device and a beam splitter for dividing the light into a signal beam and a reference beam. A first optical path is provided for directing the signal beam through an SLM and into the crystal in a first direction with respect to the axis to the crystal and a second optical path is provided for directing the reference beam into the crystal in direction transverse to the reference signal for interference with the signal beam to form and store the holograms within the crystal.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an enlarged perspective view of a crystal configured in accordance with the principals of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged graphical illustration showing a grating vector in the crystal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a diagramatical illustration of an apparatus for writing a hologram into the crystal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to thus practice a method of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graph plotting holographic efficiency as a function of angle so as to determine angular spacing of holograms written within the crystal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagramatical view of apparatus for reading holograms out of the crystal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> using a reference beam; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a diagramatical view showing an apparatus for reading holograms out of the crystal of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> by using a phase conjudate beam developed from the reference beam; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an enlarged perspective view of a cylindrical crystal configured as a disk, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an enlarged perspective view of a cylindrical crystal configured as a rod. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown a cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> configured in accordance with the principals of the present invention. The cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is preferably made of photorefractive crystal material such as lithium niobate (LiNbO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>) or lithium borate (Li<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>B<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). While these materials are preferred and available, other photorefractive materials maybe used, such as other glasses, for example SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>: Ge, or organic polymer materials and crystals. It is a practice to dope photorefractive crystals in order to enhance their holographic storage characteristics and the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may utilize such enhancements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is formed about a z-axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and has a cylindrical peripheral surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> which extends in the direction of the z-axis and an axially facing, polished x-y surfaces <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which extends transverse, or more particularly, perpendicular to the z-axis. As is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, when a hologram is created within the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a grating vector K is disposed obliquely with respect to the x,y plane of the crystal, the grating vector K being comprised of a radial vector Kr and an axial vector Kz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> there is shown an apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> configured in accordance with the principals of the present invention for writing holograms into the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in accordance with the methods of the present invention. The apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comprises a source <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for a laser beam <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which laser beam is passed through a pair of colluminating lenses <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and then through a polarizer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The colluminized and polarized laser beam <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is then split by a beam splitter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> into a signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and a reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> passes through an open shutter <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and is reflected by a reflector <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into a spacial light modulator (SLM) which encodes data or information onto the signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> preferably in the form of light and dark pixels or pixel arrays. A spherical lens <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> aligned with the c-axis of the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (the c-axis being perpendicular to the axially facing surfaces <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and aligned with the z-axis of the crystal) focuses the signal beam into the polished, axially facing flat surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. By sending the signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> through the axially facing flat surfaces <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, there is no requirement for special cylindrical lenses to prepare an ordinary polarized signal beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is directed by an optical path, comprising a reflector <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and a cylindrical lense <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, radially through the cylindrical peripheral surface <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The distance between the cylindrical lens and the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is chosen so that the reference beam is collimated in the crystal. Thus the signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are transverse with respect to one another as they pass into the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Once the beams <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> intersect within the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, they interfere to form a hologram <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> inside of the crystal containing the information provided by the SLM i.e. information encoded in light and dark pixel arrays. The grating vector of the hologram <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> lies in a plane parallel to the z-axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In noncentrosymmetric crystals, such as for example 4 mm symmetry crystals, the electro-optic tensor has circular symmetry about the z-axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the crystals. Therefore, all of the holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> that can be multiplexed by rotating the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> about the z-axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> have the same electro-optic coupling given by the following equation:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>&Delta;</mi>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mstyle>
      <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
    </mstyle>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mi>n</mi>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mo>-</mo>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mrow>
          <mn>2</mn>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msqrt>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </msqrt>
        </mrow>
      </mfrac>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <msubsup>
      <mi>n</mi>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mn>3</mn>
    </msubsup>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>r</mi>
      <mn>13</mn>
    </msub>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>E</mi>
      <mi>sc</mi>
    </msub>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="19.93005" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> where R<highlight><subscript>13 </subscript></highlight>is the electro-optic tensor element n<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>is the ordinary refractive index and E<highlight><subscript>sc </subscript></highlight>is the light induced, space charge field parallel to the grating vector K (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In 3 m symmetry crystals the electro-optic tensor is not circularly symmetric about the z-axis for holograms written as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. In this case, the electro-optic coupling is given by the following equation:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>&Delta;</mi>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mstyle>
      <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
    </mstyle>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mi>n</mi>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mo>-</mo>
      <mfrac>
        <msub>
          <mi>r</mi>
          <mn>22</mn>
        </msub>
        <mrow>
          <mn>2</mn>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msqrt>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </msqrt>
        </mrow>
      </mfrac>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <msubsup>
      <mi>n</mi>
      <mi>o</mi>
      <mn>3</mn>
    </msubsup>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mi>sin</mi>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mstyle>
      <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
    </mstyle>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mi>&varphi;</mi>
      <mo>&af;</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mo>[</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mn>4</mn>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <msup>
              <mi>cos</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msup>
            <mo>&it;</mo>
            <mi>&varphi;</mi>
          </mrow>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mn>1</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mo>]</mo>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <msub>
      <mi>E</mi>
      <mi>sc</mi>
    </msub>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00002" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00002" wi="216.027" he="18.96615" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> where R<highlight><subscript>22 </subscript></highlight>is the electro-optic tensor element and &phgr; is the angle between the x-axis and the plane of the grating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Given this theoretical background, it is seen that a plurality of holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be stored at different angular spacings in the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by rotating the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> about its axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, this is accomplished by utilizing a precision rotator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> driven by a stepper motor <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> which indexes the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through relatively small angles &thgr;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> where efficiency &eegr; is plotted as a function of &Dgr;&thgr;, it is clear that a hologram is possible wherever the curve <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> peaks. These peaks occur at a very small angle which in the illustrated embodiment 12.2<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>rad. This results in a storage density for a plurality of holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> which is extremely high. It is not necessary to store holograms at these close angular spacings if the precision rotator stepper motor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> cannot index in such small steps, or if it is inconvenient or otherwise difficult to position holograms this close together. The angular indexing steps &thgr; can be substantially larger and still produce an enormous number of holograms in a 360&deg; rotation of the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The curve <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> which plots holographic density as a function of &Dgr;&thgr; is derived from the following equation (3) for determining the efficiency &eegr; each hologram:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>&eta;</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mfrac>
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mrow>
          <mn>1</mn>
          <mo>+</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mfrac>
              <mrow>
                <mi>K</mi>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
                </mstyle>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mi>&Delta;&theta;</mi>
              </mrow>
              <mrow>
                <mn>2</mn>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mi>&kappa;</mi>
              </mrow>
            </mfrac>
            <mo>)</mo>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mfrac>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>{</mo>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <msup>
              <mi>sin</mi>
              <mn>2</mn>
            </msup>
            <mo>(</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>{</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mi>&kappa;</mi>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mstyle>
                  <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
                </mstyle>
                <mo>&it;</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>L</mi>
                  <mo>&af;</mo>
                  <mrow>
                    <mo>[</mo>
                    <mrow>
                      <mn>1</mn>
                      <mo>+</mo>
                      <mrow>
                        <mo>(</mo>
                        <mfrac>
                          <mrow>
                            <mi>K</mi>
                            <mo>&it;</mo>
                            <mstyle>
                              <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
                            </mstyle>
                            <mo>&it;</mo>
                            <mi>&Delta;&theta;</mi>
                          </mrow>
                          <mrow>
                            <mn>2</mn>
                            <mo>&it;</mo>
                            <mi>&kappa;</mi>
                          </mrow>
                        </mfrac>
                        <mo>)</mo>
                      </mrow>
                    </mrow>
                    <mo>]</mo>
                  </mrow>
                </mrow>
              </mrow>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
            <mo>}</mo>
          </mrow>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mi>and</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&NewLine;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&kappa;</mi>
            <mn>2</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>=</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mfrac>
            <mrow>
              <mn>2</mn>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>&pi;&Delta;</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>n</mi>
            </mrow>
            <mi>&lambda;</mi>
          </mfrac>
          <mo>)</mo>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00003" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00003" wi="216.027" he="47.03265" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> where &Dgr;&thgr; is the angle from the Bragg angle, K is the grating wave vector, L is the interaction length of the signal and reference beams, &lgr; is the laser wavelength and &Dgr;n is the change in the refractive index given by Eq. (1) for 4 mm symmetry crystals and Eq. (2) for 3 m symmetry crystals. For efficiencies of &eegr;&equals;2.5&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;3 </superscript></highlight>the second null occurs 80&minus;6&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>rad away from perfect Bragg matching as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> If the adjacent holograms are spaced every second null, the storage density for one layer is  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>N</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mrow>
        <mn>2</mn>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mi>&pi;</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mi>&delta;&theta;</mi>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mn>10</mn>
      <mo>,</mo>
      <mn>470</mn>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00004" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00004" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-M00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> where N is the number of holograms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Clearly, the number of holograms N is substantial when one considers that each hologram <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be a page storing 1 Mb per page as determined by light and dark pixels of pixel arrays provided by the SLM. The theoretical limit at one axial location within the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is 10,470&times;1 Mb which equals 10,470 Mbs or 10,470 Gb per 360&deg; rotation of the cylindrical crystal, provided that the precision rotor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can accurately achieve a null every 12&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>rad away from perfect Bragg matching of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The capacity of the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can then be multiplied by indexing the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the axial direction with a linear stepping actuator <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> on which the precision rotor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is mounted. For example, if the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has sufficient thickness or axially length to be indexed axially a distance of 2 mm and it is then rotated 360&deg; while being written into, an additional 10.470 Gb of data can be stored. Since this can be done five times with a cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having an effective axial length of 1 cm i.e. 10 mm, then the cylindrical crystal can store 52.350 Gb of data. Such a cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown in the enlarged view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> wherein the cylindrical crystal is shown as a disk <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> having a thickness &ldquo;L&rdquo; in the direction of axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The disk <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> has stacked layers <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> of individual holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> recorded in annular arrays <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> If the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is configured as a rod <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> with an axial length &ldquo;L&rdquo; of 10 cm then the capacity is 523.50 Gb which is a substantial amount of data. This storage capacity does not necessarily all have to be used to have enormously useful storage capacity for the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As with the disk <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the rod <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> stores stacked layers <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> of individual holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> recorded in annular arrays <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> After data has been stored in the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, it is of course desirable to read the data out from the crystal in order to utilize the data. This is accomplished by the readout apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, there is shown a readout apparatus <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> which is substantially identical to the writing apparatus <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, but includes a detector <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, in the form of a charge coupled device (CCD) such as a CCD camera. When the readout apparatus <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the shutter <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is closed so that only a reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is generated. Reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is again focused through the cylindrical lens <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> into the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is diffracted by the holograms <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> within the cylindrical crystal to produce diffracted beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime;. The diffracted reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime; emerges axially from the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is reflected by a reflector <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> in a direction transverse, i.e. normal to the axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The diffracted reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime;, reflected by the reflector <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is then focused through a spherical lens <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> into the detector <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which is preferably a CCD camera. In the readout apparatus <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, it is necessary to rotationally index the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> about the axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> during readout and this is again accomplished by the precision rotator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. It is also necessary to index the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> axially in the direction of its z-axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in order to read holograms of different layers <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. This is accomplished by the linear stepping actuator <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> which shifts the crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and perhaps the stepping motor <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in an assembly therewith, in axial increments to read stacked layers <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> axially distributed in the cylindrical crystal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, where a readout apparatus <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is shown, modification to the apparatus as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is minimal because the precision rotator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which provides rotational stepping and the linear stepping actuator <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> need not be moved. In the readout apparatus <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, a phase conjugate mirror <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> is positioned radially with respect to the axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that the reflected reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime; that passes through the cylindrical crystal can be focused by a lens <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> onto the phase conjugate mirror to create a phase conjugate diffracted beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&Prime;. The phase conjugate beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&Prime; diffracts from the hologram and the diffracted beam emerges axially from the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and is reflected by a beam splitter <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> through a cylindrical lens <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> which focuses the diffracted beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&Prime; into the detector <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which is again preferably in the form of a CCD camera. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The readout apparatuses <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> represent one of what might be numerous readouts at various locations, such as for example customer&apos;s facilities. Since readouts do not need a reference beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, beam splitter <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, shutter <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, SLM <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> or spherical lens <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, these devices may be deleted for readouts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated embodiment of the invention, the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is angularly and axially indexed because this is a preferable approach to practicing the method and apparatus of the invention. However, it is for the purposes of this invention only necessary that the signal in reference beams and the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> have relative motion. Accordingly, the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be held stationary while the apparatus is moved relative thereto. This may be accomplished by mechanically moving the apparatus around and along the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or by optically steering the signal and reference beams <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> with respect to the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In order to write into the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a combination of relative motions is also possible within the scope of this invention, wherein the apparatus is mechanically moved, the signal and reference beams are optically steered and the cylindrical crystal is moved, either rotationally or axially or both rotationally and axially. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> While in the preferred and illustrated embodiment, signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is introduced axially into the cylindrical crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is introduced radially into the cylindrical crystal, in another embodiment, the reference beam <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> might be introduced axially and signal beam <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> introduced radially to write holograms into the cylindrical crystal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the illustrated and preferred embodiment, crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is a cylindrical crystal, however, since a cylinder is a polygon with an infinite number of sides, it is within the scope of this invention to have a crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which is a polygon that rotates about the axis <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or any other shape that rotates about an axis. For example, crystal <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> could be of an oval configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing description, one skilled in the art can easily ascertain the essential characteristics of this invention, and without departing form the spirit and scope thereof, can make various changes and modifications of the invention to adapt it to various usages and conditions. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A crystal having holograms stored in layers therein comprising: 
<claim-text>a cylindrical crystal body formed about an axis and having polished flat end faces and a cylindrical periphery; </claim-text>
<claim-text>annular arrays of holograms stored in the crystal, the annual arrays of holograms being stacked in layers within the crystal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each annular array of holograms comprises individual holograms separated by an angle in the range of 2&deg; to 6&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;4 </superscript></highlight>radians. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the number of holograms or annular array is in the range of at least 200 to 10,470. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the crystal is a 4 mm symmetry photorefractive crystal polished into a cylindrical disk and having a c-axis perpendicular to the plane of the disk. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the crystal is a 3 m symmetry photorefractive crystal polished into a cylindrical disk with a c-axis perpendicular to the plane of the disk. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the crystal is formed of a crystallizing material selected from the group consisting of lithium niobate and lithium tantalate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The crystal of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the crystal is configured as a rod having an axially length greater than its diameter wherein a plurality of annular rays of holograms are stacked to form a hologram package having an axial length greater than its diameter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of storing data in the form of holograms in a crystal, comprising; 
<claim-text>providing a cylindrical crystal formed about an axis, the crystal having an axially facing surface and a peripheral surface extending transverse to the axially facing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>from a source of laser light, providing a signal beam containing the data and focusing the signal beam through the axially facing surface of the cylindrical crystal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>from a source of laser light, providing reference beam and focusing the reference beam through the peripheral surface of the cylindrical crystal to interfere with the signal beam and thereby write a hologram-in the cylindrical crystal, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the cylindrical crystal about the axis thereof to write additional holograms in the cylindrical crystal in an annular array. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> further including indexing the crystal axially with respect to the beams to write an additional annular array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further including indexing the crystal axially with respect to the beams to write numerous annular arrays stacked axially within the crystal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further including reading the hologram out of the crystal by passing a reference beam therethrough to diffract from the holograms and produce a diffracted beam including the data of the holograms, and including reading the diffracted reference beam with a detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the transmitted reference beam is converted to a phase conjugate beam that diffracts from the hologram and is read by the detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> further including reading the hologram out of the crystal by passing a reference beam therethrough diffract from the holograms and produce a diffracted reference beam including the data of the holograms and reading the diffracted reference beam with a detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the detracted reference beam is converted to a phase conjugate beam before being read with the detector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for writing holograms into a cylindrical crystal formed about an axis, comprising: 
<claim-text>a source of laser light passing through a polarizing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a beam splitter dividing the laser light into a reference beam and a signal beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical path for directing the reference beam into the crystal in a radial direction with respect to the axis of the crystal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical path for directing the signal beam through an SLM and into the crystal in an axial direction with respect to the axis of the crystal for interference with the reference beam to store holograms within the crystal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> further including a support for the crystal, the support including a motor for rotating the crystal about the axis to write angularly spaced holograms therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further including an axial translator associated with the support for moving the crystal axially to write holograms in layers axially spaced with respect to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for reading holograms into a cylindrical crystal formed about an axis, comprising: 
<claim-text>a source of laser light passing through a polarizing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical path for directing a reference beam into the crystal in a radial direction with respect to the axis of the crystal for interference with the holograms within the crystal to direct images of the holograms axially out of the crystal, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a detector positioned to receive the axially directed images. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> further including a support for the crystal, the support including a motor for rotating the crystal about the axis to read angularly spaced holograms therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> further including an axial translator associated with the support for moving the crystal axially to read holograms in layers axially spaced with respect to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the detector is a charge coupled device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the images of the holograms are coupled to the detector by a mirror reflecting the images transversely to the axis through a lens for focusing into the charge coupled device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> further including a phase conjugate mirror positioned radially of the crystal to produce a phase conjugate beam that propagates back along the axis of the crystal and for detection by the charge coupled device.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002424A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
