<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000181</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10225578</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020821</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65B053/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>053</class>
<subclass>556000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Spiral rings for spreading wrapping material at the lower rear bale-forming belt support roll of the discharge gate of a large round baler</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10225578</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020821</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09532117</doc-number>
<document-date>20000321</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Henry</given-name>
<middle-name>Dennis</middle-name>
<family-name>Anstey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ottumwa</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nissim</given-name>
<family-name>Mass</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Haemek</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yuval</given-name>
<family-name>Lieber</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>D. A. Megido</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Zvi</given-name>
<family-name>Paz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Haemek</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Deere &amp; Company</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>One John Deere Place</address-1>
<city>Moline</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>61265</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A large round baler is equipped with a net wrapping mechanism for wrapping a bale with net material that is wider that the width of the baling chamber so that the net material extends over the opposite ends of the bale. The baler has a baling chamber defined in part by a plurality of bale-forming belts mounted in side-by-side relationship on a plurality of belt support rolls extending between opposite sidewalls of the baling chamber. The net material is fed beneath the discharge gate of the baler to a crop inlet located between a lower front belt support roll carried by the discharge gate, the net being carried into the baling chamber by a fore-and-aft runs of the belts that extend between a lower rear and the lower front belt support roll, and carry the net along a guide surface defined by a plurality of channel members respectively located beneath the fore-and-aft runs of the belts. In order to ensure that the net material arrives at the baling chamber at width greater than that of the baling chamber, spiral rings are mounted at opposite ends of the lower rear belt support roll and spreader rings are mounted at the opposite ends of the lower front belt support rolls, the spiral rings being located outboard relative to the spreader rings, with a major portion of the spreader rings being located outboard of the opposite sidewalls of the baling chamber. In order to keep rogue or stray crop stems from interfering with the net material so as to prevent it from being spread to its full length and fed, shielding is provided inside the baling chamber at a location above the lower rear roll. Wrap around shields are provided to shield the spreader rings from crop that is delivered into the baling chamber and various other structures are provided for preventing the accumulation of rogue or stray crop in the vicinity of the spreader rings and other areas in the path of net travel. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to devices for wrapping net material around large round bales located in a baling chamber and more specifically relates to structure for keeping net wrap material at its dimension wider than the baling chamber so that the net material becomes wrapped over outer, opposite end segments of the ends of the bale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 6,006,504, issued on Dec.28, 1999 relates to a wrapping device of the above-mentioned type. While this patent acknowledges the importance of having the net material spread to its full width at the point of its feeding into the crop inlet of the baling chamber, it is somewhat lacking in that regard. Also, operation of a baler constructed in accordance with the patented structure has revealed shortcomings in its construction which permit crop materials to directly interfere or to accumulate and then interfere with the spreading and feeding operations of the net. It has even been found that in some instances the interfering crop materials will cause rips or tears in the net wrap material. This interference can take place at any point along the entire feed path for the net material extending beneath the baler discharge gate and into the crop inlet, but particularly in the vicinity of the lower rear and lower front belt support rolls of the discharge gate. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, there is provided a net material delivery structure which represent an improvement over the structure disclosed in the above-identified patent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> An object of the invention is to provide a net wrap feeding assembly which is capable, in a variety of crop conditions, of effectively feeding net material, at a width greater than that of the baler chamber, into the crop inlet of a large round baler so that a bale located there will be wrapped with the net extending over opposite end segments of the bale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A more specific object of the invention is to provide a net wrap feeding assembly which includes various components which cooperate to keep incoming crop flow as well as stray or rogue crop material from interfering with the spreading and delivery of the net material to the baling chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide aggressive net spreader spiral rings, on the opposite ends of the lower rear discharge gate roll, which spread the net wrap material to its full width and thus act to place the wrap material in a more suitable disposition for being engaged a spread by aggressive wrap material spreader rings, on the ends of the lower front belt support roll of the discharge gate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide the opposite ends of the lower front discharge gate roll with aggressive spreader rings which not only spread the net to a width greater than the width of the baling chamber but also act to wipe crop out of the vicinity of the ring so as to prevent accumulation of the crop with its attendant disruption of the feeding of the net into the baling chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Yet another object of the invention is to provide wrap around shields which protect the spreader rings at the opposites ends of the lower front discharge gate roll from incoming crop flow as well as from rogue or stray crop which may accumulate on baler frame members while at the same time providing an open rear area for crop to be expelled by operation of a wiper carried by the spreader ring, and additionally for defining an open path for net wrap material to enter and go around the shielded area of the spreader rings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the invention is to provide a roll scraper, at the back side of the lower front gate roll, which acts to deflect stray or rogue pieces of crop away from the spreader rings at the opposite ends of the gate roll. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide the lower front gate roll with spiral strips that act to increase the aggressiveness between the roll and the belts so that crop is carried through the nip area, chop crop when it engages the roll scraper, auger rogue or stray pieces of crop inwardly away from the spreader rings at the opposite ends of the roll, and to lift and shake the bale forming belts so that stray or rogue crop pieces carried by the belts will fall between the belts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide belt guide washers on the net material guide pan structure in the vicinity of the nip between the belts and the lower front discharge gate roll so that the net wrap material can pass over the tops of the guide washers without being inhibited from being spread by the spreader rings provided at the opposite ends of the lower front roll. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> These and other objects will become apparent from a reading of the ensuing description together with the appended drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of a large round baler equipped with a net wrapping assembly of the type with which the present invention is particularly adapted for use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view showing an enlargement of that portion <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> including the lower portion of the discharge gate and the net wrap material feed structure extending beneath the gate, but with some parts omitted for clarity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic bottom view showing the relationship between the right-hand spiral ring and the right-hand spreader ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the right-hand spiral ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a left end view of the spiral ring shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of the shield for preventing rogue or stray crop from passing sideways into the vicinity of the spiral ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a somewhat schematic right rear perspective view of a right, lower front portion of the discharge gate with parts broken away for showing how the net wrap material is supported and guided into the baling chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of the lower front portion of a bale discharge gate, with parts broken away, showing the right-hand net wrap material spreader ring and the associated shield for keeping crop from being picked up by the spreader ring, and showing the roll scraper and belt guides. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a front elevational view, with parts broken away, of the structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a vertical sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> showing the bale-forming belts, the support for the belts and the belt guides. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of the right-hand spreader ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of the right-hand spreader ring.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Initially, it is to be noted that various components are described as existing in pairs while only one of each pair is shown and it is to be understood that the absent component is the same as, or similar in construction to, or the mirror image of, the one shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown a baler <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the type for making large cylindrical bales and commonly called a large round baler. The baler <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a main frame <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> supported on a pair of ground wheels <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, of which only the left-hand ground wheel is shown. A draft tongue <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, which is adapted for being connected to a tractor, is secured to the main frame <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A pair of transversely spaced vertical sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are joined to the frame <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and have respective upright rear ends. A bale discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> including opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is vertically pivotally attached, as at <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, to upper rear locations of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> having forward ends which abut against the rearward ends of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> when the gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is in a lowered closed position as shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The pairs of sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotatably support the opposite ends of a plurality of bale-forming belt support rolls adjacent the periphery of the sidewalls. Specifically, beginning at a lower central location of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and proceeding counterclockwise, there are mounted a driven roll <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, a lower front roll <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, an intermediate front roll <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, an upper front roll <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and an upper rear roll <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>; and continuing counterclockwise from an upper rear location of the gate sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> there is mounted an upper rear roll <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, a lower rear roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and a lower front roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Located between the pairs of sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and supported in side-by-side relationship to one another across the various belt support rolls are a plurality of endless bale-forming belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Except for some of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> which skip the lower front roll <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the belts are trained so that they serially engage the rolls <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A front run <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extends upwardly from the driven roll <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the roll <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Similarly, a rear run <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extends upwardly from the lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to the roll <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Mounted between rear end locations of a pair of rearwardly extending tensioning arms <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, which are vertically pivotally mounted, as at <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, to a mid-height location at the front of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, are closely spaced, front and rear idler rolls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, with the belt runs <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> cooperating with the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to define an expansible baling or bale-forming chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, closed at its top by the idler rolls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and here shown in a state of considerable expansion and containing a bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. When the chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is empty, the front and rear runs <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> respectively converge upwardly from the drive roll <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and pass closely to each other between the rolls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, with the run <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> contacting a rear surface of the front roll <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and with the run <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> contacting a forward surface of the rear roll <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> thus being wedge-shaped as viewed from the side. The bottom of the chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is provided with a crop inlet <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> extending between the driven roll <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Crop products are introduced into the inlet <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> by a pickup <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> for being rolled into a bale, such as the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> by the action of the front and rear runs <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, which are respectively driven so as to travel toward and away from the inlet, and initially also by a starter roll <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> rotatably mounted in the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> adjacent to, and being driven in the same direction as, the driven roll <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> so that it operates to strip crop being carried downwardly by the front run of belts <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. As the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is being formed, the chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> yieldably expands, to a predetermined size as shown, against the force established in the belts by a tensioning system including the pair of tensioning arms <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> together with a pair of tensioning springs (not shown) and a pair of hydraulic cylinders (not shown) coupled between the walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the arms <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for resisting upward movement of the arms, in a manner well known in the art. A pair of gate cylinders <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are provided for swinging the gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> upwardly, about the pivotal attachment <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, to an open position when it is desired to discharge the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> onto the ground. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Mounted to the lower rear portion of the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is a net wrap dispensing mechanism <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> in which is loaded a net material supply roll <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which is located directly on a driven upper net material feed roll <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> that is located above and rearwardly of the axis of rotation of a lower feed roll <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. A length of wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extends from the front surface of the net material supply roll <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, between the supply roll <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and the net material feed roll <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and then forwardly through a nip or bite defined by the upper and lower feed rolls <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, respectively. When a bale is being wrapped, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the length of wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extends on into the inlet <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> by way of a nip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, defined by a pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> where the latter pass about the lower rear belt support roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring now also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> forms part of a net material guide assembly <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> positioned beneath the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and further comprising a support frame including a pair of fore-and-aft extending members <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) having their rear ends respectively fixed adjacent opposite ends of a cylindrical rear cross member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and converging forwardly to transversely spaced locations where they are connected to a middle portion of a cylindrical front cross member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. A pair of straps <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> are respectively fixed to opposite ends of the rear cross member <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> and are secured, as by bolts <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, to the opposite sides of the housing of the dispensing mechanism <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Similarly, a pair of straps <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are respectively fixed to opposite ends of the front cross member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and secured, as by bolts <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, to respective plates <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that are welded to outer lower portions of posts <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> forming forward stiffening members of the opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A plurality of longitudinally extending, transversely spaced, downwardly opening channel members <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are respectively located one each under each of runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>), which extend fore-and-aft between the rolls <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, with a forward section of each of the members <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> being joined to and extending forwardly beyond the front cross member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> to respective locations beneath the lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and with a rear end of each of each of the members <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> being joined to a forward side of a transverse, downwardly opening channel member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> located directly beneath the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. An upwardly bowed leaf spring <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> bridges, and has opposite ends engaged with, the pair of fore-and-aft extending members <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, with a central portion of the leaf spring <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> being coupled to a central location of the channel member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, in a manner not shown. It is noted that the pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is secured to the top of the channel member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and to the rear ends of the channel members <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as well, and that the leaf spring <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> functions to urge the pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> against the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the belt support roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> so that a free end of the length of net <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is easily caught at the initiation of the wrapping procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Thus, it can be seen that after passing through the nip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is supported on the upper flat surfaces of the longitudinal channels <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> beneath the longitudinal runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In fact, the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> act to carry the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> around the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> where it becomes wrapped about the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> which, during wrapping operation, is being rotated clockwise within the chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> by the movement of the belt runs <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The net material supply roll <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is longer than the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is wide, that is to say, the length of the roll <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is greater than the distance between the sidewalls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. It is desirable to have the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> at its full width when it enters the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> so that outer marginal portions of the net becomes folded over the opposite ends of the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, as shown at <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and to this end the opposite ends of each of the belt support rolls <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are respectively defined by net spreading devices, with only the right-hand device of each roll being shown. The left-hand spreading devices are mirror images of the right-hand spreading devices. Further, it is to be noted that the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the discharge gate each have a lower, fore-and-aft extending edge that is above the upper surfaces of the channels <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> so as to permit the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to be spread outwardly beyond the bottom edges of the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> With reference now also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 through 5</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the spreading devices defining opposite ends of the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are in the form of spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and that the spreading devices defining opposite ends of the lower front roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are in the form of spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> include a cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> received on opposite ends of a central cylindrical core <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and secured in place by set screws or the like (not shown) received in threaded holes provided in the sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>. Each sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> includes a chamfered inner end <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> having a section that is angled outwardly at an angle of approximately 10&deg; from a vertical plane intersecting the rotational axis of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> at a right angle so as to define a lead-in surface <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The lead-in surface <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> blends into and forms an outer side of a generally v-shaped notch <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight> that gradually becomes shallower so that its outer end is at the outer diameter of the sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>. The inside end of the sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> includes a portion that diverges from, and parallels a portion of the lead-in section <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, where the latter blends into one side of the notch <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>, the diverging portion of sleeve forming a leading end or nose <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of a spiral rib <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the nose having a surface which blends into a second side of the notch <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. The spiral rib <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is of a hand for engaging longitudinal strands of the adjacent side portion of the length and wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and moving the side portion outwardly beneath the discharge gate sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. It is noted that the nose <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> begins at the inside diameter of the sleeve <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, at a location inwardly of a major portion of the inner end of the sleeve, and, within an angular distance of about 90&deg;, rises to the full height of the rib <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> which continues constant over the remainder of the length of the sleeve. Thus, the nose or leading end <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of the rib <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> starts at the outer diameter of the cylindrical roll core <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> so as to effectively lift longitudinal strands of the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> from the surface of the roll core <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and initiate outward movement of the adjacent side portion of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. Importantly, the surface speed of the spiral ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is greater than the linear speed of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> so that the spiral rib <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> aggressively engages and moves the longitudinal net strands outwardly. While the particular spiral ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> described above does an excellent job of spreading the length of net material outwardly, other shapes could be used as long as they provide aggressive pick-up and outward feeding of the net material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are outside the opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and respective clearance gaps exists between the net pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which permits rogue or stray crop stems, especially long stems from crops such as corn or cane, which have passed from the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> through gaps between the belt runs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> into the void between the belt runs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and those runs of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> that extend about the periphery of the gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, to find their way outwardly through gaps or openings communicating this void with the area adjacent the spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and of the net guide pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> such as to interfere with the net path. Such interference has been found to cause the net to sometimes become torn or split and/or to block the net from spreading to full width resulting in the net not extending over the ends of the wrapped bale. In order to keep long stems of this rogue or stray crop from feeding out sideways between the outermost runs of the belts in the vicinity of the spreader spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, shield structures <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 6</cross-reference>) are angled across the lower rear corners of the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, with only the structure at the right-hand side of the gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> being shown. Specifically, each shield structure <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> includes a support <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> in the form of a length of angle iron oriented at an angle of approximately forty-five degrees to horizontal at a location above the roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and having one leg secured against, and a second leg extending perpendicular to, the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A flexible shield <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, preferably constructed of a flat, rectangular piece of smooth surface belting, is bolted or otherwise secured to the second leg of the angle member <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> such that a right-hand edge of the shield <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is engaged with the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a rear end portion is curved upwardly from the angle member and in engagement with an upright run <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of the right-hand belt <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and a front end portion is curved upwardly from the angle member and in engagement with a filler plate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a portion of which also appears in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, fixed to the bottom of the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and extending outwardly above, and in sealing engagement with, the longitudinal run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the right-hand belt <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> so as to close a gap <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> defined between the belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Thus, any stray or rogue pieces of crop that are carried downwardly towards the right-hand spiral ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by the upright run <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of the right-hand belt <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> are intercepted by the shield <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and guided past the spiral ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> where they are deposited on the belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and/or the filler plate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the latter also functioning to prevent rogue or stray crop stems from interfering with the feeding of the length of net wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. It is here noted that instead of the two shields <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, a single flexible shield could be used which extends between and is connected to the supports <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. The filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> also serve to block any air currents, existing between the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, from interfering with the feeding of the length of net wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The inner edge of each filler plate <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is rolled back as at <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> so as to present a rounded edge to the belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as to not to damage the belt <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the event that the belt fails to track properly and comes into contact with the filler plate inner edge. The filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are each provided with upwardly inclined rear and front end portions <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, respectively, which ensure that the run of belts <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> do not come into contact with end edges of the filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Referring now back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the spiral ring <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is offset a distance d outwardly of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. This creates a favorable lead-in angle which permits longitudinal strands of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to be engaged and moved outwardly by the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, as is explained in more detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, it can be seen that the front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes a main cylindrical body <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> having opposite end portions that respectively extend beneath the opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the body containing bearings <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, in its opposite ends, having respective inner races secured to a fixed hexagonal through-shaft <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> having its opposite ends tapped and threaded and held in place by respective bolts <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) extending through the vertical side plates <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> that form part of support structure fixed to the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Mounted on the cylindrical roll body <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> so as to respectively extend beneath the right- and left-hand gate sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are the right-and left-hand net wrap material spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, with only the right-hand spreader ring being shown. It is to be understood that the left-hand spreader ring is a mirror image of the right-hand spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> has an inside diameter close to the outer diameter of the roll body <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> with the spreader ring being held in place by tightening a pair of sets screws <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>) received in threaded holes <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>) extending radially through the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Respectively mounted to lower inside locations of the right- and left-hand sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are right-and left-hand guide plates of which only the right-hand guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is shown, with it to be understood that the left-hand guide plate is a mirror image of the guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. The guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes a lower forward guard portion <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> which is curved about and disposed in spaced relationship to a portion of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> that is inward of the gate sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> so as define an annular passage for the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> from which incoming crop material is blocked by the guard portion <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. The guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes a generally triangular relief area defined by a step <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> that extends inwardly from an outer surface of, and is inclined to the rear end of, the guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> from a location near the eleven o&apos;clock position of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. This relief area cooperates with the baler sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to define a passage through which the marginal edge portions of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> pass as the net material is pulled into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> during wrapping of a bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The vertical support plates <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, from which the opposite ends of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are supported, each have an upright forward edge extending downwardly from the bottom of the support post <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> so as to be just forward of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the upright portion, at approximately the three o&apos;clock position of the roll, blending into an arcuate section which continues at a fixed radius about the axis of the roll to about the seven o&apos;clock position of the roll where it straightens and goes rearwardly a short distance, this radius being slightly greater than the radius of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A wrap-around shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, which is formed from a J-shaped strap, is disposed for cooperating with the guard portion <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> of the guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to block crop material delivered by the pickup <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> from coming into contact with the portion of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> which is outward of the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. To that end, an inner edge of the stem of the J is engaged with an outer surface of the guard portion <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, with an outer margin of the stem overlapping the upright edge of the support plate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The hook of the J is formed at a radius such that it fits close about the radiused edge of the support plate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and is thus spaced from the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so as to define an annular space or gap <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> to permit passage of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. This gap <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> is preferably dimensioned so that there is a clearance of approximately 3-6 mm between the outside diameter of the associated spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. The rear end of the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is angled downwardly, as at <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, to permit a smooth entry of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> into the gap <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. For holding each of the wrap-around shields <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> in place, a mounting tab <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is located inside an upper forward location of a respective support plate <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and is welded there and also to the bottom of the sidewall post <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A pair of u-shaped, sheet metal clip-nuts <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> are received over the bottom edge of the tab <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and are respectively aligned with a pair of transversely spaced holes provided in the tab. The upper end of the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> is provided with a similarly spaced pair of holes and a pair of screws <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> are received in the aligned holes and screwed into the clip-nuts <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> so as to secure the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> in place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> To prevent rogue crop, i.e., short pieces of stems and the like, from accumulating in the partially enclosed zone about the end of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and interfering with the feeding of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, an axially projecting wiper <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> has its inner edge welded the outer face of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The wiper <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> will sweep through the outer portion of the annular space <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and force any crop pieces located there out over the rear end <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> of the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Crop pieces that do not escape from the enclosed volume between the runs of belts <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, during the time that bales are being formed, i.e., between wrapping operations, are carried by the belts runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> to the lower front roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. To aid in removing these pieces of crop so that they do not accumulate and cause net feeding problems, the surface of the core <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> extending between the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided with right- and left-hand spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> that are inclined to the axis of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> such as to cause engaged pieces of crop to be moved away from the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The outer ends of the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> are respectively engaged flush against a planer inner surface portion of the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, as is described in more detail below, this engagement ensuring that the net material will not be snagged by the outer ends of the strips. Furthermore, the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> tend to cause the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> to shake causing the crop pieces to migrate one way or the other towards the gaps defined between adjacent belts. The pieces of crop that are carried about the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are brought into engagement with a leading end of a stripper or scraper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, that is defined by an angle member extending lengthwise in parallel relationship to the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and having its opposite ends, respectively secured to tabs <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> welded to inside surface locations of the opposite side plates <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The stripper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> has a first leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> angled upwardly and forwardly at an angle of from 40-50&deg; at a location just behind the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, with the leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> terminating between the nine and ten o&apos;clock positions of the roll at a radius from the center of the roll which is just larger than that traced by an outer periphery of the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. A second leg <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> of the scraper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> is angled downwardly and forwardly at an angle of from 25-35&deg; from the horizontal and terminates at distance from the center of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> which is somewhat greater than that of terminal end of the leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. The spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and the stripper leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> cooperate to reduce the size of rogue or stray pieces of crop which, when stripped from the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, will slide down the upper surface of the leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and hopefully out through the gaps between the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Any crop pieces which pass beneath the leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> will hopefully also pass through the gaps between the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, but if these pieces and those stripped by the stripper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> do not fall through the belt gaps, they will be recirculated about the roll <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> where they will once again be reduced in size by the action of the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and the stripper leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Welded to and projecting downwardly from transversely spaced locations along the bottom of the second leg <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> of the stripper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> are a plurality of generally parallelogram-shaped, flat, center belt guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, these belt guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> are respectively located in the gaps between all adjacent pairs of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, except for the outer pair of belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> at each of the opposite sides of the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Although respective lower surfaces of the belt guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> are shown positioned below the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, this is the result of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> being shown thinner, and the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> being shown thicker than they actually are in order for the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and its path about the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to be discernable. In actuality, the bottoms of the center guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> terminate approximately 2 mm above the bottoms of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as not to impede the passage of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to the nip formed between the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the bottoms of the guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> are spaced above the cross member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the net wrap material guide or support <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> by a distance sufficiently less than the thickness of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> such that the latter are prevented from deflecting beneath the guides <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Provided for keeping the outer pair of belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, at each of the opposite sides of the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, from moving sideways into the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are a pair of washer-like outer belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> that are received about, and fixed to, the cylindrical cross member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the net wrap material guide or support structure <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The outer pair of belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> are respectively located inboard of innermost portions of the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The outer belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> respectively extend upwardly between the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the outer sides of the outer belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and terminate approximately 2 mm below the upper surface of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. The reason for using outer belt guides which project upwardly instead of downwardly beside the belts is because tension in the net causes the net strands to be pulled up against the roll between the outer edge of the outside belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the adjacent spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a downwardly projecting belt guide at the outside of the belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> would act as a wall to keep the net material from reaching the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. However, because the outer belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> project upwardly between the outer belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the net naturally moves over the top of the guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, allowing the net material to be engaged and spread by the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. It is to be noted that the upper surface of the belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> are respectively spaced below the lower surfaces of the filler strips <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> by amount less than the thickness of the belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so that the latter is blocked from moving outwardly over the belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and into interference with the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring now also to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference>, it can be seen that the exterior surface or outer periphery of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> includes a constant diameter section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> which, excluding the wiper <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, has a major width constituting approximately one third of the axial width of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, with the remaining two-thirds of the axial width of the spreader ring being in the form of a conical section <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> having its large end joined to the outer axial end of the constant diameter section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. The conical section <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> preferably makes an angle of about 22&frac12;&deg; with an axial line at the periphery of the constant diameter section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, with angles in the range of about 15-30&deg; also being functional. Located at diametrically opposite locations of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are wedge-shaped net feed notches or grooves <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, each of which includes first and second converging sides <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> respectively, which meet to define an included angle of 70&deg; (not shown), with angles in the range of about 50-90&deg; also being functional. The groove first side <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> is located in a first plane which preferably makes an included angle of 30&deg; with a second plane that is located at an inner end of, and disposed perpendicular to the rotational axis of, the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, with angles in the range of about 10&deg;-60&deg; also being functional. Due to the conical portion <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> become shallower as they extend outwardly and they each terminate about half way across the axial extent of the conical surface <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> so as to be at the surface of the conical portion where they meet at their trailing ends, with respect to the direction of rotation of the ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, this direction being clockwise as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The inner axially facing surface of the ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is provided with two lead-in surface sections <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> which, relative to the direction of rotation of the ring, respectively lead the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>. Specifically, each lead-in surface section <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> gradually tapers by a distance of 6 mm through an arc of 123&deg; from a leading end at location of maximum width of the constant diameter section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, to a trailing end of the lead-in surface, which terminates at a minimum width location of the section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> at the side <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> of the notch <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> at a location along a diameter of the ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> which leads the leading end of the side <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> by 4.5&deg;. The lengths of the lead-in surfaces <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> could be somewhat shorter or longer and still work satisfactorily, for example, an arc in the range of about 45&deg;-170&deg; could be used. Thus, the longitudinal strands of the stretched length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> will be led, in this particular case, to a location of the notch side wall <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> which is 6 mm axially within each of the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> so as to be guided thereby over the ramped surface <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Trailing each of the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> of each spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and extending over an arc of approximately 55&deg; is a flat or planar, vertical innermost surface <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> that is disposed at a right angle to the axis of rotation of the reader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. The outer end of the adjacent spiral strip <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is engaged with one of the surfaces <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> so that no gap exists between the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Another function of the surfaces <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> of each spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is to act as a belt guide which engages the outer side of the adjacent belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as to keep the belt from running into the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> It is to be noted that while two notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> are shown, a single notch, or more than two notches could be used and that angular length of the lead-in surface or surfaces to the notch or notches may be other than 123&deg; and still function satisfactorily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring once again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, it will be appreciated that because the spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are located outwardly of the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the feeding of the longitudinal strands of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> into the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> will be enhanced. Because of the ramped part <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the tensioned net will have a tendency to remain spread out. So that transverse strands of the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> are not snagged and possibly cut by an edge <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> defined where the wall <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> of each notch <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> intersects the inner face of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, each edge <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> is inclined so as to trail a radial line intersecting an inner end of the edge <highlight><bold>194</bold></highlight> by about 4.5&deg;, with greater angles also working satisfactorily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Referring now back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference>, it can be seen that a plate <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight>, which is generally triangular in side view, is used to fill an area located below the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and rearward of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. This plate <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> includes a triangular guide or deflector portion <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> that is bent outward from the plane of the sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, with a forward end of the deflector portion <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> engaging, or at least being in close spaced relationship to, the conical surface <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> at a location which is near the eleven o&apos;clock position of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. From its location adjacent the conical surface <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>, the forward end of the deflector portion <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> curves downwardly and inwardly about the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Thus, the deflector portion <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> defines an inwardly facing, angled surface which provides a space for accommodating the outer marginal portions <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, and acts to guide pieces of rogue crop towards the top of the inner belt run <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as to pass into the nip between the belt run and the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The operation of the baler <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, as concerns the feeding of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is here stated. Assuming that a bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has just been formed in the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and it is desired to wrap the same with net material, the drive to the feed rolls <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the net wrapping mechanism <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> will be activated so as to cause the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to be propelled against the upright runs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extending between the upper rear gate roll <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. These belt runs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> will carry the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> downwardly to the nip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> formed between the guide pan <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the belt runs <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> at the roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is wider than the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the leading end <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the spiral flighting of spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> located at the opposite ends of the roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> will aggressively engage and lift the longitudinal strands of the net material so as to spread the net outwardly to its full width, this aggressiveness being enhanced by the fact that the surface speed of the spirals is greater than the linear speed of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, and hence, greater than the linear speed of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The fore-and-aft extending runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> will engage the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and carry it along the net guide surfaces defined by the tops of the channels <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the guide structure <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, the net material entering the nip formed between the bale-forming belts and the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, in the middle area of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and the annular space <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> between the wrap-around shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> at the opposite ends of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. As the length of net wrap material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> reaches the top of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, it will be caught between the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, the latter having a circumferential speed which is faster than the speed at which the material is passing through the feed rolls <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. Thus, the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> place the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> in tension as it is pulled into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. This tension will have the effect of causing the width of the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to have a tendency to become narrower than the width of the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Operating in conjunction with the spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> so as to ensure that the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is at a width greater than that of the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> just prior to entering the baling chamber are the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Specifically, with reference to the disclosed right-hand spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the right-hand marginal portion of the tensioned length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> will come into engagement with the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> as the length of material passes about the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The angled sides <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> of the notches will engage longitudinal strands of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and move them outwardly onto the conical portion <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, this conical portion acting to retain the strands once placed there so that the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is spread to a width greater than that of the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> before it enters the chamber. The engagement of the notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> with the longitudinal strands of the net material is aided by the fact that the spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are outward of the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and also by the lead-in surfaces <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> formed at the inner face of the constant diameter section <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so that the axial dimension of the section <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> gradually diminishes through an arc of approximately 123&deg;. The net retaining or holding function of the conical surface portion <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> will be satisfactorily performed if the surface portion <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> makes an angle of at least 15&deg; with a line parallel to the axis of the ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Once the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> advances just beyond the top of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the marginal net material portions <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> which extend outwardly beyond the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will be drawn into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> through the channel defined between that portion of the guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> below the step <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, with the marginal portions then being placed over the ends of the bale <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Various structures serve to prevent rogue or stray pieces of crop from interfering with the spreading and feeding of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> as it passes from the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to the lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and on into the baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the flexible shields <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that are located inside gate sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and angled above the lower rear gate roll <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> serve to intercept pieces of crop carried downwardly by the upright rear run of belts <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, with the intercepted crop pieces sliding down the angled shields <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> to the tops of the filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. These pieces of intercepted crop are thus prevented from exiting the discharge gate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the spiral rings <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and, thus, are prevented from interfering with the feeding and spreading of the net material in those areas. Of specific concern are large pieces of stems from corn or cane which can cause the net material to be torn as well as prevented from spreading to its full width. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> respectively span the gaps between the opposite sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the outer belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as to prevent crop pieces from exiting the baling chamber along the sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> so as to interfere with the feeding of the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> also serve to prevent air currents generated by the operation of the belts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> from interfering with the passage of the net material. Crop pieces that accumulate on the filler plates <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> eventually move inwardly where they either fall between the gaps between adjacent belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, when no net is present, or are carried forwardly into the nip between the belts and the lower front gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. There, these crop pieces, as well as any other crop pieces that are brought forwardly by the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, are engaged by the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and carried inwardly away from the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> at the ends of the gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and about the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> into engagement with the leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> of the stripper or scraper <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> where the crop pieces are broken into smaller pieces. These smaller pieces either slide down the outside of the stripper leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> and away from the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> or down the inside of the stripper leg <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> and toward the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In either event, the crop pieces either pass between the gaps of the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> or are recirculated about the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> where they are once again reduced in size by the action of the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> against the end of the stripper leg <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Significant in aiding the movement of the pieces of crop so that they fall between the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is the shaking action imparted to the belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> by the spiral strips <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Also acting to prevent crop material from disturbing the proper feeding of the length of net material are the wrap-around shields <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, which extends forwardly of and wrap about the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> at the opposite ends of the lower gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The source of this crop is that being delivered to the baling chamber inlet <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. It is noted that unless intercepted, crop stems, particularly large hard stems, can get carried by the spreader ring notches <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> to the guide plates <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and become wedged tightly, causing wear and/or heat build-up. This wedged crop also interferes with the path of the net material, e.g., it can push the net material inward and prevent the net from going over the end or edge of the bale. The net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> enters from the rear of the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and passes through the gap <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> defined between the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and the roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The wiper <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, carried by the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, acts to keep any small pieces of crop, which finds its way into the gap, loose and wiped out of the area and thus helps to prevent crop from being packed tightly between the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and the shield <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> and/or guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. In addition to the wiper <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> acting to keep crop from accumulating in the vicinity of the spreader ring <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the angled deflector portion <highlight><bold>198</bold></highlight> of the plate <highlight><bold>196</bold></highlight> also serves to prevent such accumulation by guiding small pieces of crop into the nip point between the gate roll <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the belts baling chamber <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> by way of the net material passage defined by the guide plate <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and sidewall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Contributing to the proper spreading of the length of net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> by the spreader rings <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are the outer belt guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> which extend upwardly between each outer pair of belt runs <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> so as to permit the net material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> to take a natural path above the guides <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> when the material <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is tensioned and pulled upwardly as it is being pulled into the baling chamber by the action of a rotating bale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Thus, it will be appreciated that reliable feeding of net wrap material, that is wider than the baling chamber, into the baling chamber in such a way that the net material extends over the opposite ends of the bale requires the cooperation of various elements to ensure that the material is spread to a width greater than that of the baling chamber prior to it entering the baling chamber, and that pieces of stray or rogue crop are kept from interfering with the spreading and feeding of the net material. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including a bale-forming chamber having opposite sidewalls and a transverse opening extending the full width of said chamber between said sidewalls, said bale-forming chamber including a rotating element having an arcuate profile defining one side of said opening and including a rotatable roll having opposite ends extending outwardly beyond said opposite sidewalls, a net wrapping mechanism adapted for introducing net material, having a width greater than the distance between said opposite sidewalls, over said roll and through said opening for introduction into a nip defined by a rotating bale just formed in the chamber and said arcuate profile, whereby the net material will be carried into said bale-forming chamber, a pair of bale end engaging structures respectively extending inwardly from vertical, planar inner surface portions of said opposite sidewalls in the vicinity of said roll, each bale end engaging structure having a leading and a trailing edge relative to the direction of rotation of a bale in said chamber, a passage leading from a location outward of a given sidewall adjacent the roll to a location inwardly of the wall adjacent the trailing edge of the adjacent bale end engaging structure, and a pair of net spreader elements being carried by said roll respectively in bridging relationship to said opposite sidewalls, the improvement comprising: said pair of net spreader elements each including a spreader ring including at least one notch having a first side located for engaging longitudinal strands of outer marginal portions of said net material at or inside said planar inner surface of the adjacent sidewall and angled outwardly for moving these strands outwardly of said inner surface, whereby the net material is spread to a width greater than that of said bale-forming chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each spreader ring is provided with more than one notch with each notch being spaced angularly from each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each spreader ring includes an inner constant diameter portion joined to an outer conical portion, with the diameter of the conical portion decreasing outwardly; and said at least one notch extending partly into a surface area of said conical portion, whereby said notch is adapted for guiding net material outwardly over said conical portion, where, due to tensile forces in the net material, it will remain on the conical portion until pulled into the bale-forming chamber by a rotating bale being wrapped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each notch first side lies in a plane which forms an angle in the range of approximately 10-50&deg; with a plane extending perpendicular to a rotational axis of said roll. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one notch extends to an inner side of an associated one of the spreader rings; and said inner side defining an inwardly facing lead-in surface which is shaped such that the width of said spreader ring diminishes from a first location which leads said notch, when considered relative to a direction of rotation of the roll during normal operation, to a second location within said notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said lead-in surface extends through an arc in a range from 45 to 170&deg;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said notch includes a second side which makes an angle in a range of about 50-90&deg; with said first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a vertical support plate is located closely adjacent each outer end of said roll; each spreader ring being spaced inwardly on said roll from an adjacent outer end thereof; and a shield extending downwardly in front and extending around a lower portion of said spreader ring in spaced relationship to the spreader ring and roll for defining an arcuate space about said roll, with the shield having a rear end defining an opening through which net material may pass to said space on its way to the baling chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a wiper element is fixed to, and projects outwardly from an outer end location of each spreader ring for sweeping said space, about the circumference of that portion of the roll located outwardly of the adjacent spreader ring, so as to engage rogue pieces of crop located in said space and expel the same behind said rear end of said shield. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said rotatable roll is a bale-forming belt support roll mounted for rotation about a horizontal transverse axis and said arcuate profile is defined by a plurality of bale-forming belts supported in side-by-side relationship across a central portion of said support roll; a guide plate being positioned below each sidewall in the vicinity of the bale end engaging structure associated with the sidewall; said guide plate including a guide portion inclined across and in close proximity to the adjacent spreader ring, the guide portion being so located that pieces of crop material carried by said at least one notch will be directed onto an outer one of said bale-forming belts so as to be carried towards a second nip formed between said support roll and bale-forming belts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said rotatable roll is a bale-forming belt support roll mounted for rotation about a horizontal transverse axis and said arcuate profile is defined by a plurality of bale-forming belts supported in side-by-side relationship across a central portion of said support roll; and each spreader ring being provided with a vertical planar innermost surface disposed perpendicular to said axis, with said innermost surface being located adjacent a path traveled by an outer one of said bale-forming belts so that said innermost surface acts as a belt guide preventing the belt from entering said at least one notch of said spreader ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A spreader ring for use in a net wrap mechanism for a large round baler, comprising: said ring having a circumferential first surface portion of constant diameter joined to a circumferential conical second surface portion which decreases in diameter in a direction axially away from said first surface portion; a net engaging notch extending across said first surface portion into said second surface portion; and said notch having a first side oriented with respect to a normal operating direction of rotation of said ring so as to have a leading end at one side of said first surface portion and a trailing end at said conical second surface portion, whereby said notch operates to engage longitudinal strands of net material and move them away from said leading end to said trailing end, and, thus onto said conical second surface portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first surface portion is joined to an end face of said spreader ring defining at least one lead-in surface extending through an arc in the range of about 45&deg; to 170&deg; in length which, as considered relative to an intended working direction of rotation of said ring, has a trailing end located in said at least one notch, with the width of said first surface portion of said ring gradually diminishing in width from said leading end to said trailing end of said lead-in surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said spreader ring includes at least a second notch spaced angularly from said at least one notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said spreader ring includes a second lead-in surface, similar to said at least one lead-in surface and having a trailing end located in said second notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first side of said at least one notch lies in a first plane which makes an angle in the range of about 10&deg; to 60&deg; with a second plane disposed perpendicular to an axis of rotation of said spreader ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one notch includes a second side which makes an angle in the range of about 50&deg; to 100&deg; with said first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one lead-in surface and said one side meet at said first face so as to define an edge which is inclined outwardly away from a radial line intersecting an inner end of said edge by an angle of at least 4&deg;, with said radial line leading said edge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The spreader ring defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said conical surface makes an angle of at least 15&deg; with a line extending parallel to an axis of rotation of said ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including a bale-forming chamber defined in part by a bale discharge gate having opposite sidewalls spaced apart by a predetermined distance for forming bales in said chamber, lower rear and lower front bale-forming belt support rolls extending between and being rotatably supported by said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate with said lower front roll defining a rear side of a crop inlet leading to said chamber, a plurality of side-by-side disposed bale-forming belts having respective upright runs joined to respective fore-and-aft extending runs at locations engaging said lower rear roll with said fore-and-aft extending runs also engaging said lower front support roll, said baler being equipped with a net wrapping mechanism including a wrap material guide surface underlying said lower rear roll and said fore-and-aft extending belt runs, the wrapping mechanism being operable for introducing a length of net wrap material into said crop inlet along a path defined between said wrap material guide surface and said fore-and-aft extending runs of said belts whereby the net material is captured between the baleforming belts and a formed bale, each of said lower rear and lower front support rolls having opposite end portions extending outwardly beyond said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate and defined by respective wrap material spreader devices, and said wrapping mechanism being operable for dispensing net having a width greater than said predetermined width, the improvement comprising: a shield structure including an elongate shield support fixed to an inner surface of each sidewall so as to extend downwardly and forwardly above said lower rear roll; shield means secured to each shield support and having an outer edge disposed against an adjacent one of said sidewalls and extending between a rear end, disposed adjacent an inner surface of an adjacent one of said upright runs of said bale-forming belts, and a forward end disposed above an inner surface of an adjacent one of said fore-and-aft extending runs of said bale-forming belts, whereby the shield means will intercept any pieces of crop material which may be carried downwardly by said adjacent ones of the upright belt runs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said shield means comprises a pair of shields which are each constructed of flexible material with said rear ends of said shields being respectively engaged with said adjacent ones of said upright runs of bale-forming belts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each shield is constructed of a rectangular sheet of smooth surface belting. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said shield supports are each in the form of an angle member having a first side secured against an adjacent one of the sidewalls and a second side secured to said shield means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including a bale-forming chamber defined in part by a bale discharge gate having opposite sidewalls spaced apart by a predetermined distance for forming bales in said chamber, lower rear and lower front bale-forming belt support rolls extending between and being rotatably supported by said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate with said lower front roll defining a rear side of a crop inlet leading to said chamber, a plurality of side-by-side disposed bale-forming belts having respective upright runs joined to respective fore-and-aft extending runs at locations engaging said lower rear roll, with said fore-and-aft extending runs also engaging said lower front support roll, outer ones of said fore-and-aft extending runs being respectively spaced from said opposite side walls, said baler being equipped with a net wrapping mechanism including a wrap material guide surface underlying said lower rear roll and said fore-and-aft extending belt runs and being in a plane extending below lower edges of said opposite sidewalls, the wrapping mechanism being operable for introducing a length of net wrap material into said crop inlet along a path defined between said wrap material guide surface and said fore-and-aft extending runs of said belts whereby the net material is captured between the bale-forming belts and a formed bale, each of said lower rear and lower front support rolls having opposite end portions extending outwardly beyond said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate and defined by respective wrap material spreader devices, and said wrapping mechanism being operable for dispensing net having a width greater than said predetermined width, the improvement comprising: an elongate flat filler strip extending fore-and-aft beside the lower edge of and being secured to each sidewall, each filler strip extending across a gap defined between the sidewall to which the filler strip is attached and the adjacent fore-and-aft extending belt run, with the filler strip including an inner marginal portion in engagement with the top of the last-mentioned belt run, whereby the filler strips act to inhibit stray or rogue crop pieces from passing through said gaps into the feed path of the net material and also to prevent air currents existing between said sidewalls from interfering with the feeding of the net material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least a portion of said inner marginal portion is folded onto itself so as to define a rounded inner edge that will not have a tendency to damage the adjacent fore-and-aft extending belt run. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said filler strip has front and rear end sections which extend upwardly from opposite ends of a remaining straight section of the filler strip so that said front and rear end sections are disposed for permitting the smooth entry and exit of the belt run that is contacted by the filler strip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including a bale-forming chamber defined in part by a bale discharge gate having opposite sidewalls having respective inner planar surfaces spaced apart by a predetermined distance for forming bales in said chamber, lower rear and lower front bale-forming belt support rolls extending between and being rotatably supported by said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate with said lower front roll defining a rear side of a crop inlet leading to said chamber, a plurality of side-by-side disposed bale-forming belts having respective upright runs joined to respective fore-and-aft extending runs at locations engaging said lower rear roll, with said fore-and-aft extending runs also engaging said lower front support roll, outer ones of said fore-and-aft extending runs being respectively spaced from said opposite side walls, said baler being equipped with a net wrapping mechanism including a wrap material guide surface underlying said lower rear roll and said fore-and-aft extending belt runs and being in a plane extending below lower edges of said opposite sidewalls, the wrapping mechanism being operable for introducing a length of net wrap material into said crop inlet along a path defined between said wrap material guide surface and said fore-and-aft extending runs of said belts whereby the net material is captured between the bale-forming belts and a formed bale, each of said lower rear and lower front support rolls having opposite end portions extending outwardly beyond said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate and defined by respective wrap material spreader devices, and said wrapping mechanism being operable for dispensing net having a width greater than said predetermined width, the improvement comprising: said net spreading devices at the opposite ends of said lower rear roll each being in the form of a spiral ring having a cylindrical body with a spiral rib extending therealong and having a hand for moving net material outwardly; said raised spiral rib having a leading end, as considered with the lower rear roll rotating counterclockwise when viewed looking at a right-hand end thereof, which begins at an inside diameter of said cylindrical body and rises to a radial height, from said cylindrical body, that is at least as high as the remainder of the spiral rib. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said net material spreading devices at the opposite ends of said lower front roll are in the form of spreader rings respectively located in bridging relationship to said opposite sidewalls; each spreader ring including at least one notch formed in a radially outer surface of, and extending outwardly from an inner surface of, said spreader ring; each spreader ring notch including a trailing side, as considered in the direction of rotation of said lower front roll, that is angled for engaging longitudinal strands of outer marginal portions of said net material at or inside said planar inner surface of the adjacent sidewall and for moving these strands outwardly of said inner surface; said spreader spirals at the opposite ends of said lower rear roll being respectively spaced outwardly relative to said spreader rings, whereby longitudinal strands of net material engaged by said spiral rings will be angled inwardly towards said spreader rings to thereby be in a more favorable angle for being engaged by said notches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said inner surface of each of said spreader rings is provided with a lead-in surface which is shaped such that the width of said spreader ring diminishes from a first location which leads said notch, when considered relative to a direction of rotation of said lower front roll during normal operation, to a second location within said notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each spreader ring includes at least a second notch spaced angularly from said one notch; and a second lead-in surface, similar to that associated with said one notch, being associated with said second notch. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outside diameter of said spreader spirals is so chosen that the peripheral speed of said spreader spirals is greater than a linear speed of said length of net material, whereby the spreader spirals aggressively act to spread the length of net material to its full width. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including a bale-forming chamber defined in part by a bale discharge gate having opposite sidewalls having respective inner planar surfaces spaced apart by a predetermined distance for forming bales in said chamber, lower rear and lower front bale-forming belt support rolls extending between and being rotatably supported by said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate with said lower front roll defining a rear side of a crop inlet leading to said chamber, a plurality of side-by-side disposed bale-forming belts having respective upright runs joined to respective fore-and-aft extending runs at locations engaging said lower rear roll, with said fore-and-aft extending runs also engaging said lower front support roll, outer ones of said fore-and-aft extending runs being respectively spaced from said opposite side walls, said baler being equipped with a net wrapping mechanism including a wrap material guide surface underlying said lower rear roll and said fore-and-aft extending belt runs and being in a plane extending below lower edges of said opposite sidewalls, the wrapping mechanism being operable for introducing a length of net wrap material into said crop inlet along a path defined between said wrap material guide surface and said fore-and-aft extending runs of said belts whereby the net material is captured between the bale-forming belts and a formed bale, each of said lower rear and lower front support rolls having opposite end portions extending outwardly beyond said opposite sidewalls of said discharge gate and defined by respective net wrap material spreader devices, and said wrapping mechanism being operable for dispensing net having a width greater than said predetermined width, the improvement comprising: said lower front roll having a cylindrical center portion between said spreader devices at the opposite ends of said lower front roll; and at least a pair of right-and left-hand spiral members respectively fixed to, and extending inwardly along said cylindrical center portion from said net wrap material spreader devices, whereby said spiral members act to move crop material away from said spreader devices and to shake said fore-and-aft extending belt runs so as to cause crop material carried by said runs to fall through gaps between adjacent ones of said fore-and-aft extending belt runs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> and further including a roll scraper extending transversely adjacent a rear location of said central portion of said lower front roll; said roll scraper including a leg having a forward end disposed adjacent a path traced by respective radially outer surfaces of said spiral members whereby said leg cooperates with said spiral members to reduce the crop material into smaller pieces so that it can more easily escape through said gaps between adjacent fore-and-aft extending belt runs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said scraper leg is inclined upwardly and forwardly so that crop materials carried by said lower front roll will be stripped off by, and slide down, said leg of said scraper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said scraper is in the form of an angle iron with said leg meeting with a second leg that is angled downwardly and forwardly to a location spaced from said lower front roll so that crop material which passes below said leg enters a nip formed between said lower front roll and said fore-and-aft extending belt runs and is recirculated and subjected to further reducing action between said spiral members and said scraper leg. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. In a large round baler including an expansible baling chamber defined in part by a pair of transversely spaced discharge gate sidewalls, a plurality of side-by-side mounted bale-forming belts supported in part by a lower rear gate roll and a lower front gate roll, each gate roll having opposite ends respectively defined by right-and left-hand net wrap material spreading devices which are at least partially located outboard of said pair of sidewalls, said bale-forming belts and lower front roll defining a nip where the belts pass around a lower rear portion of said lower front roll, a net wrap material dispenser mounted on the lower rear of said discharge gate and being adapted for dispensing net material that is wider that the distance between said pair of sidewalls, a net material support structure located beneath said discharge gate and extending from said lower rear to said lower front roll, and belt guide elements including a central set of elements projecting downwardly between all except for respective outer pairs of said bale-forming belts in a location adjacent said nip, the improvement, comprising: said belt guide elements further including first and second belt guide elements respectively located adjacent said pair of sidewalls and projecting upwardly beside an adjacent one of said bale-forming belts, whereby net material extending into said nip from said dispenser may be spread by the net wrap material spreading devices at the opposite ends of said lower front roll without being hindered by said outer pair of belt guide elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said net material support structure includes a cross member located just behind said lower front gate roll; and said outer belt guide elements being fixed to said cross member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said cross member is located directly below said central set of belt guide elements and spaced therefrom a distance less than a thickness dimension of said bale-forming belts, whereby said bale forming belts are prevented from moving sideways beneath said central belt guide elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said cross member is in the form of a cylindrical member and said outer belt guide elements each being in the form of a relatively thick washer received on said cylindrical rod. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a fore-and-aft extending filler plate is mounted to each sidewall and is engagement with an upper surface of the adjacent bale-forming belt; and each filler plate being located above a respective one of said outer belt guide elements by a distance less than a thickness dimension of said bale-forming belts, whereby said adjacent bale-forming belts are prevented from moving sideways above said outer belt guide elements. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a crop stripper is located behind said lower front gate roll and includes a flat member having a forward end disposed in close proximity to said lower front gate roll; and said inner belt guide elements being mounted to said crop stripper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The large round baler defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said crop stripper is in the form of an angle member with said flat member is one leg of said angle member; said angle member having a second leg having a bottom surface to which said inner belt guide elements are secured. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A net spreading device, adapted for use with a large round baler equipped with a net wrapping apparatus capable of dispensing net having a width greater than a distance between opposite sidewalls of a bale-forming chamber of said baler, comprising: a spiral ring having a cylindrical body; a spiral rib having a major portion projecting radially from and extending about said cylindrical body; and said spiral rib having a leading end, as considered relative to a normal direction of rotation of said spiral ring during use, located at an inner diameter of said cylindrical body and joined to said major portion, whereby said rib is shaped for lifting longitudinal net strands radially from an inside diameter of said cylindrical body to the top of said major portion of said rib. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The net spreading device defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said cylindrical body has an end surface having a major portion located in a vertical plane extending perpendicular to an axis of rotation of said spiral ring and a minor portion, including said leading end of said spiral, spaced from said vertical plane so as to define the widest portion of said spiral ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The net spreading device defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said leading end blends into a notch formed in an outer surface area of said cylindrical body so as to aid in moving longitudinal net strands along said cylindrical body in an axial direction away from said leading end.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000181A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
