<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000191A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000191A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000191</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897591</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A01D069/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>056</class>
<subclass>010800</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>056</class>
<subclass>013500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multiple belt mule drive apparatus and systems/vehicles using same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Clark</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Papke</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cortland</city>
<state>NE</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Exmark Manufacturing Company, Incorporated</organization-name>
<address>
<address-1>Industrial Park N.W., P.O. Box 808</address-1>
<city>Beatrice</city>
<state>NE</state>
<postalcode>68310-0808</postalcode>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MUETING, RAASCH &amp; GEBHARDT, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 581415</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55458</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Multiple belt mule drive apparatus and systems for use with ground maintenance vehicles are provided. The apparatus may include two endless belts each engageable with a drive sheave of a prime mover and a driven sheave of a cutting deck. Each drive belt may further contact a guide pulley and an idler pulley on a tension side and a slack side of the belt, respectively. In one embodiment, the drive sheave has an axis generally parallel to a longitudinal axis of the vehicle. Preferably, the guide pulley and the idler pulley associated with the first endless belt are, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located on a first side of a vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis, while the guide pulley and idler pulley associated with the second endless belt are located on a second side. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to maintenance vehicles having ground-engaging implements attached thereto and, more particularly, to belt drive systems adapted to deliver power to such implements from a vehicle prime mover. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Ground maintenance vehicles adapted to support and operate any one of a number of ground-engaging implements are known. For instance, riding tractors may support such implements as cutting decks, snow throwers, sweepers, etc. While some of these implements may be self-powered, e.g., tow-behind cutting decks having on-board engines, other implements typically receive take-off power from a drive shaft of the vehicle&apos;s prime mover, e.g., engine. While the present invention is applicable to drive systems for use with most any ground maintenance vehicle and implement combination, it will, for the sake of brevity, be described with respect to commercial riding mowers having belly-mounted cutting decks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> For mowers having large engines, e.g., 20 horsepower (hp) or more, the engine may be mounted such that the engine drive or output shaft axis is oriented horizontally. The cutting deck, on the other hand, typically has a driven shaft having an axis that is oriented vertically. As a result, in order to deliver power to the cutting deck, rotary motion about the horizontal drive shaft must be converted to rotary motion about the vertical driven shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Generally speaking, take-off power is provided to the cutting deck via either a belt drive system or a shaft drive system (or a combination of both). Shaft drive systems deliver rotational power through a driven shaft via appropriate gearing mechanisms and couplings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> While beneficial for many applications, shaft drive systems have drawbacks. For instance, shaft drive systems require numerous parts, e.g., bearings and gear boxes, as well as adequate structure to support the same. As a result, the cost and complexity is generally perceived to be higher than that for belt drive systems. Moreover, depending on the particular configuration, shaft drive systems may require increased maintenance, e.g., lubrication of bearings and gears, when compared to belt drive systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In typical belt drive systems found on riding lawn mowers, an endless belt extends between a vertical drive sheave attached to the horizontal drive shaft and a horizontal driven sheave attached to the vertical driven shaft. Belt drive systems in which the drive shaft axis and the driven shaft axis are not parallel and may even be perpendicular or approximately perpendicular to one another (or at least lie in separate planes that may be perpendicular or approximately perpendicular to one another) are often referred to in the art as mule drive systems. An example of a mule drive system for use with a riding tractor is found in U.S. Pat. No. 4,325,210 (Marto). To accommodate belt interconnection between the vertical drive sheave and the horizontal driven sheave, two idler sheaves are typically provided. The idler sheaves may generally be mounted in vertical planes for rotation about a transverse, horizontal axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> While mule drive systems avoid some of the disadvantages of shaft drive systems, problems remain. For example, the horsepower carried by the belt is limited by its cross-sectional size, e.g., belts having larger cross-sections are able to transmit more power than those having smaller cross-sections. Although able to transmit correspondingly greater power, belts of larger cross-section have more limited rates of belt twist. As a result, as the size of the belt cross-section increases, the distance between the drive sheave and the idler pulleys must also generally increase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> To accommodate this increased spacing between the drive sheave and idler pulleys, either the drive sheave, e.g., the engine, may be raised or the idler pulleys may be lowered. Since the space available to lower the idler pulleys is limited, raising the engine is a more common solution. Raising the engine, however, results in an undesirably higher center of gravity for the mower. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Mule drive apparatus in accordance with the present invention overcome the above-identified problems and disadvantages by providing apparatus utilizing multiple mule drives, e.g., a first and a second drive belt each routed between a drive sheave and a driven sheave. As a result, belts having a smaller cross-section may be used without sacrificing total power transmission capacity, i.e., power transmission may be split between the two or more belts. In addition, apparatus of the present invention locate the idler pulleys at a more outboard location relative to the drive sheave. Therefore, the engine may be lowered while maintaining the desired distance between the drive sheave and the idler pulleys. By maintaining a lowered engine position, vehicles utilizing dual mule drive apparatus in accordance with the present invention are able to provide a vehicle having a lower center of gravity as compared to vehicles using conventional mule drive systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one exemplary embodiment, a mule drive apparatus for delivering power to a cutting deck attached to a lawn mowing vehicle is provided, where the apparatus includes a powered drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis. A driven sheave coupled to the cutting deck is also included wherein the driven sheave is operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis. The mule drive apparatus also includes a first endless belt and a second endless belt, each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt operable to frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a mule drive apparatus for delivering power to a cutting deck attached to a lawn mowing vehicle is provided. The apparatus includes a drive sheave operable to engage a power take-off shaft of the vehicle, where the drive sheave is operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis. Further included is a driven sheave adapted to couple to the cutting deck where the driven sheave is operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis. A first endless belt and a second endless belt are also included where each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt is operable to frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave. Positionable along a tension side of the first endless belt is a first guide pulley while a second guide pulley is positionable along a tension side of the second endless belt. A first idler pulley is positionable along a slack side of the first endless belt and a second idler pulley is positionable along a slack side of the second endless belt. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment, a lawn mowing vehicle is provided. A cutting deck is attached to the vehicle as is a prime mover operable to provide power to at least the cutting deck. The vehicle further includes: a mule drive apparatus for delivering power to the cutting deck where the mule drive apparatus includes a drive sheave engageable with a power take-off shaft of the prime mover, the drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis; and a driven sheave coupled to the cutting deck, the driven sheave operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis. Also included with the mule drive apparatus is a first endless belt and a second endless belt, where each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt is operable to wrap around and frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In still yet another embodiment, a method for providing power to a cutting deck of a lawn mowing vehicle is provided. The method includes coupling a first endless belt around both a drive sheave of a power take-off shaft and a driven sheave of the cutting deck. A tension side of the first endless belt is placed in contact with a first guide pulley and a slack side of the first endless belt is placed in contact with a first idler pulley. The method also includes coupling a second endless belt around both the drive sheave of the power take-off shaft and the driven sheave of the cutting deck. A tension side of the second endless belt is placed in contact with a second guide pulley and a slack side of the second endless belt is placed in contact with a second idler pulley. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The above summary of the invention is not intended to describe each embodiment or every implementation of the present invention. Rather, a more complete understanding of the invention will become apparent and appreciated by reference to the following detailed description and claims in view of the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be further described with reference to the drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view of a riding lawn mower having a dual mule drive apparatus in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged partial perspective view of the dual mule drive apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with various structure/components removed for clarity; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a rear elevation view of the dual mule drive apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with various structure/components removed for clarity; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the dual mule drive apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, with various structure/components removed for clarity; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a portion of the dual mule drive apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrating an exemplary drive sheave geometry; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a cross-section of an exemplary V-belt for use with dual mule drive apparatus of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an engine mount system for use with a dual mule drive apparatus in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a rear elevation view of the engine mount system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings which form a part hereof, and in which are shown by way of illustration specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and structural changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention as it may be incorporated on a self-propelled vehicle, e.g., a commercial riding lawn mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. While, for the sake of brevity, the invention is herein described with respect to commercial-grade riding lawn mowing vehicles (hereinafter generically referred to merely as &ldquo;vehicles&rdquo; or &ldquo;mowers&rdquo;), those of skill in the art will realize that the present invention is applicable to mule drive apparatus for use with most any ground maintenance vehicle having most any implement, e.g., walk-behind mower, garden tractor, aerator, dethatcher, snow thrower, tiller, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> While the general construction of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is not considered central to the invention, it will now be briefly described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (shown primarily in broken lines) from a bottom perspective view. The mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> illustrated includes a frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> that, among others, supports a prime mover, e.g., internal combustion engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or the like (electric motor, for example). A pair of transversely opposing, ground engaging drive wheels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may support the rear of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in rolling engagement with the ground. Each drive wheel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> may be powered in accordance with known methods. For example, direct mechanical drive systems such as those utilizing gearboxes, shafts, and/or pulleys are possible. Preferably, each drive wheel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> includes a separate hydraulic motor (not shown) which receives hydraulic power from one or more hydraulic pumps (also not shown) powered by the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Operator controls (not shown) permit independent control of the speed and direction of each drive wheel <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, thus allowing control of the speed and direction of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. A pair of front swiveling caster wheels <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are preferably connected to a forward portion of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to support the remaining weight of the mower in rolling engagement with the ground. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Although the illustrated mower has the drive wheels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> at a first or aft end <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and the caster wheels <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> at a second or forward end <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, this configuration is not limiting. For example, other embodiments may reverse the location of the wheels, e.g., drive wheels forward and caster wheels aft. Moreover, other configurations may use different wheel configurations altogether, e.g., a tri-wheel configuration. These and other embodiments are possible without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be mounted to a lower side of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, e.g., on the underside of the frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, generally between the drive wheels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and the caster wheels <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may include one or more cutting blades <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or the like (e.g., cutting line) as known in the art. A drive system, as further described below, may selectively couple the cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> so that, during operation, power may be delivered to the cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, whereby the blades <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> rotate at a speed sufficient to cut grass and other vegetation. The cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may optionally include deck rollers <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> to further support the cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> relative to the ground during operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, power is provided to the cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> from the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> through a dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of which exemplary embodiments are illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. While the present invention is described with respect to dual mule drive apparatus, other multiple mule drive systems are also possible within the scope of the invention. As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows, the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> preferably includes a power take-off (PTO) shaft <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> which, in the illustrated embodiments, extends rearwardly from the aft end <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. A drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may be selectively engagable with the PTO shaft <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> as shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As used herein, relative terms such as &ldquo;left,&rdquo; &ldquo;right,&rdquo; &ldquo;fore,&rdquo; &ldquo;forward,&rdquo; &ldquo;aft,&rdquo; &ldquo;rearward,&rdquo; &ldquo;top,&rdquo; &ldquo;bottom,&rdquo; &ldquo;upper,&rdquo; &ldquo;lower,&rdquo; &ldquo;horizontal,&rdquo; &ldquo;vertical,&rdquo; and the like are from the perspective of one operating the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> while the mower is in an operating configuration, e.g., while the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is positioned such that the wheels <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> rest upon a horizontal ground plane <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). These terms are used herein to simplify the description, however, and not to limit the scope of the invention in any way. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The PTO shaft <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> which, in the illustrated embodiment, is generally parallel to a longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> (e.g., a generally symmetric axis running from the forward end <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> of the vehicle to the aft end <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>) of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The PTO shaft <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> is capable of rotating in at least a first direction <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Rotatably coupled to the cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is a driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> adapted to permit rotation about a driven sheave axis <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The driven sheave axis <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may preferably (though not necessarily) form a line (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) normal to a horizontal plane containing the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. The driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> may further be coupled (e.g., via an endless belt or the like) to one or more spindles (not shown) attached to cutting blades <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for rotating the latter during operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> transmit power from the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the routing of the belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment of the invention. For clarity, mower structure, e.g., frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, as well as the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, are removed from this view. While illustrated as V-belts, other power transmitting devices, e.g., toothed belts, cables, etc., could also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> To guide and tension the belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> as the driven sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) rotates in the direction <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, intermediate sheaves or pulleys are provided. For example, a first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> may be positioned for contact with a tension side <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> of the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be positioned for contact with a tension side <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> of the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Further, a first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be positioned for contact with a slack side <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> of the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and a second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> may be positioned for contact with a slack side <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> of the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The first and second guide pulleys <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be secured such that a respective rotational axis of each guide pulley remains fixed relative to the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, e.g., fixed relative to the mower frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The first and second idler pulleys <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, on the other hand, may be secured such that a respective rotational axis of each idler pulley is biased relative to the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as further explained below. This configuration maintains the desired tension on the slack side of each of the belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a rear elevation view of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with structure/components removed to more clearly illustrate the dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> preferably rides along a surface, e.g., within a first groove <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>), of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> as well as within a first groove <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> of the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The slack side <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> of the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may ride along a surface, e.g., within a groove, of the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, while the tension side <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> may ride within a groove of the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In similar fashion, the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may ride along a surface, e.g., within a second groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>), of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> as well as within a second groove <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> of the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. A third groove <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> in the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> may be provided to transmit rotational power to spindles (not shown) coupled to the cutting blades <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The slack side <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> of the second guide belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may ride along a surface, e.g., within a groove, of the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> while the tension side <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may ride within a groove in the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates the dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> from a top plan view. As shown in this view, a clutching device, e.g., an electric clutch-brake <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> or other clutching device as known in the art (e.g., a centrifugal clutch), may be provided to permit selective coupling of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> to the PTO shaft <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. For clarity, structure/components, e.g., engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and cutting deck <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, are removed from this view. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference> further illustrate exemplary belt tensioning devices <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> for maintaining tension along the slack sides <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> of the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each belt tensioning device <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may include a bell crank <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) pivotally attached to the frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for pivoting about a bell crank pivot axis <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>. The respective idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> (or <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>) is attached to a first end <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) of the bell crank <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and a tension spring <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) is attached to a second end <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The tension spring <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> is, in turn, attached to the frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The spring <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight> may bias the bell crank <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> in a direction <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> about the pivot axis <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). This biasing force causes the respective idler pulleys <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> to maintain the desired tension in the belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) may be oriented generally parallel to the longitudinal axis <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are preferably located outboard to a first side of the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and downward relative thereto (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Similarly, the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> are preferably located outboard to a second side of the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and downward relative thereto, where the second side of the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> transversely opposes the first side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Stated another way, the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may, when the mower <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is in the operating configuration as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, be positioned on a first side of a vertical plane (represented as &ldquo;V&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> may be located on a second side of the vertical plane V. Further, the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> may be located on a first, e.g., lower, side of a horizontal plane (represented as &ldquo;H&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, e.g., located between the ground plane <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight> and the generally parallel horizontal plane H passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, the guide pulleys <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the idler pulleys <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> may optionally be located on an upper side of the horizontal plane H passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. In still other embodiments, the guide pulleys <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the idler pulleys <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> could be located on the same side of the vertical plane V passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, e.g., the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> could be located above the horizontal plane H passing through the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> could be located below the horizontal plane H. Accordingly, various configurations are certainly possible without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may be offset slightly forwardly, e.g., in the direction <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>A, relative to the first and second guide pulleys <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. For example, a first vertical plane <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight> containing the centerline of the groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may be offset forwardly by a distance <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> from a second vertical plane <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> that is tangent to the pitch diameter of the belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> on the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. &ldquo;Pitch diameter&rdquo; is used herein to refer to the constructive diameter of the neutral axis of the belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> when the belt is engaged with a particular sheave or pulley, e.g., the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> shows an exemplary configuration of a forwardly offset drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. While the embodiment is described and illustrated with respect to the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and the second drive sheave groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> only, the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may preferably engage the first drive sheave groove <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> and the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> in a similar manner, unless otherwise noted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A, the distance <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> may be {fraction (1/16)} inch to {fraction (3/16)} inch and, more preferably, &frac18; inch. However, the actual offset distance is dependent on many factors including sheave separation and belt size, to name a few. Thus, other embodiments may utilize offsets of most any distance without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> By configuring the relative locations of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A, initial contact <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> between the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and the surfaces of the groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> is preferably along a portion <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of the belt&apos;s upper section (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>). In the absence of the forward bias of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, the endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may initially contact the surface of the groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> along a portion <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>) of the belt&apos;s lower section. When initial contact occurs along the portion <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, premature wear of the inner belt corner <highlight><bold>407</bold></highlight> may result. Over time, this wear of the belt comer <highlight><bold>407</bold></highlight> may undesirably permit belt rolling within the groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> By offsetting the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> forwardly as described above, wear may be reduced and correspondingly longer belt life may be achieved. Moreover, this offset has also been found to assist in guiding the belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> as it twists from the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> onto the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. That is, when the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is offset as described herein, the rotation of the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may assist in guiding the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> into the groove <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. The advantages of this forward offset are obviously not limited to dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> as described herein but rather may be applied to most any mule drive system (e.g., single belt systems). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention described above provide numerous advantages over known single mule drive systems. For example, by locating the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> outwardly and downwardly to a first side of the drive sheave axis <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> and the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> outwardly and downwardly to a second side (see e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may be lowered to nest in between. As a result, the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may remain low while still maintaining adequate distance for belt twist between the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the guide and idler pulleys. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, by providing a multiple belt system, power transmission between the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the driven sheave <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> may be split between multiple, e.g., two, smaller belts rather than transmitted through one large belt. Accordingly, the distance between the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and the guide pulleys <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and idler pulleys <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> may be further decreased due to the greater permissible rate of belt twist for belts of smaller cross-section. In one embodiment, belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> are standard A-section V-belts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Still further, the dual belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of the present invention offer more symmetric loading of the PTO shaft <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> as the lateral, e.g., side-to-side, components of the respective belts may be directly opposed. This symmetric loading is believed to contribute to reduced vibration, especially when used in combination with a focused engine isolation mount system as further described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Yet another advantage of dual mule drive apparatus in accordance with the present invention is that the location of the first guide pulley <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and the first idler pulley <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> yield an arc of contact <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) between the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of more than 180 degrees. This arc of contact between the belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> improves power transmission as compared to systems having lesser angles of contact. The location of the second guide pulley <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and second idler pulley <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> relative to the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may also provide a similarly improved arc of contact for the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Still yet another advantage of dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> disclosed and illustrated herein is that the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may be of the same or generally of the same dimensions. Although generally of the same dimensions, the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is preferably not formed as a matched set with the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, e.g., the belts <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> may be replaced individually without adversely affecting drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments of the present invention, a dual mule drive apparatus as described herein may be provided in combination with a focused engine isolation mount system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> best illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. As illustrated in these views, exemplary embodiments of the mount system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may include a central mount <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and two lateral mounts <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. Other embodiments may include additional mounts as needed for the particular application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The central mount <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> may include an engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> which, in the illustrated embodiment, may form a cradle which couples to transversely opposing sides of the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. While most any configuration may be used to couple the engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> to the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, the illustrated embodiment utilizes standoffs <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> through which fasteners <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> pass before threading into the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The central mount <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> may further include a frame isolation bracket <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> which fastens to the mower frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> with fasteners <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Sandwiched between the engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and the frame isolation bracket <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is an isolation pad <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. A fastener <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> may secure, e.g., clamp, the isolation pad <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> between the engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and the frame isolation bracket <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Each lateral mount <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may similarly include an engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> coupled to the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> via standoffs <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and fasteners <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> similar to the engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. The lateral mounts <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may also include a frame isolation bracket <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> coupled to the mower frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> with fasteners <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. As with the central mount <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, an isolation pad <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> similar (if not identical) in most respects to the isolation pad <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be secured, e.g., clamped, between the engine isolation bracket <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and the frame isolation bracket <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> with a fastener <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Isolation pads <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> are typically produced from a rubber compound which is preferably optimized to be &ldquo;soft,&rdquo; e.g., to absorb energy, when loaded in shear yet remain relatively stiff when loaded in compression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The central mount <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> may define a central mount axis <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> while each lateral mount <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may define a lateral mount axis <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The central mount axis <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> may preferably be positioned such that it is substantially parallel to and, more preferably, coaxial with, the resultant belt force vector (the resultant force applied to the drive sheave <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> by the first endless belt <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and the second endless belt <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the axes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> may preferably intersect at or at least near a horizontal axis <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> of the rotational center of mass of the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. As a result, torsional vibration produced by the operation of the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is primarily reacted in shear through the isolation pads <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>. However, the mounts <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> preferably remain rigid when the engine <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> experiences axial, e.g., vertical, accelerations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> While not limited to any particular angle, the lateral mounts <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may be positioned at an angle <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> of between 30 degrees and 60 degrees from the axis <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> and, in some embodiments, between 40 and 50 degrees. However, the actual angle <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is dependent on many variables including, among others, mount geometry and the location of the rotational center of mass. As a result, the angle <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be most any value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In addition to the reasons provided above, the focused isolation mount system described and illustrated herein may be particularly advantageous when used in conjunction with the dual mule drive apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. This is attributable, at least in part, to the generally symmetrically opposed belt loading provided by the dual mule drive apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Exemplary embodiments of the present invention are described above. Those skilled in the art will recognize that many embodiments are possible within the scope of the invention. Other variations, modifications, and combinations of the various parts and assemblies can certainly be made and still fall within the scope of the invention. For example, the drive sheave axis and the driven sheave axis may be configured in non-perpendicular and/or non-planar orientations. Thus, the invention is limited only by the following claims, and equivalents thereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A mule drive apparatus for delivering power to a cutting deck attached to a lawn mowing vehicle, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a powered drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven sheave coupled to the cutting deck, the driven sheave operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first endless belt and a second endless belt, each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt operable to frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a first guide pulley positionable in contact with a tension side of the first endless belt, and a first idler pulley positionable in contact with a slack side of the first endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second guide pulley positionable in contact with a tension side of the second endless belt, and a second idler pulley positionable in contact with a slack side of the second endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located on a first side of a vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second guide pulley and the second idler pulley are located on a second side of the vertical plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley, the first idler pulley, the second guide pulley, and the second idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in the operating configuration, located on a first side of a horizontal plane passing through the drive sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first side of the horizontal plane is a lower side of the horizontal plane when the vehicle is in the operating configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the driven sheave axis lies within the vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first endless belt and the second endless belt are equal in length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A mule drive apparatus for delivering power to a cutting deck attached to a lawn mowing vehicle, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a drive sheave operable to engage a power take-off shaft of the vehicle, the drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven sheave adapted to couple to the cutting deck, the driven sheave operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first endless belt and a second endless belt, each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt operable to frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide pulley positionable along a tension side of the first endless belt and a second guide pulley positionable along a tension side of the second endless belt; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first idler pulley positionable along a slack side of the first endless belt and a second idler pulley positionable along a slack side of the second endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, the drive sheave is oriented in a substantially vertical plane and the driven sheave is oriented in a substantially horizontal plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are positioned such that an arc of contact of the first endless belt on the drive sheave is greater than 180 degrees. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, the drive sheave axis is oriented parallel to a longitudinal axis of the vehicle, the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are located outboard to a first side of the drive sheave axis and downward relative thereto, and the second guide pulley and the second idler pulley are located outboard to a second side of the drive sheave axis and downward relative to the drive sheave axis, where the second side transversely opposes the first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located on a first side of a vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis, and the second guide pulley and the second idler pulley are located on a second side of the vertical plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley, the first idler pulley, the second guide pulley, and the second idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in the operating configuration, located on a first side of a horizontal plane passing through the drive sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first side of the horizontal plane is a lower side of the horizontal plane when the vehicle is in the operating configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the second guide pulley are coupled to the vehicle such that a rotational axis of each of the first guide pulley and the second guide pulley are substantially fixed relative to the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first idler pulley and the second idler pulley are biased to tension the first endless belt and the second endless belt, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first endless belt and the second endless belt are equal in length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the power take-off shaft is powered by a prime mover mounted to the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the driven sheave is operatively coupled to one or more cutting blades rotatably coupled to the cutting deck. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of the <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the drive sheave is located near a first end of the vehicle and the driven sheave is located underneath the vehicle when the vehicle is in an operating configuration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the drive sheave includes a first groove for receiving the first endless belt and a second groove for receiving the second endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A mule drive apparatus for delivering power to a cutting deck attached to a lawn mowing vehicle, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a drive sheave operable to engage a power take-off shaft of a prime mover attached to the vehicle, the drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven sheave adapted to couple to the cutting deck, the driven sheave operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first endless belt and a second endless belt, each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt operable to frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide pulley positionable along a tension side of the first endless belt and a second guide pulley positionable along a tension side of the second endless belt; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first idler pulley positionable along a slack side of the first endless belt and a second idler pulley positionable along a slack side of the second endless belt; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first guide pulley is, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located on a first side of a vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis and the second guide pulley is located on a second side of the vertical plane. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first idler pulley is located on the first side of the vertical plane and the second idler pulley is located on the second side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the driven sheave axis lies within the vertical plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the second guide pulley are, when the vehicle is in the operating configuration, located on a lower side of a horizontal plane passing through the drive sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first idler pulley and the second idler pulley are located on the lower side of the horizontal plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A lawn mowing vehicle, comprising: 
<claim-text>a cutting deck attached to the vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a prime mover attached to the vehicle and operable to provide power to at least the cutting deck; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mule drive apparatus for delivering power to the cutting deck, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a drive sheave engageable with a power take-off shaft of the prime mover, the drive sheave operable to rotate about a drive sheave axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven sheave coupled to the cutting deck, the driven sheave operable to rotate about a driven sheave axis; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first endless belt and a second endless belt, each of the first endless belt and the second endless belt operable to wrap around and frictionally engage both the drive sheave and the driven sheave. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first guide pulley positioned along a tension side of the first endless belt and a second guide pulley positioned along a tension side of the second endless belt; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first idler pulley positioned along a slack side of the first endless belt and a second idler pulley positioned along a slack side of the second endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, the drive sheave axis is oriented parallel to a longitudinal axis of the vehicle, the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are located outboard to a first side of the drive sheave axis and downward relative thereto, and the second guide pulley and the second idler pulley are located outboard to a second side of the drive sheave axis and downward relative to the drive sheave axis, wherein the second side transversely opposes the first side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the first idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located on a first side of a vertical plane passing through the drive sheave axis and the second guide pulley and the second idler pulley are located on a second side of the vertical plane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley, the first idler pulley, the second guide pulley, and the second idler pulley are, when the vehicle is in the operating configuration, located between a horizontal plane passing through the drive sheave axis and a ground surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first guide pulley and the second guide pulley are coupled to the vehicle such that a rotational axis of each of the first guide pulley and the second guide pulley are substantially fixed relative to the vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein two or more engine mounts couple the prime mover to a frame of the vehicle, wherein the two or more engine mounts each have a mount axis that intersects or is proximate to a horizontal axis of a rotational center of mass of the prime mover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more engine mounts each include an isolation pad operable to react rotational acceleration forces of the prime mover primarily in shear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the two or more engine mounts comprise at least one central engine mount, wherein the at least one central engine mount has a central engine mount axis substantially parallel to a resultant force vector applied by the first endless belt and the second endless belt to the prime mover. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a clutching device between the drive sheave and the power take-off shaft, the clutching device operable to selectively engage the drive sheave with the power take-off shaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the drive sheave axis is, when the vehicle is in an operating configuration, located in a horizontal plane that is perpendicular to the driven sheave axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A method for providing power to a cutting deck of a lawn mowing vehicle, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>coupling a first endless belt around both a drive sheave of a power take-off shaft and a driven sheave of the cutting deck; </claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a tension side of the first endless belt in contact with a first guide pulley; </claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a slack side of the first endless belt in contact with a first idler pulley; </claim-text>
<claim-text>coupling a second endless belt around both the drive sheave of the power take-off shaft and the driven sheave of the cutting deck; </claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a tension side of the second endless belt in contact with a second guide pulley; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>placing a slack side of the second endless belt in contact with a second idler pulley. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising transmitting power from the drive sheave to the driven sheave through both the first endless belt and the second endless belt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first endless belt and the second endless belt are substantially equal in length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein coupling the first endless belt around both the drive sheave and the driven sheave comprises placing the first endless belt into a first groove in the drive sheave and a first groove in the driven sheave. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein coupling the second endless belt around both the drive sheave and the driven sheave comprises placing the second endless belt into a second groove in the drive sheave and a second groove in the driven sheave. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein transmitting power further comprises engaging a clutching device between the power take-off shaft and the drive sheave. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A lawn mowing vehicle, comprising: 
<claim-text>cutting deck means attached to the vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>prime mover means attached to the vehicle and operable to provide power to at least the cutting deck means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>drive coupling means coupled to the prime mover means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>driven coupling means coupled to the cutting deck means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first power transmission means for transmitting power from the drive coupling means to the driven coupling means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>second power transmission means for transmitting power from the drive coupling means to the driven coupling means. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising first guiding means for guiding the first power transmission means between the drive coupling means and the driven coupling means, and second guiding means for guiding the second power transmission means between the drive coupling means and the driven coupling means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The vehicle of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising first tensioning means for tensioning the first power transmission means, and second tensioning means for tensioning the second power transmission means.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000191A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
