<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000656A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000656A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000656A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000656A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000656A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000656A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000656A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000656A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000656A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000656A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000656</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10167971</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020613</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2,351,945</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E05D015/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>160</class>
<subclass>201000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>160</class>
<subclass>229100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Panels for overhead folding doors and their articulating connections</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Vic</given-name>
<middle-name>De</middle-name>
<family-name>Zen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Woodbridge</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Royal Group Technologies Limited</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Douglas S. Johnson</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Ste. 301</address-1>
<address-2>133 Richmond Street West</address-2>
<city>Toronto</city>
<state>ON</state>
<postalcode>M5H 2L7</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">For overhead folding doors which are molded from plastic, the panels have a front wall formed at its upper edge in a slightly recessed arcuate tenon and providing at the bottom a recessed area behind a bottom edge. The panels are adapted to be hingedly connected with the bottom edge of an upper panel following a path in close proximity to the tenon of a lower panel to provide a pinch proof hinging arrangement. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to overhead sectional folding doors and, more particularly, to door panels and their articulating connections for use in overhead folding garage doors and the like. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> An overhead sectional folding door typically found, for example, in garage doors comprises a plurality of panels or sections which are hinged together to articulate about horizontal axis so that the door can be moved through the articulation of the panels as guided by suitable rollers engaging in trackways on opposite sides of the door frame from a closed vertical orientation with the panels vertically aligned to a raised generally horizontal orientation with the panels generally horizontally aligned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Such panels may be made, for example, of wood, metal, which may simply be a metal skin on a support frame, or plastic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Many of these doors are relatively expensive and are subject to weathering as, for example, with wood and metal doors. Also many of the doors are subject to damage even under modest impact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, many of the prior art doors are costly to manufacture, have excessive weight, have hinge wear problems, and are dangerous from the standpoint of fingers being caught between the panel edges as they articulate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As many garages are beneath living quarters of the home or building, it is desirable that the closed garage door provide proper insulation both overall and at the juncture of the meeting hinge panels. At present, such insulation even in the best of overhead doors is not fully effective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is therefore the object of this invention to overcome the problems of the prior art and to provide extremely rugged low cost door panels adapted for reliable articulating connection in a folding overhead door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is another object to provide door panels formed for articulating connection utilizing readily available low cost conventional hinges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Again, it is an object to provide panels enabling the assembly of a low cost fully insulated overhead door in which the joint between adjoining panels when the door is closed is perfectly sealed against moisture and airflow ingress or egress. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Again, it is an object to provide articulating connections between door panels which affords complete protection against pinching of fingers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and other objects of the invention will become apparent from the following description of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the invention resides in providing extremely rugged low cost door panels formed for accurate articulating connection with adjoining, i.e. upper and lower, panels. In its preferred form, the panels are molded as a single member from composite plastic material. In its preferred form, each of the panels has a front wall and side walls, the front wall having an upper edge portion which is slightly retracted from the front surface of the front wall to provide a shoulder having a depth substantially equal to the thickness of the front wall. From this shoulder, the upper edge is arched upwardly and rearwardly forming an upwardly projecting part circular tongue or tenon adapted to be received in a socket or mortise area of an upper panel. The side walls of the panel extend to a point spaced about the bottom edge of the front wall a distance substantially equal to the height of the tongue or tenon formed by the panel upper edge portion whereby the space behind the bottom of the front wall defines a tongue or tenon accepting space or mortise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred form of the invention, the front wall is reinforced with a reinforcing formation comprising an integral gridwork of intersecting ribs formed on its rear side extending from a point adjacent the panel upper edge to adjacent the lower end of the side walls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In another aspect of the preferred form of the invention with the part circular tenon of a lower panel received in the mortis of an upper panel immediately thereabove, the panels are articulatedly connected by hinges having the axes of their pintles lying on an axis coinciding with the centre circumscribed by the part circular lower panel tenon whereby on articulation of the upper and lower panels the lower edge of the upper panel follows in close proximity to the surface of the lower panel tenon to prevent fingers from getting pinched between the panel edges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In another aspect according to a preferred form of the invention, the panels are provided with a rearwardly extending shelf immediately beneath the upper end of its tongue or tenon. This shelf projects rearwardly of the tenon to provide an anvil surface behind the tenon and a compressible bead of insulation material is supported on this anvil surface to be compressed thereagainst by a bottom wall connecting the side walls of the panel immediately thereabove when the panels are articulated into vertical alignment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Again, in another aspect according to a preferred form of the invention, each of the panels is provided with one retaining slot immediately beneath the anvil surface and another retaining slot immediately above the bottom wall connecting its side walls. These slots are provided for the insertion of stiffening members or insulation retaining brackets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In still another aspect according to a preferred form of the invention, the front wall of each of the panels is provided at its rear with fastener holding pods to receive fasteners for securing the straps of hinges to the panels, the pods being positioned to locate the pintles of the hinges as discussed above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Again, according to still another preferred aspect of the invention, reinforcing metal straps are mounted between the hinge straps and the fastener receiving pods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Again according to another preferred aspect of the invention, the edges of the panels are reinforced by metal channels which block finger entry into the ends of the hinged connections.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> These and other features of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a partially exploded perspective view of the rear of two lower panels arranged in vertical alignment ready to be hingedly connected and an upper separated top panel with some of the hinges and reinforcing metal members in position ready for attachment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a broken away perspective view taken from the rear of one of the panels showing its construction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a broken away partially exploded perspective view of the rear of the panel of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> showing the mounting of the hinges in association with the metal sidewall reinforcement and the provision for rear insulation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic elevational view illustrating the hinging relationship between an upper and lower panel in a closed door situation where the panels are in vertical alignment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> but showing the upper panel swung out of its vertical position.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION ACCORDING TO THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there are shown three panels <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for use in an overhead folding door such as an overhead folding garage door. The two lower panels are shown arranged in vertical alignment ready to be hinged together. The upper panel is shown spaced above the two lower panels ready to be assembled with the two lower panels and hingedly connected thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Each of the panels is a molded structure molded from a composite plastic material and, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, comprises a front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the upper edge of which curves upwardly and rearwardly in the form of a part circular knee portion <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which constitutes a tongue or tenon in the articulating action of the panels as hereinafater more fully explained. The knee portion or tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is offset rearwardly of the front face of the front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by a distance substantially equal to the thickness of the front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by a connector portion or shoulder <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The sides of the panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are closed by sidewalls <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> whose upper surfaces match the configuration of the upper edge of the front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and extend downwardly from the upper edge of the front wall to a point above the bottom of the front wall a distance substantially equal to the height of the tongue or tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> leaving a planar projecting front wall portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> adapted to receive the tenon of a lower panel therebehind as shown in the two assembled panels illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The sidewalls <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> project rearwardly of the tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and are joined at the top by a first transverse wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to provide a slot <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> in which a compressible sealing member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> or weather stripping is anchored as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The side walls <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected by a second transverse wall <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> spaced below the first transverse wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to provide a second retaining slot <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> as particularly shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> for purposes as will hereinafter appear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the lower ends of the side wall are joined by a transverse wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> while spaced thereabove is a second transverse wall <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> providing a retaining slot <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is reinforced on its rear side with an integral gridwork <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; of intersecting ribs running diagonally at right angles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, extending rearwardly from the rear of the front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> adjacent the sidewall <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are a series of vertically aligned cylindrical screw receiving pods comprising a pair of hinge, that is hinge strap, locating and mounting top pods <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and a corresponding pair of hinge strap, locating and mounting bottom pods <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Intermediate the top and bottom pods <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are pods <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The opposite side of the panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the center line of panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> have identical pod arrangements and are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The manner in which the hinges <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are mounted to hingedly connect adjacent panels is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> To provide increased strength the edges of the panels are reinforced with channel members <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, preferably formed of metal, which overlie the arrangement of pods <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and are secured by screws <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which engage in the pods <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the upper strap <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the lower hinge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is about to be secured in position where it overlie the rear of the channel <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> so that the hinge screws <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will pass threw the upper strap <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the channel and engage in the bottom pods <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the panel so that the screws <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> serve both to secure the lower hinge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the channel <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> to the panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The upper hinge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> has its lower strap <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> secured in position over the channel <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by hinge screws <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which engage in the top pads <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, reinforcing metal pieces <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are adapted to overlie the central arrangement of pods <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to add strength and to support hinges <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for hingedly connecting the central portions of the panels <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As above described, the panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided with transverse walls <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> at the top and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at the bottom which not only provide strength to the panel but also provide slots <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> into which stiffening members such as the stiffening member <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> may be inserted. Alternatively, the slots <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are also adapted to receive angle members <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> for retaining a layer of insulation material <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the transverse wall <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which projects beyond the tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> forms an anvil surface <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for the sealing member <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> against which it is compressed by the bottom wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of an upper panel hingedly connected to the lower panel when the panels are in vertical alignment with the folding door in the closed position. With this arrangement, the ingress or egress of air through the hinged connection is totally blocked. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The pintle or axis <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of the hinge <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> connecting the upper and lower panels <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is located at the center of the curvature of the part circular tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so that as the upper panel pivots relative to the lower panel the bottom portion <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the front wall <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> closely follows the surface of the tenon <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the lower panel to provide a pinch proof hinge connection while the end channels <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the upper panel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> block entry to the hinging connection from the edges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> It will be understood that the reinforced edges of the panels reinforced by the channel members <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> provide for the strength of mounting appropriate rollers (not shown) for engaging in trackways to effect the hinging operation when the panels are incorporated into an overhead door during the opening and closing operation of the door. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> While the preferred embodiment of the invention has been illustrated, it will be understood that variations may be made without departing from the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">The embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined as follows: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. In an overhead folding garage door incorporating hinged door panels, a first panel forming an upper panel and a second panel forming a lower panel, each said panel being a one piece molded plastic member having a front wall formed with an upwardly and rearwardly arching upper edge forming an upwardly projecting part circular tenon offset rearwardly of the front face of said front wall a distance substantially equal to the thickness of said front wall to define a recessed shoulder, each said panel having side walls extending downwardly from said tenon to a point a distance short of the bottom of said front wall corresponding to the height of said tenon to provide a front wall bottom portion defining a tenon receiving mortis therebehind and a plurality of hinges having their pintle axes located at the center of curvature of said part circular tenon of said lower panel hingedly connecting said lower panel to said upper panel with said lower panel tenon received in said upper panel mortis with the lower edge of said upper panel overlying said recessed shoulder of said lower panel with said panels in vertical alignment whereby on articulation of said panels out of vertical alignment the lower edge of said upper panel closely follows the curved surface of said lower panel tenon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which said front walls of said panels are reinforced on their rear sides between said side walls with an integral grid work of intersecting ribs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> in which the rear walls of said panels are formed with integral fastener receiving pods for the securement of the straps of said hinges to said panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> in which metal reinforcements are interposed between said hinge straps and said fastener receiving pods. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which each of said panel has a bottom wall joining said side walls and a rearwardly projecting shelf on the underside of said tenon and defining with said tenon a retaining slot, said shelf projecting rearwardly beyond said tenon to provide an anvil surface, and an elongated compression seal is supported on said anvil surface and has a tail secured in said retaining slot, said compression seal being compressed between the bottom wall of said upper panel and said anvil surface of said lower panel upon said panels being articulated into vertical alignment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> in which each of said panels has an second shelf below said rearwardly projecting shelf to define therewith a slot to receive a stiffening insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> in which each of said panels has a stiffening member inserted into said insert receiving slot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> in which said stiffening member is an angle member having one leg inserted into said insert receiving slot and the other legs projected downwardly from said insert receiving slots. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claim in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> in which each of said panels is provided with a second stiffening member receiving slot above said bottom wall, an angle stiffening member having one leg is inserted into said second slot above said bottom wall and the other leg projecting upwardly on a layer of insulating material secured at the rear of said front wall between said downwardly and upwardly projecting legs of said stiffening members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In a garage door as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in which said plastic material comprises a composite material of particulate filter material bound together with a thermoplastic binder, said tenon being offset rearwardly of the front surface of said front wall by a rearwardly projecting shoulder having a depth corresponding to the thickness of said front wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel molded from a plastic material, said panel having a front wall having an upper edge portion arched upwardly and rearwardly to form a part circular tenon, said panel having side walls extending down from said tenon, and said front wall having an integral reinforcing formation on its rear side between said side walls, said front wall projecting downwardly beyond said side walls a distance substantially equal to the height of said part circular tenon to define a mortis space therebehind, the axial center of said part circular tenon forming a locating axis for a pintle of a hinge for hingedly connecting said panel to a corresponding panel immediately thereabove in a pivotal tenon and mortis joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> having integral hinge locating means for locating hinges with their pintles lying on said locating axis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> provided with a horizontal shelf immediately beneath said arched upper edge and extending rearwardly beyond said arched upper edge to define therewith a retainer groove for a compression seal member and an anvil surface rearwardly of said retainer groove for supporting a compression seal member </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> having a second horizontal shelf below said first horizontal shelf to define a first slot to receive a stiffening member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> having a bottom wall joining said side walls and having a second slot immediately above said bottom wall for receiving a stiffening member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> having said rear side of said front wall covered with a layer of insulating material between said second horizontal shelf and said bottom wall, said material being retained in position by angle members having one leg retained respectively in said first and second slots </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A garage door panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> provided with a channel member closing the entrance to said mortis space at each side of said panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A panel for an overhead folding door, said panel comprising a one piece plastic molded member formed with a front wall having an upwardly and rearwardly turned upper edge forming a part circular knee shaped tenon having at its lower end offset rearwardly of the front face of said front wall by a distance substantially equal to the thickness of said front wall, said panel having side walls extending downwardly from said tenon to a point a distance short of the bottom of said front wall corresponding to the height of said tenon to provide a front wall bottom portion defining a tenon receiving mortise therebehind said panel having integral hinge locating means on its rear side adjacent said tenon and adjacent said front wall bottom portion such that hinges when secured at said hinge locating means adjacent said tenon and at hinge locating means adjacent the bottom front wall of a corresponding upper panel will provide an articulating pinch proof joint in which the bottom wall of the upper panel closely follows the surface of said panel tenon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> in which said front wall is provided with integral reinforcing ribs on its rear side. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A panel as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> in which said side walls are connected by a transverse wall below said tenon and a transverse wall adjacent the bottom of said side walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A panel as claimed in any one of claims <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in which said plastic comprises the composite plastic material formed of filler or waste particles bonded together by a thermoplastic binder. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A panel as claimed in claims <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in which said means for mounting hinges at the rear side thereof comprise screw receiving pods.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000656A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000656A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000656A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000656A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000656A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
