<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001738A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001738A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001738</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894141</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G08B013/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>568100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>571000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>340</class>
<subclass>555000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Light sensing hidden object location system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ravi</given-name>
<family-name>Chandar</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An object locating system for automatically locating a hidden or lost wireless object. This is applicable to objects such as remote controls for TVs and VCRs and the like. An ambient light photosensor is located on the object. The object locating system also includes an alarm located on the wireless object, which is electrically connected to the ambient light photosensor. The ambient light photosensor senses ambient lighting conditions. The alarm is actuated when the ambient light photosensor detects ambient light below a predetermined level. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to a locating system for locating lost or hidden objects such as a television remote control device, and more particularly, a system for finding lost or hidden objects when lighting is reduced. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND FOR THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Remote control devices are well known for the operation of electronic devices such as audio and/or video equipment, e.g. television (TV) sets, video recorders (VCR), cable boxes, and compact disc (CD) players. Because remote control devices are conveniently portable, they allow users to operate electronic devices from remote locations. Often a user would misplace a remote control and not remember where he left it. Usually these devices are lost between cushions of a sofa, under magazines, or blankets, or articles of clothing, depending on where the remote control device is being used. In other words, these remote control devices are often lost in dark areas where they are not in plain view, and therefore difficult to find. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Problems associated with finding these devices have been addressed in the prior art. The most common types of locating devices have detectors that have to be activated in order to be found. Typically, a user who has misplaced his remote control would activate some sort of transmitter usually located on the parent appliance (TV set or CD player etc). A receiver located in the remote control receives the transmitted signal. The reception of this signal triggers some sort of alarm on the remote control device, thereby enabling the user to find it. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A possible disadvantage associated with such a remote control locating device is that the locating function cannot operate in an automatic mode. In order to locate the misplaced remote, the user must first trigger the locating system. Another disadvantage is that these systems require extra components, such as the transmitter attached to the parent device, which can be costly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another known type of remote control locator device is the &ldquo;clapper&rdquo;. When the user has discovered that the device is missing, he activates an alarm in the remote control device by clapping his hands. This enables him to locate the remote control. Some of these remote control devices may also be voice responsive. Similar to the other devices, a disadvantage associated with these devices is that they cannot be operated in an automatic mode. In order to locate the misplaced remote, the user must trigger the locating system. Input such as clapping is required by the person looking for the remote. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In one respect, the invention is a method for locating a hidden object. This method involves several steps. One step is the sensing an ambient light level in the near proximity of the object. Another step is the determination of whether the light level is below a predetermined level. Another step in this method is the activation of an alarm connected to the object, in response to the determination step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In another respect, the invention is a device to aid in locating an object. In this respect, the device comprises an ambient light sensor that is connectable to the object. The device also comprises an alarm that is electrically connected to the ambient light sensor. The alarm is activated when the ambient light detector senses light at a level that is below a predetermined level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In this respect, the device may be divided into parts including, a first part and a second part. In this respect, the first part may consist of a first power source, a transistor, and the ambient light sensor. In this respect, the second part may consist of a second power source and the alarm. The system may also include an electro-magnetic relay that electrically connects the first part to the second part. The electro-magnetic relay may be connected to actuate the alarm when the ambient light photosensor senses light at a level below the predetermined level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In another respect, the invention is a system to aid in locating an object. In this respect, the system comprises an object and an ambient light sensor that is connected to the object. The system also includes an alarm that is electrically connected to the ambient light sensor. The alarm according to this invention is activated when the ambient light detector senses light at a level that is below a predetermined level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In this respect, the system to aid in locating an object may be divided into parts including, a first part and a second part. In this respect, the first part may consist of a first power source, a transistor, and the ambient light sensor. In this respect, the second part may consist of a second power source and the alarm. The system may also include an electro-magnetic relay that electrically connects the first part to the second part. The electro-magnetic relay may be connected to actuate the alarm when the ambient light photosensor senses light at a level below a predetermined level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In comparison to known prior art, certain embodiments of the invention are capable of achieving certain advantages. One advantage is the economy of parts associated with this device. The locating system is wholly independent of the parent device, and therefore does not require any additional elements in the parent device, such as transmitters etc. Another advantage is the use of a photosensor, which senses ambient conditions and reacts automatically to being placed in concealed locations. These and other advantages will be apparent to those skilled in the art upon reading the following detailed description of preferred embodiments, with reference to the below listed drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a wireless object according to a first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the circuitry of a wireless object locating system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> shows the Part A components of the circuitry of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> shows the Part B components of the circuitry of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the components of the electro-magnetic relay of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flowchart of a method according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to a first embodiment. This wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be a remote control device for operating a parent electronic appliance. The parent appliance may be a TV or a CD player or the like. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the wireless object has a control panel <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> that includes control buttons for operating the object related functions. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> also illustrates an alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> that is located on the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. This alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be a beeper, and upon actuation, may produce an audio signal to notify the user of its location. Also illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. This switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is used to disconnect the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, when the locating service is not desired. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> also illustrates an ambient light photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is preferably located on an upper face of the wireless object, i.e., the face of the device that has the control panel <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and the ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. However, the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be fitted on any other surface of the object without deviating from the scope and spirit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the circuitry of a wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> has a first power source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a resistor <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, a photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, and an electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. This system may also include a transistor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a second power source <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> also shows the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, which were already illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> can be divided into two parts, Part A and Part B, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> shows the Part A components of the circuitry of the wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Part A includes the power source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> that may be a conventional battery. The power source <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is connected to the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, which may be a photocell, such as a cadmium sulphide photo resistor. The photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> detects ambient light. The photocell operates in such a way that its resistance changes according to the amount of light that shines on it. The resistance of the photocell is inversely proportional to the light detected. As a result, current passing through the photocell <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> from the battery <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> changes in direct proportion to the amount of light shining on the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> also shows the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is the element that electrically couples Parts A and B of the system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. With respect to Part A, the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The current flowing from the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> activates the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Part A may also include a transistor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in conjunction with the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. This transistor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be necessary because the photocell may not be able to draw enough current to activate the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The transistor <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is used to amplify the current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> shows the Part B components of the circuitry of the wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Part B includes the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and the ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is also connected to the second power source <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. According to the switch setting, the power to the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can be turned OFF or turned ON. The default setting is preferably ON. This is achieved by having the switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> closed. However, the power to the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can also be turned OFF. The alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> can be turned OFF in one of two ways. First, a user using the ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> could disconnect the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> from the power source <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. The alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> could also be disengaged by the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, as will be described in reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the components of the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Also, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> schematically shows the connections to Parts A and B. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is the element that couples Parts A and B of the locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> includes an electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The relay system also includes a movable armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, which is biased by a spring <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> also shows a pair of contacts <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. The electro-magnetic relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be used to connect and to disconnect the alarm circuit. When a sufficiently strong current is flowing through the relay <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> becomes energized. This current is the output current from Part A. When the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> becomes energized, the armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is attracted towards the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and the armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> engages the contact <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. The effect of this is to keep the alarm circuit in an open or disengaged state. When no current flows or the current is sufficiently low, the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is not energized and the biasing force of the spring <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> pulls the armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> away from the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, bringing it into engagement with the contact <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. This closes/engages the alarm circuit in Part B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The general operation of the locating system is as follows. When the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> detects a sufficient amount of light, the cell has almost no resistance. Therefore it conducts electricity freely. In this instance, the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is energized. As a result, the armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is attracted by the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, brining it into engagement with the contact <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. As explained above, this causes the alarm circuit to open. As a result, no alarm is produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> When no light shines on the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the resistance becomes high, thereby restricting the flow of electricity to almost zero. Because of the inadequate flow of electricity, the electro-magnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is not energized, and the biasing force of the spring <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, pulls the armature <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> away from the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and into engagement with the contact <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. In effect, this closes the alarm circuit and activates the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. As stated above, the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is located on the upper surface of the object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Therefore, a &ldquo;no-light&rdquo; condition sensed is usually indicative of a situation where the object is covered or hidden. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flowchart of a method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. This figure outlines the steps performed by the wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in locating a wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, after the process has started, the wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> goes through a decision stage <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. At this decision stage <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, the position of the ON/OFF switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is considered. If the switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is in the OFF (open) position, then the entire process ends because in the OFF position, the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is disengaged. If, however, the switch <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is the ON (closed) position, the next stage <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is the sensing of the ambient light. This is performed by the ambient light photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, which is preferably positioned on the upper face of the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. After the ambient light has been sensed, the next stage is a decision stage <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>. At this stage, it is decided if the ambient conditions are too dark, i.e., if the ambient light is below a predetermined level. If the answer is NO, then wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> re-starts the process and repeats step <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and the relevant subsequent steps. If the decision at stage <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> is YES, i.e., the ambient lighting is too dark, i.e., if the ambient light is below a predetermined level, then the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is activated in step <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. This ends the process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> With respect to the predetermined level of light, it should be noted that a predetermined level of light might be any chosen level of light in a lighting spectrum that ranges from absolute darkness to visible light. This predetermined level can be varied to any desired level. For most users, the predetermined level would be closer to the absolute darkness portion of the spectrum. However, in the case of a visually impaired user, the predetermined level may be closer to the visible light portion of the spectrum. The light level at which the alarm is activated may be altered by adjusting the strengths of the electromagnet <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and/or the strength of the spring <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In the vast majority of cases, the predetermined level is not a parameter that demands exact determination. The predetermined level is simply a threshold level that distinguishes the relatively well-lit condition to which the object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is typically exposed when uncovered, from the relatively dark condition to which the object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is typically exposed when covered. Those skilled in the art can easily conduct an experiment to measure these two extreme conditions and pick any level intermediate to these extremes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be integrated with the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In other words, the wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be formed as an integral part of the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> during the manufacture of the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The wireless object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may also be attached or retrofitted onto the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> subsequent to the manufacture of the wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In the case of a remote control device, the object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be incorporated with the remote control device at the manufacturing stage, or the object locating system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be retrofitted to a pre-existing remote control device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> With respect to the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, it has already been stated that the alarm may be a noisemaker such as a beeper that upon activation may produce an audio signal. In addition to a noisemaker, the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be any known type that is applicable to this invention. For instance, the alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be a flasher that may preferably emit bright light. Preferably the flasher is located on a surface different from that of the photosensor <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The light emitted would enable a user to locate the lost object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may also be a vibrator that signals a user by vibrating. The alarm <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may also be a beacon signal (radio frequency) transmitter that may produce a &ldquo;lost&rdquo; signal to a user via a receiver of some type. The receiver may be in a separate device. In the case where the lost wireless object <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is a remote control device, the receiver may be located in the parent appliance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> What has been described and illustrated herein are preferred embodiments of the invention along with some variations. The terms, descriptions and figures used herein are set forth by way of illustration only and are not meant as limitations. For instance, the remote control device may be for the operation of other devices other than those mentioned specifically herein. Those skilled in the art will recognize that many variations are possible within the spirit and scope of the invention, which is intended to be defined by the following claims and their equivalents, in which all terms are meant in their broadest reasonable sense unless otherwise indicated. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for locating a hidden object, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>sensing an ambient light level in the near proximity of the object; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining if the light level is below a predetermined level; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>activating an alarm connected to the object, in response to the determining step. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing step comprises sensing an ambient light level at an upper surface of the object. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the alarm is one or more selected from the group consisting of a noisemaker, a light emitter, a vibrator, and a radio signal transmitter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the object is a remote control device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sensing of the ambient light is performed with a photosensor, and the alarm is triggered by the photosensor activating the alarm via an electro-magnetic relay device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a switch is used to electrically disengage the alarm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A device to aid in locating an object, the device comprising: 
<claim-text>an ambient light sensor connectable to the object; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an alarm electrically connected to the ambient light sensor, wherein the alarm is activated when the ambient light detector senses light at a level below a predetermined level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the device is divided into parts including a first part and a second part, the first part comprising: 
<claim-text>a first power source, a transistor, and the ambient light sensor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second part comprises: 
<claim-text>a second power source and the alarm. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, the device further comprising: 
<claim-text>an electro-magnetic relay, the electro-magnetic relay electrically connecting the first part to the second part, the electro-magnetic relay connected to activate the alarm when the ambient light photosensor senses light at a level below a predetermined level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a switch in the second part electrically connected the second power source, for deactivating the locating device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the alarm is one or more selected from the group consisting of a noisemaker, a light emitter, a vibrator, and a radio signal transmitter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The device <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ambient light photosensor is a cadmium sulphide photoresistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A system to aid in locating an object, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>the object; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an ambient light sensor connected to the object; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an alarm electrically connected to the ambient light sensor, wherein the alarm is activated when the ambient light detector senses light at a level below a predetermined level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the system is divided into parts including a first part and a second part, the first part comprising: 
<claim-text>a first power source, a transistor, and the ambient light sensor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the second part comprises: 
<claim-text>a second power source and the alarm. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, the system further comprising: 
<claim-text>an electro-magnetic relay, the electro-magnetic relay electrically connecting the first part to the second part, the electro-magnetic relay connected to activate the alarm when the ambient light photosensor senses light at a level below a predetermined level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>a switch in the second part electrically connected the second power source, for deactivating the locating system. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the alarm is one or more selected from the group consisting of a noisemaker, a light emitter, a vibrator, and a radio signal transmitter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ambient light photosensor is a cadmium sulphide photoresistor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001738A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
