<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000737A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000737A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000737A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000737A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000737A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000737A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000737A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000737A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000737A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000737A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000737</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10186441</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020701</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L023/14</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H05K007/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>256000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>704000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>680000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>174</class>
<subclass>052400</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>762000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>361</class>
<subclass>761000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Masking layer in substrate cavity</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301985</doc-number>
<document-date>20010630</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jwei</given-name>
<middle-name>Wien</middle-name>
<family-name>Liu</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Plano</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>O&apos;Connor</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TEXAS INSTRUMENTS INCORPORATED</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P O BOX 655474, M/S 3999</address-1>
<city>DALLAS</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75265</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A package that resists creation of particles in a package cavity. The package is ideally suited for use with microelectromechanical devices. A package according to one embodiment of the present invention contains a mechanical device (<highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>), for example a micromirror device, attached to the floor (<highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) of the package substrate (<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>). Epoxy (<highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>) typically is used to attach the device (<highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). Electrical connections are provided by bond wires (<highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>) connecting bond pads (<highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>) on the substrate (<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>) with bond pads on the device (<highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>). A window (<highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>) is attached to the substrate (<highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>) to form a cavity (<highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>) around the device. A thin masking layer (<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>) on portions of the package cavity surface prevents the surface from generating particles. The thin masking layer (<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>) may be any material that resists particle generation. Malleable metals are ideal. For example, gold plating on the inner cavity walls bonds well to the ceramic surfaces, captures particles that are already loose, and resists chipping to avoid the generation of additional particles. The masking layer (<highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>) on the cavity walls optionally extends out of the cavity and onto the upper surface of the package. The preceding abstract is submitted with the understanding that it only will be used to assist in determining, from a cursory inspection, the nature and gist of the technical disclosure as described in 37 C.F.R. &sect;1.72(b). In no case should this abstract be used for interpreting the scope of any patent claims. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to the field of semiconductor packaging, more particularly to packaging of micro-electro-optical systems (MEOMS) and micro-electro-mechanical systems (MEMS). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Micromechanical devices are small structures typically fabricated on a semiconductor wafer using techniques such as optical lithography, doping, metal sputtering, oxide deposition, and plasma etching which have been developed for the fabrication of integrated circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Micromirror devices are a type of micromechanical device. Micromirror devices are primarily used in optical display systems. In display systems, the micromirror is a light modulator that uses digital image data to modulate a beam of light by selectively reflecting portions of the beam of light to a display screen. Other types of micromechanical devices include accelerometers, pressure and flow sensors, gears and motors. While some micromechanical devices, such as pressure sensors, flow sensors, and micromirrors have found commercial success, other types have not yet been commercially viable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Packaging MEOMS and MEMS presents special challenges. In the case of the micromirror device, the package must provide a hermetically, or near-hermetically sealed environment while providing a distortion-free optical path to the surface of the device and a large number of electrical connections to the device. The package must also me robust enough to withstand extreme thermal gradients when the micromirror array is illuminated by a high optical flux beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the package must not create particles during the life of the device. Particles generated within the device can enter the moving superstructure of the MEMS device and electrically short circuit portions of the device or mechanically block the movement of the moving parts. Because of the moving parts and the requirement for some devices to maintain an optical path with the device in the package, the package cavity cannot simply be filled with a potting compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Ceramic substrates are preferred for micromirror devices because they provide a good barrier against moisture entering the package. Additionally, ceramic substrates are mechanically robust, allowing them to withstand stresses generated by uneven heating that occurs when the micromirror is illuminated. Unfortunately, ceramic substrates generate particles that can destroy the packaged devices. What is needed is a method and system for preventing particle generation by ceramic package substrates. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Objects and advantages will be obvious, and will in part appear hereinafter and will be accomplished by the present invention which provides a method and system for coating the inside of a ceramic package substrate to prevent particle generation. One embodiment of the claimed invention provides a method of forming a package substrate. The method comprising: forming a substrate, the substrate having a cavity; and coating portions of the cavity surface with a masking layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the present invention provides a package. The package comprising: a substrate having an upper surface and a cavity surface formed therein, the cavity having at least one wall surface and at least one floor surface; a device attached to the cavity floor; a lid attached to the upper surface enclosing the device; and a masking layer on at least a portion of the cavity surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Yet another embodiment of the present invention provides a package substrate. The package substrate comprising: a substrate having an upper surface and a cavity surface formed therein, the cavity having at least one wall surface and at least one floor surface; and a masking layer on at least a portion of the cavity surface. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For a more complete understanding of the present invention, and the advantages thereof, reference is now made to the following descriptions taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a small portion of a micromirror array of the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of a single micromirror element from the micromirror array of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross section side view of a micromechanical device in a package according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a ceramic substrate according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides an improved package and package substrate that is useful for packaging of MEMS devices. Particle generation by the substrate is reduced by the application of a liner over the inner ceramic surfaces. The liner is particularly useful when applied over the rough edges of the substrate cavity wall and over the sharp edges of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The improved package substrate of the present invention is particularly useful when used to package micromirror devices such as the one shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> typical hidden-hinge micromirror <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is actually an orthogonal array of micromirror cells, or elements. This array often includes more than a thousand rows and columns of micromirrors. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a small portion of a micromirror array of the prior art with several mirrors <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> removed to show the underlying mechanical structure of the micromirror array. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an exploded view of a single micromirror element of the prior art further detailing the relationships between the micromirror structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A micromirror is fabricated on a semiconductor, typically silicon, substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Electrical control circuitry is typically fabricated in or on the surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> using standard integrated circuit process flows. This circuitry typically includes, but is not limited to, a memory cell associated with, and typically underlying, each mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and digital logic circuits to control the transfer of the digital image data to the underlying memory cells. Voltage driver circuits to drive bias and reset signals to the mirror superstructure may also be fabricated on the micromirror substrate, or may be external to the micromirror. Image processing and formatting logic is also formed in the substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of some designs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The silicon substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and any necessary metal interconnection layers are isolated from the micromirror superstructure by an insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which is typically a deposited silicon dioxide layer on which the micromirror superstructure is formed. Holes, or vias, are opened in the oxide layer to allow electrical connection of the micromirror superstructure with the electronic circuitry formed in the substrate <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Address electrodes <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and a mirror bias connection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are formed from a metal layer deposited on the insulating layer <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Some micromirror designs have separate and distinct landing electrodes that are electrically connected to the mirror bias connection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Landing electrodes limit the rotation of the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and prevent the rotated mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> from touching the address electrodes <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, which have a voltage potential relative to the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. If the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> contacts the address electrodes <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the resulting short circuit could fuse the torsion hinges <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> or weld the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the address electrodes <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, in either case ruining the micromirror. Since the same voltage is always applied both to the landing electrodes and the mirrors <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the mirror bias connection and the landing electrodes are combined in a single structure when possible. The landing electrodes are combined with the mirror bias connection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> by including regions on the mirror bias/reset connection <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, called landing sites, which mechanically limit the rotation of the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by contacting either the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> or the torsion hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. These landing sites are often coated with a material chosen to reduce the tendency of the mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and torsion hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> to stick to the landing site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Hinge support spacervias <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and upper address electrode spacervias <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, typically extend approximately 1 &mgr;m above the address electrodes <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and mirror bias connections <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. A hinge cap <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and upper address electrodes <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> are supported by the hinge support spacervias <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and upper address electrode spacervias <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The hinge cap <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> anchors the ends of torsion hinges <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. A hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is formed between and supported by the torsion hinges <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is allowed to rotate by twisting the thin torsion hinges <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. A mirror support spacervia <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is formed on the hinge yoke, and supports a mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> approximately 2 &mgr;m above the hinge yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Electrostatic attraction between an address electrode <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and a deflectable rigid member, which in effect form the two plates of an air gap capacitor, is used to rotate the mirror structure. Depending on the design of the micromirror device, the deflectable rigid member is the torsion beam yoke <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, the beam or mirror <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a beam attached directly to the torsion hinges, or a combination thereof. The upper address electrodes <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> also electrostatically attract the deflectable rigid member. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross section side view of a micromechanical device, in a package according to one embodiment of the present invention. The mechanical device <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, for example a micromirror device, is attached to the floor <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of the package substrate <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, typically by epoxy <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Electrical connections are provided by bond wires <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> connecting bond pads <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> on the substrate with bond pads on the device <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. A window <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> is attached to the substrate <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> to form a cavity <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> around the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Ceramic is the material of choice for hermetic device package substrates. Unfortunately, ceramic substrates create many particles that can destroy the MEMS device. Of particular concern are the sharp edges and cavity walls. The sharp edges create particles because the concentration of forces on the thin sharp edge makes it easy for particles to break away from the edge. The exterior edges of the ceramic substrate are chamfered to prevent this. Unfortunately, there is no automated process for chamfering the inner edges of the cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A second particle-rich area is the rough cavity wall. Not only does the rough surface of the inner cavity wall harbor particles, the rough surface creates many points susceptible, like the sharp edges mentioned above, to fracture. Furthermore, the rough edges are often fractured during substrate manufacture leaving particles that can easily break free. Current processes use a chemical process to smooth the inner cavity wall. This is a manual process and is expensive and time consuming to perform. The surfaces of the package cavity not only are difficult to clean, and therefore likely to harbor and create particles, but any particles created by the cavity surfaces will be captured in the sealed package where they are likely eventually to damage the packaged device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A solution to the particle generation problem is to apply a thin masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> to the portions of the package cavity surface that source particles. The thin masking layer may be any material that resists particle generation. Malleable metals are ideal. For example, gold plating on the inner cavity walls bonds well to the ceramic surfaces, captures particles that are already loose, and resists chipping to avoid the generation of additional particles. A further benefit of gold plating is the ability of gold, as well as many other metals, to withstand the lubricants often used in MEMS packages. For example, the perfluordecanoic acid used in micromirror packages. Since gold is already used to form the bond pads <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> on the cavity floor, the additional steps need to add the plating to the cavity walls are minimal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> on the cavity walls extends out of the cavity and onto the upper surface of the package. Although this extension <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is not necessary, it does make it easier to completely enclose the upper sharp edge of the cavity. The extension <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may also be used to attach the window <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, in the case of a micromirror package, or lid. A further benefit of the extension <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of the masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is that it raises the window <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> further above the MEMS device <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. In a micromirror system, raising the package window moves it further out of the focal plane and makes defects in the glass less visible&mdash;allowing higher yields with the use of cheaper materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a portion of a ceramic substrate according to one embodiment of the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> extends across the floor <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of the package cavity. Thus, the masking layer nearly covers the entire substrate in the cavity. When a conductive masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is used, for example a metal layer, gaps must be formed between the bond pads <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and the masking layer <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The masking layer described above may be applied in a number of ways. For example, a metal masking layer may be sputtered over the cavity surface, with areas masked to prevent bonding with the substrate. The masking layer may also be plated on the surface. Other masking materials, such as epoxy, lend themselves to methods of spraying or brushing the masking layer onto the surface of the cavity. Excess masking materials may be removed by chemical processes, such as various etch steps, or by laser etching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Thus, although there has been disclosed to this point a particular embodiment for a masking layer in a substrate cavity and method therefore, it is not intended that such specific references be considered as limitations upon the scope of this invention except insofar as set forth in the following claims. Furthermore, having described the invention in connection with certain specific embodiments thereof, it is to be understood that further modifications may now suggest themselves to those skilled in the art, it is intended to cover all such modifications as fall within the scope of the appended claims. In the following claims, only elements denoted by the words &ldquo;means for&rdquo; are intended to be interpreted as means plus function claims under 35 U.S.C. &sect;112, paragraph six. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a package substrate comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a substrate, said substrate having a cavity; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>coating portions of said cavity surface with a masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said forming comprising forming a ceramic substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising coating walls of said cavity with said masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising coating walls of said cavity with a gold masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising coating walls of said cavity with an epoxy masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising sputtering walls of said cavity with a metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising plating walls of said cavity with a metal layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said coating comprising coating walls of said cavity with a masking layer extending onto an upper surface of said substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A package comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate, said substrate having an upper surface and a cavity surface formed therein, said cavity having at least one wall surface and at least one floor surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a device attached to said cavity floor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lid attached to said upper surface enclosing said device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a masking layer on at least a portion of said cavity surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said lid comprising a window. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a metal masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising an epoxy masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a gold masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer on said cavity walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer on said cavity floor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer extending onto said upper surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The package of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, said lid attached to said masking layer extending onto said upper surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A package substrate comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate, said substrate having an upper surface and a cavity surface formed therein, said cavity having at least one wall surface and at least one floor surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a masking layer on at least a portion of said cavity surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a metal masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising an epoxy masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a gold masking layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer on said cavity walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer on said cavity floor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The package substrate of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, said masking layer comprising a masking layer extending onto said upper surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000737A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000737A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000737A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000737A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000737A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
