<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004733</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09882198</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010615</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F017/60</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>705</class>
<subclass>001000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Pet food kiosk</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gregory</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Norsworthy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lexington</city>
<state>KY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bryan</given-name>
<middle-name>Wilson</middle-name>
<family-name>Badger</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Kirkwood</city>
<state>MO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bhajmohan</given-name>
<middle-name>(Ricky)</middle-name>
<family-name>Singh</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>St. Louis</city>
<state>MO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<family-name>Carvalho</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ballwin</city>
<state>MO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>John S. Beulick</name-1>
<name-2>Armstrong Teasdale LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2600</address-1>
<address-2>One Metropolitan Sq.</address-2>
<city>St. Louis</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>63102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A kiosk configured for selling and manufacturing customized food for a pet is disclosed. The kiosk comprises a customer interface area, a biological sample analysis and handling area, a base product display area, a product additive storage area, and an ingredient mixing and customer observation area. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to methods for marketing pet foods, and more particularly, to an apparatus configured to the manufacture of a pet food customized to the health and nutrition requirements of an individual pet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Retail pet food manufacturers typically manufacture their pet foods in large quantities and in only a limited number of formulations. Most manufacturers offer, for example, dog food in several flavors, and in a puppy formula, an adult dog formula, and a mature or inactive dog formula. Some manufacturers offer breed-specific or size-specific formulas. In addition, some manufacturers offer more specialized formulas for dogs having specific food allergies or nutrient responsive diseases. Similarly, retail cat food is typically offered in a limited variety of formulas having different flavors or for different stages of development. However, all of the above described food selections are for a totally pre-made product and hence the range of pet food choices is not necessarily compatible with the highly variable preferences and dietary requirements of individual pets. Thus, making a selection to suit a particular pet&apos;s dietary needs is sometimes difficult and sub-optimal. For example, an individual pet may have specific dietary requirements because of an existing illness or disease, or because of a genetic predisposition towards a particular disease. Further, the existing variety of pet food choices typically available at, for example, retail outlets, makes it difficult for pet owners to choose the food which most closely meets their own pet&apos;s nutrient needs. In addition, once a food is chosen, knowing how to feed the food correctly can be difficult. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In one aspect, a kiosk is provided which is configured for selling and manufacturing a customized food for a pet. The kiosk comprises a customer interface area, a biological sample analysis and handling area, a base product display area, a product additive storage area, and an ingredient mixing and customer observation area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, a method is provided for marketing a customized food product for a pet using a kiosk, where the kiosk includes at least one of a consumer interaction station, an analysis station, and a workstation. The method comprises providing a questionnaire at the consumer interaction station to profile the pets, performing an analysis of a biological sample for a pet at the analysis workstation, determining a customized pet food product based on the questionnaire answers and the biological sample, and preparing a sample of the customized product for the consumer at the workstation.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a simplified kiosk for marketing a customized pet food. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagram of a workstation used to customize pet food. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a flowchart illustrating a customized pet food marketing process.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Exemplary embodiments of apparatus and methods for marketing customized pet products are described below. The apparatus and methods facilitate the manufacture of a customized product that is directed to the specific needs of an individual pet. As used hereinafter, pet product includes pet foods as well as pet food components. Although the pet products may include food components that are manufactured in bulk, i.e., pre-made, the pre-made components are combined with customized products to produce an end product that is customized to the particular needs of an individual pet. Thus, the phrase customized product includes products that have no pre-made food components as well as products that include pre-made food components and custom made products. In addition, although the method is often described in terms of a complete process, it should be understood that any portion of the process can be used separately or in combination with any other portion of the process described hereinafter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a simplified diagram of a kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment of the present invention. In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a customer interface area <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a biological sample analysis and handling area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a base product storage area <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, at least one product additive storage area <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and an ingredient mixing and customer observation area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, product additive storage area <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> includes dry inventory storage and liquid inventory storage. In the exemplary embodiment, areas <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> described above are incorporated into three stations, a consumer interaction station <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an analysis station <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and a workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In a further exemplary embodiment, consumer interaction station <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, analysis station <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are constructed using at least one of wire shelving <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, stainless steel supports <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, plastic bins (not shown), drawers (not shown) and laminated wood or steel shelves <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A height of shelves <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and wire shelving <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is adjustable so that a kiosk operator (not shown) can arrange kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a manner that is most efficient for that operator. In one embodiment, consumer interaction station <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes brochures describing the customized pet food product. In an alternative embodiment, biological sample analysis and handling area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is configured with a biological sample disposal area (not shown). In still another embodiment, biological sample and analysis and handling area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is configured with a computer (not shown) used for analysis of the biological samples along with other instruments, including, but not limited to, a microscope and utensils. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a set of wheels <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and is configured to be portable. Although not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in other embodiments, kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is configured to be covered and locked, for security when, for example, kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is located in a shopping mall. One method for covering kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a custom cover, made for example, from canvas, which slips over kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and is locked to kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of wheels <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Further, kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is configurable to be expanded or contracted based upon the space available. In an alternative embodiment, workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes the functionality of analysis station <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, thus providing a kiosk with two stations, and base product storage combined with product additive dry storage. Being expandable and contractable allows for placement of kiosks, in various configurations, for example, at the end cap of an aisle in a store, or alternatively, freestanding such as in a shopping mall. Not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, and depending upon a location (e.g. veterinarian, shopping mall, pet food store) of each individual kiosk, kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is configurable to include graphic side panels and other advertising materials to draw attention of consumers to kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, consumer interaction station <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a computer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for storing custom pet product groupings for one or more pets analyzed, where the consumer can return to kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to quickly purchase additional supplies of the pet product in either a completed form, or alternatively, the consumer purchases the product additives, dry or liquid, for adding to a base product which can be purchased elsewhere. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagram of one embodiment of workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Components of workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, identical to those components shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, are identified in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> using the same reference numerals as used in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Referring specifically to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes wire shelving <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> for storage, a steel shelf <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> used as a work surface, and drawers <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> for storage of supplies used by the kiosk operator (not shown). Stocked on wire shelves <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are bags of base formula food (kibble) <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and other dry ingredients <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, there are multiple varieties of base formula foods <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and the variety used in developing a customized food for a particular pet is based upon the pet&apos;s needs, as further described in an example below. Further stocked on shelves <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are empty bottles <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> used to provide additives to customers, measuring spoons <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and measuring cups <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> which are provided to customers as part of the customized pet food purchase or sold separately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As the kiosk operator prepares customized food for a pet, which is placed in bottle <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> for presentment to a customer, the operator prepares a customized additive for the particular pet using at least one of packets <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of dry additive or one of a variety of liquid additives stored in dispensers <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Other dry ingredients <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> include at least one of base formula foods <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, extra bottles <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, packets <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, spoons <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and cups <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> stored in bulk. As described in further detail below, the kiosk operator prepares a custom additive, using at least one of packets <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and liquids in dispensers <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to be stored in bottle <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and presented to the customer. In one embodiment, the dry ingredients in packets <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and the liquids in dispensers <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> include multiple, different varieties for preparing unique customized additives to be added to one of base formula foods <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a method <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of obtaining a customized pet food product utilizing kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In an exemplary embodiment, a pet owner (consumer) that is a first-time purchaser of a customized pet food product approaches <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> pet food product kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, or booth, located in a retail location, including but not limited to, a mall, a store, a veterinarian office, a clinic, an airport, and an outdoor event. In other embodiments, customer interest is solicited through any one of direct mail, electronic mail, brochures and telephone. The consumer supplies <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> a biological sample (i.e., stool sample) and completes a questionnaire, typically at customer interaction station <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The questionnaire is provided in advance of the visit on the Internet, in the mail, or personally picked up and answered at kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The questionnaire profiles the pet. In an alternative embodiment, customer interest is solicited by supplying a customer with a bag to contain a biological sample for analysis at kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> using a direct mail campaign. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, analytical data is obtained from the biological sample by a veterinarian/technician located on site, for example at biological sample and analysis and handling area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). In an alternative embodiment, the sample is sent to a central lab for analysis. The analysis is performed on the biological sample with respect to examining several health and digestive indicators. Data from the biological sample analysis is combined <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> with the pet profile information and entered into a system, for example, computer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), including a pet food product customization model. Alternatively, the biological sample analysis is forwarded by the pet&apos;s veterinarian to the kiosk operator and the results are incorporated into the pet profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The system processes <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> the data utilizing at least one algorithm and generates a pet profile. Each profile has a unique identifying code and contains the specific customized food product and feeding instructions recommended for the specific pet. The recommended food product includes a pre-manufactured kibble, typically stored at base product display area <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the kibble being sometimes referred to as base formula food <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and a customized additive, sometimes referred to herein as a sauce. In one embodiment, the pre-manufactured kibble is selected from a variety of pre-manufactured base formula foods <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and the additive is a liquid additive that is made on site, typically in the presence of the consumer, and typically at mixing and observation area <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The system directs <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> the kiosk operator to the pre-manufactured kibble best suited for the pet and supplies <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> the operator with a customized additive formula that has been created based upon the individual pet&apos;s profile. Alternatively, the system indicates a recommendation for the pet to see a veterinarian prior to buying a customized food, if certain &ldquo;warning&rdquo; signs are present in the profile. This warning provides the consumer with added health information about the pet between regular vet visits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The kiosk operator then obtains <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> a bag of the recommended kibble and prepares <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> a food additive in bottle <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) using an additive formula at workstation <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, including, but not limited to, a sauce, a gravy, a topping, a thickener, a powder, and a coating, utilizing the customized additive formula. In the exemplary embodiment, a sauce is made. In addition, customized feeding instructions and package labels are printed <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The consumer is provided <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> a package containing a bag of dry base formula food <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, such as kibbles, a bottle <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of customized sauce, printed information, a customized measuring cup <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) for the dry kibbles, a custom-selected spoon <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) for measuring the sauce into the food bowl, and any other accessories associated with the custom food purchase. Additionally, the consumer receives information about the recommended frequency and conditions of future biological sample analyses and/or profile updates for their pet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, the pet profile is utilized by the system to direct the kiosk operator to a pre-manufactured kibble (base formula food <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) best suited for the pet and a pre-manufactured sauce best suited for the pet. The kiosk operator provides the consumer with the appropriate pre-manufactured kibble and pre-manufactured sauce and the consumer mixes the appropriate amounts of each for the pet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> For a repeat purchase, a consumer returns to kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and provides their pet&apos;s unique code, generated during a previous visit, to access their pet&apos;s profile. They may update/change the profile information and/or provide a new biological sample, either of which could result in a difference in the recommended food, either the base formula food <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> or the product additive or both. Alternatively, the consumer leaves the profile as is and replenishes their pet&apos;s current food supply. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The process described above is further illustrated by an example. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> A pet questionnaire is administered regarding a pet named &ldquo;Bruno&rdquo; at a remote manufacturing location, such as a retail store. The questionnaire is completed by Bruno&apos;s owner and the following information, among other information, is obtained about Bruno, and provided to the operator of kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="133PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Name of pet:</entry>
<entry>Bruno</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Breed of Pet:</entry>
<entry>Golden Retriever</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Weight:</entry>
<entry>65 lbs</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Age:</entry>
<entry>4 Years</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Gender:</entry>
<entry>Male</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Spayed/Neutered:</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Activity Level:</entry>
<entry>Moderate</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Season:</entry>
<entry>Summer</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Feeding Method:</entry>
<entry>Measured</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Snack Schedule:</entry>
<entry>Once a day</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Flavor Preference:</entry>
<entry>Chicken for Base and Beef Stew for Sauce</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Body Condition:</entry>
<entry>Ideal/Fit</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In addition or in a subsequent visit, Bruno&apos;s owner delivers a typical stool sample of Bruno to the kiosk operator where the feeding and care program is being administered. The following stool sample analyses of Bruno is performed.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="91PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="91PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Moisture:</entry>
<entry>Normal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Texture:</entry>
<entry>High-Above Normal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Discomfort:</entry>
<entry>Yes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Particulates:</entry>
<entry>None</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Color:</entry>
<entry>Normal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Mucin:</entry>
<entry>None to Normal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Parasites:</entry>
<entry>None</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Based on the above information, a pre-manufactured kibble (Base B2) is selected that is appropriate for adult, medium sized dogs with a moderate level of activity, good body condition score, the desired flavor preference and no other special health condition. Based on the kibble selected, a pre-manufactured sauce is selected (S4) which is appropriate for dogs with hard stool and/or fecal straining issues. The sauce is formulated to be distributed in a 10 oz. bottle and to complement a 5 lb. bag of dry kibble. The sauce&apos;s composition is:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sauce Percentage</entry>
<entry>12.50%</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Base Code</entry>
<entry>B2 (Adult)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sauce Code</entry>
<entry>S4 Overweight w/Fiber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Formula No.</entry>
<entry>Beef Stew</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Ingredient Name</entry>
<entry>Step %</entry>
<entry>Formula %</entry>
<entry>Grams</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Animal Digest</entry>
<entry>15.2%</entry>
<entry>1.90%</entry>
<entry>48.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sodium Bisulfate</entry>
<entry>3.8%</entry>
<entry>0.48%</entry>
<entry>12.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Deionized Water</entry>
<entry>56.2%</entry>
<entry>7.03%</entry>
<entry>180.0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Sorbic Acid</entry>
<entry>0.2%</entry>
<entry>0.02%</entry>
<entry>0.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Psyllium</entry>
<entry>0.6%</entry>
<entry>0.07%</entry>
<entry>1.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Corn Oil</entry>
<entry>16.00%</entry>
<entry>2.00%</entry>
<entry>51.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Lactulose</entry>
<entry>8.00%</entry>
<entry>1.00%</entry>
<entry>25.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Beef Stew Flavor</entry>
<entry>0.20%</entry>
<entry>0.03%</entry>
<entry>0.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Total Percentage</entry>
<entry>100.0%</entry>
<entry>12.50%</entry>
<entry>320.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Next, an appropriate daily feeding amount is calculated based on the nutrient profile and &ldquo;sauce&rdquo; selected, the weight of the dog, body condition, season of the year and snacking habit. Both the pre-manufactured kibble and the pre-manufactured sauce are given to the owner with feeding instructions and a copy of the above report. A copy of the individual pet profile and sample stool test is sent to Bruno&apos;s veterinarian. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The methods for customizing pet foods and pet products provide a way for pet food manufacturers to address the individualized health and nutrition requirements, and preferences, of individual pets and their owners. For example, the customized pet food and pet products can be tailored to provide a desired nutritional balance for a pet of a specific age, gender and weight, at a particular time of year, and having a specific health problem, such as, for example, a food allergy. Kiosk <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> provides means and a way for engaging consumers in the marketplace, to introduce the consumers to customized pet foods and further leaves an impression with the consumers of high quality pet and pet food products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in terms of various specific embodiments, those skilled in the art will recognize that the invention can be practiced with modification within the spirit and scope of the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A kiosk configured for selling and manufacturing customized food for a pet, said kiosk comprising: 
<claim-text>a customer interface area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a biological sample analysis and handling area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a base product display area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one product additive storage area; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an ingredient mixing and customer observation area. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said biological sample analysis and handling area is configured with a biological sample disposal area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said kiosk is further configured to be expanded or contracted. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said kiosk is further configured to be portable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said kiosk is further configured to be covered and locked. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a base product storage area. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said kiosk is constructed from at least one of wire shelving, stainless steel supports, plastic bins, and laminated wood and stainless steel shelving. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said at least one product additive storage area is stocked with at least one of a dry inventory and a liquid inventory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said kiosk comprises three separate units, including at least one of a consumer interaction station, an analysis station, and a workstation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a computer configured to store at least one custom pet food for an individual pet profile. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A kiosk according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising graphics panels to advertise said kiosk and the functionality of said kiosk. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for marketing a customized food product for a pet using a kiosk, the kiosk including at least one of a consumer interaction station, an analysis station, and a workstation, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a questionnaire at the consumer interaction station for profiling pets; </claim-text>
<claim-text>performing an analysis of a biological sample for a pet at the analysis station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a customized pet food product formula based on the questionnaire answers and the biological sample at the analysis station; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>preparing a sample of the customized product for the consumer at the workstation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising storing results of the questionnaire and the biological sample analysis as a pet profile at the analysis station. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising using the pet profile stored at the analysis station to prepare additional portions of the product additive at the workstation for repeat consumers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein preparing a sample of the customized product at the workstation further comprises preparing a custom product additive to be added to a base formula. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising affixing graphics panels to at least one of the consumer interaction station, the analysis station, and the workstation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein preparing a sample of the customized product comprises adding at least one of a dry product additive and a liquid additive to the base formula. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein receiving a customized pet food product formula further comprises modeling questionnaire responses and the analysis of the biological sample. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein performing an analysis of a biological sample for a pet comprises performing the analysis using a computer located at the analysis station. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for providing a customized food product for a pet using a kiosk, the kiosk including at least one of a customer interface area, a biological sample analysis and handling area, a base product storage area, at least one product additive storage area, and an ingredient mixing and customer observation area, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving at least one of a biological sample and pet questionnaire information at the customer interface area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>processing the data from the sample and the questionnaire at the biological sample analysis and handling area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a kibble from the base product storage area based on the processed data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mixing a customized additive from ingredients stored in the product additive storage area at the ingredient mixing and customer observation area based on the processed data; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>presenting the selected kibble and the customized additive to the customer at the ingredient mixing and customer observation area. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein processing the data from the sample and the questionnaire further comprises generating feeding instructions and package labels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein presenting the selected kibble and the customized additive further comprises providing feeding instructions and package labels to the customer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein presenting the selected kibble and the customized additive further comprises presenting the customer with a customized measuring scoop for the kibble and a custom-selected spoon for the customized additive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein presenting the selected kibble and the customized additive further comprises presenting the customer with recommendations concerning frequency and conditions of future biological sample analyses and profile updates for their pet.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004733A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004733A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004733A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004733A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
