<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000466A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000466A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000466</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10230662</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020828</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B05C011/11</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>504000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Electrostatic coating apparatus and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10230662</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020828</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09969832</doc-number>
<document-date>20011002</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6464787</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09969832</doc-number>
<document-date>20011002</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09522784</doc-number>
<document-date>20000310</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6325899</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Charles</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>DeWent</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>El Cajon</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BROWN, MARTIN, HALLER &amp; MCCLAIN LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1660 UNION STREET</address-1>
<city>SAN DIEGO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92101-2926</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The invention relates to an intermediate component for protecting hangers associated with electrostatic coating processes. The component is an electrically conductive, pliable, tubular member, and inexpensive relative to the hanger which it serves to protect. The component lessens the cost associated with traditional hanger cleaning and preserves hanger life and integrity. The tubular member may have a longitudinal slit for installing the member over a cross bar of a hanger. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a Continuation-in-Part of Application Ser. No. 09/522,784 filed Mar. 10, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Electrostatic coating processes rely on a charge differential between an article to be coated and what is used to coat that article. In such processes, the article is typically grounded whereas the coating to be applied is endowed with a charge. When the article and coating are then brought into contact with one another, the result is that the coating adheres to the article. It is estimated that more than 10,000 facilities for accomplishing this exist in the US alone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Most such coating procedures and facilities employ a variety of steps, i.e., a cleaning step, a drying step, a coating step, and a heating step wherein the adhered coating is cured to afford a more desirable and permanent coat. These steps usually take place sequentially using batch operations commonly employed in the art, or else in specialized stations connected by a continuous conveyor line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conveyor lines can be of varying length depending on the facility. Articles to be coated are hung from these lines via spaced electroconductive racks or hangers that serve to ground articles attached thereto. Racks and hangers are popular that have the capacity to hang multiple articles. This is accomplished by multiple hooks, usually spot welded at set distances from one another on the same rack. Such rack and hook configurations vary widely in shape, size, and configuration to support different types and sizes of articles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Once attached, the hangers or racks bearing grounded articles are conveyed through a coating station followed by a curing station. Once coating and curing are finished, the coated objects are removed and the process begins anew. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The hangers and racks of such systems, being expensive, are typically re-used. After passing through the painting station a number of times, that portion or portions of the hanger which contact the article gradually becomes fouled by coating. The net effect is interference with grounding capacity, with consequent poor transfer efficiency and an eventual possibility for spark or fire. This necessitates periodic replacing or cleaning, which is both time-consuming and expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the case of recycling, conventional cleaning methods include chemical stripping, molten bath stripping, burning, and mechanical stripping, i.e., sandblasting, hammering, and filing. These processes reduce the useful life and capacity of racks by compromising their structural integrity over time. For example, it is the Applicants&apos; experience that hooks break off fairly regularly, thereby lessening the capacity and desirability of continuing with that rack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The art has thus far failed to provide a cost-effective alternative. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention provides a surprisingly efficient solution to the long-felt need described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is an object of the invention to provide an electrically conductive intermediate at an interface or contact point between the hanger and article to be coated. This intermediate may be conveniently replaced or recycled at a comparatively small cost relative to existing procedures and implements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In a first aspect, the invention features a system for extending the operating life of hangers or racks associated with electrostatic coating. This is accomplished by use of a relatively cheap, electrically conductive, and preferably pliable, intermediate that is suitable for grounding an article to be coated. The intermediate is interposed at a contact junction of the article and electroconductive hanger. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In exemplary embodiments, the intermediate slideably engages, wraps, or clamps to the hanger and may even adapt in shape or be engineered to accommodate the particular shape of a hook. In most preferred embodiments the article, via an orifice or recess, envelops at least a portion of the hook and intermediate attached thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Various embodiments contemplate different conductive materials and configurations, including shape, of the intermediate. By way of materials, rubber, plastic, tape, and metalic foils all exist that are conductive and suitable, depending on the precise application. The intermediate may be a silicone sleeve or cap having a hollow interior for receiving a hook portion of a hanger. The article to be coated then fits over or engages this enveloped portion of the hook, usually via an orifice of sufficient dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Concentric &ldquo;layers&rdquo; of pliable sleeves are also envisioned for some coating applications wherein one sleeve is positioned over another for rapid exposure of fresh contact surfaces as appropriate. A spent layer is simply peeled away or cut off thereby exposing a fresh one. One such embodiment contemplates a tape. Other embodiments contemplate a plurality of hollow tubes, one over the top of the next. These may be slit lengthwise and deposited one over the top of the next, or else constructed in multiplied layers which are then curled and fixed in form to wrap or clamp to a hanger of interest. Of course, the diameter differential associated with this technique must accordingly be accommodated by the article. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In other embodiments, at least a portion of the hanger itself comprises a nonmetallic material such as a conductive silicone rubber or plastic. This new material can be conductively and integrally fixed during manufacture, e.g., by injection molding. Preferably, the material is pliable or bendable with the hands or other gentle means to quickly release or free unwanted deposits of coating that hinder contact and hence grounding ability. In such embodiments, the sleeve or intermediate is recyclable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In still other embodiments, the sleeve intermediate is disposable. Of course, everything including hangers are disposable at a cost, but what distinguishes the present invention is the relatively low cost of the intermediate relative to the cost of replacing or recycling a hanger or rack. In embodiments where the intermediate is integrally a part of the hanger, the novelty resides in the hanger being easily cleaned relative to conventional hangers, e.g., metal ones, and more durable or receptive to cleanings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In exemplary embodiments, the intermediate bridges a hanger and an article to be coated. This bridge may occur in a variety of configurations as one of skill will appreciate. It may occur as described above, or else it may occur by a more comprehensive envelopment, not only of the hanger but also of the entire juncture, including a portion of the article itself. U.S. Pat. No. 5,897,709 issued to Torefors describes one such example. However, instead of a conductive bridge, Torefors specifies a non-conductive (&ldquo;dielectric&rdquo;) cover. The present invention, by contrast, serves a dual function in further providing a conductive bridge to facilitate grounding and suitable coating, while simultaneously preserving the operative part of the hanger or hook for future use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In another exemplary embodiment of the invention, an intermediate member is designed for fitting over a horizontal cross-bar type of workpiece hanger which suspends large size panels or the like for electrostatic coating, and comprises a longitudinal, hollow sleeve of pliable, electrically conductive material having a longitudinal slit extending along its length so that the sleeve can be engaged transversely over a cross bar extending between two vertical hangers via the slit. An article to be coated, such as a large flat panel, can then be suspended from the cross bar via conductive hooks which engage over the sleeve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The elongate sleeve may be of any suitable cross-sectional shape, such as circular, square, rectangular, or octagonal. The slit may form a longitudinal gap or slot in the sleeve, or may be a simple linear cut along the length of the sleeve. Alternatively, the sleeve may have opposite longitudinal edges which are overlapped along the length of the sleeve, so that there is no opening in the sleeve after it has been engaged over the cross bar. In another alternative, the sleeve may have no slit, for engagement over hook like hanger. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment, the intermediate may be a sheet or strip of pliable, electrically conductive material which is secured on top of a hanger by an electrically conductive adhesive, such that an article to be coated engages the strip or layer. The pliable strip may have any suitable cross-sectional and peripheral shape, such as square, rectangular, circular, triangular, and the like, and may be solid or may have a through bore. The adhesive may cover all or only part of an inner face of the strip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The intermediate may suitably be made of a conductive material, preferably rubber, plastic, tape, foil, or grease that can be conveniently removed, disposed of, replaced, or recycled. The intermediate may have resistance of less than 6 megaohms, or one or less megaohms, or 0.5 megaohms, and in one example has a resistance of about 0.1 megaohms or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In exemplary embodiments, such intermediates are also heat resistant to temperatures up to 600&deg; F., and may be heat resistant in ranges of between about 250&deg; F. and 450&deg; F. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> At present, the favorite known material for the intermediate is conductive silicone, which may be fashioned by mixing different conductive and nonconductive commercially available grades in certain proportions testable by one of skill in the art, using routine experimentation to arrive at a final suitable product. Alternatively, fully conductive commercially available conductive silicone alone can be used that, while more expensive, still represents an improvement in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The material used, e.g., silicone, may be molded to fit the myriad different sizes and shapes of hooks available, or else a universal piece may be used that fits a variety of hook shapes and sizes by conforming pliably in shape. Preferably, these sleeves or caps pull on and off conveniently with minor effort, but are not too loose as to permit undue amounts of coating to seep inside. Looseness is not known to otherwise disadvantage the system, provided there is some contact through which a ground may be established. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A second aspect of the invention features methods for electrostatic coating that make use of the above embodiments, either singularly or, where appropriate, combined. One method of providing an electrostatic pliable coating layer on one or more hanger members comprises dipping at least part of at least one hanger member in a bath of liquid electroconductive material, such as conductive silicone, so that the dipped surface is coated with a layer of electroconductive material, and then lifting the hanger member out of the bath and allowing the coating layer to cure in order to form a pliable, electroconductive coating layer. Some or all of the hanger member may be dipped, and entire hanger racks for use in electrostatically coating many parts at once may be dipped and coated with the pliable electroconductive intermediate.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be better understood from the following detailed description of some exemplary embodiments of the invention, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like reference numerals refer to like parts, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a rack with conductive sleeves according to a first embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an enlarged sectional view taken on line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a sleeve with rectangular configuration, according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alternative, cylindrical sleeve; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a sleeve with a flange for ease of fastening and removal from a hook; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of the flanged sleeve mounted on a hook; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a different type of hanger rack and an attached conductive sleeve according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-section on the lines <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a section similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrating a modified sleeve for use with the rack of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates another modified sleeve; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a section similar to FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrating another modified sleeve; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a view similar to FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrating a modified sleeve shape; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates a sleeve according to another embodiment; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view similar to FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> illustrating yet another modified sleeve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a cross-section similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrating a hanger with an intermediate strip or layer according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a cross-section on the lines <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a cross-section similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrating an alternative shape for the strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a cross-section similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference> illustrating another alternative shape; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a cross-section similar to FIGS. <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> illustrating an intermediate strip engaged over a cross bar of the hanger rack of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the inner face of an alternative version of an intermediate strip for adhering over a hanger member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a cross-section illustrating the stip of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> adhered to a hanger with an article suspended over the strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a rear plan view of a intermediate strip illustrating an alternative shape for the strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a rear plan view of a strip similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> but with a different adhesive arrangement; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a plan view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 22 and 23</cross-reference> illustrating an alternative shape; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a plan view similar to FIGS. <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> illustrating another alternative shape for the strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a perspective rear view of an alternative arcuate strip; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> is a schematic side elevational view illustrating a method for coating part or all of a hanger member with a pliable electroconductive cover layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27A</cross-reference> illustrates the hanger end of a hanger member coated according to the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27B</cross-reference> illustrates a hanger member fully coated according to the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> illustrates an entire hanger rack coated with a pliable electroconductive coating layer according to the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference> illustrates another type of hanger member partially coated with an electroconductive cover layer according to the method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> is a cross-section on the lines <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an end cap of pliable electroconductive material according to another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference> illustrates the end cap of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference> in use during an electrostatic coating process for an automobile hood or the like; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 33</cross-reference> illustrates a modified, open-ended cap; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference> is a perspective view illustrating a pliable electroconductive intermediate according to another embodiment of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The invention makes use of novel intermediate components for use in electrostatic coating processes. The intermediate is conductive and relatively inexpensive in cost and practice, allowing for ready cleaning and/or replacement with a concomitant more efficient operation afforded to the overall system. The object is the preservation of proper grounding and the protection and preservation of more expensive implements used in the process, e.g., hangers, hooks, and racks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> As used herein, and in the claims, the following terms have the following meanings: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> A &ldquo;system&rdquo; includes, but is not limited to, traditional apparatuses used in electrostatic coating processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;electrostatic coating&rdquo; embraces any powder, paint, or electroplating procedure wherein a charge differential is established to facilitate coating of an object to be coated. This includes but is not limited to the use of thermoplastics and teflon-type additions. Those of skill in the art know the broad latitude of the term, which can apply to different charging techniques and systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> By &ldquo;intermediate&rdquo; refers to an object which interfaces in some fashion with both an article to be coated and an electrically conductive hanger. The shape is not to be construed as limited by the drawings or discussion herein, so long as one or more objects of the invention are otherwise met. The intermediate is typically hollow or capable of being made so, e.g., in the case of foil by wrapping it around a hook to be used in an electrostatic coating process of the invention. In tubular embodiments, this can be a uniform, hollow piece of varying internal and external dimensions, additionally including in some embodiments one or more flanges or grips that allow easy placement and replacement, in addition to providing leverage or mechanical manipulation and recycling. The intermediate can be a sleeve or cap, with the difference being that a sleeve has opposing free ends while a cap does not. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;suitable for grounding&rdquo;, &ldquo;grounding&rdquo; and &ldquo;conductive&rdquo; are to be understood jointly. &ldquo;Conductive&rdquo; means capable of passing a charge, e.g., a stream of electrons, and can mean any substance having suitable resistance and capable of fulfilling one or more objectives of the invention. Preferably, the material should have between about 0 and 6 megaohms of resistance, more preferably less than 1 megaohm of resistance, still more preferably less than 0.5 megaohm of resistance, and most preferably having about 0.1 megaohm or lower resistance. The more preferred parameters respect, although are not limited by, National Fire Protection Agency (NFPA) standards and rationale: &ldquo;To minimize the possibility of ignition by static electric sparks, powder transportation, application, recovery equipment, work pieces and all other conductive objects shall be grounded with a resistance . . . not exceeding one megaohm.&rdquo; NFPA Bulletin No. 33, Ch. 13, paragraph 13-4c. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> &ldquo;Ground&rdquo; or &ldquo;grounding&rdquo; is a phenomenon that describes an equilibration of charge approximating that of the earth&apos;s surface. It is a reference standard by which more or less charge is gauged. For purposes of the invention, however, ground can also embrace situations where the hanger possesses a charge opposite to that of the coating material such that electrostatic bonding is achieved and promotes good transferability and coating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;hanger&rdquo; is not meant to be geometrically or materially limiting and may embrace a variety of structures and compositions known in the art, including but not limited to conventional metal hangers, racks, hooks, combinations of racks and hooks, and any other instrument useful in securing or supporting an article to be electrostatically coated. Of course, the piece must also be electroconductive and otherwise suitable for electrostatic coating processes. Magnetic systems and applications are also envisioned. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;slideably engages&rdquo;, &ldquo;wraps&rdquo;, and &ldquo;clamps&rdquo; are each broad terms descriptive of many potential, not necessarily mutually exclusive embodiments. Besides what are shown in the instant drawings, another non-limiting example of a clamp, for instance, includes that disclosed in U.S. Pat. 5,897,709, herein incorporated by reference. Although the clamp described there is nonconductive, the geometry and-other functions can be recruited for purposes of the instant invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;silicone&rdquo;, &ldquo;plastic&rdquo;, &ldquo;tape&rdquo;, and &ldquo;foil&rdquo; similarly have many acceptable permutations that are envisioned to be suitable for the invention, and which are either known in the art, or can be readily determined and implemented without undue experimentation by one of ordinary skill. These are discussed in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;integral with said hanger during manufacture&rdquo; denotes either the conjoining of multiple individual components during manufacture of the hanger itself, or else embodiments where the hanger itself is made entirely of a homogeneous material, e.g., conductive silicone, which presents durability and cleaning advantages over previous compositions, systems, and methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;disposable&rdquo; and &ldquo;recyclable&rdquo; are meant to demonstrate alternative, not necessarily mutually exclusive, embodiments. Thus, at the discretion of the end-user a disposed of intermediate may also be suitably recycled. In other embodiments, there can be mutual exclusivity, e.g., where the sleeve, cap, etc., is engineered to fulfill its grounding and protective function only once, and then degrades, e.g., during the heating/curing step. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Other Features of the Intermediates </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The conductive intermediates of the invention preferably withstand a temperature in the range of temperatures 200&deg; F. to 600&deg; F., most preferably 450&deg; F., and over course of time about ten (10) or more minutes. Conforming intermediates are preferably pliable adapt in shape to envelop at least that portion of the hanger or rack to which the article to be coated is fastened or hangs. The point of this contact may represent substantially the whole of the exterior surface area of the intermediate, or else may represent any subfraction or portion thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The intermediate may assume the shape of a prophylactic cap or sleeve, e.g., tubular or hollow, that has one or more exposed hanger or rack portions flanking its point of engagement with the hanger. Also, the shape of the intermediate may appear much different in appearance when affixed to the hanger relative to when not affixed. This owes to the intermediate&apos;s pliability and/or ready ability to conform in shape to the shape of the hook or subportion thereof to which the intermediate attaches. However, as noted, in certain embodiments the fit can be engineered to be more or less precise, so that pliability is not as great a consideration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> A further aspect is that the intermediate may be readily engaged and detached with minimal effort, e.g., peeled, unwrapped, scraped, or slideably disengaged as needed, and conveniently replaced or recycled so as to economically promote proper grounding and coating efficiency. This is, at least in part, because the cost of the intermediate is typically a fraction of the cost of the other system hardware, e.g., the racks, hooks, and hangers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The ease with which recycling (where appropriate) is accomplished depends on the physical characteristics of the intermediate. In most preferred embodiments, the intermediate is a conductive silicone having suitable thermal stability. The intermediate is ideally elastomeric or pliable, easily engageable with the hanger, e.g., by sliding over, wrapping, or impaling a surface thereof, and readily disengageable as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A further embodiment, as mentioned, is the layered intermediates, wherein a plurality of intermediates overlaying one another are positioned on the rack and peeled off as needed to expose fresh contact area for new objects to be coated or recoated. This layered effect may result either from tape or from layers deposited one atop another. In tubular formats, multiple tubes may be stretched substantially over one another while the bottom most tube directly contacts the hanger/hook/rack and the subsequent added layers indirectly contact it via electrical conductance across the layers. Assumed is that the means for attachment of the article to the intermediate can accommodate a range of thicknesses supplied by the additional layers, and that sufficient contact and hence conductance between the layers can be maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Characteristic of preferred recycling embodiments is that by using minimal or mild perturbation the intermediate can be easily regenerated, i.e., freed of unwanted coating deposits. This is especially so for silicone sleeve embodiments, but not advised for metalic foil embodiments. In the latter case, disposal, or recycling by burning or chemical stripping is preferred. Recycling and nonrecyling embodiments, as stated, are not necessarily mutually exclusive and may be at the discretion of the operator using the system. Such intermediate may therefore be suitable for either process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> It is also anticipated that the inherent benefits of the invention will find additional merit in automation. This will be more or less practicable depending on the specific embodiment used. At present, conductive silicone sleeves or caps are envisioned to best perform the task. They are easily mounted via sliding, clamping, or adhering, and similarly disengageable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In summary, prior to the invention racks and hangers in the art required frequent replacement or cleaning which entailed considerable cost and labor. Down-time associated with these processes was unacceptable and/or, in the case of recycling, exacted a heavy toll on one or more of the following factors: structure and usable life of the racks and hangers, labor allocation, environmental impact, and energy consumption. With the teachings of the invention, these concerns are overcome, simplifying the overall coating and manufacturing process. The net result is increased efficiency and profit, which may in turn be passed on to the consumer. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Determining Suitable Ground and Resistance </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> A common device used to measure continuity to ground, and which may be used to further optimize parameters and configurations suitable for the invention, is an ohm meter having a megaohm scale. This can be a volt/ohm meter (VOM) or a Megger. A VOM is adequate for checking electrical circuits, but its low voltage power source makes it less suited for checking the proper grounding of a coating system. The best device is the Megger which has a power source of 500 volts or higher. This higher voltage provides the current required to accurately measure the resistance to ground. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> An exemplary technique for measuring resistance is to start at the end of the process and work backward. The meter is connected between a known building ground and the uncoated part to be tested using a long test lead. This procedure is used to determine that the part is correctly ground through the entire spray booth. The amount of resistance to ground can be read on the meter, as one of skill aware. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Because the meter is attached to a known ground and to a clean part on the conveyor in the booth, all the devices in between (hanger, conveyor, swivels, etc.) are in the circuit and the resistance to proper ground can be measured. If the reading is less than one megaohm, the grounding is ideal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> If the resistance reading is greater than one megaohm, one can verify by hooking the lead to the contact point on the hanger and read it again. Then, by repeating the procedure and working back through the system (swivel or conveyor hook, conveyor) until the resistance reads in the proper range. By this method it can be determined which device needs corrective action. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> A similar technique can be used to check for proper grounding of other objects and equipment in the coating area and system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Silicone Sleeve or Cap </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> A prototype intermediate was designed and built as follows: Three quarter parts conductive silicone rubber compound (Shin-Etsu Chemical Co., Japan; part KE3611U) combined with one quarter part nonconductive silicone paste (Shin-Etsu; part KE961U) was mixed, compression molded, and cured in the form of tubing having a wall thickness of about 0.1 cm and an overall tubing diameter of about 1 cm. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the resulting tubing was then cut to approximately 5 cm in length and the resulting sleeve intermediate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> slideably coaxed over and along the shaft of a metal conductive hook <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> via a free end <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of said sleeve intermediate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. This was done until the sleeve <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> substantially covered the hook <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, or at least that portion fated to engage and contact a workpiece or article to be coated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> The overall concept, e.g., for a multi-hooked rack, is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, which depicts one configuration of sleeve mounted onto a plurality of hooks of a single rack. Each work-piece hook in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is analogized to the individual configurations demonstrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 6</cross-reference>. With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the article or articles to be coated <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> engage the hooks <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by virtue of one or more orifices or recesses <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in said article(s) <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> having suitable dimensions for receiving the intermediate sleeve/hook combination <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. At the vertically highest point in the figure is another hook <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to which the overall rack of the Figure is typically grounded. The hanger diameter for this prototype measured approximately 0.6 cm, although the particular dimensions are not limiting and merely illustrative of one workable embodiment. For this particular prototype, the depth of curve of said portion of the hanger measured 6 cm, and the vertical length of the hanger, not including curve, measured about 55 cm. Analogy may be had with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for other rack and hook configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Coating and curing then proceed as standard in the art. Upon coating, the coated article is removed, an uncoated article added, and the process repeated. Between coatings, typically every 3-5 rounds, the sleeve/fitting is examined for paint build-up and manipulated gently to peel away or relieve unwanted coating build-up on the intermediate, thereby re-establishing a suitable ground for the electrostatic process. If desired, the recycling can take place in situ, or else can first entail removal of the rack or hanger from the conveyor. The latter is preferred so that new racks can be added as the intermediates on the old racks are serviced, thereby promoting a more continuous operation. &ldquo;Used&rdquo; sleeves may be replaced with unused ones, followed by a resumption of coating operations, or else the individual sleeves can be removed, gently manipulated to recycle them, and replaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> For purposes of the prototype, the Applicants formulated the 75:25 mix to decrease costs. Higher ratios of conductive silicone, e.g., 76-100% will also work and still be more economical than previously described art methods, and the Applicants further believe that lower ratios can also be determined without undue experimentation, and using routine procedures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> As one of skill in the art is aware, however, conductive silicones exist that vary in constituents. This may have a bearing on the relative success of the precise functional ratios used. Moreover, as one of skill is also aware, there can be lot-to-lot variations in silicone performance. However, as stated, one of skill may easily determine suitability using minimal, routine experimentation. Indications of some of the variations that exist and methods for preparation of the same may be found, e.g., in U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,010,646, 6,013,201, 5,217,651, 5,164,443, 5,135,980, 5,082,596, 4,957,839, 4,898,689, 4,672,016, 4,571,371, 4,552,688, pertinent disclosures of which are herein incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Besides Shin-Etsu, other current commercial vendors of conductive and nonconductive silicones include Dow Corning (Indianapolis, Ind.) and Toshiba (JP). No doubt other vendors also exist and improvements in silicone structures and characteristics are anticipated. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Flanged Prototype </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Electrostatic coating is performed as per Example 2, except that instead of a uniformly dimensioned sleeve or cap, the sleeve or cap possesses a flange or rib for gripping or otherwise facilitating the process. This is demonstrated by the prototype exhibited in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. The dimensions shown (mm) are designed to fit over a wire hook 2.35 mm in diameter. The internal diameter of the tubing is 2.75 mm, the length is 75.00 mm, the diameter of the flange is 13.00 mm, the flange thickness 1.6 mm, and the tube wall thickness 0.8 mm. This particular embodiment demonstrates a cap format wherein a flange exists on an end opposing the capped (closed) end . When positioned onto the wire hook, this flanged cap or sleeve resembles the format shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Foil Intermediates </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> Electrostatic coating is performed as per Example 2, except that instead of using the silicone sleeve fitting, conductive metalic foil, e.g., tin or aluminum, is substituted and wrapped around the bare or otherwise conductive hook to provide an equivalent effect. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Hybrid Hanger Comprising Conductive Silicone </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, hangers are produced via compression molding that are comprised, at least in part, of conductive rubber, e.g., silicone, as described above. The silicone portion, if a minority, is preferably localized to that portion of the hanger as described for Examples 2 and 3. Thus, sleeve fittings as described above are either eliminated or else rendered redundant to the process, with the latter embodiment also anticipated to have independent advantage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> illustrate an intermediate sleeve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of electrically conductive, pliable material according to another embodiment of the invention. The sleeve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is an elongate, cylindrical, tubular member which is open at both ends and which has a longitudinal slit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> extending between its opposite ends. It is designed for fitting over a different type of rack <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for suspending workpieces such as large, flat panels <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> to be electrostatically coated, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The rack <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> has a pair of vertical posts <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> having grounding hooks <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> for attachment to a conveyor or grounding system, and a cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extending between the posts and from which the workpiece <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is suspended via conductive hooks <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The elongate conductive sleeve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be fitted over the cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> via the slit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. In this example, the slit <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is defined between opposite longitudinal side edges <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which are spaced apart to form a gap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a modified cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> in which a simple longitudinal slit <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is cut, with no gap between opposing side edges of the cut. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates another alternative sleeve configuration <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in which opposite longitudinal side edges <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the sleeve are overlapped. Due to the pliable nature of the sleeve material, opposite side edges of the sleeve can be urged apart in both of the embodiments of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference> while the sleeve is inserted transversely over cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and then released to close the slit as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>, for added security. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates a modified cylindrical sleeve <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> similar to that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> but with a thicker wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> illustrate some alternative cross-sectional shapes for the elongate tubular sleeve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the elongate tubular sleeve <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> for fitting over a cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is of square, rather than circular, cross-section, and has a longitudinal slit <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> extending along one side of the sleeve. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the sleeve <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is of triangular cross-section and has a slit <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> at one apex of the triangle. Finally, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the sleeve <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is of octagonal cross-section and has a slit <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. In each of these cases, the slit may define a gap as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, or no gap as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, or have overlapping side edges as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. Many other alternative cross-sectional shapes may be used if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Each of the sleeves of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 11</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be provided without any longitudinal slit, for use on racks with hangers having free ends over which the sleeve can be engaged. The sleeve may be closed at one end, as in the embodiments of FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, or may be open ended. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15 and 16</cross-reference> illustrate another alternative embodiment, in which the intermediate comprises a strip or piece <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> of calendared, pliable conductive silicone adhered to an upper surface of a hanger <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> or cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of a rack by a backing layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> of conductive adhesive. The strip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may be secured over only that region of the hanger or support bar which is engaged by the part, or by a hanger or hook <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> for the part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Strip <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may be of rectangular cross-section, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. However, any cross-sectional shape may be used, such as a strip <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> of circular cross-section, as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, or a strip <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> of triangular cross-section, as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, or any other shape. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> illustrates a pliable strip <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> adhered over the upper face of the cylindrical cross bar <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of the rack in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, in place of sleeve <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 20 and 21</cross-reference> illustrate a rectangular or square shape strip <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of pliable electroconductive material such as conductive silicone in which, instead of a backing layer of conductive adhesive extending over the entire inner face of the strip, stripes <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of adhesive material are provided along the opposite side edges <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> of the strip, each stripe <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> being covered with a peel-off cover layer <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> of paper or the like to protect the adhesive stripe until the strip is to be applied to a hanger member. The strip <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may be provided in a continuous length for cutting to a desired size by an end user. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, after removing the cover layers <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, the strip <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> may be adhered to a hanger member <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> using the side stripes <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of adhesive. An article to be coated can then be suspended from the hanger member, with a portion <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> of the article engaging over the center of the strip <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> so as to press the central portion directly against the hanger member, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. Thus, the conductive silicone strip <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> forms a direct junction between the article <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and the electroconductive hanger member, with no intervening adhesive. In this case, the adhesive need not be electroconductive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The adhesive-backed pliable electroconductive member may have one or more adhesive coating layers covering all or part of its inner surface, and may be of any desired peripheral shape. Some alternative shapes are illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 23 and 24</cross-reference>, an electroconductive member <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> of circular shape is provided. The member <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> has a central stripe <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> of adhesive in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>, and a peripheral layer <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> of adhesive extends around an annular portion of the periphery of member <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. Alternatively, the inner face may be completely coated with an adhesive layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> illustrates an electroconductive member <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of alternative, trapezoidal shape with side stripes <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of adhesive material. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, the electroconductive pliable member is a flat, generally diamond shaped panel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> coated with an inner layer <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of adhesive. In each case, the panel or electroconductive member may have an adhesive layer completely or partially coating its inner surface, with the adhesive provided in any desired region or regions. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> illustrates an alternative electroconductive strip member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> which is of rectangular shape but generally arcuate cross-section, for conforming to the outer surface shape of a round bar or rod like hanger. Member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is provided with strips <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of adhesive along its opposite side edges, in a similar manner to the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>, although the adhesive may completely coat the inner surface of member <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in alternative examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> In each of the embodiments of FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the adhesive material may be any suitable electroconductive adhesive, such as a silicone base adhesive available from Kirkhill Rubber of Los Angeles, Calif., or a high temperature acrylic adhesive. The alternatives which have only side strips of adhesive may not require the adhesive to be conductive, which will increase the choice of possible high temperature adhesives for use in these embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> illustrates an alternative method of providing an electroconductive pliable intermediate at a junction between an electrically conductive, rigid hanger and an article to be coated. In this method, instead of engaging a pre-formed sleeve, tube or adhesive backed strip on the hanger, part or all of a hanger member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is dipped into a bath <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> containing a liquid form <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the electroconductive, pliable material. The surface of the hanger member which is submerged in the liquid will be coated with the material, and the hanger member is then removed from the bath into a drying station at a suitable temperature for curing the coating layer of electroconductive pliable material. Where the material is electroconductive silicone, the curing temperature will be at or around room temperature. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27A</cross-reference> illustrates one alternative where the hanger member has been partially dipped in bath <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, to form a coating layer <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of pliable electroconductive material on the hanger end of the member only. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27B</cross-reference> illustrates a second alternative where the entire hanger member <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is submerged in the bath to form a coating layer <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> extending over its entire length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> Instead of dipping an individual hanger <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in bath <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and subsequently hanging the hanger from a-coating rack, an entire rack <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> may be dipped in the bath <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> so that it is completely covered with a layer of the conductive silicone material <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Rack <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> comprises a framework of side rails <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and cross rails <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, with a plurality of spaced hangers <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> secured on each cross rail. After the rack is dipped and coated, and the coating layer is allowed to cure, an intermediate, pliable coating will cover the entire surface of the rack, forming a conductive bridge between any article hung from the rack and the rigid conductive material of the rack. Because the coating layer is soft and pliable, it can be pinched and kneaded in order to remove any powder build up as a result of the electrostatic coating process. It will be understood that the same procedure may be used for coating racks and hangers of any shape or size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 29 and 30</cross-reference> illustrate an alternative, loop-type hanger <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> which has been coated with an outer layer <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> of a pliable electroconductive material such as conductive silicone. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29, a</cross-reference> series of spaced, loop hangers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> are welded or otherwise secured to a conductive cross bar <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> of a rack or the like. The hangers <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be dipped in a bath <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> of liquid electroconductive material in the manner illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>, so that each loop <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> becomes coated with a layer of the material, which is subsequently allowed to cure at room temperature to form an electroconductive, pliable coating layer <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> or intermediate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 31 and 32</cross-reference> illustrate an electroconductive, pliable cap or sleeve <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the invention. Cap <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is similar to the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, except that it is of shorter length and of round, rather than rectangular, cross-section. It basically comprises a short tubular portion with one closed end <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and an annular flange <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> at the opposite end for ease of handling and placement. The cap is formed of an electroconductive pliable material such as conductive silicone. Cap <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may be placed over the end of a metal conductive hook <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight>, as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference>, with a series of such hooks with caps being used to support a large item <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> to be coated, such as a car hood or body. It has been found that, without such a protective cover, the paintwork of the hood or body may be scratched when it is lifted off the hooks, by the metal ends of the hooks. With this arrangement, the pliable caps <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> will protect the paint from such scratches. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 33</cross-reference> illustrates a modified cap <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> which has a through bore open at both ends and an annular flange <highlight><bold>139</bold></highlight> at one end. The caps <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may be made in various different lengths and diameters, depending upon the application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Finally, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference> illustrates an alternative electroconductive sleeve or tubular member <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the invention. Unlike the sleeves of FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, sleeve <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is not of uniform thickness along its length. Instead, the sleeve <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> has a through bore <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of uniform diameter, but has a stepped outer diameter, with a first end portion <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> of a first diameter and a second end portion <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> of a second, larger diameter, with an annular flange <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> at the end of the larger diameter portion <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>. The sleeve may be closed at its smaller diameter end. The sleeve is of a suitable electroconductive pliable material, for example electroconductive silicone. This version may be used in cases where a stepped diameter hanger or support for electrostatic coating is required. Rather than making the metal hanger or rod of stepped diameter, the pliable cover sleeve is stepped, so that a simple, uniform diameter hanger rod may be used, which will be less expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Although exemplary embodiments of the invention have been described above by way of example only, it will be understood by those skilled in the field that other embodiments are also possible and that significant modifications may be made to the disclosed embodiments without departing from the scope of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An electrostatic coating system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a disposable or recyclable intermediate interposed at a junction between an article to be coated and an electrically conductive hanger, wherein said intermediate is of pliable, electrically conductive material and serves to protect said hanger, thereby preserving its useful life, while simultaneously promoting coating of said article; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the intermediate comprising a tubular member for engaging over a hanger. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has a longitudinal slit forming an opening for placing the member transversely over a cross bar extending between two posts. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said conductive intermediate is disposable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said conductive intermediate is re-usable. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate comprises a conductive material selected from the group consisting of rubber, plastic, and metallic foil. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said conductive material comprises silicone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate has a resistivity of less than about 1 megaohm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate is capable of withstanding heat between about 200&deg; F. and 600&deg; F. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said conductive material further comprises a mixture of silicone compounds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is of circular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is of rectangular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is of square cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is of triangular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is of polygonal cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has opposite side edges extending along opposite sides of said slit, the side edges being spaced apart to form a gap for allowing the tubular member to be installed transversely over a cross bar. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has opposite side edges extending along opposite sides of said slit, the side edges being overlapped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the slit comprises a linear slit with no gap between opposite side edges of the slit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has a through bore of substantially uniform diameter along the length of the tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has an outer surface having a first diameter along a first part of its length, and a second diameter larger than said first diameter along a second part of its length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has an outwardly projecting peripheral flange at one end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member is closed at one end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tubular member has a through bore which is open at both ends. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An electrostatic coating system, comprising: 
<claim-text>an electroconductive hanger for suspending an article to be coated on a conveyor, the hanger having a cross bar from which an article is suspended; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an electroconductive, pliable intermediate member engaged over said cross bar between the cross bar and the article to be coated, the intermediate member comprising an elongate tube having opposite open ends and a longitudinal slit extending between its ends, the slit forming an opening for placing the tube over the cross bar with the cross bar extending inside the tube. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An electrostatic coating method, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>engaging an elongate, tubular intermediate member of pliable, electroconductive material over a cross bar forming part of an electroconductive hanger by inserting the cross bar through a longitudinal slit in the tubular intermediate member in a direction transverse to the longitudinal axis of the cross bar and tubular member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>suspending an article to be coated from the cross bar by engaging at least two hooks secured to the article over the tubular intermediate member, whereby the tubular intermediate member forms an electrically conductive intermediate at a pair of junctions between the hanger and the article to be coated; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>electrostatically coating the article. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate comprises a material selected from the group consisting of rubber, plastic, and metallic foil. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said material comprises conductive silicone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00024">claims 24</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00026">26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate has a resistivity of less than about 1 megaohm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said intermediate is capable of withstanding heat less of between about 200&deg; F. and 600&deg; F. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An electrostatic coating system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a disposable or recyclable intermediate interposed at a junction between an article to be coated and an electrically conductive hanger, wherein said intermediate is of pliable, electrically conductive material and serves to protect said hanger, thereby preserving its useful life, while simultaneously promoting coating of said article; </claim-text>
<claim-text>the intermediate comprising a strip of pliable, electroconductive material having an upper face and a lower face, and a layer of electrically conductive adhesive for securing the strip to an upper surface of the hanger. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip is of rectangular cross section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip is of circular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip is of triangular cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of adhesive covers the entire lower face of said ship. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the layer of adhesive covers only part of the lower face of said strip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip is of rectangular shape and the adhesive layer comprises a pair of adhesive stripes extending along opposite sides of the lower face of said strip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said strip is of arcuate cross-section to follow the contour of the hanger to which it is adhered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip is of circular shape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive is heat resistant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive is a silicon base on adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. An electrostatic coating system, comprising: 
<claim-text>an electroconductive pliable intermediate disposed between an article to be coated and a substantially rigid electrically conductive hanger from which the article is suspended, wherein said intermediate serves to protect said hanger, thereby preserving its useful like while simultaneously promoting coating of said article; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said intermediate being made of conductive silicone. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the intermediate forms a cover layer of substantially uniform thickness over the hanger. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the intermediate comprises a tubular sleeve having an annular flange at one end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the intermediate forms a cover layer of substantially uniform thickness over the hanger. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the intermediate forms a cover layer of variable thickness over the hanger. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the intermediate comprises a strip of pliable, electroconductive material having an upper face and a lower face, and at least one layer of electrically conductive, heat resistant adhesive covering at least part of the lower face of the strip for adhering the strip to the hanger. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive has a silicone base. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the strip has a peripheral edge and the adhesive layer extends around at least part of the peripheral edge of the strip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The system as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference>, including a peel-off cover member covering the adhesive layer prior to application to a hanger. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A method of providing an electroconductive pliable intermediate on an electroconductive hanger, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>dipping at least an article suspending end of at least one electroconductive hanger into a bath of a liquified form of a pliable electroconductive material in order to coat the dipped surface of the hanger with a layer of the liquid electroconductive material; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>allowing the coating layer of electroconductive material to cure in order to form an intermediate of pliable, electroconductive material over the hanger member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electroconductive material comprises silicone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of dipping at least one hanger member comprises dipping an electroconductive rack having a plurality of hanger members in the bath of liquid electroconductive material and allowing the material to form a pliable coating layer over the entire electroconductive rack.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>NONE</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000466A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
