<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005466A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005466A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005466</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896727</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04N007/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>141000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>133000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>134000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>153000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>142000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Content personalization system for mobile users</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hsinchao</given-name>
<family-name>Liao</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Berkeley</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HSINCHAO LIAO</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P. O. BOX 5644</address-1>
<city>BERKELEY</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94705-0644</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A broadcast receiver (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) containing an embedded computer (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) receives digital content such as news, sports, weather and stocks. The broadcast receiver personalizes, i.e. filters and processes, the content received according to the user-chosen configuration software (<highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>) loaded from a removable storage device (<highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>), such as a compact flash card. The broadcast receiver displays, announces or writes to the same removable storage device the desired content. Without needing any user interaction, this broadcast receiver is well suited for the mobile environment. An interactive computer (<highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>), as instructed by its user, writes the configurable software, including parameters, software and firmware updates to the removable storage device. The interactive computer optionally downloads the configurable software, for example, the personal stock portfolio of its user, from Internet. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Not applicable </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SEQUENCE LISTING OR PROGRAM </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not applicable </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to the mobile implementation of content personalization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Descript of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Several Internet services provide personalized content including stock quotes, local weather, news headlines, and sports scores. See, for example, my.yahoo.com. Mobile implementations are typically based on cellular networks. For example, Semotus Solutions Inc., formerly DataLink Systems Corporation of Canada, provides the QuoteXpress service. It transmits personalized stock quotes and alerts to pagers and personal cellular service (PCS) devices. However, QuoteXpress does not transmit data to each receiver continuously. A user is limited to one set of updates in each of the 46 predetermined time windows. Some other services use wireless connections through cellular or proprietary networks to provide mobile access to Internet and the online personalization services. Usage of these cellular and paging services requires a subscription and its associated fee. These services can support only limited numbers of receivers and subscribers. These limits are imposed by, for example, the number of valid telephone numbers and by the number of allowable concurrent connections within each network cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An alternative solution uses receivers pre-configured by their users to filter and process continuous broadcast data in real-time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> One suitable mode of broadcast transmission uses subcarriers. Many systems transmit digital data using FM radio and television subcarriers. Services such as DeskTop Data, Inc. of Waltham, Mass. use subcarriers to transmit financial information. The radio data system (RDS) in Europe and the radio broadcast data system (RBDS) in the USA have been widely implemented to broadcast station and program information. The Subcarrier Traffic Information Channel (STIC) developed by Mitre Corp. is used for broadcasting traffic conditions. Personal messaging services such as that provided by CUE Corporation of Irvine, Calif. also use subcarrier broadcast. In Japan and Europe, FM Mutiplex is the more common name given to the broadcast of digital data and graphics over FM subcarriers using the DAta Radio Channel (DARC) standard. Another version of DARC is available over amplitude modulation (AM). A multi-carrier version of DARC is disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/579,144 and briefly described in the white paper titled &ldquo;SKYSPEED: A HIGH SPEED FM SUBCARRIER NETWORK FOR INTERNET APPLICATIONS&rdquo; released by CUE Corp. on Jan. 7, 2000. See also U.S. Pat. No. 6,057,808, No. 5,734,780, No. 5,963,563 and No. 6,081,699. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The performance of subcarrier broadcast can be summarized by the following estimates for DARC FM. A stock quote consisting of a stock symbol and a number can be reported using about 10 characters or 10 bytes. Each data record needs approximately 10 additional bytes to encode content provider identification and data classification. Hence, for each stock quote, approximately 20 bytes (160 bits) of data are broadcasted. Since DARC FM systems can effectively transmit data, with error correction, at approximately 8 kilobits per second (kbps), about 50 quotes can be broadcasted per second or 3,000 quotes per minute. Thus all symbols listed on NASDAQ and NYSE can be broadcasted in two to three minutes, or less than one minute if compression techniques are used. Thus any personal portfolio can be fully updated in one minute using subcarrier broadcast. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The problem that remains is that of providing personalized views of the broadcast data. Prior inventions use databases and interactive computers to process received data. Various methods of input by the user to the receiver have been disclosed. U.S. Pat. No. 5,406,626, No. 5,406,626, No. 5,590,195 and No. 5,751,806 disclose a system where the user uses voice commands and push buttons to navigate through menus. Internet RadiOH of Infodia Co., Ltd. of Korea uses pen-based input. After some interaction with the user interface, the desired result is finally displayed or announced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> There are two disadvantages to these systems. First, memory is wasted because all received data, including all unwanted data, is entered into the database. It is more memory efficient to filter the data according to the user&apos;s preferences as they are being received so that only data desired by the user are stored. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Second, in the mobile environment, the amount of interaction required to operate one of these systems is a safety hazard. The only devices that do not require interaction with their users are beepers and pagers. Radio paging services use phase-shifting techniques (e.g. PSK and BPSK) to personalize data. See for example, U.S. Pat. No. 4,816,769. However, similar to cellular services, because private data is included in the broadcast, each pager must occupy a distinct portion of the allocated bandwidth to deter eavesdropping. Thus the number of users concurrently receiving data is limited; and therefore, data is available in discrete time windows rather than continuously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> It is worth noting that the problem of presenting a personalized view of public data is very different from the problem of enabling mobile access to private data. The solutions to the latter problem, for example personal pagers and smart card commerce systems, must include security measures for the protection of privacy. In contrast, security measures are taken for the first problem only to deny access by non-subscribers. Thus if the provider&apos;s revenue is not based on subscriptions, the security measures can be minimized or even eliminated to improve data throughput. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> 3. Objects and Advantages </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The goal is to present a personalized view of broadcast content to the mobile user. The present invention meets this goal with these objects and advantages: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> (a) to enable the user to personalize his or her own view of broadcast content through minimal interaction with the mobile system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> (b) to enable the user to synchronize personalization settings of the mobile service with an Internet service so that he or she can obtain the same personalized content using either service; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> (c) to provide mobile units each of which can be shared by unlimited number of users; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> (d) to provide a system that can be implemented with existing technologies. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A system for presenting personalized content comprises a mobile receiver unit, a removable storage device and the necessary hardware and software for managing this device. The system personalizes broadcast content received by the receiver in accordance with parameters stored on the removable storage device. The system optionally displays, announces and stores the personalized content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The removable storage device is programmed by an interactive computer whose software is supplied by the content provider who may choose to unify the service with that of an Internet personalized content provider. The storage device contains personalization parameters such as a stock portfolio, a listing of favorite baseball teams, a favorite voice to use with the receiver&apos;s speech synthesizer etc. In addition, the storage device may contain firmware updates and other software for the receiver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Each receiver of this system is readily shared by an unlimited number of users through the use of separate storage devices. The user interface of the simplest receiver consists of the removable storage device receptacle and optionally, a switch that controls audio output. The shareability and the minimal user interface of the receiver are most valuable in the mobile environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The receiver can be integrated with a automobile stereo especially in the case where radio subcarrier broadcast technology is used, or manufactured as a standalone unit. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a block diagram of one embodiment of the mobile receiver unit in accordance with the present invention, in conjunction with the removable storage device that stores personalization parameters and the hardware that manages this device.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">REFERENCE NUMERALS IN THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> Mobile receiver unit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> Antenna </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> Demodulator </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> Digital data </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> Embedded computer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> Personalized content </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> Data ready indicator (LED) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> Video display </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> Loudspeaker or earphone </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> Audio power amplifier </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> Synthesized audio signal </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> Voice synthesizer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> Input selector switch </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> Internet personalized content service </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> Internet connection </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> Interactive computer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> Removable storage device </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> Personalization and system parameters and programs </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> Other audio inputs </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a system in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. It consists of mobile receiver unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> writes personalization and system parameters, and system programs <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> to removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> optionally synchronizes these parameters with, and downloads updated software from online personalized content service <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> through Internet connection <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring to mobile receiver unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, antenna <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provides a broadcast signal to demodulator <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which converts this broadcast signal to digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which is processed by embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In the case where radio or television broadcast is used, demodulator <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be combined with a common analog tuner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> takes as its input broadcast digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and personalization and system parameters <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> that are stored on removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> minimally requires a processor and the hardware and firmware for accessing device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may contain additional rewritable memory that is not necessary if device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is rewritable, has enough capacity, and can be accessed quickly in real-time by embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. This extra memory is clearly necessary if personalization is required to continue after device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is detached. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, where device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is a compact flash card or another memory device of similar physical size, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is physically no larger than a pocket-sized digital camera and technologically no more complex than a hand-held computer without the keyboard, writing implement or any interactive input component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> contains system and personalization parameters <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The personalization parameters chosen by the user typically specify the user&apos;s stock portfolio, the user&apos;s favorite sports, teams etc. Additional parameters may be chosen by the content provider&apos;s software to personalize advertising content. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> uses these personalization parameters to filter digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and produce personalized content <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> discards immediately any content that does not fit the personalization parameters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Personalization is not limited to data filtration. In one embodiment, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> interprets programs stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> for processing digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. For example, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may execute a program that converts all temperature measures in degrees Celsius to degrees Fahrenheit. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may implement an event-driven system in which user-specific conditions that trigger audio and visual alerts are specified as programs stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, upon attachment of device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, configures itself and other components of receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with system programs and system parameters <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. One system parameter controls whether personalization stays in effect when the user detaches device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> from mobile receiver unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A second parameter selects the preferred voice that voice synthesizer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> generates. Other parameters control various functions of voice synthesizer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and video display <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. One category of system programs consists of parser programs specific to the content providers. By loading these programs from device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and executing them, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is able to interpret different data formats, thus allowing receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be used with more than one content provider. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be programmed to save a user-selected subset of personalized content <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. For example, the user may instruct embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, through a simple program stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, to store the highest and lowest prices of each stock in the user&apos;s portfolio that receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has received each day. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Video display <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is the default output venue of receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In one compact embodiment, the content is displayed in a small LCD of the types typically found on automobile stereos and personal pagers. System parameters that control the scrolling of text, the length of the pause between displaying consecutive units of content, etc., are stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Audio output is essential in mobile devices. Voice synthesizer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> produces analog audio signals <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> from digital personalized content <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Analog audio signals <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are provided to audio power amplifier <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which drives loudspeakers or earphones <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> to which the user listens. In the case of loudspeakers, the user can turn on and off the audio output using switch <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Volume and other audio controls are part of standard audio equipment; they are not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In one embodiment where receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is integrated with a personal stereo or an automobile stereo that facilitates other audio inputs <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, audio power amplifier <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and loudspeakers <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> are shared between the stereo and voice synthesizer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Hence in this integrated embodiment, switch <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is provided to the user for selecting the desired audio input. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> switches on data ready indicator LED <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> whenever it receives error-free digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, regardless of whether the system is initialized and regardless of whether the parser program is loaded. LED <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> serves two purposes. First it notifies the user that digital data is available for personalization and reminds the user to attach device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Second, for branding purpose, LED <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be masked in the shape of one of the trademarks belonging to the manufacturer or a content provider. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> contains multiple profiles, i.e. sets of parameters and programs. For example, the user may store two distinct investment portfolios for use with one content provider and a third portfolio for use with another content provider. One system parameter specifies the default profile to be used with each content provider. Embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> personalizes content using the default profile of each content provider whenever data from that content provider is received. Using a selector on mobile receiver unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the user can override the profile chosen by embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, where removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> contains only one profile, the user switches profiles by replacing device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> with another. The trade off is between carrying extra compact flash cards and having an extra switch on mobile receiver unit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> operates without device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> having been attached. In this embodiment, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is installed with a default behavior. For example, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be programmed to display advertising, if it is being received from a known content provider, continuously and repeatedly until device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is attached. Upon attachment of removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may load and execute new programs, configure the display according to parameters, perform personalization of received content, etc, as described previously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> writes software to device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> for use with receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Using any input device such as a keyboard, a writing implement, touch screen, etc, the user selects any number of personalization settings and programs to be applied to the broadcast data received by receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In addition, the content provider may store extra parameters for targeted advertising. These parameters are hidden from the user and may not be altered by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The content provider may enable interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to synchronize personalization parameters stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> with the online parameters for the user&apos;s Internet personalized content service <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. For content categories available on both Internet and broadcast, these synchronized parameters ensure that receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> provides the same personalized content as the Internet service. The parameters for targeted advertisement can be downloaded from Internet as well, perhaps in collaboration with an e-commerce analyst who monitors and predicts the user&apos;s Internet shopping behavior. In this embodiment, the user may only need to interact with the Internet service. The programming of device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> requires only a confirmation, possibly with one click of a button, by the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The content provider may provide programs to the user for processing data received by receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As mentioned previously, some of these programs perform temperature scale conversion, archival of highest and lowest stock prices, etc. In addition to ready-built programs, the content provider may provide one or more programming environments to the user for building his or her own programs using interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The programming environment may be built as an Internet application so that interactive computer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is only required to execute an Internet browser program. The programs selected by the user are written to device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and executed by embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The results, written to removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> by embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> as instructed by the user-selected programs, can be processed further by any machine capable of reading data from device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The behavior of embedded computer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be specified as three processes: a configuration process, a personalization process and an output process. The configuration process sets up receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the system parameters and initializes the data structure for storing personalized data. The configuration process may also update the system firmware and the programs that implement any of these three processes, including itself. The personalization service filters and performs custom processing on digital data <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> according to the personalization parameters and programs <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The output process traverses the personalization data structure and delivers units of personalized content to video display <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and voice synthesizer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The configuration process sets a &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag whenever it has finished initializing the system. If receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is configured to retain personalization settings after removable storage device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is detached, then the configuration process removes this &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag when device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is attached. Otherwise, the configuration process removes this flag when device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is detached. The personalization and output processes perform their functions only when this &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag is set. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The personalization process locks the personalization data structure before it stores a unit of content and its corresponding checksum into this structure. It unlocks the structure when it has finished storing the content or as soon as it detects the absence of the &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag. To reinitialize the system, for example when the user attaches device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the configuration process first removes the &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag; then it waits for the personalization process to unlock the data structure; and then it initializes receiver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the personalization data structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The output process does not respect the lock on the personalization data structure. While &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag is set, the output process continuously traverses the personalization data structure. It outputs any unit of content that has a valid checksum computed and stored by the personalization process. The output process is idle when the &ldquo;system ready&rdquo; flag is absent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The asynchronous nature of the output process enables it to execute at a configurable pace. A user-specified system parameter stored on device <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> controls the length of the pause between consecutive units of content. Other system parameters hidden from the user determine when advertisements are displayed or announced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The broadcast data must follow some simple requirements. Each unit of content must identify its content provider and a sequence of categorization keys. For example, one such sequence of keys might be &ldquo;sports, college football&rdquo;. Using numeric codes for these keys would naturally compress the data and increase data throughput. In the case of free-form text categories such as news and advertisement, each unit of content must contain a unique identifier. These identifiers enable the personalization process to identify and discard duplicated content. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> A user of a personalized news service would typically request some number of top stories in each category, for example, the top five stories in entertainment. Thus each headline must include a ranking. The rankings enable the personalization process to discard headlines of relatively little importance and to replace old headlines with new ones. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> A content provider may enforce additional data formatting requirements through the software it distributes. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A mobile receiver unit for receiving from broadcast and personalizing digital data, comprising 
<claim-text>a broadcast receiver for demodulating digital data from broadcast signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an embedded computer, including an interface for accessing a removable storage device, for processing the demodulated digital data according to the software stored on said removable storage device attached to said embedded computer through said interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said embedded computer loads from said removable storage device software containing parameters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said embedded computer loads from said removable storage device software containing programs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said embedded computer includes a signaling means for alerting the user that demodulated digital data is available. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a video display for displaying digital data. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said video display comprises a pacing means for displaying content with a plurality of pause lengths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pacing means includes selection of pause lengths through software stored on said removable storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an audio output system including a voice synthesizer for converting digital data to analog audio signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an integrating means for connecting to a device selected from a group consisting of an automobile stereo, a personal stereo and a radio tuner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A personalization system, comprising 
<claim-text>an interactive computer, including an interface for accessing a removable storage device, for providing to the user an interactive means for choosing interactively a subset of a collection of personalization software, and for writing said collection of personalization software to said removable storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mobile receiver unit for receiving from broadcast and personalizing digital data, comprising 
<claim-text>a broadcast receiver for demodulating digital data from broadcast signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an embedded computer, including an interface for accessing said removable storage device, for processing the demodulated digital data according to said collection of personalization software stored on said removable storage device attached to said embedded computer through said interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said interactive computer is a machine selected from the group consisting of desktop computers, laptop computers, handheld computers, television set top boxes and interactive television sets. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said interactive computer writes to said removable storage device software containing parameters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said interactive computer includes a synchronizing means for synchronizing parameters stored on said removable storage device with the parameters used by a service selected from the group consisting of Internet personalization services and interactive television services. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said interactive computer writes to said removable storage device software containing programs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the interactive computer includes a downloading means for downloading programs from Internet to said removable storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said interactive computer includes a programming means for identifying and building, by the user, programs to be executed by said embedded computer of said mobile receiver unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005466A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005466A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
