<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000021A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000021A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000021</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893365</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47C017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>005</class>
<subclass>739000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Mattress border construction and method</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>O&apos;Connell</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Downingtown</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Allen</given-name>
<family-name>Bixby</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Avila</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CONNOLLY BOVE LODGE &amp; HUTZ, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1220 N MARKET STREET</address-1>
<address-2>P O BOX 2207</address-2>
<city>WILMINGTON</city>
<state>DE</state>
<postalcode>19899</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A mattress border assembly and method for preparing foam rails for shipment prior to assembly to form a mattress border assembly are disclosed. Strips of double-faced, high strength acrylic adhesive tape are applied to at least portions of the end walls of two foam rails. The second adhesive surface of the tape is covered with a protective liner until the border is to be assembled. When assembled, the end walls of the two foam rails are adhered with the tape to side walls of two other foam rails to form a generally rectangular frame structure that comprises the mattress border assembly. Optionally, additional strips of double-faced, high strength acrylic adhesive tape are applied to portions of the top walls and portions of the bottom walls of the foam rails so that additional mattress components may be adhered thereto. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a mattress border construction formed from pre-assembled components held together with adhesive tape. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Generally, mattresses are formed with a mattress central portion surrounded by a mattress border construction. The mattress central portion may comprise a series of coil springs connected together and encased in a quilted fabric. Alternatively, the mattress central portion may comprise polyurethane or latex foam layers or synthetic or natural fibers, optionally in combination with springs, and encased in quilted fabric. The central portion might also constitute an air mattress or water mattress or other body-supporting mattress structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Mattress border constructions stabilize the edge or border portion of the mattress. It is desirable to have a more firm or more rigid border portion surrounding a less firm, body-supporting mattress central portion. Mattress border constructions of various types have been disclosed in the prior art. U.S. Pat. No. 5,537,699 discloses a mattress border construction formed with a foam rail sleeve surrounding a plurality of springs arranged in a row. The foam rail sleeve defines a core into which the row of springs is inserted. The foam is slit along its length so that it may be opened to permit insertion of the row of springs. The slit is then sealed with a liquid adhesive or a hot melt adhesive. The mattress border construction forms a periphery around the mattress center section, and is joined to the mattress center section also with a liquid adhesive or a hot melt adhesive. The adhesive coats the foam strands and penetrates into the foam pores to securely bond the mattress border construction to the mattress center section. It has been found, however, that the liquid adhesive can be difficult to apply, and can create more need for substantially clean up of applicators and surrounding surfaces on which excess adhesive collects. In addition, liquid adhesive and hot melt adhesive cannot be pre-applied before the mattress border construction is delivered to a mattress fabricator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,701,623 shows a composite mattress topper, as opposed to a complete mattress construction. The topper has a latex foam rubber core section surround by border sections of urethane foam. The border sections are attached to the core section with adhesive to create the finished topper. The adhesive is not shown as able to be pre-applied before the component parts are shipped for later assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A mattress assembly shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,953,779 has a stack of foam mattress elements positioned one atop the other and joined together at their peripheral edges with hook and loop fasteners (VELCRO&reg;). The fasteners keep the foam mattress elements aligned in stacked relation, but are intended to be removably separated and reassembled. The mattress so formed does not have a mattress border construction, and a retainer rope is secured around the outer edge of the mattress to hold the elements together. Additional holding support is provided by containment blocks optionally attached with VELCRO&reg; to the head and foot of the mattress assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 2,326,441 shows a mattress covering in which strips of fabric are secured to the sidewall of a foam sponge rubber mattress core with an adhesive. The fabric strips form an anchor onto which the mattress covering material may be stitched. No mattress border construction is provided around the sponge rubber mattress core. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A border assembly for a mattress or bedding material according to the invention has at least a first foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall, and a second foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall. A strip or piece of double-faced, high strength adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the end wall of the first foam rail so that said end wall may be fixedly adhered with said adhesive tape to at least a portion of the side wall of the second foam rail sleeve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the adhesive tape is an acrylic adhesive tape with a thickness of 0.002 inch to 0.010 inch. A suitable width and length of the tape may be selected depending upon the specific to application. To ensure secure bonding to foam, the adhesive tape preferably has from 30 to 34 grains of adhesive per 24 square inches, most preferably 32 grains of adhesive per 24 square inches. The target bonding strength is from about 5 to 15 psi, preferably about 10 psi. The adhesive tape should set and bond relatively quickly, such that it reaches about 90% of full bonding capability within about 10 minutes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first foam rail has a second end wall and a second piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the second end wall so that the first foam rail may be fixedly attached to at least a portion of the side walls of each of the second foam rail and another foam rail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In the most preferred embodiment, the mattress border assembly comprises a series of four foam rails, with the first and third foam rails having double-sided adhesive tape applied to each end wall so that the first and third foam rails may be fixedly attached to at least a portion of the side walls of the second and fourth foam rails to form a generally rectangular frame. The double-sided tape preferably is applied to the end walls of the first and third foam rails by the foam fabricator prior to shipment to the mattress assembler. The side of the adhesive tape not adhered to the end walls is covered with a protective liner that may be removed when the border assembly is assembled by the mattress assembler. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In a most preferred embodiment, strips of double-faced adhesive tape are applied to at least a portion of each of the top and bottom walls of each of the first, second, third and fourth foam rails. The tape may be applied to the foam rails by the foam fabricator prior to shipment to the mattress assembler. When so applied, the adhesive surface not applied to the walls of the foam rails is covered with a protective liner that may be removed when the border is assembled by the mattress assembler. The adhesive tape on the top and bottom walls of the foam rails fixedly adheres the rails to other components of the mattress construction. In one such construction, sheets of foam are applied to cover the top and bottom walls and encase the mattress construction (such as springs) within the enclosed space defined by the foam rails (forming the mattress border assembly) and the sheets of foam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, double-sided adhesive tape strips may be applied to the end walls of the first and third foam rails, and to the portions of the side walls of the second and fourth foam rails to which the end walls of the first and third foam rails are to be adhered. The additional tape provides additional bonding strength. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A further aspect of the invention is a method of preparing a mattress border assembly for pre-assembly and shipment prior to assembly into a mattress construction. With such method, a strip or piece of double-faced adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of an end wall of a first foam rail, wherein one face of said adhesive tape adheres to the end wall and the other face of the adhesive tape is covered with a removable liner. The first foam rail and a second foam rail may be shipped unassembled to a mattress fabricator. When the mattress border assembly is ready to be assembled together, the removable liner may be removed and the end wall of the foam rail may be attached to a portion of the side wall of a second foam rail with the exposed adhesive face of the adhesive tape. Similarly, a piece of double-faced adhesive tape may be applied to at least a portion of a top wall or a bottom wall of a foam rail, wherein one face of said adhesive tape adheres to the top wall (or bottom wall) and the other face of the adhesive tape is covered with a removable liner. In this manner, the mattress border assembly may be shipped in unassembled condition, as a series of separate foam rails, or other components or parts, with adhesive tape applied thereto. The frame-like mattress border assembly then may be assembled together by the mattress assembler as the mattress itself is being constructed. The pre-assembly with the adhesive tape avoids the problems inherent with liquid and hot melt adhesives. In addition, shipping costs are reduced because the foam rails can be more efficiently packed. Moreover, the foam rails are less likely to be damaged when shipped prior to assembly into a mattress border construction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The invention comprises in yet another aspect a method for making a mattress border assembly by fixedly adhering together at least a portion of an end wall of a first foam rail to at least a portion of a side wall of a second foam rail with an adhesive tape. In the preferred embodiment, the end walls of the first and third foam rails are fixedly adhered to at least a portion of the side walls of the second and fourth foam rails to form a generally rectangular frame structure or mattress border assembly.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE FIGURES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is perspective view of a first side rail for a mattress border assembly showing adhesive tape applied to the end walls of the first side rail; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in elevation taken along line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is an end cross sectional view showing multiple side rails packed in a shipping carton wherein each side rail has a strip of double-sided adhesive tape applied to its end walls, with one surface of said strip covered by a removable protective liner; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of a mattress construction having a mattress border assembly according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a top plan view of a mattress border assembly according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of the mattress border assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of a mattress border assembly according to the invention including upper and lower cover sheets; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the mattress border assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, partially broken away to show strips of adhesive tape applied on the side wall surfaces of the side rails and end rails; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of the mattress border assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> formed of a resilient material such as polyurethane foam has a top wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a bottom wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, two side walls <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and two end walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be comprised of polyurethane foam surrounding springs or other firming central mattress structure, such as shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,537,699, or latex core, or fiber core or water or air mattress, or the like. Strips of double-sided adhesive tape <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are applied to each end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. If the side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is intended for shipment to a mattress fabricator for later assembly, the exposed adhesive surfaces of the strips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are covered with a removable protective liner <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the adhesive <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> applied to each surface of the strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Ideally, the strips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape are pre-applied to multiple foam side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> before the side rails are intended for assembly into a mattress border construction. The pre-assembled side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive applied to each end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may be stacked in a shipping carton <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for delivery to a mattress fabricator. Hence, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, twelve side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may be stacked in a shipping carton <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in pre-assembled form for later assembly into a mattress border assembly. Of course, it is also possible to ship end rails with pre-applied adhesive tape, or to include a combination of side rails and end rails in a single shipping carton. The strips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of double-sided adhesive tape are covered with liner <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to prevent the side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from adhering to the carton <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> or other side rails. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown best in FIGS. <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, a mattress border assembly <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> comprises a frame-like structure formed from two side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; adhered to two end rails <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. Each end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; preferably is formed of polyurethane foam, but may be comprised of polyurethane foam surrounding a network of supporting springs or other firming structure, such as shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,537,699, or the like. Each end rail has a top wall <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, a bottom wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, two side walls <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and two end walls <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape applied to a first end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of a first side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> adheres to a portion of a side wall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of a first end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Concurrently, a strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape applied to a second end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime; of the first side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> adheres to a portion of a side wall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>&prime; of a second end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. In like manner, a strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape applied to a first end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of a second side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; adheres to a portion of a side wall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of a first end rail, and a strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape applied to a second end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime; of the second side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime; adheres to a portion of a side wall <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>&prime; of the second end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The adhesive tape must have sufficient bonding strength to adhere to the strands of a polyurethane foam network. We have found that the tape should have a bonding strength in the range of 5 to 15 psi, preferably 10 psi. The tape preferably is coated with an acrylic adhesive to a coating weight in the range of 30 to 34 grains per 24 square inches, preferably 32 grains per 24 square inches. The bond must tack and set quickly, reaching about 90% of its full bonding capability within about 10 minutes of adhering parts together with the tape, and preferably reaches full bonding capability within about 15 minutes. The bond also should hold securely such that a 100 g weighted material held to foam with such adhesive tape will remain secure for at least 10,000 minutes. Preferably, the double-sided adhesive tape is 3M &num;9695 tape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Whereas a liquid adhesive or hot melt adhesive has ability to penetrate into the foam strand network to increase bonding sites and form a strong bond, the adhesive present on a strip of an adhesive tape does not penetrate the strands. Heretofore, adhesive tapes were not believed to have sufficient bonding strength to hold foam components together. Surprisingly, we have found that adhesive tapes with the above adhesive coating weigth, bonding strength and adhesive setting time, sometimes called dwell time, are able to hold foam components together so that tear strengths greater than about 15 psi are required to separate the foam components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment, the strips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape are applied to portions of the end walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of a side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so as to minimize the amount of adhesive tape and reduce costs. We have found that the strips should be applied at minimum to a portion of the end walls of the side rails that will be adjacent the outer edge of the mattress border assembly when the border assembly is fully assembled. Bonding along the outer edge of the mattress border encasement system efficiently maintains the durability and integrity of the system. We prefer to use adhesive tapes with a minimum width of two inches, although other widths may be suitable and perform effectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the present invention is that the side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and end rails <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be shipped in a pre-assembled form with strips <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape applied to their surfaces. One side of the double sided tape is applied to the rails by the foam fabricator, and the other side is covered with protective liner until such time as the rails are intended to be brought together to form a mattress border assembly. Such pre-assembly of mattress border assembly components for shipment prior to final assembly has not heretofore been possible with liquid adhesives and hot melt adhesives. Shipping the mattress border assembly as a fully-assembled construction is more costly because the mattress border assembly does not efficiently fill standard shipping cartons, but leaves a void space in the central portion bounded by the rails. By contrast, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, shipping cartons can be efficiently packed with multiple side rails (or with end rails or a combination of side rails and end rails or other components) in stacked relation, without wasted space or volume within a shipping carton. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a foam mattress core <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> surrounded by a mattress border assembly <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment of the invention. In this embodiment, each side rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes additional strips of adhesive tape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown best in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> first end rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a top wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a bottom wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, two side walls <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and two end walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime;. A strip <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of adhesive tape is applied to each end wall <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime; just as in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. In addition, an elongated strip <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of double-sided adhesive tape is applied to the top wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and an elongated strip <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of double-sided adhesive tape is applied to the bottom wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the first end rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Similarly, strips <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>&prime; are applied to the top wall <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; and bottom wall <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; of the second end rail <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. A first end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has an elongated strip <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of double-sided adhesive tape applied to the top wall <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and an elongated strip <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of double-sided adhesive tape applied to the bottom wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Similarly, strips <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>&prime; and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>&prime; are applied to the top wall <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime; and bottom wall <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime; of the second end rail <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;. In this preferred embodiment, the strips of adhesive tape are shown covering only a portion of the top walls and bottom walls of the end rails. While tape could be applied to cover the entire top and bottom wall surfaces of the side and end rails within the scope of this invention, it has been found that sufficient bonding is obtained by applying the strips to the portions nearest to what will become the outer perimeter of the mattress border assembly. With this preferred construction, less tape is required resulting in substantial material cost savings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The strips <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> are covered with protective liner (not shown) as in the prior embodiment to permit the rails to be shipped in an unassembled form for assembly by a mattress fabricator. When the mattress is ready for assembly, the protective liners are removed first from the strips of adhesive covering the end walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime; of the side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;. The end walls <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>&prime; are then adhered to portions of the side walls of the end rails <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; to form the mattress border assembly frame-like structure such as previously shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, the mattress core <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is positioned within the frame-like structure. The mattress core <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has been illustrated as a foam mattress, but might be any other mattress core structure known in the art, such as a network of springs within a casing or ticking material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The protective liners are then removed from tape strips <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to expose the adhesive surface of the strips on the top walls <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the top walls <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the end rails <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A first foam sheet cover <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is then adhered to the top walls <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> by the adhesive tape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The protective liners are then removed from tape strips <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to expose the adhesive surface of the strips on the bottom walls <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the side rails <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the bottom walls <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> of the end rails <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A second foam sheet cover <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is then adhered to the bottom walls <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by the adhesive tape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The mattress construction so formed comprises a mattress border assembly encasing a mattress core <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>. Assembly is completed by the mattress fabricator without use of liquid adhesives or hot melt adhesives. The mattress border assembly components are fixedly adhered together using only the adhesive tape. The mattress construction can then be completed in the customary fashion, by encasing the assembly in a fabric or quilting or ticking to form the completed mattress. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The invention has been illustrated by detailed description and examples of the preferred embodiments. Various changes in form and detail will be within the skill of persons skilled in the art. Therefore, the invention must be measured by the claims and not by the description of the examples or the preferred embodiments. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A border assembly for a mattress or bedding material, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a piece of adhesive tape applied to at least a portion of the end wall of the first foam rail so that said end wall may be fixedly adhered with said adhesive tape to at least a portion of the side wall of the second foam rail sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive tape comprises a double-faced adhesive tape having a first face and a second face. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first face and the second face of the adhesive tape are each coated with adhesive to a coating weight of at least 30 grains per 24 square inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive tape achieves a bonding strength of at least 5 psi when adhered to foam. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first face is adhered to the end wall and the second face is adhered to the side wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a second piece of adhesive tape applied to the portion of the side wall of the second foam rail sleeve so that the piece of adhesive tape applied to the portion of the end wall of the first foam rail fixedly adheres to the second piece of adhesive tape applied to the portion of the side wall of the second foam rail sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first foam rail has a second end wall and a second piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the second end wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a second piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the top wall of the first foam rail. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a second piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the top wall of the second foam rail. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a third foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth foam rail having a top wall, a bottom wall, a side wall and an end wall, wherein a second piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the end wall of the third foam rail so that said end wall may be fixedly adhered with said adhesive tape to at least a portion of the side wall of the fourth foam rail sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first foam rail has a second end wall and a third piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the second end wall of the first foam rail so that said end wall may be fixedly adhered with said adhesive tape to at least a portion of the side wall of the fourth foam rail sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the third foam rail has a second end wall and a third piece of adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the second end wall of the third foam rail so that said end wall may be fixedly adhered with said adhesive tape to at least a portion of the side wall of the second foam rail sleeve. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a second piece of adhesive tape is applied along at least a portion of the top wall of the first foam rail so that the top wall may be fixedly adhered to a foam sheet or another component of a mattress with said adhesive tape. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second piece of adhesive tape is applied along the entire length of the top wall of the first foam rail. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the top walls of each of the second, third and fourth foam rails. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The border assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein adhesive tape is applied to at least a portion of the bottom walls of each of the first, second, third and fourth foam rails so that the bottom walls may be fixedly adhered to a foam sheet or another component of a mattress with said adhesive tapes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of preparing a mattress border assembly for pre-assembly into a mattress construction, comprising: 
<claim-text>applying a piece of double-faced adhesive tape to at least a portion of an end wall of a foam rail, wherein a first face of said adhesive tape adheres to the end wall and a second face of the adhesive tape is covered with a removable liner. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising applying a second piece of double-faced adhesive tape to at least a portion of a top wall of a foam rail, wherein a first face of said second adhesive tape adheres to the top wall and the second face of the second adhesive tape is covered with a removable liner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method for making a mattress border assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>fixedly adhering together at least a portion of an end wall of a first foam rail to at least a portion of a side wall of a second foam rail with an adhesive tape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>fixedly adhering together at least a portion of a an end wall of a third foam rail to at least a portion of a side wall of a fourth foam rail with an adhesive tape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>fixedly adhering together at least a portion of a second end wall of the first foam rail to at least a portion of the side wall of the fourth foam rail with an adhesive tape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>fixedly adhering together at least a portion of a second end wall of the third foam rail to at least a portion of the side wall of the second foam rail with an adhesive tape. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adhesive tape comprises a double-faced adhesive tape having a first face and a second face, the first face and the second face each having adhesive thereon to a coating weight of at least 30 grains per 24 square inches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising joining the mattress border assembly to a body-supporting section of a mattress.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>7</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000021A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000021A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000021A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000021A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
