<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002876</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894376</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03B017/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>396</class>
<subclass>429000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>396</class>
<subclass>535000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Fluid-filled bodies for portable devices</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Baron</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Longmont</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Generally, the present invention relates to body casings for portable devices, wherein the body casing has at least one viewable chamber for holding a material. The present invention also relates to portable devices which comprise a functional unit having a housing which is configured to include at least one viewable chamber for holding a material. Portable devices according to the invention include a functional unit having a housing surrounding at least a portion of the functional unit. The housing comprises mating inner and outer walls which define a fluid-tight chamber for holding a material. The outer wall has a transparent section to allow a viewer to perceive the contents of the chamber. Body casings for portable devices according to the invention include mating top and bottom portions which are configured to define a casing chamber for holding a portable device. At least one of the top or bottom portions includes an inner wall and an outer wall defining at least one fluid-tight chamber for holding a material. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to bodies or housings for portable devices and more particularly, to bodies or housings for portable devices, wherein the body or housing has an inner and outer wall defining a fluid-fillable chamber therebetween. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Housings for portable devices are known in the art. Typically, housings for portable devices are designed of a rigid, shatterproof material, such as hard plastic, to protect the inner workings of the portable device from damage and provide a container for the device. One drawback of prior art housings lie in their mass production. When mass produced, the consumer is not given a choice as to the color of the housing. For example, most portable electronic devices have a black plastic housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Prior artisans have attempted to overcome this drawback by mass producing devices with a variety of different-colored housings. This solution suffers from several drawbacks. The consumer is still left with limited choices in the color of the device, and the manufacturer may be left with a large inventory of unsold devices if a particular color is not accepted by the consuming public. The consumer is also left with a housing having an unchangeable appearance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Other prior artisans have attempted to limit the potential for unsold inventory of devices by selling the device with a removable housing or face plate. The consumer may then purchase a colored face plate to snap on the device. If a particular color or design of a face plate does not entice the buying public&apos;s interest, the loss from unsold merchandise is minimized. However, this solution still limits the color and design of the housing to those selected by the manufacturer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In addition, if the user wants to change the color of the device, the user is forced to purchase a new faceplate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Still other prior artisans have attempted to allow a user to personalize a portable device by constructing a housing to include a photographic image provided by the user. For example, Nokia Corporation will make a personalized phone faceplate for a cellular phone incorporating a photograph supplied by a user for a fee. However, these personalized bodies still suffer from the drawback that the user must purchase a new faceplate if the user desires a change in the appearance of the device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to the invention there is provided a housing for a portable device comprising an inner wall and an outer wall defining a chamber. At least a part of the outer wall is translucent or opaque. In accordance with one aspect of the invention, the inner wall may be solid color, opaque or translucent; or alternatively, the inner wall or outer wall may comprise a logo or design. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, the chamber is filled with a material. In accordance with this aspect of the invention, the material preferably comprises a single or multi-colored fluid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, the housing includes a sealable port which provides access to the chamber. In accordance with this aspect of the invention, the port allows a user to change the contents of the chamber if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to yet another aspect of the invention, the housing defines a plurality of separate chambers. In accordance with this aspect of the invention, the chambers may be configured into a logo or design. Likewise, the chambers may have different colored materials or fluids therein. Further, one or more of the chambers may have a re-sealable port to allow a user to access the contents of the chambers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, the housing is configured as a body cover for a portable device already having a housing. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an embodiment of a body cover for a portable device; such as a camera according to the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is an exploded view of a camera body cover according to the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Generally, the present invention relates to a body cover for a portable device having at least one viewable chamber therein for holding at least one material, and relates to a portable device having a functional unit having a housing which is configured to include at least one viewable chamber for holding at least one material. The body covers and housings of the present invention may be configured for use in connection with any suitable device or functional unit. When used in connection with a functional unit, the housing preferably comprises the only protective housing for the unit, whereby removal of the housing (for refilling or otherwise) provides intimate access to the electronic or other components of the functional unit. When used in connection with a portable device, the housing preferably serves as a body cover for the entire device, wherein the portable device already possesses a housing. In a presently preferred embodiment, the invention is directed to a body cover for use in connection with a camera serving as the portable device to be housed. However, as will be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art, the concepts disclosed herein can be easily modified for a housing for a functional unit. Accordingly, the present invention should not be viewed as limited by whether a body casing or housing is desired, nor by the particular portable device or functional unit employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for a camera according to the invention. Body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and bottom portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is configured to define chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> which is sized to hold a camera. Top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is also configured to include control panel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> which allows a user to operate a camera disposed in chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. Control panel <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> includes mechanism <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> for advancing film or otherwise interacting with the camera and button <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> for activating the camera shutter release button to take a picture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> comprises inner wall <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and outer wall <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Inner wall <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> and outer wall <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> are configured to define chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> therebetween. Access to chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> may be effectuated by the provision of re-sealable port <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Preferably, re-sealable port <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> allows a user to fill chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> with a material. As will be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art, any suitable material may be provided in chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. For example, chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> may be filled with a colored liquid; two differently colored, two or more immiscible liquids; liquids containing solid particles such as glitter; a powder; or any other material which allows a user to personalize body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is presently preferred to fill chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> with fluids. Fluids are easier to remove from chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> if a user desires to, for example, change the color of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> It is also presently preferred to construct top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> out of a rigid material, such as plastic. Rigid materials resist tearing or breaking, thereby protecting contents of chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> (such as an electrical device) and the user from the contents of chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, use of a pliable material such as vinyl, may provide, in combination with a fluid filling, added mechanical protection for the camera by absorbing mechanical shock caused by dropping or otherwise bumping the container. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In a presently preferred embodiment, top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> comprises clear plastic to allow a user to view the contents of chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> and perhaps the contents of chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, only outer wall <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is translucent or opaque. Inner wall <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> may be white (to allow colored material in chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> to be easily viewable) and/or include a design or logo to be viewed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> also has a plurality of windows <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> which are configured to be isolated from chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> and to correspond with the camera&apos;s lens and view finder so as to prevent the contents of chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> from interfering with the operation of the camera. Alternatively, top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may define apertures in addition to, or instead of, windows <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. The provision of apertures may facilitate the use of certain portable devices by allowing access to the device or allowing the device to function more freely. For example, a camera with a protruding lens assembly or telescopic assembly would require an aperture in which to operate without obstruction from top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Other windows <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> should also be provided to provide a user an unobstructed view of the device&apos;s operational features so the device does not have to be removed from body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> during normal use and to provide access to other camera controls. Alternatively, the device&apos;s housing could be constructed to leave these areas unencumbered by a fluid-fillable housing according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may also include strap holder <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> to aid the portability of the device by means of a hand strap (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> An alternate body cover configuration is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> incorporating an alternative shutter release mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> on the front of the housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> At best, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, bottom portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is configured to mate with top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> to seal chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> and camera device <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> disposed in chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. Bottom portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable material and may connect to top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> by any suitable means. Preferably, bottom portion <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> comprises clear hard plastic and is frictionally engageable with top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Although not shown, bottom portion may be provided with an interstitial chamber, with or without a port, for holding a material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, chamber <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> may be configured into a design or logo, whereby when filled with a material, the logo or design is readily viewable. Also in accordance with the invention, body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be provided with a plurality of chambers <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> whereby a plurality of materials or colors may be viewable. For example, each side of generally cubic shaped body cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may comprise separate chamber <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, top portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> may have front face <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> comprising first chamber <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and second chamber <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated by one of ordinary skill in the art, almost any configuration of chambers is possible such that, for example, a user can personalize of portable device to have stripes of colors or organizations can configure a housing to portray a corporate logo, team mascot or team colors. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A portable device comprising: 
<claim-text>a functional unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing surrounding at least a portion of said functional unit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said housing comprising a mating inner wall and outer wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said inner wall and said outer wall defining a fluid-tight chamber therebetween for accepting a material within said chamber and wherein said outer wall of said chamber has a transparent section whereby a viewer can perceive a material accepted within said chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing comprises a rigid material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said rigid material comprises plastic. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said plastic is translucent. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing completely surrounds said functional unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said inner wall and said outer wall define a plurality of chambers, each of said chambers adapted for accepting a material therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing is of an integral construction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing comprises a plurality of pieces attached to each other or said functional unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said material comprises a granular solid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said material comprises a colored liquid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said material comprises a plurality of differently colored immiscible liquids. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said material comprises one or more colored liquids and solid flakes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing includes a resealable port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing is configured to depict a design to a viewer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein one or more of said chambers includes a resealable port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the chambers of said housing are configured to depict a design to a viewer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The portable device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said functional unit comprises a camera. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A body casing for a portable device comprising: 
<claim-text>a top portion and a bottom portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said top portion configured to define a casing chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said bottom portion being engageable to said top portion to seal said chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>one of said top and bottom portions comprising an inner wall and an outer wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said inner wall and said outer wall defining at least one fluid-tight chamber therebetween; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said outer wall further defining at least one re-sealable port in communication with said fluid-tight chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby a user may add or remove a material from said fluid-tight chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The body casing of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said housing comprises clear plastic and said material comprises a colored liquid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of changing the perceived texture of a device, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>surrounding at least on several sides, said device with a relatively narrow chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>pouring into said chamber material representing a perceived desired texture. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said narrow chamber defines the only housing of said device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said perceived texture is a color. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of encasing a portable device within a custom housing comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a sealable housing including a liquid containing portion viewable from outside said housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002876A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002876A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002876A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
