<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005196</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09681971</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>710</class>
<subclass>300000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and methods for using USB in programmable logic controllers</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Reed</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Charlottesville</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JOHN S. BEULICK</name-1>
<name-2>C/O ARMSTRONG TEASDALE, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE METROPOLITAN SQUARE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 2600</address-2>
<city>ST LOUIS</city>
<state>MO</state>
<postalcode>63102-2740</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A programmable logic controller (PLC) includes a central processing unit (CPU), at least one input/output (I/O) module and a communications interface between the CPU and the I/O module. The communications interface incorporates a universal serial bus (USB) protocol to create a standard, open interface providing a low cost, reliable communication link. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to communications between controllers and modules and, more specifically, to communications within programmable logic controller (PLC) systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> PLCs have a variety of configurations, including rack mounted I/O systems. The racks provide mechanical/electrical connection slots for power supply, CPU boards, and controlled I/O modules, which provide interfaces to external devices to be controlled. In a rack system, the CPU communicates across a fixed size backplane in a main rack with local I/O modules. In many applications, more I/O modules are needed than can fit in the main control rack. Therefore, expansion racks, or multiple expansion racks, are used to hold additional I/O modules. A communication link also exists between the main rack which includes the CPU and the expansion racks to allow data transfers between all I/O modules in the application and the main rack CPU. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Other PLC systems incorporate modular configurations which allows a CPU to interconnect to a varying number of I/O modules through a common connector interface, extending the backplane communication as each I/O base is added to the previous module. This allows flexibility in installation since there is not a fixed size, as in the rack systems. The I/O modules provide different functionalities to the PLC system but all use a common communication scheme passed through the module bases. Modular systems, also, do not have to be singularly interconnected but may use a communication link between groups of interconnected modular I/O. The modular system communication link is similar to the expansion rack communication links with the main CPU controlling the flow of data to all modular I/O groups either directly through the common base connectors and through the communication cable link to an expansion grouping, or groupings, of I/O modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> PLC systems require reliable data transfer methods to move data back and forth between the CPU and the I/O modules. With such a requirement, PLC systems need reliable error detection. Since most PLC systems are produced in large quantities, it is desirable that the communications interface be inexpensive. Further, some known PLC systems also have I/O modules that can be removed and inserted while the PLC system is powered, commonly referred to as hot-insertion and removal. Hot-insertion and removal allows the I/O modules to be replaced without shutting down the system. Also, for a PLC system to be economically viable, the functionality described above should be delivered at a minimal cost, at a minimal size and include readily available cabling. For ease of use, insertion of I/O modules should cause the CPU to auto configure the PLC system as I/O modules are added to the system. Further, upon power application the CPU should auto configure the PLC system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Known PLC systems incorporate many different proprietary and standard communication protocols and configurations for communications between a CPU of a PLC and I/O modules and PLC expansion racks or groups. Known industrial communications standards are still evolving, and include many different standards. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention is, in one aspect, a programmable logic controller (PLC) which includes a central processing unit (CPU), at least one input/output (I/O) module and a communications interface between the CPU and the I/O module(s), the communications interface incorporating a universal serial bus (USB) protocol. The communications interface can be placed in one or more of a rack backplane, or a modular backplane that interconnects I/O modules directly, or through interconnecting cables to wherever I/O modules are mounted. The interface allows the CPU to communicate directly with the I/O modules using USB protocol. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In other aspects, the USB interface provides a data communication link between main and expansion racks or expansion I/O groups, allowing more flexibility in installing the control system with existing non-USB supporting I/O modules. USB providing the standard communication link to allow rack I/O, modular I/O, and I/O modules with integrated USB support to be supported in any mix by a single CPU. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In other aspects of the invention, I/O units and I/O modules incorporate USB interfacing for connection to a USB port of any CPU. This allows for I/O control without having to use an embedded PLC CPU, but rather I/O module control using any computer CPU that supports USB. In another aspect, there is described a method of using USB communications protocols to control and monitor performance of I/O modules.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of a rack PLC system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a pictorial view of a modular PLC system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a view of stand alone USB slave I/O modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a modular PLC system based on a USB link and stand alone USB slave I/O modules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a PLC system using USB for expansion rack and I/O control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an example of using a generic PC to control USB slave I/O modules and an expansion I/O grouping.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a PLC <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment of the present invention. PLC <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a central processing unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, with embedded memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a plurality of Input/Output (I/O) units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, power supplies <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and communications interfaces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. PLC system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further includes multiple racks <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to support I/O modules <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in addition to I/O modules within main rack <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Although multiple I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in multiple racks <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, PLC <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include only one I/O unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, for example, an I/O unit for interfacing to a motor, or an I/O unit for receiving various input signals from devices, i.e., a switch (not shown). In addition, PLC <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include only one of racks <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, in operation, typically are coupled to one or more external devices (not shown). A user program (not shown) is stored in memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The user program controls operation of CPU <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> so that based at least in part on inputs from external devices, read by I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, appropriate outputs to external devices, from I/O unit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are generated. Specifically, control and data signals (not shown) are bidirectionally coupled between CPU <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The signals are utilized to exchange information between CPU <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Information is exchanged between I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and external devices using various means, for example individual wires and multiple conductor cables. In addition, certain external devices typically have integrated wires or cables to be coupled to I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Communications interfaces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are configured to provide communications between CPU <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in main rack <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in expansion racks <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, thereby allowing for CPU control of all I/O units <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> with CPU <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, communications interfaces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are configured as USB interfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a pictorial diagram of a PLC system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which includes a CPU <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> with an embedded memory <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, I/O modules <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and power supplies <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. System <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> provides similar functionality to system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). However system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is configured to be modular. CPU <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and I/O modules <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> plug together to create a single PLC group and I/O modules <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are interchangeable to create flexible I/O module groupings, dependent upon a specific application PLC system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is supporting. PLC system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> further includes communications interfaces <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which, as in system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, allow a single CPU to control grouping of I/O modules which are located at separate locations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows I/O modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> which are configured with a slave USB port as its data communication link to the host CPU. Rather than providing communications interfaces <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> respectively, I/O modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> are configured with a USB interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> which allows for CPU control of each of I/O modules <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> directly. In alternative embodiments, USB interface <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is configured as a Universal Serial Bus (USB) connector, either series A, series B, or mini series B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a PLC system <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, which incorporates I/O modules <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). System <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is similar to system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), but I/O modules <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> communicate with CPU <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> through a USB cabling arrangement. System <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> differs from system <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in that, I/O modules <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) are configured for both mechanical and electrical attachment of I/O bases, into which I/O modules are installed. In system <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> a USB hub <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> provides a USB interface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> from CPU <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to each of I/O modules <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. In alternative embodiments, CPU connector <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, and USB interface <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> are configured as Universal Serial Bus (USB) connectors, either series A, series B, or mini series B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Universal Serial Bus (USB) has become a standard in the personal computer industry. USB is advantageous over other computer interfaces because up to 127 devices can be supported on one port and USB supplies power to the peripherals, reducing the need for additional power supplies. Further, depending on the speed of the peripheral, USB supports communications at 1.5 Mbps, 12 Mbps and in some cases up to 480 Mbps. In another embodiment, USB incorporates a tiered star topology. In addition, USB devices can be adding during system operation. USB also eliminates problems encountered with existing peripheral additions, such as cabling, for example, null modem cables and handshaking lines. Also, USB devices are configured with slave ports for communications with a host port of the CPU. USB supports four different data transfer types:- isochronous, control, interrupt, and bulk. Most CPUs being produced support USB, including those being used as the CPUs for PLC systems. Further, USB allows placement of I/O modules up to five meters apart. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram view of a PLC system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> incorporating USB where the CPU and I/O modules are interconnected via USB cabling. System <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a central processing unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, an embedded memory <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, a plurality of Input/Output (I/O) units <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, power supplies <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, communications interface <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, I/O expansion racks <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and stand alone I/O modules <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. CPU <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> includes USB connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. USB connector <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is attached to a USB cable <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a USB hub <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Hub <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> provides a USB interface from CPU <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to I/O expansion racks <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and communications interface <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, thus allowing CPU <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to control all I/O units <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. USB connector <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is attached to a USB cable <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> that is connected to a USB hub <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. Hub <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> provides a USB interface from CPU <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to stand alone I/O modules <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, thereby allowing CPU <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to control stand alone I/O modules <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In alternative embodiments, USB connectors <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are configured as Universal Serial Bus connectors, either series A, series B, or mini series B. In one exemplary embodiment, communications interface <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is configured as Universal Serial Bus (USB) connector. USB cables <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> are configurable, in one embodiment, to be up to five meters long. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, not shown, a PLC is configured with an I/O rack for connecting the CPU to the individual I/O modules. In such an embodiment, the I/O rack is configured to facilitate communication between the CPU and the I/O modules by incorporating a USB interface into the I/O rack. The CPU and the I/O modules interface to the USB when inserted into the I/O rack. In such an embodiment, the CPU is incorporated into the I/O rack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In a further alternative embodiment, the CPU is located separate from the I/O rack. The I/O rack incorporates USB slave ports as part of a backplane for communication with one or more I/O modules inserted into the I/O rack and the I/O rack provides a USB interface for one or more external USB devices, one being a CPU module. Designing USB into the I/O rack minimizes cabling requirements between USB compatible modules while still utilizing the open communications standards of USB. Such a design allows a single cable between a CPU module and an I/O rack. An I/O rack configured as a USB slave port is further configured to perform local I/O scanning and report data from all I/O modules in one or more series of messages to and from the CPU module. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a block diagram view of a personal computer (PC) system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> incorporating USB where the PC and I/O modules are interconnected via USB cabling. System <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> includes a PC <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, multiple Input/Output (I/O) units <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, a power supply <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> and a communications interface <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. I/O unit <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> includes a USB connector <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a USB cable <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. USB cable <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> is connected to a USB connector <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> on PC <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> thereby allowing PC <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to control I/O unit <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. PC <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> also includes a USB connector <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>, which is connected to a USB cable <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. USB cable <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is connected to a USB connector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> on communications interface <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> thereby allowing PC <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> to control I/O units <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. In alternative embodiments, USB connectors <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> are configured as Universal Serial Bus connectors, either series A, series B, or mini series B. In one exemplary embodiment, communications interface <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is configured as Universal Serial Bus (USB) connector. USB cables <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> are configurable, in one embodiment, to be up to five meters long. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> USB is a common communication standard and is incorporated into many known CPU designs. In incorporating open communications standards, USB is used for implementing hardware communications and controls, without drawbacks of known PLC proprietary communications platforms. In addition, use of USB allows interfacing of I/O modules to multiple CPUs, provided that software drivers for each of the individual I/O modules are installed with the CPU to be connected to. In such embodiments, such as the example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, I/O modules or racks incorporating I/O modules are compatible with CPU modules from multiple suppliers, due to the open communications standards of USB, thereby providing a user with portability options between multiple PLC systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in terms of various specific embodiments, those skilled in the art will recognize that the invention can be practiced with modification within the spirit and scope of the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A programmable logic controller (PLC) comprising: 
<claim-text>a central processing unit (CPU); </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one input/output (I/O) module; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a communications interface between said CPU and said at least one I/O module, said communications interface incorporating a universal serial bus (USB) protocol. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said CPU is configured as a USB host. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said CPU comprises at least one USB port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said I/O module is connected with a tiered star topology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said I/O modules are configured with USB slave ports. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> comprising standard USB hub and cabling for connecting said CPU to said I/O modules. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising an I/O rack for connecting said CPU to said I/O modules, said rack configured to facilitate communication between said CPU and said I/O rack by embedding a USB interface into a rack backplane. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A PLC according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said communications interface is configured to operate at at least one of 1.5 MBPS and 12 MBPS currently but allowed to expand to future supported data transfer rates according to the USB standards. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. An I/O unit for a PLC system comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one connector for coupling to an external device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one connector for coupling to existing I/O modules (existing normal I/O modules, either rack or modular in nature); and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector for coupling to a CPU, said connector comprising a slave USB interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A connector for coupling to a CPU according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, said connector for coupling to a CPU comprising at least one of a USB series A connector, a USB series B connector and a USB mini-series B connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An I/O unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a connector for coupling to other I/O units, wherein the other I/O units communicate through the I/O unit in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> to a CPU through the connector in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, said connector comprising a USB interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. An I/O unit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> said connector for coupling to a CPU comprising at least one of a USB series A connector, a USB series B connector and a USB mini-series B connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An I/O module for a PLC system comprising: 
<claim-text>a circuit configured to interface to an external I/O device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit configured to interface to a USB bus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An I/O module according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said circuit configured to interface to a USB bus is configured as a USB slave port. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An I/O module according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said circuit configured to interface to a USB bus is configured to communicate at at least one of 1.5 MBPS, 12 MBPS, and 480 MBPS. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. An I/O module according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said circuit configured to interface to a USB bus is configured to be inserted and removed from a turned on PLC system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An I/O module according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said circuit configured to interface to a USB bus is configured with a tiered star topology. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method for incorporating a communications protocol into a PLC system, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a PLC system CPU with at least one USB host port; </claim-text>
<claim-text>configuring at least one I/O module as a USB slave port; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the PLC system CPU to the I/O module using a USB interface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the PLC system CPU is configured to communicate on said USB interface at least one of 1.5 MBPS and 12 MBPS. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said I/O module is configured to be inserted and removed from a turned on PLC system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the PLC system CPU is configured to support a tiered star topology.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005196A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
