<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002290A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002290A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002290</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10224612</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020820</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01B005/24</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>362</class>
<subclass>460000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Sliding style headlamp adjuster</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10224612</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020820</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09504250</doc-number>
<document-date>20000215</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6474850</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Burton</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ludington</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>GODFREY &amp; KAHN S.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>780 NORTH WATER STREET</address-1>
<city>MILWAUKEE</city>
<state>WI</state>
<postalcode>53202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A sliding adjuster includes a base housing with a slide positioned at least partially therein. The base housing includes mounting tabs so that the adjuster can be secured to the back of a headlamp assembly support frame. The base housing includes channels along its sides in which rails extending from the slide are disposed. A ball stud extends from the slide, the ball of which is engaged in a reflector within the headlamp assembly such that axial movement of the ball stud causes movement of the reflector. Movement of the slide is caused by rotation of an adjustment screw that is threaded into the slide but held in axial position with respect to the base housing. The adjuster may include a vehicle headlamp aiming device (&ldquo;VHAD&rdquo;) if required for the particular application. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to adjuster mechanisms, and more particularly to a sliding headlamp adjuster mechanism for use in motor vehicles. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In traditional sealed beam style headlamps, the lamp&apos;s aim is adjusted by rotating one or more screws that hold the frame of the lamp to the vehicle. Such adjustment is made from the front of the vehicle by inserting a screwdriver or the like between the lamp frame and the vehicle trim and turning the screws to alter the orientation of the lamp and effectuate the desired adjustment. As the design of motor vehicles has evolved, headlamps have continually been reconfigured to improve the aerodynamics and styling of the front end of the vehicle. Modem headlamps are designed so that their lenses follow the contour of the vehicle to provide an aerodynamically efficient exterior surface. Adjustment of these headlamps must still be performed in order to provide an optimal beam of light and to prevent the aiming of light beams toward oncoming vehicles. Such adjustment is made by moving a reflector within the lamp assembly so that light is directed in the desired manner. Automotive manufacturers&apos; demand for aerodynamically efficient headlamp designs has lead to modular designs where the headlamp adjustment mechanism is located within the interior of the engine compartment and positioned such that adjustment can be easily performed without removing any trim pieces. Thus, the constraints of the installation area and the demands of the automobile manufacturers for aerodynamic headlamp designs dictate the location from which adjustment must be made. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> There are many adjuster devices designed for use in connection with aerodynamic headlight designs including, among others, the devices disclosed in U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,707,133 and 5,214,971 to Burton, the inventor of the present invention. Modern automotive headlamp assemblies typically include several basic parts: a support frame, a reflector, a lens, a bulb, and one or more adjusters. The support frame houses the reflector and the bulb on a pivotable mounting to allow the aim of the light to be adjusted using the adjusters and provides a mounting surface for attaching adjusters. The lens seals the front of the support frame to protect it from the elements assailing the front end of the vehicle and provides an aerodynamic shape and attractive appearance. The reflector mounts on one fixed ball joint and is adjustable horizontally and vertically using adjusters that interface with the reflector through moving ball joints. The moving ball joints are moved by actuating the adjusters connected to the moving ball joints by a ball stud. Geared angle style adjusters, such as the ones disclosed in the referenced Burton patents, are often used to adjust the aim of the headlamp. However, such devices are designed to allow adjustment of the headlamp from a location behind the assembly, typically from within the engine compartment and immediately behind and above the lamp assembly. Accordingly, such devices cannot be effectively used in vehicles where the area immediately behind and above the lamp assembly is not accessible. One such vehicle design is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. In that design, the vehicle fender <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> covers the headlamp assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rendering the area behind and above the assembly substantially inaccessible without removal of the fender <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the vehicle. The area below the headlamp assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is similarly inaccessible because of the bumper <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and other vehicle components. Thus, existing geared angle style headlamp adjusters have not been found to be effective for use in such vehicle designs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventionally in a vehicle such as the one shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14, a</cross-reference> sealed beam style headlamp is used. However, due to consumer and vehicle manufacturer styling preferences and performance objectives, it is desirable to use a reflector style headlamp in such vehicles. The conventional method for adjusting sealed beam lamps cannot be used to adjust a reflector style lamp and the area immediately above and behind the lamp is inaccessible such that a conventional geared angle style adjuster cannot be used. Accordingly, a need exists for a headlamp adjuster which can be used in connection with a vehicle design where the area behind and above the lamp assembly is substantially inaccessible and the use of a reflector style lamp is desired. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a sliding headlamp adjuster that allows for precise adjustment control, can be used where the area above and behind the lamp assembly is inaccessible, ensures smooth operation, can include a vehicle headlamp aiming device (&ldquo;VHAD&rdquo;), is cost effective, and which solves the problems raised or not solved by existing headlamp adjuster designs. As described in more detail below and shown in the accompanying drawings, the sliding headlamp adjuster uses a two-piece sliding body construction to meet these objectives. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> A headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention includes a base housing with a slide disposed at least partially therein. The base housing includes one or more mounting tabs such that the adjuster can be mounted to the back of a headlamp assembly support frame. The base housing has channels along its sides in which rails extending from the slide are disposed. A ball stud is threaded into the slide and protrudes therefrom passing through the base housing into the headlamp assembly. The ball of the ball stud is engaged in a socket in the reflector so that axial movement of the ball stud causes movement of the reflector. The ball stud is caused to axially move by a corresponding sliding of the slide along the channels in the base. Movement of the slide results from rotation of an adjustment screw that is threaded into the sliding piece but held in axial position (free to rotate) in the base. Thus, rotation of the axially-fixed adjustment screw causes movement of the slide and the ball stud with respect to the base housing. Because the base is fixed to the headlamp assembly support frame and the ball is engaged in a socket in the reflector, rotation of the adjusting screw causes changes in the orientation of the reflector within the assembly and the aim of the lamp is thereby adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In certain applications, the adjuster must include a VHAD. U.S. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (&ldquo;NHTSA&rdquo;) standards require that horizontal adjuster mechanisms be either non-readjustable after the proper aim has been achieved or be equipped with a non-recalibratable VHAD. Currently, VHADs are required for horizontal adjusters but not for vertical adjusters. The VHAD used in the sliding adjuster includes an indicator plate with a post extending therefrom. The post includes a groove with a partial helical twist and is axially fixed (free to rotate) with respect to the base housing. A tab jutting from the slide is disposed in the groove. The indicator plate is positioned on the base near the adjustment screw such that indicator lines on the plate can be seen by the person adjusting the aim of the lamp. The base includes aiming rails behind the plate that, in connection with the indicator lines, allow the person making the adjustment to perceive how much of an adjustment has been made. Because the groove includes a partial helical twist, as the tab jutting from the slide moves along the groove with movement of the slide, the post and indicator plate are caused to rotate. The scale of the movement of the plate as reflected in the indicator lines is designed to reflect the corresponding movement of the reflector. If no VHAD is required, the indicator plate and post are simply not installed in the sliding adjuster. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The new design has numerous benefits that make it advantageous for use in connection with reflector style headlamps. The new design allows precise control of reflector aim, has smooth operational characteristics, can include a VHAD, and effectively maintains adjustment. Further, the new adjuster can be used where the area above and behind the lamp is inaccessible and it is cost effective to manufacture and install. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> While the present invention is particularly useful in automotive headlamp assemblies, other applications are certainly possible and references herein to use in a headlamp assembly should not be deemed to limit the application of the present invention. Rather, the present invention may be advantageously adapted for use where similar performance capabilities and characteristics are desired. These and other objects and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the detailed description, claims, and accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a sliding headlamp adjuster constructed in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front view of a sliding headlamp adjuster constructed in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a rear view of a sliding headlamp adjuster constructed in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a section detail of the rear view of a sliding headlamp adjuster constructed in accordance with the embodiment of the present invention shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is cross-sectional view of the adjustment screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> taken generally along the line <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a perspective view of a portion of the adjustment screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is a section detail of the threads of the adjustment screw shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b; </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partial cross-section of the sliding headlamp adjuster in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> taken generally along the line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a partial front view of a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention wherein the adjustment screw is being rotated in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> resulting in movement of the VHAD indicator plate in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention with the adjustment screw being rotated in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> resulting on movement of the VHAD indicator plate in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and the ball stud in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is another rendering of the cross-section shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> with the adjustment screw having been rotated such that the slide is in a different position from that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is partial front view of a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention wherein the adjustment screw is being rotated in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> resulting in movement of the VHAD indicator plate in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a side view of a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention installed in a headlamp assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic representation of the positioning of sliding headlamp adjusters in accordance with the present invention with respect to a headlamp assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a front view of a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention shown in an installed position; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a vehicle with which a sliding headlamp adjuster in accordance with the present invention might advantageously be used.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a sliding headlamp adjuster (identified generally as <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention includes a base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> with a slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> disposed at least partially therein. The base housing <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has one or more mounting tabs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> such that the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be mounted to the back of a headlamp assembly support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>). The amount and configuration of the tabs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be configured as necessary for particular installations. Alternatively, a quarter-turn mounting system could be used. The base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has interior channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> running along its sides <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. When viewed from the exterior, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> appear rectangular in cross-section. However, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, on the interior, the channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> have a generally sideways T-shaped open cross section with a top T portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, a bottom T portion <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and a narrower neck T portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has rails extending from each of its sides. The rails include an upper rail <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and a lower rail <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Each rail includes a leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> with a foot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extending therefrom. The rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are disposed within the channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> so as to allow the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to move with respect to the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> extend along the side(s) of the slide and provide ample length of engagement to allow a smooth sliding movement and to resist binding. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> of the lower rail <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> interfaces with the neck portion <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the channel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Because this interface is relatively near to the base of the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, there is little flex of the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The foot <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of upper rail <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> interfaces with the top T portion <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the channel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> such that the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is flexed at an angle as indicated by arrows <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> which reflect the difference from straight of the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The continually flexed engagement of the upper rail <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> with the channel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> helps reduce any &ldquo;play&rdquo; or &ldquo;slop&rdquo; in the operation of the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, reduces problematic headlamp &ldquo;flutter&rdquo; (flutter is the apparent flickering of a headlamp caused by an improperly secured headlamp that moves when a vehicle hits a bump), and maintains the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the desired adjustment. This resistance to &ldquo;flutter&rdquo; is typically tested by applying a set force to the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction of arrow <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> while measuring the resulting deflection of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the same direction. In this test, deflection of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is resisted primarily by the rigidity of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the slide rail <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and housing channel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> connection described, and the connection points of adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The rail and channel connection is subjected to a bending moment when the test load is applied urging the slide to rock in the rail channel. Minimizing rocking of the slide in the rail channel area as a result of this bending moment minimizes deflection of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Since the leg <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the lower rail <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> resists flex, a greater resistance to rocking and hence to deflection is achieved. While this configuration for the engagement between the rails <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and the channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has been found effective, alternative configurations could also be effective. Similarly, while it has been found effective to have two rail/channel engagements, one on each side of the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, other numbers and configurations could be used. For example, if additional stability is desired, an additional rail/channel could be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11, a</cross-reference> ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> extends from the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> passing through the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the assembly support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and into the headlamp assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The ball <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is engaged in a socket (not shown) in the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> so that axial movement of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> causes movement of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is caused to move along its axis by movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> along the channels <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> results from rotation of an adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> that is threaded into the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has a head <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, a narrow neck portion <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, and a threaded portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is free to rotate and is secured in axial position in the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> by a screw retainer clip <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) that snap-fits around the narrow neck portion <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Because the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is threaded into the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> but is axially fixed and free to rotate with respect to the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, when the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is rotated it causes movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with respect to the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Thus, rotation of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> causes movement of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> with respect to the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Because the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is fixed to the headlamp assembly support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the ball <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is engaged in a socket in the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, rotation of the adjusting screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> causes changes in the orientation of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> within the assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the aim of the lamp is thereby adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> may include an anti-thread-stripping plate <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> between the narrow neck portion <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and the threaded portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The anti-thread-stripping plate <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is a disc-shaped protrusion from the shaft of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> that has one or more engagement barbs <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The purpose of the anti-thread-stripping plate is to reduce the possibility of the threaded portion <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of the adjustment screw stripping the plastic threads in the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> when an over-adjustment is attempted. As best visualized by referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, if the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is rotated to the point where the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> abuts the anti-thread-stripping plate <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, the engagement barbs <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> project into the end of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to prevent further rotation of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. Thus, stripping of the threads in the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in which the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is engaged is prevented because the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> cannot be further rotated. The adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> can be rotated to release the engagement barbs <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> to restore the normal operation of the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are manufactured from glass-filled nylon using conventional injection molding processes. The ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is preferably made from steel and manufactured in a conventional cold-heading process. Due to the possible exposure to harsh elements, manufacturing the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> from a zinc alloy using a die casting method is preferable to help prevent corrosion and increase durability. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, the threaded portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> has flattened sides <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and a forty-five degree thread angle. The flattened sides <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, while facilitating manufacture of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> using a die-cast process, are advantageous in that they facilitate a thread-forming initial threading of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> into the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the forty-five degree thread angle is advantageous in the thread forming because it requires the displacement of a minimal amount of material while maximizing the strength of the threads in the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The combined use of a forty-five degree thread angle and flattened sides <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is helpful in achieving a low drive torque, low prevailing torque, and a resistance to stripping. Of course, other materials and part configurations could be used for particular designs and the description herein of particular materials and configurations should not be deemed to limit the scope of the invention. For example, the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> could be manufactured from plastic or a metal other than steel and other plastics or materials could be used to form the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In certain applications, the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> must include a VHAD. Preferably, the VHAD used in the sliding adjuster (identified generally as <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>) includes an indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> with a post <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> extending therefrom. The post <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> includes a groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> with a partial helical twist <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 9</cross-reference>) and is axially fixed (free to rotate) in a snap fit to the base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> jutting from the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is disposed in the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is positioned on the base <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> near the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> such that indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> on the plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> can be seen by the person adjusting the aim of the lamp. The base housing <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes aiming rails <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> behind the plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> that, in connection with the indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, allow the person making the adjustment to perceive how much of an adjustment has been made. Because the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes a partial helical twist <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, as the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> jutting from the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> moves along the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> with movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the post <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are caused to rotate. The scale of the movement of the indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> with respect to the aiming rails <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is designed to reflect the corresponding movement of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> within the assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. If no VHAD is required, the VHAD <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> is simply not installed in the sliding adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The other materials could be used, manufacture of the VHAD <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> from nylon using an injection molding process is preferable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11, 12</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the sliding headlamp adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is installed to the rear of the headlamp assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> using the mounting tabs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> extends into the assembly <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> through the support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> where the ball <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is disposed in a socket in the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. An oaring <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> may be disposed about the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to provide a seal between the shaft of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the assembly support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A lens <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> covers the front of the support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and protects the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and bulb (not shown) from the elements assailing the front of the vehicle. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the left adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> controls the horizontal movement of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and is thus equipped with a VHAD <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. The right adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> controls the vertical movement of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and is not equipped with a VHAD. As shown in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and VHAD indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are positioned such that they are visible and accessible from the front of the vehicle between the lens <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and the bumper <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> includes indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> that are appropriate for reflecting adjustment when the adjuster is installed on either side of a vehicle. A portion of the indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is covered by the assembly support frame <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or lens <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> such that the indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> that are visible through the gap will properly reflect the adjustment being made. Such a covering of the indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> allows the manufacturer to supply one adjuster for installation on both sides of the vehicle. Alternatively, the indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> could have indicator lines that are specifically arranged for a particular side of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The operation of the sliding headlamp adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to effectuate adjustment of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> once installed is quite simple. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and in detail in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, rotation of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> causes the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to move toward the head <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. This movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> results in the movement of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. As the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> that extends from the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> into the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> moves with the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is caused to move within the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and along the partial helical twist <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Movement of the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> along the partial helical twist <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> causes a rotation of the post <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the VHAD <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>. The amount that that the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> has moved (and caused adjustment of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>) is shown by reference to the indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and aiming rails <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Operation of the adjuster <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to effectuate movement of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction of that described in the immediately preceding paragraph is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In such operation, the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is rotated in the direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> which causes the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to move away from the head <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the adjustment screw <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. This movement of the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> results in the movement of the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the direction opposite that indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. As the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> that extends from the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> into the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> moves with the slide <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> is caused to move within the groove <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and along the partial helical twist <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. Movement of the tab <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> along the partial helical twist <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> causes a rotation of the post <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and indicator plate <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> of the VHAD <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in the direction indicated by arrow <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The amount that the ball stud <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> has moved (and caused adjustment of the reflector <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>) is shown by reference to the indicator lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and aiming rails <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As illustrated by the foregoing description and shown in the Figures, the present invention is more suitable as a headlamp adjuster than are conventional adjusters. The present invention overcomes the limitations and disadvantages of existing adjusters by utilizing an effective design which allows precise control of reflector aim, has smooth operational characteristics, effectively maintains adjustment, can be used where the area behind and above the lamp is inaccessible, and which is cost effective and efficient to manufacture and install. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Although the invention has been herein shown and described in what is perceived to be the most practical and preferred embodiments, it is to be understood that the invention is not intended to be limited to the specific embodiments set forth above. Rather, it is recognized that modifications may be made by one of skill in the art of the invention without departing from the spirit or intent of the invention and therefore, the invention is to be taken as including all reasonable equivalents to the subject matter of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An adjuster mechanism comprising: 
<claim-text>a base housing having a plurality of channels therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide having a plurality of rails extending therefrom; the slide at least partially disposed within the base housing such that the rails are in sliding engagement in the channels; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment screw axially fixed in the base housing and threaded into the slide such that rotation of the adjustment screw causes movement of the slide with respect to the base housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An adjuster comprising: 
<claim-text>a base housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a slide at least partially disposed within the base housing and in sliding engagement therewith; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment screw axially fixed with respect to the base housing and threaded into the slide such that rotation of the adjustment screw causes movement of the slide with respect to the base housing in a direction substantially parallel with the axis of the adjustment screw. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A headlamp comprising: 
<claim-text>an assembly support frame housing a reflector having a socket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjuster secured to the support frame housing, the adjuster having a ball stud extending therefrom with a ball engaged in the socket of the reflector, wherein the adjuster includes a base housing, a slide at least partially disposed within the base housing and in sliding engagement therewith, and an adjustment screw axially fixed with respect to the base housing and threaded into the slide such that rotation of the adjustment screw causes movement of the slide with respect to the base housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A headlamp assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>an assembly support frame housing a reflector having a socket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjuster secured to the assembly support frame, the adjuster having a ball stud extending therefrom with a ball engaged in the socket of the reflector, wherein the adjuster includes a base housing having a plurality of channels therein, a slide having a plurality of rails extending therefrom at least partially disposed within the base housing such that the rails are in sliding engagement in the channels, and an adjustment screw axially fixed in the base housing and threaded into the slide such that rotation of the adjustment screw causes movement of the slide with respect to the base housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A process for adjusting the aim of a headlamp comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>mounting an adjuster on an assembly support frame that houses a reflector having a socket therein, the assembly support frame having a lens covering a front thereof, the adjuster mounted such that an adjustment screw extending therefrom extends toward the front of the assembly support frame and such that a ball stud extending therefrom is engaged in the socket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the adjustment screw to cause the ball stud to move the reflector to effectuate the desired adjustment. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. An adjuster comprising: 
<claim-text>a main body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second body moveable relative to the main body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment screw axially fixed relative to the main body, wherein rotation of the adjustment screw moves the second body relative to the main body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an extension member extending from the second body for interacting with and imparting movement of the second body to a third body to be adjusted.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1-14</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002290A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
