<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001644A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001644A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001644</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894188</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H03K003/037</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>327</class>
<subclass>206000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Input circuit with switched reference signals</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chi-Yeu</given-name>
<family-name>Chao</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gregory</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Taylor</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Portland</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Lawrence E. Lycke</name-1>
<name-2>BLAKELY, SOKOLOFF, TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Seventh Floor</address-1>
<address-2>12400 Wilshire Boulevard</address-2>
<city>Los Angeles</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025-1026</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An input circuit includes a comparator circuit and a multi-reference circuit. The input circuit receives an input signal and generates an output signal as a function of the input signal and a reference signal received from the multi-reference circuit. The comparator circuit detects a crossing of the input signal relative to the reference signal and causes a corresponding transition of the output signal. In response to the transition of the output signal, the multi-reference circuit provides a different reference signal to the comparator circuit. The reference signals provided by the multi-reference circuit are selected to create hysteresis in the operation of the input circuit. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This disclosure relates generally to integrated circuits, and in particular but not exclusively, relates to input circuits. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A typical integrated circuit includes input circuits to receive signals from other parts of the integrated circuit and to output them with &ldquo;restored&rdquo; voltage levels and the appropriate driving current for the circuitry receiving the output signal of the input circuit. As is well known, a variety of sources may inject noise into the signal received by the input circuit. For example, sources include ringing caused by mismatched output drivers or interconnect impedance, signal cross-coupling, and power supply noise. This noise can cause an input circuit to improperly output the received signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> One conventional solution to this noise problem is create hysteresis in the input circuit by changing the relative &ldquo;strength&rdquo; of pull-up and pull-down paths in the input circuit, as a function of the logic level of the output signal generated by the input circuit (e.g., a Schmitt trigger circuit). However, this solution tends to be sensitive to process, temperature and voltage (PVT) variations and, further, tends to be relatively slow.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Non-limiting and non-exhaustive embodiments of the present invention are described with reference to the following Figures, wherein like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the various views unless otherwise specified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating a computer system incorporating an input circuit according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating the processor of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating an input circuit according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating the operation of the input circuit depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagram illustrating an implementation of the trip point circuit depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram illustrating an implementation of the input circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, according to one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a timing diagram illustrating the operation of input circuit depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a timing diagram illustrating in more detail the response of the input circuit depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE ILLUSTRATED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of a circuit and method for receiving and input signal are described herein. In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth (such as, for example, the components/functional units of a microprocessor) to provide a thorough understanding of embodiments of the invention. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize, however, that the invention can be practiced without one or more of the specific details, or with other methods, components, materials, etc. In other instances, well-known structures, materials, or operations are not shown or described in detail to avoid obscuring aspects of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Reference throughout this specification to &ldquo;one embodiment&rdquo; or &ldquo;an embodiment&rdquo; means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the present invention. Thus, the appearances of the phrases &ldquo;in one embodiment&rdquo; or &ldquo;in an embodiment&rdquo; in various places throughout this specification are not necessarily all referring to the same embodiment. Furthermore, the particular features, structures, or characteristics may be combined in any suitable manner in one or more embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In one aspect of the present invention, an input circuit includes a comparator circuit and a multi-reference circuit. The input circuit receives an input signal and generates an output signal as a function of the input signal and a reference signal received from the multi-reference circuit. In one embodiment, the comparator circuit includes a differential pair, which allows the comparator circuit to be relatively fast (e.g., compared to Schmitt trigger circuits). In particular, the comparator circuit detects a crossing of the input signal relative to the reference signal and causes a corresponding transition of the output signal. Further, in accordance with this aspect of the invention, in response to the transition of the output signal, the multi-reference circuit provides a different reference signal to the comparator circuit. The reference signals provided by the multi-reference circuit are selected to create hysteresis in the operation of the input circuit. This aspect allows the input circuit to be relatively fast while reducing the input circuit&apos;s sensitivity to noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention is described below in the context of a bus input circuit of a microprocessor; however, in light of the present disclosure, those of ordinary skill in the art will understand that the methods and apparatus of the present invention are generally applicable to input circuits for signals other than bus signals and to IC devices other than microprocessors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Shown schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a computer system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> incorporating a processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> with an input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. This embodiment of computer system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also includes a read only memory (ROM) <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, one or more input devices <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, one or more output devices <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and one or more data storage devices <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. In this exemplary embodiment, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is connected to receive a bus signal from bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. In accordance with the present invention, processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can have a large number of input circuits identical to input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> connected to receive other signals from bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and other circuits within or external to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Various embodiments of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are described below in conjunction with FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is coupled via bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which may include one or more dynamic random access memory (DRAM) devices for storing information and instructions to be executed by processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may also be used for storing temporary variables or other intermediate information during execution of instructions by processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. ROM <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, for storing static information and instructions for processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, is coupled to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> via bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Input devices <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, such as a keyboard or mouse, are coupled to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Output devices <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are also coupled to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> via bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Typical output devices <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> include printers and display monitors. Storage devices <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are also coupled to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> via bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Common data storage devices include hard disk drives, floppy disk drives, and CD ROM drives. In light of this disclosure, those of ordinary skill in the art will understand that computer system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include other components and subsystems in addition to those shown and described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. By way of example, computer system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include video memory, cache memory, as well as other dedicated memory, and additional signal lines and busses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), which is coupled to external clock source <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a supply voltage source <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. This embodiment of processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes an instruction decoder unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, an execution unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, internal clock circuitry <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, register file unit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, address translation unit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is part of bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, supply voltage source <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and external clock source <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> respectively provide a supply voltage VCC and a system clock SCLK to processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> presented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is illustrative. In light of this disclosure, those of ordinary skill in the art will understand that, in practice, a modern processor is generally more complex and may include additional components, such as internal cache, which have been omitted for ease of understanding. To improve clarity, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> does not show internal buses and other communication paths that electrically interconnect internal clock circuitry <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and various functional units of processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (e.g., instruction decode unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, execution unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, register file unit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, address translation unit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, and bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> does not show other input circuits substantially similar to input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> that may be used to receive other signals. Accordingly, processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is presented without limitation, and the present invention is generally applicable to all types of processors (e.g., microprocessors, microcontrollers, digital signal processors, etc.), irrespective of the specific architecture employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is coupled to bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, as well as main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and ROM <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. As previously mentioned, bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> includes input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (and substantially identical input circuits for other lines of bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) for receiving signals via bus <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Bus interface unit <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> facilitates transmission of data between main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, and performs fetching of instructions and other data from ROM <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Address translation unit <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> performs memory management for processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Specifically, address translation unit stores the memory addresses (whether in main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, internal cache, or other memory) of data being used by the processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> during operation. Instruction decoder unit <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> decodes instructions and other control signals received by processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Execution unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is intended to present a broad category of microprocessor functional units providing a wide range of functions. By way of example, execution unit <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may comprise an arithmetic and logic unit for performing arithmetic operations, including shifts, addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. Register file unit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may comprise one or more types of registers for storing data being used by processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. For example, register file unit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may include integer registers, status registers, instruction pointer registers, and floating point registers, as well as others. If present, the internal cache (not shown) may be used, for example, to store data and control signals from main memory <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> External clock <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> provides a clock signal having an external clock frequency to internal clock circuitry <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Internal clock circuitry <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, which may comprise a phase lock loop (PLL) circuit, adjusts the external clock frequency (either increasing or decreasing this frequency) to achieve a desired operating frequency for processor <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), according to one embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is implemented using a sense amplifier circuit that generates an output signal as a function of the input signal. For example, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can generate the output signal to be an inverted or non-inverted version of the input signal, as desired for the application. In this embodiment, multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> provides either a first reference signal or a second reference signal to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as a function of the logic level of the output signal on a line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The two reference signals are selected to create hysteresis in input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. One embodiment of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is described below in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The elements of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are interconnected as follows. Comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to receive the input signal at a N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> input node via a line <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> input node connected to an output lead of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> via a line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The output lead of comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to an input lead of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> via line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Thus, multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is connected to provide feedback to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to both <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and the flow diagram of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> operates as follows. Input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> receives an input signal IN via line <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and generates an output signal OUT as a function of the input signal via a line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and the reference signal received via line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. As described above, multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> provides the reference signal with a level designed to create hysteresis. For example, when input signal IN is at a logic low level, the reference signal is at a relatively high level (REFH). Conversely, when input signal IN is at a logic high level, the reference signal has a relatively low level (REFL). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> receives input signal IN at its N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> input node (via line <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) and a reference signal from multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> at its N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> input node (via line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>). Comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> compares the level of input signal IN to the level of reference signal to detect a transition of input signal&apos;s logic level (e.g., a low-to-high or a high-to-low logic level transition). In particular, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> compares the levels to determine whether the level of input signal IN crosses that of the reference signal. The term &ldquo;crosses&rdquo; is used in this context to refer to the level of input signal IN either: (a) increasing from being less than to being greater than the level of the reference signal; or (b) decreasing from being greater than to being less than the level of the reference signal. This operation is illustrated as steps <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> If comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> detects that the level of input signal IN does not cross that of the reference signal being received at its input node N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> leaves its output signal unchanged. This operational flow is illustrated by the looping back to step <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from step <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> if no crossing is detected in step <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Conversely, if comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> detects that the level of input signal IN crosses that of the reference signal being received at its input node N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> causes a corresponding transition of output signal OUT at line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. This operation is illustrated as a step <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, flowing from step <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In this exemplary embodiment, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> generates output signal OUT with the opposite logic level as that of input signal IN. In other embodiments, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can generate output signal OUT with the same logic level as that of input signal IN. Because comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is differential in nature, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can operate faster than circuits that an input circuit that uses a single input signal. For example, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will generally be faster when the signals on node N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are switching in opposite directions (i.e., one signal is increasing while the other is decreasing). Thus, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be relatively fast (e.g., compared to Schmitt trigger circuits). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In response to the transition of output signal OUT, multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> provides the other reference signal to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. For example, if prior to the transition of output signal OUT multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> was providing the reference signal at the REFL level, then a high-to-low transition of input signal IN that causes comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to transition output signal OUT will in turn causes multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to provide the reference signal at the REFH level. Conversely, if prior to the transition of output signal OUT multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> was providing the reference signal at the REFH level, then a low-to-high transition of input signal IN that causes comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to transition output signal OUT will in turn causes multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to provide the reference signal at the REFL level. This operation is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> as a step <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> will then compare the level of input signal IN to the &ldquo;new&rdquo; level of the reference signal. This operational flow is illustrated by the looping back from step <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to step <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates an implementation of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), according to one embodiment of the present invention. This embodiment of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and a reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provides a reference signal REFH and a reference signal REFL. In this embodiment, reference signals REFH and REFL are reference voltages. In view of the present disclosure, those skilled in the art can design several suitable implementations of voltage reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> without undue experimentation. Multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> operates to provide either reference signal REFH or reference signal REFL at its output lead, as a function of the logic level of the signal received at its control terminal. Any suitable multiplexer implementation can be used. One implementation is described below in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, the elements of multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are interconnected as follows. Multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is connected to receive reference signals REFH and REFL from reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> via lines <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, respectively. The output lead of multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is connected to line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, which is connected to input node N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) of comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). The control terminal of multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is connected to receive output signal OUT via line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In operation, reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> generates reference signals REFH and REFL with levels that were predetermined to define the hysteresis of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> receives these reference signals from reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at its input terminals via lines <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, along with output signal OUT at its control terminal via line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. In response to the level of output signal OUT, multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> provides either reference signal REFH or REFL to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) via line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. For example, if comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) generates output signal OUT as an inverted version of input signal IN, then a logic high level of output signal OUT will cause multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to provide reference signal REFH to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Thus, the level of input signal IN would have to exceed the level of reference signal REFH to cause comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) to transition output signal OUT to a logic low level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Conversely, a logic low level of output signal OUT will cause multiplexer <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to provide reference signal REFL to comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). Thus, the level of input signal IN would have to drop below the level of reference signal REFL to cause comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) to transition output signal OUT to a logic high level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> One of the advantages of this implementation is that input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has relatively good PVT performance. One reason for this is that input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a reference generator. Voltage generators typically have very accurate temperature compensation and low sensitivity to process variations and supply voltage noise. Thus, reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> can provide reference signals REFH and REFL with very accurate levels over a wide PVT variation. Accordingly, this embodiment of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> tends to be relatively temperature and voltage insensitive when compared to input circuits that do not use reference generators (e.g., Schmitt triggers). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> schematically illustrates an implementation of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), according to one embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) includes N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and P-channel transistors <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are connected as a differential pair (i.e., having their sources connected together and their gates connected to receive input signals). In particular, the gates of N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are respectively connected to receive input signal IN and the reference signal from multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> via line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The sources of N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are connected to the drain of N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The drains of N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> are connected to a current mirror formed by P-channel transistors <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The drain of N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> (indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> as a node <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>D) is connected to line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, with its voltage level serving as output signal OUT. Further, N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> has its gate and source respectively connected to the VCC bus and the ground bus, serving as a current source for the differential pair formed by N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes inverters <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates the implementation of inverter <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>; namely P-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>P and N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N. In particular, P-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>P has its source, gate and drain connected to line <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, a node <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, respectively. Line <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> provides a reference voltage VREFH from reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N has its source, gate and drain connected to line <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, node <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Line <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> provides a reference voltage VREFL from reference generator <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Reference voltages VREFH and VREFL are preselected to have levels that are less than that of the VCC voltage and greater than the VSS voltage (also referred to herein as ground potential). For example, in one embodiment, reference voltages VREFH and VREFL are respectively about 1.2 volts and 0.3 volts, when using a 1.5 volt power supply. Thus, transistors <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>P and <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N form a reduced-swing inverter, outputting either reference voltage VREFH or VREFL in response to the logic level at node <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments, reference voltages VREFH and VREFL can be set at other levels that meet the following three requirements to facilitate interoperability with comparator circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. First, reference voltage VREFH should be more than a P-channel threshold voltage (Vtp) below the VCC voltage level. Second, reference voltage VREFL should be more than a N-channel threshold voltage (Vtn) above the VSS voltage level (i.e., ground potential). Third, the difference between reference voltages VREFH and VREFL should be greater than or equal to the sum of the magnitudes of Vtn and Vtp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> has its input and output leads connected to line <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>, respectively. In this embodiment, inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is implemented as a standard CMOS (complementary symmetry metal-oxide semiconductor) inverter connected between the VCC and ground buses. The transistors implementing inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are omitted to improve clarity; however, the connections to the VCC and ground buses are shown to indicate that inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> provides a full rail-to-rail output signal. The operation of this embodiment of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is described below in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, which illustrates the timing of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) by way of a voltage versus time graph. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> operates as follows. Input signal IN, output signal OUT and reference signal REF are represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> by waveform <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, waveform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> and waveform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, respectively. Starting with input signal IN being at a steady state logic low level, output signal OUT is at a logic high level and the signal REF from multi-reference circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is at the VREFH level. For purposes of this description, this is the initial state of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> When the level of input signal IN increases to cross the VREFH level, as indicated by edge <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A of waveform <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, the differential pair formed by N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> pull down the voltage level at node <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>D, thereby causing output signal OUT to transition to a logic low level, as indicated by an edge <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>A of waveform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. In this operational phase, voltage levels of input signal IN that are below the VREFH level do not cause a transition of output signal OUT. In response to output signal OUT transitioning to the logic low level, inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> outputs a logic high level signal to reduced-swing inverter <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Consequently, P-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>P is turned off and N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N is turned on. Thus, N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N pulls down the voltage level of reference signal REF on line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to that of reference voltage VREFL, as indicated by edge <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>A of waveform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. As illustrated by the &ldquo;overlap&rdquo; of edges <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A with edge <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>A, input signal IN and reference signal REF are switching in opposite directions (as described above in conjunction with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) before output signal OUT is fully switched. Thus, the speed at which edge <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>A of output signal OUT is generated relative to edge <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A of input signal IN is typically faster than can be achieved using other conventional circuits. This faster operation (i.e., small propagation delay) is desirable in many applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> When the level of input signal IN decreases to cross the VREFL level (which is below the VREFH level), as indicated by edge <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>B of waveform <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, the differential pair formed by N-channel transistors <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> causes the voltage level at node <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>D to increase. This increase in the voltage level at node <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>D results in output signal OUT transitioning to a logic high level, as indicated by an edge <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>B of waveform <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. In this operational phase, voltage levels of input signal IN that are above the VREFL level do not cause a transition of output signal OUT. In response to output signal OUT transitioning to the logic high level, inverter <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> outputs a logic low level signal to reduced-swing inverter <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Consequently, N-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>N is turned off and P-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>P is turned on. Thus, P-channel transistor <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>_pulls up the voltage level of reference signal REF on line <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to that of reference voltage VREFH, as indicated by edge <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>B of waveform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is thus placed back in the initial state described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates in more detail the response of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) to transitions of input signal IN by way of a voltage versus time graph. Input signal IN is represented by a waveform <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and output signal OUT is represented by a waveform <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. In an initial state, input signal IN is a logic low level and output signal OUT is at a logic high level. In this example, input signal IN begins a low-to-high transition at about the ten nanosecond mark of the graph. In response to the transition of input signal IN, output signal OUT begins a high-to-low transition slightly after the ten nanosecond mark, which essentially completes at about the eleven nanosecond mark. In addition, between the eleven and twelve nanosecond marks, input signal IN experiences a glitch, as indicated by an arrow <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. This glitch reduces the level of input signal IN to a minimum of about 0.7 volts. However, there is essentially no change in output signal OUT due to this glitch because the local minimum of this glitch did not drop below the level of reference voltage VREFL, which is indicated by a horizontal line <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> at about 0.45 volts in this example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Then, in this example, input signal IN begins a high-to-low transition at about the twenty-three nanosecond mark of the graph. In response to this transition of input signal IN, output signal OUT begins a low-to-high transition slightly after the twenty-three nanosecond mark, which essentially completes at about the twenty-four nanosecond mark. In addition, between the twenty-three and twenty-four nanosecond marks, input signal IN experiences a glitch, as indicated by an arrow <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. This glitch increase the level of input signal IN to a maximum of about 0.7 volts. However, there is essentially no change in output signal OUT due to this glitch because this local maximum of the glitch did not rise above the level of reference voltage VREFH, which is indicated by a horizontal line <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> at about 1.05 volts in this example. Thus, this embodiment of input circuit <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also achieves a significant decrease in input noise sensitivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The above description of illustrated embodiments of the invention, including what is described in the Abstract, is not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed. While specific embodiments of, and examples for, the invention are described herein for illustrative purposes, various equivalent modifications are possible within the scope of the invention, as those skilled in the relevant art will recognize. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> These modifications can be made to the invention in light of the above detailed description. The terms used in the following claims should not be construed to limit the invention to the specific embodiments disclosed in the specification and the claims. Rather, the scope of the invention is to be determined entirely by the following claims, which are to be construed in accordance with established doctrines of claim interpretation. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A circuit, comprising: 
<claim-text>a comparator circuit having a first input node coupleable to receive an input signal and having a second input node coupleable to receive a reference signal, the comparator circuit to generate an output signal having a level that is dependent on the input signal and the reference signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first reference generator to generate a first signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference generator to generate a second signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplexer having a control lead, a first input lead, a second input lead, and an output lead, the control lead coupled to receive the output signal, the first and second input leads coupled to the first and second reference generators, and the output lead of the multiplexer coupled to the other input node of the comparator circuit, wherein the multiplexer to output the reference signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the comparator circuit comprises a pair of transistors coupled to form a differential pair, one transistor of the differential pair coupled to the first input node and the other transistor of the differential pair coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multiplexer to select the first signal to serves as the reference signal when the output signal is at one level and to select the second signal to serve as the reference signal when the output signal is at another level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a change in the level of the input signal causes a change in the level of the reference signal in an opposite direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multiplexer comprises a reduced-swing inverter having an output lead coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reduced-swing inverter comprises: 
<claim-text>a P-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the source of the P-channel transistor coupled to receive a voltage of a first level and the drain of the P-channel transistor coupled to the second input node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a N-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the gate and drain of the N-channel transistor coupled to the gate and drain of the P-channel transistor, the source of the N-channel transistor coupled to receive a voltage of a second level, the second level being less than the first level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multi-reference circuit further comprises a second inverter having an input lead coupled to receive the output signal and having an output lead coupled to an input lead of the reduced-swing inverter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A circuit, comprising: 
<claim-text>comparator means, coupled to receive an input signal at a first input node and a reference signal at a second input node, for generating an output signal having a level that is dependent on the input signal and the reference signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>multi-reference means, coupled to receive the output signal, for providing the reference signal, the reference signal having a level that is dependent on the level of the output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the comparator means comprises a pair of transistors coupled to form a differential pair, one transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the first input node and the other transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multi-reference means comprises a multiplexer and a reference generator, the reference generator to provide a first signal and a second signal to the multiplexer, the multiplexer to select the first signal when the output signal is at one level and to select the second signal when the output signal is at another level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multi-reference means comprises a reduced-swing inverter having an output lead coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reduced-swing inverter comprises: 
<claim-text>a P-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, wherein the source of the P-channel transistor is connected to receive a voltage of a first level and the drain of the P-channel transistor is connected to the second input node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a N-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, wherein the gate and drain of the N-channel transistor is connected to the gate and drain of the P-channel transistor, the source of the N-channel transistor is connected to receive a voltage of a second level, the second level being less than the first level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A processor, comprising: 
<claim-text>a comparator circuit having a first input node coupleable to receive an input signal and having a second input node coupleable to receive a reference signal, the comparator circuit to generate an output signal having a level that is dependent on the input signal and the reference signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first reference generator to generate a first signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second reference generator to generate a second signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a multiplexer having a control lead, a first input lead, a second input lead, and an output lead, the control lead coupled to receive the output signal, the first and second input leads coupled to the first and second reference generators, and the output lead of the multiplexer coupled to the other input node of the comparator circuit, wherein the multiplexer to output the reference signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The processor of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the comparator circuit comprises a pair of transistors coupled to form a differential pair, one transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the first input node and the other transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The processor of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multiplexer to select the first signal when the output signal is at one level and to select the second signal when the output signal is at another level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The processor of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multiplexer comprises a reduced-swing inverter having an output lead coupled to the second input node, the reduced-swing inverter comprising: 
<claim-text>a P-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the source of the P-channel transistor being connected to receive a voltage of a first level and the drain of the P-channel transistor being connected to the second input node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a N-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the gate and drain of the N-channel transistor being connected to the gate and drain of the P-channel transistor, the source of the N-channel transistor being connected to receive a voltage of a second level, the second level being less than the first level. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The processor of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multiplexer further comprises a second inverter having an input lead coupled to receive the output signal and having an output lead coupled to an input lead of the reduced-swing inverter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method, comprising: 
<claim-text>comparing an input signal with a reference signal, the reference signal having a level; </claim-text>
<claim-text>causing a transition of an output signal in response to a crossing of the input signal and the reference signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>causing the level of the reference signal to change in response to the transition of the output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a differential pair is used to compare the input signal to the reference signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the level of the reference signal is changed to a first level in response to the output signal transitioning to a first logic level and to a second level in response to the output signal transitioning to a second logic level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>means for receiving an input signal and a reference signal, the reference signal having a level; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for causing a transition of an output signal in response to a crossing of the input signal and the reference signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for causing the level of the reference signal to change in response to the transition of the output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second levels of the reference signal are voltage levels are less than a VCC voltage level and greater than a VSS level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the level of the reference signal is changed to a first level in response to the output signal transitioning to a first logic level and to a second level in response to the output signal transitioning to a second logic level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the level of the reference signal changes while the level of the input signal is changing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for receiving comprises two transistors coupled to form a differential pair, one transistor of the differential pair being coupled to receive the input signal and the other transistor of the differential pair being coupled to receive the reference signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the means for causing the level of the reference signal to change comprises a reduced-swing inverter. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A computer system, comprising: 
<claim-text>an input circuit to receive an input signal and to generate an output signal in response to the input signal, wherein the input circuit comprises: 
<claim-text>comparator means, coupled to receive the input signal at a first input node and a reference signal at a second input node, for generating the output signal with a level that is dependent on the input signal and the reference signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>multi-reference means, coupled to receive the output signal, for providing the reference signal, the reference signal having a level that is dependent on the level of the output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the comparator means comprises a pair of transistors coupled to form a differential pair, one transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the first input node and the other transistor of the differential pair being coupled to the second input node. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multi-reference means comprises a multiplexer and a reference generator, the reference generator to provide a first signal and a second signal to the multiplexer, the multiplexer to select the first signal when the output signal is at one level and to select the second signal when the output signal is at another level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the multi-reference means comprises a reduced-swing inverter having an output lead coupled to the second input node, the reduced-swing inverter comprising: 
<claim-text>a P-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the source of the P-channel transistor being connected to receive a voltage of a first level and the drain of the P-channel transistor being connected to the second input node; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a N-channel transistor having a source, a gate and a drain, the gate and drain of the N-channel transistor being connected to the gate and drain of the P-channel transistor, the source of the N-channel transistor being connected to receive a voltage of a second level, the second level being less than the first level.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001644A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
