<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002150A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002150A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002150A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002150A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002150A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002150A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002150A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002150A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002150</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10193265</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020712</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>11-328781</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991118</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2000-319435</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001019</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B005/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B007/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>431000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>831000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>835000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Real image viewfinder optical system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10193265</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020712</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09714536</doc-number>
<document-date>20001117</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Akihiko</given-name>
<family-name>Obama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sakura-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Nikon Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>3</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Nelson H. Shapiro</name-1>
<name-2>Miles &amp; Stockbridge P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 500</address-1>
<address-2>1751 Pinnacle Drive</address-2>
<city>McLean</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22102-3833</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The object of the present invention is to provide a real image viewfinder optical system with high optical performance and compactness, whose dimension of a whole optical system including an image inverter optical system is small in the thickness direction, and whose dimension to an object side of an eyepiece lens system is small in the thickness direction. A real image viewfinder optical system comprises, in order from an object side, an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole, an eyepiece lens system for observing a real image formed by the objective lens system and having a positive refractive power, and an image inverter optical system for erecting the image to be observed and arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system. Conditional expressions are satisfied. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">INCORPORATION BY REFERENCE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The disclosures of the following priority applications are herein incorporated by reference: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Japanese Patent Application No. 11-328781 filed Nov. 18, 1999. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Japanese Patent Application No. 2000-319435 filed Oct. 19, 2000. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a real image viewfinder optical system for a camera, a digital still camera, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A real image viewfinder optical system includes an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole, an eyepiece lens system having a positive refractive power for observing a real image formed by the objective lens system, and an image inverter optical system for erecting an inverted image formed by the objective lens system. In a compact type real image viewfinder used for a camera and the like, a reflection type image inverter optical system is commonly used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the reflection type image inverter optical system, there are a Porro type for inverting an image by reflection elements, such as a single or a plurality of Porro prisms having more than four reflection surfaces and a roof type for inverting an image by reflection elements, such as a roof prism having roof reflection surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Coordinates crossing at right angles with each other in a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of an incident light into a viewfinder optical system or a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of a light reflected by each reflection surface are to be called a vertical direction and a horizontal direction, respectively. A direction parallel to only the optical axis of the incident light into the viewfinder optical system is to be called a thickness direction. A direction in the horizontal direction relative to the optical axis of the incident light into the viewfinder optical system is to be called a width direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In the Porro type, the reflection type image inverter optical system is liable to become large in the horizontal direction when used for inverting an image in the horizontal direction, and in the vertical direction when used for inverting an image in the vertical direction. Therefore, an optical system according to the Porro type is liable to become large, so that it is not suitable for miniaturization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Then, in a roof type, a projected direction of a roof ridgeline of a roof type reflection element on a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the incident light or a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the light reflected by each reflection surface is defined to be a horizontal direction. A direction perpendicular to the horizontal direction is defined to be a vertical direction. In this case, since an image inversion in vertical direction is performed on the roof surfaces composing the roof ridgeline, the dimension of the optical element in vertical direction can be small in comparison with the Porro type. Therefore, the roof type is advantageous for miniaturization relative to the Porro type. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> There have been known an optical system using a pentagonal prism and an optical element using a combination of two triangle or trapezoidal prisms for performing an image inversion in horizontal direction by using an optical system of a roof type. Hereinafter the former is called a reflection type image inverter optical system using pentagonal and a roof prisms and the latter is called a reflection type image inverter optical system using triangular and roof prisms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As for reflection type image inverter optical system using pentagonal and roof prisms, there have been optical systems proposed in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open Nos. 4-63313 and 8-304880. In an optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 4-63313, an optical axis of an incident light to a roof mirror makes an angle of approximately 45 with a roof ridgeline. Accordingly, the roof mirror reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of approximately 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light. The exit light is incident to a pentagonal prism, and is led to an eyepiece via two reflections in the pentagonal prism. In an optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 8-304880, an optical axis of an incident light to a roof prism makes an angle of more than 45&deg; with a roof ridgeline. Accordingly, the roof prism reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of less than 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light. The exit light is incident to a pentagonal prism, and is led to an eyepiece via two reflections in the pentagonal prism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, as for reflection type image inverter optical system using triangular and roof prisms, there have been optical systems proposed in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 8-179400 and the like. In an optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 8-179400, an optical axis of an incident light to a roof prism makes an angle of less than 45&deg; with a roof ridgeline. Accordingly, the roof prism reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of more than 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light. The exit light is incident to a first triangular prism, to a second triangular prism via two reflections in the first triangular prism, and is led to an eyepiece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> However, in the optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 4-63313, since the roof mirror reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of approximately 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light, the pentagonal prism is arranged at right besides the roof mirror. Accordingly, the eyepiece is located to an exit pupil side of the pentagonal prism, so that it is difficult to reduce the dimension of the whole optical system of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in the optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. No. 8-304880, since the roof prism reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of less than 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light, the pentagonal prism is arranged to the object side relative to the roof prism. Accordingly, the position of the eyepiece in the thickness direction can be the same as that of the roof prism, so that it is possible to reduce the dimension of the whole optical system of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system in the thickness direction. However, in the object side of the eyepiece, the pentagonal prism protrudes to the object side, so that it is difficult to reduce the dimension in the thickness direction to the object side of the eyepiece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in an optical system disclosed by Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 8-179400, since the roof prism reflects the incident light in the width direction making an angle of more than 90&deg; with the optical axis of the exit light, the first and second triangular prisms are located to the exit pupil side relative to the roof prism. Accordingly, the eyepiece is arranged to the exit pupil side of the second triangular prism, so that it is difficult to reduce the dimension of the whole optical system of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present invention is made in view of the aforementioned problems and has an object to provide a real image viewfinder optical system with high optical performance and compactness, whose dimension of whole optical system including an image inverter optical system is small in the thickness direction, and whose dimension to an object side of an eyepiece lens system is small in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the aforementioned problems, the present invention provides a real image viewfinder optical system comprising, in order from an object side, an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole, an eyepiece lens system that observes a real image formed by the objective lens system and has a positive refractive power, and wherein said real image viewfinder optical system has an image inverter optical system that erects the image to be observed and is arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system, wherein the image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along an optical axis of the viewfinder optical system, a roof reflection element that reflects an incident light from the object side, a first prism having a first reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element to the object side and a second reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface to the exit pupil side, and a second prism having a third transmitting surface approximately parallel to the first reflection surface, wherein the first prism includes a first transmitting surface that intersects the optical axis of the exit light from the roof reflection element approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface in the same plane as the first reflection surface, wherein the second prism includes a fourth transmitting surface that intersects an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism approximately perpendicularly, and wherein the following conditional expression (1) is satisfied: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>45&deg;&lE;&thgr;&lt;50&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> where &thgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between an optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element and a roof ridgeline of the roof reflection element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The refractive index and the dispersion of the first prism are preferably the same as those of the second prism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In this situation, it is preferable to satisfy the following conditional expression (2): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> where S1 denotes a projected area of the first transmitting surface to a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of the incident light to the first prism and including an intersection of the first transmitting surface and the optical axis, and S4 denotes a projected area of the fourth transmitting surface to a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light from the second prism and including an intersection of the fourth transmitting surface and the optical axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, a real image viewfinder optical system comprises, in order from an object side, an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole, an eyepiece lens system that observes a real image formed by the objective lens system and has a positive refractive power, and an image inverter optical system that erects the image to be observed and is arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system, wherein the image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along an optical axis of the viewfinder optical system, a roof reflection element that reflects an incident light from the object side, a first prism having a first reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element to the object side and a second reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface to the exit pupil side, and a second prism having a third transmitting surface approximately parallel to the first reflection surface, wherein an optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element makes a skew relation to the roof ridgeline, wherein the first prism includes a first transmitting surface that intersects an optical axis of the exit light from the roof reflection element approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface in the same plane as the first reflection surface, wherein the second prism includes a fourth transmitting surface that intersects an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism approximately perpendicularly, and wherein the following conditional expression (3) is satisfied: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>40&deg;&lt;&phgr;&lE;45&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(3) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> where &phgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element and the roof ridgeline of the roof reflection element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The refractive index and the dispersion of the first prism are preferably the same as those of the second prism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In this situation, it is preferable to satisfy the following conditional expression (4): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(4) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> where S1 denotes a projected area of the first transmitting surface to a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the incident light to the first prism and including an intersection of the first transmitting surface and the optical axis, and S4 denotes a projected area of the fourth transmitting surface to a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light from the second prism and including an intersection of the fourth transmitting surface and the optical axis.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a first example of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a second example of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a third example of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> A real image viewfinder optical system according to an example of the present invention will be described below. In the following explanation, a direction parallel to only an optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of an incident light to a viewfinder optical system is defined to be a thickness direction. A direction of a roof ridgeline of a roof reflection element projected on a plane perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light and a plane perpendicular to an optical axis (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the like) of a reflected light by each reflection surface is defined to be a horizontal direction and a direction perpendicular to the horizontal direction is defined to be a vertical direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A, 2A</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A, a direction in a plane perpendicular to each optical axis and also in the plane of the drawing or parallel to the plane of the drawing is the horizontal direction, and a direction perpendicular to the plane of the drawing is the vertical direction. In the plane of the drawing, the thickness direction is a direction of the optical axis of the incident light to the viewfinder optical system and the width direction is a direction perpendicular to the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> An optical system of a real image viewfinder includes, in order from an object side, an objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power as a whole, and an eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for observing a real image formed by the objective lens system. In this construction, the observing image becomes an inverted image with respect to both vertical and horizontal directions, so that it is general that an image inverter optical system is included in order to erect the inverted image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Moreover, it is preferable that the image inverter optical system is arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. When the image inverter optical system is arranged to the object side of the lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is arranged in the width direction, so that the dimension in the width direction of the real image viewfinder optical system as a whole becomes large. As a result, it cannot be made compact. Accordingly, an object of the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the image inverter optical system is arranged to the exit pupil side of the lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is arranged in the width direction, so that the dimension in the width direction of the real image viewfinder optical system as a whole becomes large. As a result, it cannot be made compact. Accordingly, an object of the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> By the way, in the present invention, an exit pupil means the exit pupil of the eyepiece lens system, and is located at the eyepoint. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Then, the construction and an effect of the image inverter optical system will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, a roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that reflects an incident light from the object side, a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> having a first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the object side and a second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to the exit pupil side, and a second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>approximately parallel to the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is arranged such that a projection of a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light or a plane perpendicular to an optical axis (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the like) of a reflected light by each reflection surface is in the horizontal direction, and performs an image inversion in the vertical direction by roof surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>putting the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in between. In the construction shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, although the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is constructed by a roof mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> having mirrors composing roof surfaces, the present invention is not limited to the example, and it is possible to construct by a roof prism using rear-surface total reflections. On the other hand, an image inversion in the horizontal direction is performed by the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> having the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Therefore the image inversion is performed by the effect of these four reflection surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> includes a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that intersects an optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the same plane as the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. By making the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to be in the same plane, the plane performs two functions, a reflection and a transmission, relative to the effective light flux, so that the real image viewfinder optical system can be made compact. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Here, since the exit light from the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> comes out from the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>not being perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light, the optical path in the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is different in the horizontal direction. In order to correct the difference in the optical path, the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes the third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>approximately parallel to the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly. The real image viewfinder optical system capable of observing an erected image can be realized by the construction described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Then, conditional expressions according to the present invention will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> It is preferable for the present invention to satisfy the following conditional expression (1): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>45&deg;&lE;&thgr;&lt;50&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> where &thgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between an optical axis of the incident light <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof reflection element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Conditional expression (1) defines an appropriate range of &thgr; in order to make a dimension of a real image viewfinder optical system including an image inverter optical system as a whole smaller in the thickness direction and also to make a dimension to the object side of the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> smaller in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> When the angle &thgr; between the optical axis of the incident light <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is set, the angle &PSgr; (unit: degree) between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is necessarily set in accordance with the reflection law. The relation is expressed by the following expression (5): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&PSgr;&equals;180&deg;&minus;2&thgr;&emsp;&emsp;(5). </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> When &thgr; falls below the lower limit of conditional expression (1), in other words, when &PSgr; exceeds 90&deg;, the exit light <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comes out away from the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are arranged relatively to the exit pupil side of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, so that the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is arranged to the exit pupil side of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As a result, the real image viewfinder optical system as a whole becomes large in the thickness direction, so that the object of the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when &thgr; exceeds the upper limit of conditional expression (1), in other words, when &PSgr; falls below <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, the exit light <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comes out near to the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Since an angle between the incident light to the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes small, the area of the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes excessively large in the direction projected the incident light onto the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in order to maintain effective light flux. As a result, the dimension of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> becomes large in the width direction, so that the object of the present invention for providing a compact viewfinder optical system cannot be accomplished. Moreover, in accordance with the relative expansion of the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the width direction, the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is to be located largely to the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. As a result, a dimension of the viewfinder optical system to the object side of the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> becomes large in the thickness direction, so that the object of the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in the present invention, it is preferable to satisfy following conditional expression (2): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> where S1 denotes a projected area of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of the incident light and including an intersection of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, and S4 denotes a projected area of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and including an intersection of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Conditional expression (2) is for realizing miniaturization of a real image viewfinder optical system as a whole and for providing an optical system with fewer ghost images. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>A, effective light flux <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> shown by broken lines passes or reflects in the first and second prisms. As apparent from the figure, the diameter of the effective light flux <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is smaller than that in the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. This is for increasing qualities of the optical system by making an eye relief longer on observing peripheral images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> When the ratio of S1/S4 exceeds the upper limit of conditional equation (2), in other words, when S1 is bigger than S4, the projection area S4 of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is larger or smaller than the effective light flux. In the former case, the projected area S1 of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>becomes excessively large relative to the effective light flux. Accordingly, the dimension of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> itself becomes too large, so that the object of compactness cannot be accomplished. On the other hand, in the latter case, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can be made to be a moderate dimension. However, since the projected area S4 of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes smaller than the effective light flux, a light passing through the most peripheral areas hits on surrounding walls of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that it causes ghost images produced by inner surface reflection of the prism. As a result, the production of these ghost images deteriorates imaging quality of the viewfinder optical system, so that the object of high quality cannot be accomplished. Therefore, in either case, the objects of the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in order to obtain a high quality viewfinder optical system, the refractive index and the dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are preferably approximately the same as those of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As described above, the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> corrects the optical path difference in the horizontal direction in the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. When the refractive index of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is not approximately the same as that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the optical path difference of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the horizontal direction is different from that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that these differences cannot be canceled out. Accordingly, the optical path from the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>differs in the horizontal direction, so that dioptral difference is produced at left and right of a visual field. As a result, a high quality viewfinder optical system cannot be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Further, when the dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is not approximately the same as that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the optical path difference of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the horizontal direction in each wavelength is different from that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that these differences cannot be canceled out. Accordingly, the optical path from the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>differs in the horizontal direction in each wavelength, so that dioptral difference in each wavelength at left and right of a visual field produces color smear. As a result, a high quality viewfinder optical system cannot be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Then, a real image viewfinder optical system according to the present invention will be explained from another point of view. By the way, a coordinate system used here is defined as the same as the one described in the aforementioned real image viewfinder optical system. Moreover, the constructions of the real image viewfinder optical system and the arrangement of the image inverter optical system are to be the same as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The construction and function of the image inverter optical system is explained with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, a roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> that reflects an incident light from the object side, a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> having a first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the object side and a second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to the exit pupil side, and a second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>approximately parallel to the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> having a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the horizontal direction performs an image inversion in the vertical direction by roof surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>putting the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in between. In the construction shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, although the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is constructed by a prism having roof surfaces for rear-surface total reflection, that is a roof prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the present invention is not limited to the example, and it is possible to construct by a roof mirror. On the other hand, an image inversion in the horizontal direction is performed by the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> having the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Therefore the image inversion is performed by the effect of these four reflection surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> makes a skew relation to the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. On the other hand, if the incident optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> intersects the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a light passing approximately through the center of field while observing the viewfinder optical system, which is substantially the optical axis, intersects the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. On observing a viewfinder optical system, optical performance of a central part of an observing image psychologically affects the whole appearance of an image formed by the viewfinder optical system. Accordingly, to make optical performance of the central part an observed image high is to make optical performance of the whole viewfinder optical system high. However, if the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> cannot be manufactured with sufficient accuracy, the observed image is blurred in the central part, so that a high quality viewfinder optical system cannot be provided. Accordingly, by making the incident optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> a skew relation to the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the effect of manufacturing accuracy of the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>can be moved from the central part of the observing image, so that a high quality viewfinder optical system can be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> includes a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that intersects an optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the same plane as the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. By making the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to be in the same plane, the plane performs two functions, a reflection and a transmission, relative to the effective light flux, so that the real image viewfinder optical system can be made compact. However, since the exit light from the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> comes out from the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>not being perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light, the optical path in the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is different in the horizontal direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes the third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>approximately parallel to the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>approximately perpendicular to the exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The optical path being different in the horizontal direction can be corrected by arranging the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> By employing the above mentioned construction, a real image viewfinder optical system capable of observing a high quality erected image not seriously affected with the accuracy of the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>can be realized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Then, conditional expressions according to the present invention are going to be explained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> It is preferable for the present invention to satisfy the following conditional expression (3): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>40&deg;&lt;&phgr;&lE;45&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(3) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> where &phgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between a plane perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Conditional expression (3) defines an appropriate range of the angle between a plane (for example, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>) perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in order to reduce a dimension of a real image viewfinder optical system including an image inverter optical system in the thickness direction and a dimension of the viewfinder optical system to the object side of an eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> When the angle it between a plane perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is set, the angle &PSgr; (unit: degree) is necessarily set in accordance with the geometrical relation and the reflection, where the angle &PSgr; (unit: degree) is an angle between projections of the optical axes <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> being a skew relation with each other onto a plane (which is called a projective plane) parallel to both axes <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. This is shown, for example, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. The relation between &phgr; and &PSgr; is shown in following expression (6): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&PSgr;&equals;2&phgr;&emsp;&emsp;(6). </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> When the value &phgr; exceeds the upper limit of conditional expression (3), in other words, when &PSgr; exceeds 90&deg;, the exit light <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comes out away from the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are located relatively to the exit pupil side of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is located further to the exit pupil side of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. As a result, a dimension of the real image viewfinder optical system becomes large in the thickness direction, so that an object according to the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the value &phgr; falls below the lower limit of conditional expression (3), in other words, when &PSgr; is smaller than 80&deg;, the exit light <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> comes out to the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. However, since an angle between the incident light to the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes small, the area of the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes excessively large in the direction of the incident light projected to the first reflecting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in order to maintain an effective diameter of the light. Accordingly, a dimension of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> becomes large in the width direction, so that the object of the present invention for providing a compact viewfinder optical system cannot be accomplished. Moreover, in accordance with expansion of the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the width direction, the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is located largely to the object side relative to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. As a result, a dimension to the object side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> becomes large in the thickness direction, so that the object according to the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, it is preferable for the present invention to satisfy the following conditional expression (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(4). </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Conditional expression (4) defines an appropriate range of a ratio of areas for providing a real image viewfinder optical system that is compact and has less ghost images. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, an effective light flux <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is attached to the first and second prisms. It is understood from the drawing that a dimension (size) of the effective light flux <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> at the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is smaller than that at the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. This is for the sake of improving optical quality by making an eye relief longer while observing peripheral images. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> When the ratio exceeds the upper limit of conditional expression (4), in other words, when S1 is larger than S4, the following two cases can be conceivable. Namely, the projected area S4 of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is larger or smaller than the effective light flux. In the former case, a projected area of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>becomes excessively large relative to the effective light flux, so that the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> itself becomes too large and, as a result, compactness cannot be accomplished. In the latter case, the dimension of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can be made an appropriate size. However, the projection area S4 of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes smaller than the effective light flux, so that a light passing through periphery hits side walls of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and, as a result, it produces ghost images reflected from inside of the prism. The ghost images degrade the viewfinder optical system, so that high optical performance cannot be expected. Accordingly, in either case, an object according to the present invention cannot be accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in order to obtain a high quality viewfinder optical system, a refractive index and a dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are preferably the same as those of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> As described above, the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> corrects the optical path difference in the horizontal direction produced in the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. If the refractive index of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is not approximately the same as that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the optical path difference in the horizontal direction produced in the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> becomes different from that produced in the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the optical path from the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>becomes different in the horizontal direction, so that dioptral difference is produced at left and right of a visual field. As a result, a high quality viewfinder optical system cannot be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Further, when the dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is not approximately the same as that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the optical path difference of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the horizontal direction in each wavelength is different from that of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, so that these differences cannot be canceled out. Accordingly, the optical path from the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>differs in the horizontal direction in each wavelength, so that dioptral difference in each wavelength at left and right of a visual field produces color smear. As a result, a high quality viewfinder optical system cannot be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Each example according to the present invention is going to be explained below. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIRST EXAMPLE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A through 1D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a first example of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the first example observed from the vertical direction. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the first example sectioned by a vertical plane including an optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from a roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and observed from an eyepiece side. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S1 of a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis and also including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S4 of a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of an exit light from the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and also including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> By the way, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A, a</cross-reference> direction in a plane perpendicular to each optical axis and also in the plane of the drawing or parallel to the plane of the drawing is the horizontal direction, and a direction perpendicular to the plane of the drawing is the vertical direction. Moreover, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1C and 1D</cross-reference>, a direction in the plane of the drawing and also denoted by an arrow x is the horizontal direction, and a direction denoted by an arrow y is the vertical direction. The definitions are the same as in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The real image viewfinder optical system includes, in order from an object side, an objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for forming a real image, and an eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for observing the real image. The objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, a first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a roof reflection mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and a fourth lens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and forms the real image of the object in the vicinity of a field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, the field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, a second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and an eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and makes it possible to observe the real image formed by the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> An image inverter optical system consists of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> composed of the roof reflection mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the eyepiece-side prism system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> composed of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and is arranged to an exit pupil side of the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> located to the most object side of the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and also to the object side of the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The roof reflection mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is arranged such that a projection of a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to an optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light or a plane perpendicular to an optical axis, (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the like) of a reflected light by each reflection surface is in the horizontal direction, and performs an image inversion in the vertical direction by roof surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>putting the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in between. On the other hand, an image inversion in the horizontal direction is performed by a first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that intersects the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the same plane as the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being approximately parallel to the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In this construction, a light from the object transmits through the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and is incident to the roof reflection mirror <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the roof reflection surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Then, a real image of the object is formed once in the vicinity of the field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> after passing through the fourth lens <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Then, the light is incident to the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, and comes out from the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Then, an erected image is observed through the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> after transmitting through the third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the materials used for the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and those for the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are the same one. Therefore, the refractive index and dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are the same as those of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Various values of the example are shown in Table 1. In Table 1, &thgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and &PSgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Moreover, x1 denotes a horizontal dimension of a projection of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, y1 denotes a vertical dimension, and S1 denotes an area. Likewise, x4, y4, S4 denote a horizontal dimension, vertical dimension, and area of a projection of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the light exit from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, respectively. By the way, since the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are both planes, the area of them coincide with S1 and S4, respectively. Moreover, the unit for length such as x1, y1, x4, y4, and the like is mm, and the unit for area such as S1 and S4 is mm<highlight><superscript>2, </superscript></highlight>and the same applies to the following examples.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&thgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>47.5&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&psgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>85&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x1 &times; y1 &equals; 72</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x4 &times; y4 &equals; 76.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1/S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>72/76.8 &equals; 0.9375</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> By using the aforementioned construction according to the example, it is obvious that a dimension of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system is small in the thickness direction, and a dimension to the object side of the eyepiece is small in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SECOND EXAMPLE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A through 2D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a second example of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the second example observed from the vertical direction. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the second example sectioned by a vertical plane including an optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from a roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and observed from an eyepiece side. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S1 of a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis and also including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S4 of a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of an exit light from the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and also including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The real image viewfinder optical system according to the second example includes, in order from an object side, an objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for forming a real image, and an eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for observing the real image. The objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, a first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a roof prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and forms the real image of the object in the vicinity of a field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, the field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, a second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and an eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and makes it possible to observe the real image formed by the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> An image inverter optical system consists of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> composed of the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the eyepiece-side prism system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> composed of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and is arranged to an exit pupil side of the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> located to the most object side of the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and also to the object side of the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is arranged such that a projection of a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to an optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light or a plane perpendicular to an optical axis (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the like) of a reflected light by each reflection surface is in the horizontal direction, and performs an image inversion in the vertical direction by roof surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>putting the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in between. On the other hand, an image inversion in the horizontal direction is performed by a first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that intersects the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the same plane as the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being approximately parallel to the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> In this construction, a light from the object transmits through the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, is incident to the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the roof reflection surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Then, a real image of the object is formed once in the vicinity of the field plate <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Then, the light is incident to the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, and comes out from the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Then, an erected image is observed through the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> after transmitting through the third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the materials used for the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and those for the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are the same one. Therefore, the refractive index and dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are the same as those of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Various values of the second example are shown in Table 2. In Table 2, &thgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and &PSgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Moreover, x1, y1, S1 denote a horizontal dimension, vertical dimension, and area of a projection of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, respectively. Likewise, x4, y4, S4 denote a horizontal dimension, vertical dimension, and area of a projection of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the light exit from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, respectively. By the way, since the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a plane, the area coincides with S4.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&thgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>45&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&psgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>90&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x1 &times; y1 &equals; 81</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x4 &times; y4 &equals; 108</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1/S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>81/108 &equals; 0.75</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> By using the aforementioned construction according to the example, it is obvious that a dimension of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system is small in the thickness direction, and a dimension to the object side of the eyepiece is small in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">THIRD EXAMPLE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A through 3D</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an outline of a real image viewfinder optical system according to a third example of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a top plan view of the third example observed from the vertical direction. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the third example sectioned by a vertical plane including an optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from a roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and observed from an eyepiece side. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S1 of a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis and also including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> is a drawing showing a projected area S4 of a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of an exit light from the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and also including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> The real image viewfinder optical system according to the third example includes, in order from an object side, an objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for forming a real image, and an eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> having a positive refractive power for observing the real image. The objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, a first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a roof prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and forms the real image of the object in the vicinity of a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes, in order from the object side along the optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, a second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and an eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and makes it possible to observe the real image formed by the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> An image inverter optical system consists of the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> composed of the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the eyepiece-side prism system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> composed of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and is arranged to an exit pupil side of the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> located to the most object side of the objective lens system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and also to the object side of the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> The roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is arranged such that a projection of a roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to an optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light or a plane perpendicular to an optical axis (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or the like) of a reflected light by each reflection surface is in the horizontal direction, and performs an image inversion in the vertical direction by roof surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>putting the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in between. On the other hand, an image inversion in the horizontal direction is performed by a first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and a second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Further, the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of a light incident to the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is made to be a skew relation to the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> has a first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that intersects the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly and a second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the same plane as the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>being approximately parallel to the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and a fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> approximately perpendicularly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> In this construction, a light from the object transmits through the first lens <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the second lens <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the third lens <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, is incident to the roof reflection prism <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the roof reflection surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Then, a real image of the object is formed in the vicinity of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of a first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Then, the light is incident to the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and is reflected by the first reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the second reflection surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, and comes out from the second transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. Then, an erected image is observed through the eyepiece <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> after transmitting through the third transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the materials used for the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and those for the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are the same one. Therefore, the refractive index and dispersion of the first prism <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are the same as those of the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Various values of the third example are shown in Table 3. In Table 3, &phgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between a plane <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>perpendicular to the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the roof ridgeline <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and &PSgr; (unit: degree) denotes an angle between the optical axis <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the incident light to the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the optical axis <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the exit light from the roof reflection element <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Moreover, x1, y1, Sidenote a horizontal dimension, vertical dimension, and area of a projection of the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis including an intersection between the first transmitting surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, respectively. Likewise, x4, y4, S4 denote a horizontal dimension, vertical dimension, and area of a projection of the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the light exit from the second prism <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and including an intersection between the fourth transmitting surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the optical axis, respectively.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center">TABLE 3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>&thgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>45&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>&psgr; &equals;</entry>
<entry>90&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x1 &times; y1 &equals; 54</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>x4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>y4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>x4 &times; y4 &equals; 108</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>S1/S4 &equals;</entry>
<entry>54/108 &equals; 0.5</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> By using the aforementioned construction according to the example, it is obvious that a dimension of the real image viewfinder optical system including the image inverter optical system is small in the thickness direction, and a dimension to the object side of the eyepiece is small in the thickness direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Thus, a real image viewfinder optical system according to the present invention has a dimension of a whole real image viewfinder optical system including an image inverter optical system that is small in the thickness direction, and also a dimension of the image inverter optical system to an object side of an eyepiece lens system that is small in the thickness direction. Accordingly, a real image viewfinder optical system with high optical performance and compactness can be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Although a few preferred embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes may be made in these embodiments without departing from the principles and spirit of the invention, the scope of which is defined in the claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A real image viewfinder optical system comprising, in order from an object side: 
<claim-text>an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an eyepiece lens system that observes a real image formed by the objective lens system and has a positive refractive power, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said real image viewfinder optical system has an image inverter optical system that erects the real image and that is arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along an optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roof reflection element that reflects an incident light from the object side, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first prism having a first reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element to the object side, a second reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface to the exit pupil side, a first transmitting surface that intersects the optical axis of the exit light from the roof reflection element approximately perpendicularly, and a second transmitting surface that transmits an exit light from the second reflection surface and that is in a common plane with the first reflection surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second prism having a third transmitting surface and a fourth transmitting surface along an optical axis of an exit light from the first prism, the third transmitting surface being approximately parallel to the first reflection surface, and the fourth transmitting surface intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism approximately perpendicularly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the real image is formed between the roof reflection element and the first prism by the objective lens system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a surface having a refractive power is disposed between said roof reflection element and said first reflection surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the following conditional expression (1) is satisfied: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>40&deg;&lE;&thgr;&lt;50&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>where &thgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between an optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element and a roof ridgeline of the roof reflection element, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the following conditional expression (2) is satisfied: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(2) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>where S1 denotes a projected area of the first transmitting surface onto a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of the incident light to the first prism and including an intersection of the first transmitting surface and the optical axis, and S4 denotes a projected area of the fourth transmitting surface onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light from the second prism and including an intersection of the fourth transmitting surface and the optical axis. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A real image viewfinder optical system comprising, in order from an object side: 
<claim-text>an objective lens system having a positive refractive power as a whole; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an eyepiece lens system that observes a real image formed by the objective lens system and has a positive refractive power, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said real image viewfinder optical system has an image inverter optical system that erects the real image and that is arranged to an exit pupil side of a lens located to the most object side of the objective lens system and also to the object side of a lens located to the most exit pupil side of the eyepiece lens system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the image inverter optical system includes, in order from the object side along an optical axis of the real image viewfinder optical system: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roof reflection element that reflects an incident light from the object side, an optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element making a skew relation to a roof ridgeline of the roof reflection element, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first prism having a first reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the roof reflection element to the object side, a second reflection surface that reflects an exit light from the first reflection surface to the exit pupil side, a first transmitting surface that intersects the optical axis of the exit light from the roof reflection element approximately perpendicularly, and a second transmitting surface that transmits an exit light from the second. reflection surface and that is in a common plane with the first reflection surface, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second prism having a third transmitting surface and a fourth transmitting surface along an optical axis of an exit light from the first prism, the third transmitting surface being approximately parallel to the first reflection surface, and the fourth transmitting surface intersecting an optical axis of an exit light from the second prism approximately perpendicularly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the real image is formed between the roof reflection element and the first prism by the objective lens system; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a surface having a refractive power is disposed between said roof reflection element and said first reflection surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the following conditional expression (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is satisfied: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>40&deg;&lt;&PHgr;&lE;45&deg;&emsp;&emsp;(3) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>where &PHgr; denotes an angle (unit: degree) between a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the incident light to the roof reflection element and the roof ridgeline of the roof reflection element, and wherein the following conditional expression (4) is satisfied: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>1/<highlight><italic>S</italic></highlight>4&lt;1&emsp;&emsp;(4) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>where S1 denotes a projected area of the first transmitting surface onto a plane perpendicular to an optical axis of the incident light to the first prism and including an intersection of the first transmitting surface and the optical axis, and S4 denotes a projected area of the fourth transmitting surface onto a plane perpendicular to the optical axis of the exit light from the second prism and including an intersection of the fourth transmitting surface and the optical axis. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The real image viewfinder optical system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein light incident on the second prism from the first prism passes directly through the second prism without reflection. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The real image viewfinder optical system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein light incident on the second prism from the first prism passes directly through the second prism without reflection.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002150A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002150A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002150A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002150A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
