<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000429A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000429A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000429</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10228234</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020826</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47B023/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A47B037/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>108</class>
<subclass>042000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Work surface for luggage and luggage carriers</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10228234</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020826</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09643079</doc-number>
<document-date>20000821</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6439134</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09643079</doc-number>
<document-date>20000821</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08970400</doc-number>
<document-date>19971114</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6105508</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jon</given-name>
<middle-name>B.</middle-name>
<family-name>Ryburg</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Ann Arbor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HARNESS, DICKEY &amp; PIERCE, P.L.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 828</address-1>
<city>BLOOMFIELD HILLS</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48303</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A portable work station having a work surface, a leg assembly operably coupled to said work surface and a clamp coupled to said work surface, for mounting the portable work station to an upright support. The work surface and leg assembly may be foldable into a compact unit for storage and transportation. The portable work station is particularly well-suited for use in conjunction with wheeled luggage having an extendable handle. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/643,079 filed on Aug. 21, 2000 which is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/970,400 filed on Nov. 14, 1997. The disclosure of the above applications are incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to portable secretaries and more particularly to a work surface which attaches to a luggage carrier, enabling a traveler to establish a portable office while waiting in airport terminals and the like. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Several contemporaneous trends are pointing to the need for mobile amenities usually relegated to established or stationary office environments. An increasing number of business people rely on travel in their jobs because of air travel and enhanced airport security. Such individuals often find themselves spending a considerable amount of time in public places waiting for departures or arrivals. Concurrently, computing machinery has become increasingly portable with notebook computers and laptops equipped with sufficient hard disk and CD-ROM storage to carry sophisticated application programs and enormous files with work related information. Indeed, terms such as &ldquo;mobile computing&rdquo; and &ldquo;nomadic computing&rdquo; are becoming more prevalent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Additionally, for the sake of convenience, an increasing number of air travelers are resorting to carry-on luggage, as opposed to checked luggage, to avoid loss in transit and circumvent delays associated with baggage claim. Due to the increase in carry-on luggage, more individuals are using rolling carts and other structural mechanisms to assist in transferring bags from one place to the next, removing the need to lift and carry these cumbersome items. Likewise, the types of luggage used by travelers has evolved to include integrated wheels and handles. As a result, it is common to see frequent fliers with such luggage carriers. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> This invention addresses such trends by providing a portable work station having a work surface that may be secured to a luggage carrier. As used herein, a luggage carrier is intended to encompass all types of luggage-related devices including but not limited to luggage carrier, luggage carts, rolling or sliding luggage, rolling or sliding cases and the like. Such a work surface provided by the invention is not only preferably universal in its coupling to existing luggage carriers, but is substantial and stable enough to support at least two 8&frac12;&times;11 documents side-by-side or a laptop computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The work station attaches to an upright support member such as the vertical extensible handle support members common to a wide variety of wheeled luggage carriers by grasping or frictionally engaging the support members with a clamping mechanism. The height of the work surface may be varied depending on whether the user is in a seated or standing position. The front of the work surface is supported by a collapsible rod assembly which varies in length according to the position of the work surface and extends down to the floor or alternately to the upright support member. The rod assembly in conjunction with the support member creates a stable arrangement to support the work surface. The rod assembly may be positioned between the legs of a user so that in a seated position, the legs of the user will fit underneath the work surface allowing easy access to the work surface.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of the rod assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side elevation view of the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a rear elevation view of the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view of the first embodiment of the present invention in a collapsed state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the second embodiment of the present invention utilizing a strap connection; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the second embodiment of the present invention utilizing a leg support; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective of the third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective of the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a perspective of the fifth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an exploded view of the clamp of the sixth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a folded view of the sixth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is a sectional view of the hinge along <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view of the storage pouch of the sixth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a partial perspective view of the paper document holder of the sixth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a bottom perspective view similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a partial perspective view of the document holder showing an alternate orientation for positioning the paper.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> With reference to the figures, the present invention is directed to a portable workspace solution which is assembled in combination with a luggage carrier to provide a suitable work surface. The preferred embodiments are described below in connection with a luggage carrier in the form of rolling luggage. However, one skilled in the art will recognize that the present invention may be used with other luggage carriers including but not limited to luggage carts, rolling or sliding luggage, rolling or sliding cases and the like. Thus, the term luggage carrier is used in a broad sense to encompass any or all of these such devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> With reference now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> perspective view of the first embodiment of the present invention is shown. The first embodiment includes a work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which engages with one or more vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, forming part of an assembly which connects a handle portion <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to luggage <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> through an engaging means comprised of cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Although in this figure two vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are shown, more or fewer may be present. The work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be positioned in any manner upon the luggage carrier that allows the engaging means to couple with the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. It should also be noted that the various dimensions depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, including the size of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, may be varied according to the circumstances and still remain within the spirit and scope of this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is generally a flat sheet cut or formed to the depicted shape, although other similar shapes may be used with the same general result. The work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> provides the area from which a laptop computer or other office device may be placed in order to provide a suitable work platform. In the preferred embodiment, the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided in the form of a hardwood-surfaced plywood having a thickness of &frac14;&Prime;, but a variety of other dimensions and materials may be used. The alternate materials include various woods, plastics, metals, composites, and combination of these materials. Alternate embodiments of the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> include hinged configurations which allow the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to be folded or collapsed into a more portable form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes a stop <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> mounted to its top surface, providing a stable point of contact for a laptop computer or other office equipment. The work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is also pivotally coupled to auxiliary work surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B by pivots <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B. Auxiliary work surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B are normally located underneath work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> but may be swiveled from underneath work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to an extended position with relation to work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Work surfaces <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B provide additional surface area for assorted office implements such as a computer mouse or files. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is frictionally coupled to the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> attached to luggage <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by a pair of rotating cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and a pair of uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Rotating cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are coupled to the back end <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and create a stable foundation from which to further erect the present invention. An additional support structure, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, is operably coupled to the front of work surface <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The rod assembly includes a support member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> operably coupled to said work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and further coupled to support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having apertures <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An adjustment pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is elastically coupled to support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> by elastic cord <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and coupling means <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The coupling means <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> may be a circular elastic band or other device which prevents the loss of the adjustment pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The elastic cord <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is designed to allow maximum freedom of movement for the adjustment pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> while minimizing its slack. The adjustment pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> rigidly joins support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to support rod <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> having apertures <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> by penetrating apertures <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Support rod <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is coupled to upright member <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> which is further coupled to foot <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, creating a structure which supports work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> on it front end <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. This first embodiment of the rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> may be adjusted to fit the height of any luggage by operably sliding support rod <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> into support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in a telescopic fashion until the desired elevation is reached. The adjusting pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> then fixes the relative position of support rods <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to create a rigid structure from which the working surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may rest on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A second embodiment of the rod assembly <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. This second embodiment includes support member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and support rods <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> having apertures which may be coupled in the same manner as the first embodiment. This embodiment of the present invention also includes a third support rod <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> having threaded aperture <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> located in its top surface. Threaded aperture <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> couples support rod <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> to support rod <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> by a threaded member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> located in recess <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Support rod <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is placed into recess <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> until threaded member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> slightly penetrates threaded aperture <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. Support rod <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is then rotated, with reference to support rod <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, until threaded member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and threaded aperture <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> are fully engaged, creating a rigid structure from which the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may rest, as in the first embodiment. This second embodiment of the rod assembly <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> allows flexibility in its break down and reduces the overall length of the separate support rods so that they may be better stored under smaller dimensioned work surfaces <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of the first embodiment of the present invention illustrating its operation. Rotating cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are coupled to bushings <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> by fasteners <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> which penetrates cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, bushings <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> in a fashion which allows the rotation of cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. Vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of luggage <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are placed between rotating cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> at the desired height, and cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> are rotated until they pinch or constrain the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> against the uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are covered with a resilient frictional compressible material such that they better grip the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and prevent slippage. In another embodiment cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> have been formed with a concave surface to better engage with the generally cylindrical shape of the handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is further assembled to the desired vertical height and rotated so that angle A measured from vertical line B is approximately 15 degrees. As rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> rotates about pivot point <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, it will come to a stop when the top surface of support member <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> contacts the underside of the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, creating a rigid foundation for supporting the front <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Upon completion of the rotation, angle A is approximately 15 degrees and foot <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is in contact with the ground through points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment of the present invention, there are three points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> spaced in a triangular manner on the bottom of foot <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to create a tripod arrangement. When the rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is assembled in the manner as detailed above, the three points <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> will contact the floor simultaneously, creating a sturdy tripod base which braces the rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Laptop <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> can then be placed and operated upon the finished structure with confidence in the steadiness of the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A person skilled in the art would recognize that the base may be configured in numerous permutations that would not depart from the spirit and scope of the disclosed invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a rear elevational view of the first embodiment of the present invention. Bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is coupled to the underside of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and its internal edges define slots <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> which are operably coupled to cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> may be moved along slot <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, varying their relative spacing, to accept any luggage handle configuration. Once cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are positioned in the desired manner they are locked in position with a securing means. In one embodiment of the present invention, the securing means is a fastener assembly <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> comprised of threaded fasteners <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> disposed through a bore in cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>, further disposed through slot <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, and coupled to threaded nuts <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> which are tightened to secure cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. Washers with a coarse surface may be used in addition to the threaded nuts <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> and threaded fasteners <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to help secure the cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> against bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The coarse surface of the washers will increase friction against bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to help prevent the movement of cams <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and uprights <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a perspective bottom view of the first embodiment of the present invention in a collapsed state. The present invention when not being used must be reduced to a small volume in order to be convenient and portable. The rod assembly <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is collapsed by removing pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and disengaging support rods <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. Support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be rotated around pivot assembly <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> until it reaches a fully collapsed position under work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Bracket <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> has external edges which define a generally semicircular cut-out <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> in which the end of support rod <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> may be placed in and then restrained with elastic band <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Support rod <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is then coupled to grips <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> underneath work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a manner that positions foot <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> within the perimeter of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments, which include a rod assembly composed of three or more rod supports, extra grips are added to secure the additional rods within the perimeter of work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The grips <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> may be constructed from Velcro&reg;, hooks, clamp, clasps, or other securing devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In a second embodiment of the present invention, illustrating a second engaging means shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> pair of side support members <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (only one of the support members <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is visible) are adhered transversely to the bottom of a work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> similar to the work surface of the first embodiment. These side support members <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> are pivotally attached to members <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> which support horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> straddle the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in diagonal fashion as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Preferably, horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are fashioned from rigid rods of wood or other suitable light weight materials such as a tubular metal, polymer or composite. To enhance the frictional gripping between the horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are preferably coated or covered with a resilient compressible and non-skid or Agrabby&cong; material such as natural latex rubber or other suitable polymeric alternatives. With the horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> placed over the handle as shown, a downward force is applied to the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Horizontal member <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is biased against the forward sections of the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, while horizontal member <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is biased against the back surfaces of the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. A secure frictional pinching or compression engagement will take place between the horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A pair of <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> on both sides of this second embodiment (only one of the pins is visible in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>) permit adjustment of the front-to-back distance of vertical opening between the two parrallel members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> so that the resulting assembly may readily fit over various thickness&prime; of vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> associated with a wide variety of luggage units. Although such thickness&prime; for currently available units is in the range of &dgr;-:&rdquo;, the flexibility of the invention enables it to accomodate a much wider range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As mentioned previously, the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment of the invention is frictionally secured on the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the luggage carrier by placing slight downward pressure on the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Preferably, such downward pressure may be applied through one or more steps <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, or through an extensible leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> with a base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> adapted for accomodation beneath the luggage or carrier components, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The choice of which pressure-applying mechanisms is most appropriated depends upon several key variables, including the base depth of the wheeled luggage unit. For example, the strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> option should be used when the front-to-back depth of the wheeled luggage unit is 10 inches or greater with the force on the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> not exceeding 20 pounds, and/or when the lateral forces experienced by the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are not excessive during use. The leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> should be used when the front-to-back depth of the wheeled luggage unit is less than 10 inches, when the load on the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> exceeds 20 pounds or whenever the usage of the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is subject to particularly vigorous side-to-side or front-to-back forces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> or leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is preferable placed at position <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, though other positions <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> may be used instead of, or in conjunction with, the placement at <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> material is preferably of a nonelastic variety and includes an adjustment device enabling one of its ends to be removably connected to the front underside of the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The other end of the strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is then anchored to some point on the luggage or frame below the luggage via any appropriate means such as hooks, buckles or Velcro&reg; as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. When the strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is shortened by the adjustment device, the strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> will be in tension and will pull the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> slightly. This tensioning will frictionally engage the horizontal members <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> as previously described. Disengagement of the strap <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> at either end or significantly loosening the adjustment device will release the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> will then spring slightly upward to a level position for storage or to reposition the work surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> at a more convenient level on the handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the second embodiment of the present invention illustrating the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The bottom end of the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is coupled to the base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The objective of the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is to generate sufficient downward pressure on the work surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> to frictionally lock it into position, while also stabilizing the entire unit. The leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is preferably a two-piece construction including a manually operable tightening/loosening portion such as textured ring <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, enabling the length of the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> to be adjusted in a telescopic fashion. Other adjustment means such as the adjustment pin <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> described in a previous embodiment may also be used to vary the length of leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Making particular reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes an upper portion which is removably and preferably hinged to the front underside surface of the work surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>. As previously described, the bottom portion of the leg <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> includes an outer tube which transitions into a base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> that rests on the floor. The base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> preferably includes a member <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> which fits under the front edge of the luggage or frame at floor level. With the element <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> in a loosened state, the upper portion of the leg assembly may be shortened, causing the work surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> to be pulled-slightly downward. This shortening frictionally secures the work surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> to the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> as previously described, at which point the device <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> may be tightened to hold the resulting configuration in place. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> further illustrates that base unit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> may take the form of an assembly having criss-cross members which may be folded relative to one another for a more compact storage capability. In the preferred embodiment, the assembly may be provided with locking means to ensure that after unfolding, the members remain in a locked position. A pin may be laterally inserted through adjustment holes in both like pieces to provide this locking function. When the base is locked and fitted underneath the luggage/frame at the floor, and with the length of the leg adjusted to apply sufficient downward pressure on the work surface <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, the overall structure assumes a very stable configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is an oblique perspective of a third embodiment of the present invention where the luggage extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are grasped from their exterior sides <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, a work surface <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> includes a rear edge having a track <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> into which opposing rigid bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> slidingly engage. These rigid bodies each have contoured sections <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> facing toward one another. These contour sections <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> are generally cylindrical in cross section and preferably include compressible resilient pads that grip the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> on their exterior sides <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. These compressible resilient pads slip over the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> when the rigid bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> are pulled apart. This simple pulling action aids in level adjustment and the removal of the work surface <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> To bias the bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> toward one another, different tensioning mechanisms may be used, such as a pair of elastic bands <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. As an alternative, springs may be used, the choice in tensioning mechanisms depending upon the way in which bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> slidingly engage with track <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. The additional rearward biasing element such as elastic band <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be omitted if the engagement between the bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and the track <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is sufficiently controlled. In this case, the user need only pull the two bodies <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> apart and place the assembly onto the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the handle assembly. If a rearward elastic band such as <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> were to be used, the assembly would have to be brought down over the top of the handle assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> illustrates a fourth embodiment of the present invention where the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> are grasped by an engaging means from the front and back. This fourth embodiment executes this capability with first and second clamping members, <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, which are respectively brought together and apart through use of a pair of manually adjustable fasteners in the form of bolts <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> coupling to wing nuts <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. It will be apparent to one skilled in the art that other types of clamping mechanisms may alternatively be used, including cams and levers facilitating quicker and more forceful engagement and/or release. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Although the shaft of fasteners <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may be positioned more closely toward one another in the preferred embodiment, they are sufficiently spaced apart so as to be on the outside of the handle assembly. In this manner this embodiment of the invention is also applicable to luggage carrier handle assemblies having one piece extensible handle support members as well as those having a plurality of extensible handle support members. Attached to the forward clamping member <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is a work surface <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> which in the preferred embodiment is hingedly affixed to the member <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. This facilitates an adjustment of tilt angle relative to a user. Once adjusted, the surface <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may be locked into place at a particular tilt angle using a variety of mechanisms, including the use of rod assemblies and legs discussed in previous embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, which shows a front-to-back clamping arrangement in the spirit of the fourth embodiment. In this fifth embodiment, a spring loaded clamping mechanism is used to engage the present invention with the vertical extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of a luggage carrier. A U-shaped member <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> includes two parallel ends <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> which are guided by tracks <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> and spring-loaded to bias a rearward member <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> toward a rearward edge <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of a work surface <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. In the present embodiment, a pair of springs <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> are utilized to provide bias loading. A handle <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is also preferably provided to the rearward-most aspect of the member <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> to facilitate a more convenient operation described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> To install the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10, a</cross-reference> user simply uses one hand to grasp the work surface <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> proper and employs the other hand to bias the rearward member <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and rearward edge <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of the work surface <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow C. This biasing creates a space between rearward member <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> and edge <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> that is sufficiently large to be placed over the luggage carrier handle assembly. When the work surface <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> is set at a desirable height, the user may reduce force on the handle to allow the rearward member <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> to move toward the rearward edge <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. The bias of the springs <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> will grasp the front and back portions of the extensible handle support members <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of the luggage carrier. As in the case of other embodiments described herein, the surfaces associated with the grasping of the handle assembly may be provided with a frictional compressible material such as rubber to enhance the frictional engagement. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The sixth embodiment according to the present invention is shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. This embodiment includes a work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> and a hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>, a clamp <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> and a rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> includes a pair of support halves. The first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is connected to the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> by the hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>. The first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> and the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> are preferably in the shape of a rectangle, however, this is not to be taken as a limitation of the invention. Other shapes, such as a polygon, are optional. The first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> has four peripheral edges <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>529</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>531</bold></highlight> which define the extremities of the first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> has four peripheral edges <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>539</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>541</bold></highlight> which define the extremities of the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. The first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> has a support flange <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> along peripheral edge <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight>. The support flange <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> acts to stiffen the first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> so that it minimizes deflection of the top surface when an object is placed on the support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> has a support flange <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>. The flange <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> has a friction portion <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> and the flange <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight> has a friction portion <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight>. The friction portions <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight> are each made of a thin elastomeric layer having an adhesive backing so that they each may be adhesively bonded to their respective support flanges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> The support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> has a stiffener <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight> along edge <highlight><bold>539</bold></highlight> which is substantially perpendicular to the support flange <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight> at one end and at the other end they are joined by a third flange <highlight><bold>547</bold></highlight> to form a partial cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. The purpose of the partial cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> will be described later on. Those skilled in the art will recognize that the support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> may also be constructed with stiffener <highlight><bold>533</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As stated earlier, the first half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is connected to the second half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> by the hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight>, or preferably a series of hinges. The hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> permits the first and second halves <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>, to take one of two positions. In a first position, the first half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is pivoted about the hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> so that the top surface <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight> of the first half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> is adjacent to the top surface <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight> of the second half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. In the other position, the top surfaces <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight> form a work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> upon which a laptop computer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> may be placed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The hinge member <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> includes a first portion <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight> adhesively attached to stiffener <highlight><bold>533</bold></highlight> and a second portion <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> adhesively attached to stiffener <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight>. The intermediate portion <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> joins the first and second halves <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> together so as to form a flat work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> when the stiffeners <highlight><bold>533</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight> are adjacent to each other and the hinge <highlight><bold>533</bold></highlight> prevents over-rotating of the surfaces <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight>. The intermediate portion <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> is preferably thinner than the first and second portions <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight>. The hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> may be made of thermoplastic elastomer material or a metalocene plastomer, both of which exhibit good high cycle fatigue properties. Alternately, the hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> may be co-extruded such that the first and second portions <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> are suitable for adhesively securing the hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> to the stiffeners <highlight><bold>533</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight> and the intermediate portion <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight> is sufficiently pliable to form a durable hinge. For example, hinge <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> may be co-extruded with a glueable acrylic or ABS plastic material for first and second portions <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight> and a flexible polypropylene or polyethylene material for intermediate portion <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>. The number of hinges <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> used to connect the first support surface to the second support surface may vary from a minimum of one up to any number as the design may dictate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The clamp <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> includes a disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> and a threaded member <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight> which extend substantially perpendicular to the planar surface of the disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight>. A portion of the disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> is fastened to one of the support flanges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, but not to both, in order to facilitate folding of the first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> to the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. The clamp <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> also includes a jaw <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight> having a disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight>, with a central aperture <highlight><bold>569</bold></highlight>, and a pair of elongated arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight>. The arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> pivot about rivets <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>573</bold></highlight> in the disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight>. Thus, the arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> can pivot about their respective rivet members <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>573</bold></highlight> in order to take one of two positions. In a first position, arm <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight> extends in an orientation aligned with, but spaced away from, support flange <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> and the arm <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> extends in an orientation aligned with, but spaced away from, support flange <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>. A pair of stops (not shown) may extend from disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> and function to locate and orientate arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight> in a desired extended position. As presently preferred, the stops take the form of a pair of pins extending from disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> towards disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight>. Alternately, the steps may be formed integrally on disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight>. In another position, the arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>, fold toward one another to be substantially parallel to each other so as to be in a compact, folded condition. This position is preferably done when the top <highlight><bold>527</bold></highlight> is folded adjacent to the top <highlight><bold>537</bold></highlight>. The clamp <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> is also provided with a thumb wheel or knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> which has an aperture portion and a threaded portion <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight>. The <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> knob has a plurality of finger engaging surfaces <highlight><bold>575</bold></highlight> to rotate the knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As stated earlier, the disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> has an aperture <highlight><bold>569</bold></highlight> which permits the threaded member <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight> to extend through the disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> so that the threaded portion <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight> of the knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> engages the threaded member <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight>. The knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> advances the disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> toward the disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight> when the knob is turned in one direction. In the other direction of turning, the disk <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight> separates from the disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight> has a friction surface <highlight><bold>578</bold></highlight> and the arm <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> has a friction surface <highlight><bold>579</bold></highlight> so that any freestanding upright support may be clamped between the support flanges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight> and the jaw <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight>. To enhance the friction gripping capability of the jaw <highlight><bold>566</bold></highlight>, arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> are provided with friction members <highlight><bold>578</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>579</bold></highlight>. The friction members <highlight><bold>578</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>579</bold></highlight>, are each made of a thin elastomeric member having an adhesive backing so that each may be adhesively bonded to their respective supports. An elastomeric material having a thickness in the range of {fraction (1/32)}-{fraction (1/16)} of an inch sold as Bumpon resilient rollstock by Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Co. (3M) and in particular Model No. SJ 6032 has been found to have desirable friction and compliance to adequately secure the work station to the upright support. However, one skilled in the art will recognize that the suitable materials may be available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As stated earlier, the first support half has a second stiffener <highlight><bold>547</bold></highlight> adjacent but spaced apart from another stiffener <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight> forming a partial cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. A rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> is disposed in the partial cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. The rod <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> includes a first extensible rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight> and a second extensible rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight>. Optionally, the rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> can also include a third extensible rod <highlight><bold>586</bold></highlight> with a foot or cap on its end. A pair of pivot flanges <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> extend from the stiffener flanges <highlight><bold>543</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>547</bold></highlight> located beneath the work surface. A pin <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> extends between the pivot flanges <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to pivotally attach the rod <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> thereto. A pin <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> is disposed in the first rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight>. The pin <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> is biased by a spring into apertures <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> formed in one or both of the pair of adjacent flanges <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight> to lock the rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> in a support condition for the work station. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The first rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight> is larger in diameter than the second rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> so as to permit the second rod to nest inside the first rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight>. The nesting of the second rod into the first rod permits the rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight>, when collapsed, to be stowed in the partial cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. The cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> is formed on the opposite or back side <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> of the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. When the portable work station is being used to support a laptop computer, the rod <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> swings down out of the cavity <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight> and the second rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> is longitudinally extended out of the first extensible member and locked into position by means of a cam lock or other mechanism well known in the art of telescoping members. In one angular position the cam lock allows the second rod to nest within the first rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight>, and by twisting the cam lock in one angular direction or rotation, the cam locks the second rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> axially to the first rod. The rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> is secured in the stored or extended position by the pin <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> or other similar mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> may optionally include a storage pouch <highlight><bold>592</bold></highlight> attached to the opposite side <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> by means of eyelets and fasteners <highlight><bold>594</bold></highlight> to flanges <highlight><bold>595</bold></highlight> defining a cavity <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> on the opposite side <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight>. In a first preferred form, the pouch <highlight><bold>592</bold></highlight> defines a rectangular compartment with a lid <highlight><bold>596</bold></highlight> that may be zippered closed thereto. Alternately, the pouch <highlight><bold>592</bold></highlight> may take the form of an expandable folder for holding various documents or other folders. In this manner, documents are readily accessible to the user and the work station is opened and the folder deployed. The storage pouch <highlight><bold>592</bold></highlight> fits within the cavity <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> on the opposite side <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> of the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. The cavity <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight> may be partially formed by the stiffener <highlight><bold>547</bold></highlight> and the support flange <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, which forms a four sided structure with flange <highlight><bold>595</bold></highlight> to define the partial cavity <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight>. The pouch <highlight><bold>592</bold></highlight> may be fastened up in the cavity <highlight><bold>548</bold></highlight>, by means of Velcro&reg; strips, to the opposite side <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The portable work station may also optionally include a document holder <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. The holder <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> is pivotably mounted at <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> to the first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> or, optionally, to the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. The holder <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> includes a first elongated flat rod <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>, an angular pivot member <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> and a second elongated flat rod <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>. The pivot member <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> is mounted to the one end of the first rod <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> by means of a rivet. The second rod <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> is mounted at the other end of the pivot <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> by another rivet to form an L-shaped holder. The second rod <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> has a pair of L-shaped cutouts <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight> to permit a document P to be inserted into each of the L-shaped cutouts <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>519</bold></highlight>, which capture the document P between them so as to frictionally retain the document P therein as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. Alternately, the documents P may be positioned vertically such that the upper edge of the paper is inserted into the cutouts as seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. In this manner, multiple layers of documents are readily accessible to the user. When the portable work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is in a storage position, the second rod <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> is rotated ninety degrees about its rivet in the pivot <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>. The pivot <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> and second rod <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> are in turn rotated ninety degrees relative to the first rod <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> positioning them beneath the first rod <highlight><bold>572</bold></highlight>. The first rod <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> swings about pivot point <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> under the work station on the opposite side <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> of the station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> When the portable work station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is used in connection with the laptop computer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, the user pivots the first support half <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> away from the second support half <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> in order to form the substantially flat work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The clamp <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> is positioned next to a freestanding upright support (not shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), such as for example, an extensible luggage handle or a freestanding, vertically extending column or baluster of a railing, and the knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> is rotated by engaging the surfaces <highlight><bold>575</bold></highlight> in a rotational manner so that an internally threaded portion <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight> engages the threaded member <highlight><bold>564</bold></highlight> to advance the arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> toward the disk <highlight><bold>562</bold></highlight>. Continuing the rotational movement of the knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> causes the upright support members to be sandwiched or clamped between the arms <highlight><bold>570</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> and the support flanges <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, respectively. As the knob <highlight><bold>574</bold></highlight> advances further in the clamping condition, one or more freestanding upright supports is engaged by the friction portion <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> and, friction portion <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight>, and the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is secured to the upright support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Optionally, in order to provide further stability for the flat work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> is rotated about a pin <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> and the second rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> is moved out of its nesting condition in the first rod and the cam lock <highlight><bold>588</bold></highlight> is rotated so as to lock the second rod <highlight><bold>584</bold></highlight> relative to the first rod <highlight><bold>582</bold></highlight>. The cap or foot portion of the rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> engages a support surface (not shown), such as a floor, to support of the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. The rod assembly <highlight><bold>580</bold></highlight> is further locked into position by having the spring loaded pin <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> engage an aperture <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> in one support edge. Thus, the work surface <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> provides a temporary planar work surface from which a laptop computer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> or other office device may be operated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> is made of a polymeric material such as thermoplastic or thermoset plastic. Alternatively, the work station <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> may be made of metal, wood or any other material suitable for the application. A non-slip surface is preferably formed on the planar work surface. Examples of such non-slip surfaces include a textured or roughened surface formed in the work surface. Alternately, a coating or additional layer of non-slip material may be adhered to the top of the work surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the exact construction illustrated and described above, but that various changes and modifications may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A portable work station comprising: 
<claim-text>a luggage carrier having a handle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a support member having a first portion, a second portion and a hinge interconnecting said first and second portions, said second portion being movable relative to said first portion between a closed position wherein said first and second portions are arranged in a facing relationship and an open position wherein said first and second surfaces are arranged in a side-by-side relationship to form a generally planer work surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamping mechanism releasably securing said support member to said handle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an leg pivotally coupled to said first portion, said leg being movable relative to said first portion between a stowed portion wherein said leg is adjacent said support member and an extended position wherein said leg extends away from said support member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said leg comprises a collapsible rod assembly attached to said support member and adjustable to vary the height of said work surface relative to ground level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said hinge includes a first hinge plate secured to said first portion and a second hinge plate secured to said second portion of said work surface and a hinge portion interposed between said first and second hinge plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said hinge is comprised of a polymeric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said hinge comprises said first and second hinge plates being formed of a glueable plastic material and said hinge portion being formed of a flexible plastic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said hinge is a co-extruded member wherein said first and second portions are formed of a glueable plastic material selected from the group consisting of acrylic and ABS, and said hinge portion is formed of a flexible plastic material selected from the group consisting of polyethylene and polypropylene. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said clamping mechanism comprises: 
<claim-text>a clamping flange formed on each of said first and second portions of said support member; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a clamping member positionable relative to said clamping flange and engageable with said support member releasably securing said support member to said handle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said clamping mechanism further comprises a friction-enhancing material interposed between said clamping flange and said clamping member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a document holder operably coupled to at least one of said first and second portions, said document holder being positionable between an stowed position and a use position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said document holder comprises a first arm coupled to at least one of said first and second portions and a second arm pivotally coupled to said first arm, said second arm having an L-shaped slot formed therein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The portable work station as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a storage pouch operably coupled to at least one of said first and second portions, said storage pouch being positionable between an stowed position and a use position.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000429A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
