<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004627A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004627A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004627</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09893924</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B60R021/32</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>701</class>
<subclass>045000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>735000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Rollover-sensing system for a vehicle and method of operating the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kyle</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Williams</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Auburn Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frank-Juergen</given-name>
<family-name>Stuetzler</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Farmington Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Robert Bosch Corporation</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MICHAEL BEST &amp; FRIEDRICH, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 E WISCONSIN AVENUE</address-1>
<city>MILWAUKEE</city>
<state>WI</state>
<postalcode>53202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method and system of activating a safety device of a vehicle having x, y and z-axes. The method includes generating a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the y-axis, generating an angular-rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle with respect to the x-axis, calculating a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal and being representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis, determining an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal, comparing the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold, and activating a safety device when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a rollover-sensing system, and particularly to a rollover-sensing system that senses trip rollover events, and activates at least one safety device in response to sensing the trip rollover event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Vehicle rollover events are situations where vehicle occupants are at risk of serious injury. To reduce the risk of injury, a vehicle may include a rollover sensing system that senses when a vehicle rollover event occurs, or more precisely, senses the occurrence of conditions that are indicative of a rollover event occurring. A rollover event occurs very quickly and in order to activate safety devices in time to protect vehicle occupants, a rollover sensing system must act at the beginning of the event. In use, most systems make decisions based on data that indicates that the vehicle will or is likely to rollover. Nevertheless, such systems are often explained in terms of detecting the occurrence of a rollover event even though the systems act before the vehicle has fully rolled over. This convention is followed in the discussion below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Rollover events can be categorized in three groups. An upward rollover event occurs when the vehicle is traveling in a forward direction, and then travels across an object or an inclined surface resulting in an upward roll. A downward rollover event occurs when the vehicle is traveling in a forward direction, and then travels across an object or a declinated surface resulting in a downward roll. A third type of rollover event is a &ldquo;trip&rdquo; rollover event. The trip rollover event occurs when the vehicle is initially traveling in a forward direction, rotates about the z-axis of the vehicle such that the vehicle is &ldquo;sliding&rdquo; sideways, and travels or &ldquo;trips&rdquo; across an &ldquo;object&rdquo; resulting in a vehicle roll. The object may be a curb, a depression, a location where there is a change in the coefficient of friction of the surface upon which the vehicle is travelling, or a similar item. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Some prior rollover-sensing systems sense upward or downward rollover events. Most vehicle manufacturers typically require that one or more safety devices be activated approximately 700 ms after the upward or downward rollover event begins. However, for trip rollover events, vehicle manufacturers requires that safety devices be activated within approximately 200 ms. One reason for the shorter activation time in trip rollover events is that such rollovers cause the occupants to continue moving sideways at great velocities. Unless the occupants&apos; speed is reduced, they may collide into a side window or eject from the vehicle. In order for the system to deploy a safety device quickly, the trip rollover event requires faster fire or activation times. Prior rollover-sensing systems are unable to consistently predict likely trip rollover events such that the system activates safety devices within the required activation time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, in one embodiment, the invention provides a rollover sensing system designed for use with an overland vehicle with x, y and z-axes and a frame. The system includes an accelerometer connected to, or mounted on or in the frame. The accelerometer is operable to generate a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis. The system also includes an angular-rate sensor connected to, or mounted on or in the frame. The angular-rate sensor is operable to generate an angular rate signal representation of the angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis. The system also includes a processor such as a microcontroller and coupled to the accelerometer and the angular-rate sensor. The microcontroller is operable to receive the y-acceleration signal and the angular-rate signal and calculate a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal. The calculated vehicle angle is representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis. The microcontroller also determines an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal, compares the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold, and generates an output signal when a magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. The output signal is preferably transmitted or sent to a safety device of the vehicle. The safety device is activatable in response to receiving the output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The invention also provides a method of activating a safety device of a vehicle having x, y and z-axes. The method includes generating a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the y-axis, generating an angular-rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle with respect to the x-axis, and calculating a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal and being representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis. The method also includes determining an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal, comparing the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold, and activating a safety device when a magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The microcontroller determines an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the y-acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis, and the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis. Using both the y-acceleration and the angle for calculating the angular-rate threshold reduces the firing times for activating safety devices. For example, if the y-acceleration is high, which signifies a trip rollover event, then the rollover-sensing system of the invention reduces the angular-rate threshold, allowing the safety device to activate earlier than if the y-acceleration is low. This results in the system being more responsive to a trip rollover event. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of the invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon review of the following detailed description, claims, and drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an illustration of a vehicle equipped with a rollover-sensing system of one embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are schematic diagrams of a system for activating one or more safety devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are schematic diagrams of a trip criteria module. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Before any embodiments of the invention are explained in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of construction and the arrangement of components set forth in the following description or illustrated in the following drawings. The invention is capable of other embodiments and of being practiced or of being carried out in various ways. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology used herein is for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting. The use of &ldquo;including,&rdquo; &ldquo;comprising,&rdquo; or &ldquo;having&rdquo; and variations thereof herein is meant to encompass the items listed thereafter and equivalents thereof as well as additional items. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> equipped with a rollover detection system of one embodiment of the invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As used herein, the term vehicle is defined as including any automobile, car, truck, van, bus, tractor or similar apparatus. The vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a front <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, a rear <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and has x, y and z-axes referenced to the vehicle. The x or roll axis extends through the front <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and rear <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the vehicle, the y or pitch axis extends through sides <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> of the vehicle, and the z or yaw axis extends through top <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and bottom <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> of the vehicle. The vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is equipped with a rollover-sensing system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (shown schematically) and one or more safety devices (e.g., a seat-belt restraint system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>, and an air-bag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>). The rollover-sensing system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is mounted to the frame <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and generally includes an angular rate sensor <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, one or more accelerometers (e.g., y-accelerometer <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and z-accelerometer <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight>), and a processor such as a microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. The exemplary rollover-sensing system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> also includes a y-accelerometer and a z-accelerometer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The angular-rate sensor <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> is a device that senses an angular rate or angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis, and generates an angular-rate signal correlated with the angular rate of the vehicle. The angular-rate signal is provided to the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. An exemplary angular-rate sensor <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> of the invention is a CMG044-MM2 angular rate sensor chip manufactured by Robert Bosch GmbH. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The y-accelerometer <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> senses the inertial reaction of the vehicle in the y-axis, and generates a y-acceleration signal representative of the y-acceleration of the vehicle. The z-accelerometer <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> senses the inertial reaction of the vehicle in the z-axis, and generates a z-acceleration signal representative of the z-acceleration of the vehicle. Although the y and z-accelerometers are shown separately, they may be combined into one chip. For example, an exemplary accelerometer chip of the invention that provides y and z-acceleration is an SMB100 accelerometer chip manufactured by Robert Bosch GmbH. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> receives the angular rate, y-acceleration, and z-acceleration signals, analyzes the signals to determine if a rollover condition exists, and generates one or more output signals (which are also referred to herein as activation signals, or fire signals) to control or activate the one or more safety devices <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. For the embodiment shown, the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> includes a processing unit and memory on a single chip <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>. The memory includes one or more software modules (which may also be referred to herein as software blocks) having instructions. The processing unit obtains, interprets and executes the instructions according to the description provided below. Although the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> is shown and described, the invention may be implemented with other devices including a variety of integrated circuits (e.g., an application-specific-integrated circuit) and discrete devices, as would be apparent to one of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The one or more safety devices, a seat-belt pretensioner or restraint system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> and an airbag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, are coupled to the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and are activated in response to control signals generated by the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Although the description herein is limited to the airbag-deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and the seat-belt restraint system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, other devices may be used (e.g., roll bars, automatic locks, and other existing and yet to be developed safety devices). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The air-bag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, which is well known in the art, includes an air bag and a gas supply for inflating the bag. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the air bag is a side deployment air bag for the driver. However, other air-bag deployment systems may be added, including systems for other occupants and for other deployment positions (e.g., a front deployment). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The seat-belt restraint system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>, which is well known in the art, includes a seat belt and a pretensioner device for controlling slack in the seat belt. The pretensioner device removes slack or provides tension to the seat belt upon receiving a control signal from the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. Although only one seat belt retention system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> is shown, other systems may be included for other passengers of the vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> further includes a power source (not shown) that provides power to the rollover-sensing system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, the airbag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and the seat belt restraint systems <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>. For example, the power source may be a battery. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Upon activating the vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (i.e., turning the vehicle &ldquo;on&rdquo;) the power source provides power to the system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Upon receiving power, the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> performs appropriate initialization operations and obtains, interprets, and executes one or more software modules from the memory. For the embodiment shown, the microcontroller executes instructions to analyze the angular rate signal, the y-acceleration signal and the z-acceleration signal to determine if a rollover condition exists. One way of analyzing the angular rate signal, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal is shown schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate functional blocks (such as filters, integrators, logic gates, switches, and other similar functional representations) which could be implemented in hardware, but are preferably implemented in software executed by the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>. One of ordinary skill in the art could readily generate software to implement an embodiment of the invention based on the function block illustrations and description provided herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the angular-rate signal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is provided to an angular-rate software filter <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> that removes noise from the angular rate signal. Similarly, the y-acceleration signal <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> is provided to a y-acceleration software filter <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> that removes noise from the y-acceleration signal. The z-acceleration signal <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is provided to a first z-acceleration software filter <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> that removes noise from the z-acceleration signal <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. In addition, the z-acceleration signal <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is provided to a path decision software filter <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> that also removes noise from the z-acceleration signal <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The filtered angular rate (from module <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>) is provided to an integrator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, a rebound detection module or block <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, an energy criteria module or block <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, an impulse criteria module or block <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and a trip criteria module or block <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. The filtered y-acceleration (from module <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>) is provided to the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, a plausibility module or block <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, and a path decision module or block <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>. The filtered z-acceleration (from module <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>) is provided to the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> and the plausibility module <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. The filtered path decision z-acceleration (from module <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>) is provided to the path decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>. As used herein the term module implies one or more software instructions that are executed by the microcontroller <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> to perform the function associated with the particular module or block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The integrator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight> integrates the filtered angular rate to calculate a current vehicle angle about the x-axis. An exemplary integrator is the Rose brand integrator manufactured by Robert Bosch GmbH. The vehicle angle is provided to the rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, the impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> receives the vehicle angle from the integrator <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> and the filtered angular rate from the software filter <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. The rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> analyzes the vehicle angle and the angular rate to determine whether the vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> returned to a &ldquo;stable&rdquo; state from an &ldquo;unstable&rdquo; state. For example, if the vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is an automobile having four wheels, and if the vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> started to roll such that two wheels left the pavement (i.e., the vehicle has entered an &ldquo;unstable&rdquo; state) followed by all four wheels returning to the pavement (i.e., the vehicle has returned to the &ldquo;stable&rdquo; state), the rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> recognizes that the vehicle <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> returned from the roll, and ensures that a large angular rate signal <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> does not produce a fire decision. If the rebound detection module determines a rebound condition is not occurring, then a logic value of one is provided to AND gates or modules <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to the AND gates <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. The rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> is known in the art and will not be discussed in further detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The energy criteria module receives the filtered angular rate from the software filter module <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and the vehicle angle from the integrator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. The energy criteria module analyzes the vehicle angle and the filtered angular rate to determine if an upward roll event is occurring. For example, in one embodiment, the energy criteria module creates an angular rate threshold based on the angle of the vehicle, and compares the magnitude of the actual angular rate with the angular rate threshold. If the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> determines an upward roll is occurring (e.g., the magnitude of the angular rate is greater than the angular rate threshold), then the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> provides a logic value of one to the first path-select module <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and the second path-select module <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to path-select modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. The energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> is known in the art and will not be discussed in further detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> receives the filtered angular rate from the software filter module <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> and the vehicle angle from the integrator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. The impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> analyzes the vehicle angle and the angular rate to determine whether a downward roll event is occurring. For example, in one embodiment, the impulse criteria module creates an angular rate threshold based on the angle of the vehicle, and compares the magnitude of the actual angular rate to the angular rate threshold. If a downward roll event is occurring (e.g., the magnitude of the angular rate is greater than the angular rate threshold), then the impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> provides a logic value of one to the path-select modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to path-select modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. The impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is known in the art and will not be discussed in further detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> receives the filtered angular rate from the software filter <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>, the vehicle angle from the integrator <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, the filtered y-acceleration from the software filter <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> and the filtered z-acceleration from the software filter <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. In general, and as discussed in further detail below, the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> analyzes the angular rate, the vehicle angle, the y-acceleration, and the z-acceleration to determine whether a trip rollover event is occurring. If a condition or conditions indicative of a trip rollover occur, then a logic value of one is provided from &ldquo;fire stage <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) to the path select module <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to path select module <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>. If conditions indicative of a trip rollover are present or detected for a defined time period, then a logic value of one is provided from &ldquo;fire stage <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&rdquo; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) to the path select module <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> For example, if a trip rollover event is occurring, then the trip criteria module generates a first output signal (i.e., fire stage <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) signifying the event. The first signal activates a first safety device (e.g., the seat-belt pretensioner of the seat-belt restraint system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>). If a trip rollover event is sensed for a defined time period, then the trip criteria module generates a second output signal (i.e., fire stage <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) signifying the prolonged event. The second signal activates a second safety device (e.g., the side airbag of an air-bag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>). The two-stage firing process is beneficial for trip rollover events. Due to the firing time for trip rollover events being as low as <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> ms, the two-stage firing system of the invention helps to delay the final decision of activating the air-bag deployment system <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. When a trip rollover event is detected, the embodiment shown activates the seat-belt pretensioner to reduce slack in the seat belt around the occupant. This secures the occupant, and reduces the lateral speed of the occupant. Reducing the lateral speed of the occupant allows the system <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> more time to determine whether a likely trip rollover event is occurring. If the system determines a trip rollover event is occurring for a specified time period (e.g., 50ms), then the side airbag is deployed to further reduce the lateral speed of the occupant. During the time period, the processor <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> may determine that the vehicle will likely return to a stable state (e.g., via the rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>). If the vehicle will likely return to a stable state, only the seatbelt pretensioner was activated, preventing unwanted use of the side air bag. One embodiment of the trip criteria module is schematically shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and is discussed in further detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The plausibility module <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> provides a second independent decision path for the processor <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> to determine whether a logic value of one produced by the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, the impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, or the trip criteria module is a valid determination. For example, in certain driving maneuvers, the angular rate and vehicle angle provided to the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, the impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, and the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> may incorrectly, or falsely predict, a rollover condition. For example, the driving maneuver may be a slalom maneuver or a maneuver occurring on a banked curve such that the potential rollover decision does not make sense given the circumstances. The plausibility module <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> analyzes the filtered y-acceleration and the filtered z-acceleration to verify that a rollover condition exists. If the plausibility module determines a rollover condition exists, then a logic value of one is provided to the AND gates <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to the AND gates <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The path-decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> receives the filtered y-acceleration from the software filter <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> and the filtered z-acceleration from the software filter <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. The path decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> generates a value that selects the logic decision generated by the energy-criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, or the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. The value produced by the path decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> is provided to the path-selection modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>, which select the corresponding logic values generated by one of the criteria modules <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> For example, if the y-acceleration is greater than a y-acceleration threshold signifying a trip event, then the path decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> generates a value that results in the path selection modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight> outputting the fire-stage-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and fire-stage-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> logic decisions of the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, respectively. If the y-acceleration is less than the y-acceleration threshold, then the path decision module <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> analyzes the z-acceleration. If the z-acceleration is greater than the acceleration due to gravity, then the output of the energy criteria module <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> is selected by both path selection modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. If the z-acceleration is less than the acceleration due to gravity, then the output of the impulse criteria module <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is selected by both path selection modules <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The AND gate <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> receives the rebound detection value provided by the rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, the criteria value provided by the path selection module <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight>, and the plausibility decision value from the plausibility module <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. If all three have a logic value of one, then a fire or activation signal is generated that results in a first safety device activating (e.g., the seat-belt pretensioner of the seatbelt restraint system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>). If any of the values provided to the AND gate <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> have a logic value of zero, then an activation signal is generated that results in none of the safety devices activating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The AND gate <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> receives the rebound detection value provided by the rebound detection module <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, the criteria value provided by the path selection module <highlight><bold>276</bold></highlight>, and the plausibility decision value from the plausibility module <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. If all three have a logic value of one, then a fire or activation signal is generated that results in a second safety device activating (e.g., the side airbag of the air-bag deployment system <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight>). If any of the values provided to the AND gate <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> have a logic value of zero, then an activation signal is generated that results in the second safety device not activating. Other AND gates may be added to activate other safety devices or to provide different relationships among the modules <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As was discussed above, the trip criteria module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> senses whether a trip rollover event is occurring. One exemplary trip criteria module is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the filtered angular rate is provided to a first sign detection module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and a magnitude value module <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>. As used herein, a sign detection module (e.g., module <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>) generates a logic value signifying whether the value provided to the module is positive or negative. For example, if the angular rate is positive (e.g., the rotation is clockwise), a logic value of one is generated; if the angular rate is negative (e.g., the rotation is counter-clockwise), a logic value of zero is generated. A magnitude value module (e.g., module <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>) generates an absolute value or magnitude of a signal or value being provided to the module. Referring back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the sign of the angular rate is provided to comparator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, and the magnitude of the angular rate (which is also referred to as the &ldquo;angular-rate magnitude&rdquo;) is provided to comparator <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The filtered vehicle angle is provided to a second sign analysis module <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> and a second magnitude value module <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>. The sign of the vehicle angle, signifying the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis, is provided to comparator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The magnitude of the vehicle angle (also referred to as the &ldquo;vehicle-angle magnitude&rdquo;) is provided to a first look-up table <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, a second look-up table <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>, and a comparator <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The filtered z-acceleration is provided to a first z-factor module <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> and a second z-factor module <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight>. The filtered y-acceleration is provided to a third magnitude value module <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight>. The magnitude value of the filtered y-acceleration (also referred to as the &ldquo;y-acceleration magnitude&rdquo;) is provided to a continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The first look-up table <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, the second look-up table <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight>, the first z-factor module <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, the second z-factor module <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight>, and the continuously variable threshold table <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> form an analysis module <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight>. In general, the analysis module <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight> analyzes the vehicle angle, the z-acceleration and the y-acceleration to produce an angular rate threshold. The angular rate threshold is compared to the magnitude of the actual angular rate (at module <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>) to determine if a trip rollover is occurring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> For the embodiment shown, the first look-up table <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> receives the vehicle angle and generates a first threshold value. The second look-up table <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> receives the vehicle angle and generates a second threshold value. The first and second threshold values are angular rate values representing the highest and lowest angular rate thresholds for the vehicle angle. For example and at a particular angle, the first lookup table generates a first or high threshold value that corresponds to a very low y-acceleration, and the second look-up table generates a second or low threshold value that corresponds to a very large y-acceleration. If the magnitude of the y-acceleration is very small, then the vehicle is less prone to experience a trip rollover event and the high-threshold value is selected. If the magnitude of the y-acceleration is very large, then the vehicle is more prone to experience a trip rollover event and the low-threshold value is selected. As is discussed further below, the continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> selects a value between the first and second thresholds depending on the y-acceleration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The first and second look-up tables provide high and low thresholds that vary depending on the vehicle model. For one embodiment, the tables use known conservation of energy tables for the vehicle model that are then modified based on obtained crash-test data. The initial conservation of energy tables are based on vehicle parameters (e.g., mass, location of the center of gravity of the vehicle, the moment of inertia of the vehicle, etc.), and are used to determine how much kinetic energy is required to roll the vehicle. The amount of kinetic energy required to roll the vehicle is proportional to the angular rate required to rotate the vehicle past the critical angle of the vehicle (i.e., the angle at which the vehicle &ldquo;tips-over&rdquo;). The crash-test data is used to adjust the tables, and takes into account variables not factored into the original conservation of energy tables (e.g., spring constants, the affect of loads within the vehicle, etc.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the first threshold value is provided to the first z-factor module <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. The z-factor module <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> modifies the first threshold value by a value proportional to the z-acceleration. For example, the z-acceleration may be multiplied by a first scaling factor and then subtracted (or added) to the magnitude of the first threshold value. If the z-acceleration is high, then the first threshold may be reduced (or increased) by a larger value than if the z-acceleration is low. The first scaling factor varies depending on the vehicle module crash test data for the vehicle module. In one embodiment, the first scaling factor may be zero (i.e., the analysis module <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> does not take into consideration the z-acceleration). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Similar to the first threshold value, the second threshold value is provided to the second z-factor module <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight>. The second z-factor module <highlight><bold>355</bold></highlight> includes a second scaling factor, which may be different than the first scaling factor, and performs similar to the first z-factor module <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The modified first and second thresholds are provided to a continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight>, which also receives the magnitude of the y-acceleration value. The continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> generates the angular-rate threshold based on the magnitude of the y-acceleration. For a first example embodiment, the continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> sets the angular-rate threshold to the first threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration is less than a y-acceleration selection value, and sets the angular-rate threshold to the second threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration is greater than the y-acceleration selection value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> For a second example embodiment, the continuously variable threshold module interpolates the angular-rate threshold between the first and second threshold values based on the magnitude of the y-acceleration. For a specific second example, the continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> may create a line between the high threshold value (e.g., corresponding to a y-acceleration of one g) and the low threshold value (e.g., corresponding to a y-acceleration of six g). The module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> then sets the angular rate threshold to a value between the high and low values based on the magnitude of the y-acceleration (e.g., if the y-acceleration is 3.5 g, then the angular rate threshold is the median of the high and low threshold values). The angular rate threshold generated by the continuously variable threshold module <highlight><bold>365</bold></highlight> is provided to a third path selection module <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a comparator <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight> receives the magnitude of the vehicle angle, and compares the vehicle angle to a minimum angle threshold. If the minimum angle threshold is greater than or equal to the minimum angle, a logic value of one is provided to path selection module <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a value of zero is provided to the path selection module <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. The path selection module <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> selects either the angular rate threshold or a maximum threshold depending on whether the vehicle angle is greater or less than the minimum angle threshold. If the magnitude of the vehicle angle is less than the minimum angle threshold, then the path selection <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> passes a maximum threshold. In some embodiments, if the vehicle angle is less than the minimum angle, then the vehicle is prevented from firing even if the angular rate is high. To accomplish this, the angular rate threshold is set to an unobtainable threshold value. Otherwise, the angular rate threshold is set to the rate set by the analysis module <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, the angular rate threshold is compared to the magnitude of the filtered angular rate in the comparator <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>. If the magnitude of the filtered angular rate is greater than the angular rate threshold, then a logic value of one, signifying a trip rollover condition, is provided to AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is provided to AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In comparator <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, the sign of the angular rate is compared to the sign of the angle. If the two signs are the same, then a logic value of one is provided to the AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. Otherwise a logic value of zero is provided to the AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight>. A logic value of zero signifies that the magnitude of the vehicle roll angle is decreasing(i.e., the vehicle is returning to a &ldquo;stable&rdquo; state). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> receives the results from the comparators <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight>. If both comparators provide a logic value of one, then the AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> generates a logic value of one. Otherwise, a logic value of zero is generated. The output of AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> is the fire stage <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> signal. In addition, a logic one is provided to a step counter <highlight><bold>385</bold></highlight>. The step counter <highlight><bold>385</bold></highlight> times how long the AND gate <highlight><bold>375</bold></highlight> generates the logic value of one. The counted time is compared to a time period in comparator module <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight>. If the counted time is greater than the time period, signifying a trip rollover is likely occurring, then the comparator <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> generates a logic value of one. Otherwise, the comparator <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> generates a logic value of zero. The output of comparator <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> is the fire stage <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As can be seen from the above, the invention provides a new and useful rollover-sensing system and method of operating the same. Various features and advantages of the invention are set forth in the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of activating a safety device of a vehicle having x, y, and z-axes, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>generating a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating an angular-rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal, and being representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>activating a first safety device when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising activating a second safety device when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first safety device is a seat-belt restraint system, and wherein the second safety device is an air-bag deployment system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein calculating an angular-rate threshold includes 
<claim-text>providing a y-acceleration selection value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining a second threshold value having a second relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; setting the angular-rate threshold to the second threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than the y-acceleration selection value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the angular velocity threshold to the second threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration selection value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein calculating an angular-rate threshold includes 
<claim-text>obtaining a first threshold value having a relationship to the angle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining a second threshold value having a relationship to the angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>interpolating the angular-rate threshold between the first and second threshold values based on a magnitude of the y-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein interpolating the angular-rate threshold is performed using linear interpolation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method further comprises generating a z-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the z-axis, and wherein calculating an angular-rate threshold includes calculating an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein calculating an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal includes: 
<claim-text>obtaining a first threshold value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining a second threshold value less than the first threshold value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>modifying the first threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>modifying the second threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein calculating an angular-rate threshold includes setting the angular-rate threshold to a maximum threshold if the vehicle angle is less than a minimum angle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method includes providing a y-acceleration threshold, and wherein comparing the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold occurs when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method further includes: 
<claim-text>calculating a second angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the angular-rate to the second angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than the acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A vehicle having x, y, and z-axes, the vehicle comprising: 
<claim-text>a frame; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an accelerometer connected to the frame, the accelerometer being operable to generate a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an angular-rate sensor connected to the frame, the angular-rate sensor being operable to generate an angular rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microcontroller connected to the frame, and coupled with the accelerometer and the angular-rate sensor, the microcontroller being operable to 
<claim-text>receive the y-acceleration signal and the angular-rate signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculate a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal and being representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis, </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculate an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generate an output signal when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a safety device connected to the frame and coupled to the microcontroller, the safety-device being activatable in response to receiving the output signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to generate a second output signal when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold for a continuous time period, and wherein the vehicle further comprises a second safety-device connected to the frame and coupled to the microcontroller, the second safety-device being activatable in response to receiving the second output signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first safety device is a seat-belt restraint system, and wherein the second safety-device is an air-bag deployment system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value, </claim-text>
<claim-text>set the angular-velocity threshold to the first threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than a y-acceleration selection value, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>set the angular-velocity threshold to the second threshold if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration selection value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>interpolate the angular-rate threshold between the first and second threshold values based on a magnitude of the y-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the interpolating of the angular-velocity is performed by linear interpolation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vehicle further includes a second accelerometer connected to the frame, the accelerometer being operable to generate a z-acceleration signal correlated with the acceleration of the vehicle in a z-axis, wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to calculate an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates of an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value, </claim-text>
<claim-text>modify the first threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>modify the second threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to set the angular-rate threshold to a maximum threshold if the vehicle angle is less than a minimum angle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to 
<claim-text>provide a y-acceleration threshold, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A vehicle as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to 
<claim-text>calculate a second angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the second angular-rate signal to the second angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A rollover sensing system for a vehicle having x, y and z-axes, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>an accelerometer being operable to generate a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an angular-rate sensor being operable to generate an angular rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a microcontroller coupled with the accelerometer and the angular-rate sensor, the microcontroller being operable to 
<claim-text>receive the y-acceleration signal and the angular-rate signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculate a vehicle angle having a relationship to the angular-rate signal and being representative of the angle of the vehicle about the x-axis, </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculate an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generate an output when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to generate a second output when the magnitude of the angular-rate signal is greater than the angular-rate threshold for a continuous time period. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value, </claim-text>
<claim-text>set the angular-velocity threshold to the first threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than a y-acceleration selection value, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>set the angular-velocity threshold to the second threshold if the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration selection value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>interpolate the angular-rate threshold between the first and second threshold values based on a magnitude of the y-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the interpolating of the angular-velocity is performed by linear interpolation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the system further includes a second accelerometer being operable to generate a z-acceleration signal correlated with the acceleration of the vehicle in a z-axis, wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to calculate an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates of an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration signal, and the z-acceleration signal by being further operable to 
<claim-text>obtain a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value, </claim-text>
<claim-text>modify the first threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>modify the second threshold value based on the z-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller calculates an angular-rate threshold by being further operable to set the angular-rate threshold to a maximum threshold if the vehicle angle is less than a minimum angle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to 
<claim-text>provide a y-acceleration threshold, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the angular-rate signal to the angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the microcontroller is further operable to 
<claim-text>calculate a second angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>compare the second angular-rate signal to the second angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is greater than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A method of sensing the occurrence of a rollover event for a vehicle having x, y, and z axes, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>determining a y-acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an angular-rate of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a vehicle angle of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle and the y-acceleration signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the magnitude of the angular rate to the angular-rate threshold; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating an output signal when the magnitude of the angular rate is greater than the angular-rate threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining an angular-rate of the vehicle includes sensing an angular rate of the vehicle about the x-axis, generating an angular rate signal having a relationship to the sensed angular rate, and filtering the angular rate signal, and wherein determining a y-acceleration includes sensing a y-acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis, generating a y-acceleration signal having a relationship to the sensed y-acceleration, and filtering the y-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining a vehicle angle includes calculating the vehicle angle using a relationship to the angular rate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> and further comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a time period; </claim-text>
<claim-text>increasing a counter when the magnitude of the angular rate is greater than the angular-rate threshold; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a second output signal when the counter is greater than the time period. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vehicle includes first and second safety devices, and wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>providing the first output signal to a first safety device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing the second output signal to a second safety device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining an angular velocity threshold includes: 
<claim-text>providing a y-acceleration selection value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second threshold value having a second relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the angular velocity threshold to the second threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration is greater than the y-acceleration value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the angular velocity threshold to the second threshold value if the magnitude of the y-acceleration is less than the y-acceleration value. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining an angular-rate threshold includes 
<claim-text>determining a first threshold value having a relationship to the angle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second threshold value having a relationship to the angle, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>interpolating the angular-rate threshold between the first and second threshold values based on a magnitude of the y-acceleration signal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein interpolating the angular-rate threshold is performed using linear interpolation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method further comprises determining a z-acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the z-axis, and wherein determining an angular-rate threshold includes determining an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration, and the z-acceleration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining an angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the angle, the y-acceleration, and the z-acceleration includes: 
<claim-text>determining a first threshold value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a second threshold value greater than the first threshold value; </claim-text>
<claim-text>modifying the first threshold value based on the z-acceleration; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>modifying the second threshold value based on the z-acceleration. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein determining an angular-rate threshold includes: 
<claim-text>setting the angular-rate threshold to a maximum threshold if the vehicle angle is less than a minimum angle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method includes providing a y-acceleration threshold, and wherein comparing the angular-rate to the angular-rate threshold occurs when the magnitude of the y-acceleration is greater than the y-acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the method further includes: 
<claim-text>determining a second angular-rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle angle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>comparing the magnitude of the angular-rate to the second angular-rate threshold when the magnitude of the y-acceleration signal is less than the acceleration threshold. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. A rollover-sensing system for a vehicle including x, y, and z-axes, a frame, and a safety-device connected to the frame, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>an accelerometer being operable to generate a y-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the y-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an angular-rate sensor being operable to generate an angular rate signal representative of the angular velocity of the vehicle about the x-axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing unit and memory coupled with the accelerometer and the angular-rate sensor, the memory including one or more software modules having instructions that are executable by the processing unit, the software modules including 
<claim-text>an integrator that receives the angular rate signal and calculates a vehicle angle; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a trip criteria module that receives the angular rate signal, vehicle angle, and y-acceleration signal, analyzes the angular rate signal, vehicle angle, and y-acceleration signal to generate a first output signifying a trip rollover event. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the trip criteria module includes 
<claim-text>a first magnitude value module that receives the angular rate signal and produces an angular-rate magnitude, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second magnitude value module that receives the vehicle angle and produces a vehicle-angle magnitude, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third magnitude value module that receives the y-acceleration signal and produces a y-acceleration magnitude, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an analysis module that generates an angular rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle-angle magnitude and the y-acceleration magnitude, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a comparator that compares the angular-rate threshold to the angular-rate magnitude and generates. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the analysis module includes 
<claim-text>a first look-up table that receives the vehicle-angle magnitude and generates a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle-angle magnitude, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second look-up table that receives the vehicle-angle magnitude and generates a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle-angle magnitude, the second threshold value being less than the first threshold value, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a continuously variable threshold module that receives the vehicle-angle magnitude, the first threshold, and the second thresholds, and interpolates the angular-rate threshold between the first and second thresholds based on the y acceleration magnitude. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the interpolation is a linear interpolation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the system further comprises a second accelerometer being operable to generate a z-acceleration signal representative of the acceleration of the vehicle in the direction of the z-axis, wherein the analysis module generates an angular rate threshold having a relationship to the vehicle-angle magnitude, the y-acceleration magnitude, and the z-acceleration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in claim <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> wherein the analysis module further includes a first z-factor module that receives the first threshold value and the z-acceleration magnitude, and modifies the first threshold value based on the z-acceleration magnitude. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in claim <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> wherein the analysis module further includes a second z-factor module that receives the second threshold value and the z-acceleration magnitude, and modifies the second threshold value based on the z-acceleration magnitude. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. A system as set forth in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the analysis module includes 
<claim-text>a first look-up table that receives the vehicle angle and generates a first threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second look-up table that receives the vehicle angle and generates a second threshold value having a relationship to the vehicle angle, the second threshold value being greater than the first threshold value, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a continuously variable threshold module that receives the vehicle angle, and the first and second thresholds, sets the angular-rate threshold to the first value if the y-acceleration is less than a y-acceleration selection value, and sets the angular-rate threshold to the second value if the y-acceleration is greater than a y-acceleration selection value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004627A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
