<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003625A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003625A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003625A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003625A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003625A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003625A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003625</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896452</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>112000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>735000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Leadframe pedestals for uniform die attach</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Barbara</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kotzias</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Orlando</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>William</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Finley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Windermere</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CHRISTIE, PARKER &amp; HALE, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>350 WEST COLORADO BOULEVARD</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 500</address-2>
<city>PASADENA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>91105</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A leadframe assembly including a semiconductor die coupled to a mounting area includes at least three pedestals extending above the surface of the mounting area. The pedestals are of the same height and contact the bottom surface of the semiconductor die which is joined to the mounting area by an adhesive formed continuously over the mounting area. The method for forming the leadframe includes forming the pedestals by stamping a malleable leadframe or joining separately formed pedestals to the mounting area. The method further provides for forming an adhesive on the mounting area and joining the semiconductor die to the leadframe such that the adhesive advantageously extends along the sides of the semiconductor die. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates, most generally, to semiconductor products and packages. More particularly, the invention relates to leadframes upon which a semiconductor device may be mounted, and to methods for forming the leadframe and joining the semiconductor device to the leadframe. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Electronic circuit packages including a plurality of semiconductor chips are widely used in a variety of well-known applications from computers to computer controls of a wide variety of devices, for example, automobiles and home appliances, among others. Electronic circuit packages for complex systems are typically comprised of several interconnected semiconductor chips which may be integrated circuits or various other semiconductor devices. The integrated circuits and other semiconductor devices are usually made from a semiconductor material such as silicon, gallium arsenide, or indium phosphide and may be collectively referred to as semiconductor chips. A semiconductor chip may be considered a shaped and processed semiconductor die which is a sawed or otherwise machined piece of semiconductor substrate which includes a semiconductor device. The semiconductor chips are mounted in packages which are then mounted on printed circuit boards or the like. Packages including integrated circuit chips or other semiconductor devices typically have numerous external pins which are mechanically attached by solder or a variety of other known techniques, to conductive patterns on the printed circuit board. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Typically, the packages on which these semiconductor chips are mounted, include a substrate or other chip mounting apparatus. One example of such a substrate is a leadframe. Leadframes typically include numerous external pins for electrical coupling to printed circuit boards and the like. In addition to the numerous external pins, leadframes also typically include an area on which the semiconductor chip is mounted. The semiconductor chips may be attached to the leadframe by use of adhesives, soldering, or other techniques. After the semiconductor chip is mounted on the leadframe, a wire bonding process is typically used to connect the integrated circuits or other semiconductor components on the chips to the leadframe and therefore to the other components in the electronic circuit package. The wire bonding processing includes joining a wire, typically under 40 microns in diameter, to bond pads formed on the upper surface of the chip. The bond pads may be on the order of 50 microns in diameter and therefore the alignment between the bond pad and the wire being bonded, is quite critical. In addition to the tight tolerance requirements along the x,y plane of the chip surface, wire bonding tools include a similarly precise alignment requirement in the z direction. This is so to avoid punching through the metal formed on the bond pad or failing to contact the bond pad and bond the wire thereto. As such, it can be understood that it is critical to maintain all portions of the top surface of the chip at the same, known height. Alternatively stated, it is critical to maintain the semiconductor chip level with the mounting surface of the leadframe since the wire bonding apparatus typically references the leadframe when performing the wire bonding operation. Furthermore, it is critical to initially mount the chip level with the mounting surface of the leadframe because attempts to re-position and level the chip after the initial mounting, often result in damage to the chip. When chips are mounted on leadframes, it is equally important to assure that the adhesive, solder or other bonding material is free of voids in the region between the chip and the mounting surface of the leadframe. Voids in the adhesive or solder between the chip and the leadframe, result in poor thermal contact and poor thermal conductivity. This is especially troublesome in arrangements in which the leadframe acts as a heat sink to draw heat from the functioning integrated circuit device on the chip. Poor thermal conductivity from the chip can result in overheating and device failure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It can be therefore understood that it is desirable to mount a chip on a leadframe such that the adhesive joining the chip to the leadframe is uniform and continuous in the region between the chip and the mounting surface of the leadframe. It is also desirable to mount the chip on the leadframe such that the top, exposed surface of the chip is parallel to the mounting surface of the leadframe as originally mounted. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To achieve these and other goals, and in view of its purposes, the present invention provides a method for joining a semiconductor die to a leadframe comprising the steps of forming a leadframe having a mounting area for receiving the semiconductor die, and forming at least three pedestals raised above the leadframe surface in the mounting area. The method further provides for introducing an adhesive material onto the mounting area, the adhesive including an average thickness being at least as great as the pedestals, and joining the semiconductor die to the mounting area of the leadframe such that the semiconductor die contacts each of the pedestals and the adhesive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention also provides the assembly including the semiconductor die attached to the surface of a leadframe by an adhesive, in which the leadframe includes at least three pedestals of substantially the same pedestal height extending from the leadframe surface and in which the semiconductor die contacts each of the pedestals and the adhesive.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The invention is best understood from the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawing. It is emphasized that, according to common practice, the various features of the drawing are not to scale. On the contrary, the dimensions of the various features are arbitrarily expanded or reduced for clarity. Included in the drawing are the following figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view showing an exemplary die mount area of a leadframe according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view showing another exemplary die mount area of a leadframe according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an exemplary leadframe pedestal according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a perspective view of another exemplary leadframe pedestal of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a perspective view of yet another exemplary leadframe pedestal according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of exemplary leadframe pedestals protruding above the mounting surface of a leadframe according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> show an exemplary process sequence used to join a semiconductor chip to an exemplary leadframe according to the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view showing an exemplary leadframe according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the leadframe shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> after an adhesive has been added, and showing a semiconductor die positioned to be attached thereto; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a side view showing a semiconductor die attached to an exemplary leadframe according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Like numerals denote like features through the specification and figures. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides for forming a leadframe having a mounting area to which a semiconductor die may be attached. A semiconductor die may alternatively be referred to as a semiconductor chip. More particularly, a semiconductor chip may be considered a shaped and processed semiconductor die which is ready for mounting. Hereinafter, the expression semiconductor die will be used to describe the various embodiments of the invention. It should be understood, however, that the terms semiconductor die and semiconductor chip are typically used interchangeably. The leadframe of the present invention includes at least three pedestals of substantially the same height, formed in the mounting area. The pedestals may be formed by various means and may be formed as separate pieces and joined to the surface of the leadframe in the mounting area, or the pedestals may be protrusions of the leadframe itself. The present invention covers the method for joining a semiconductor die to the mounting area of the leadframe using an adhesive such as an epoxy or solder, and the present invention also provides the assembly formed including the semiconductor die mounted on the novel leadframe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Now turning to the figures, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> including die attach or mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. It should be understood that leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> also includes a plurality of external pins which extend from the portion of the leadframe shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and are used to physically and electrically couple the leadframe to a printed circuit board or the like. For clarity, only the portion of the leadframe including mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will be shown. The external pins, which may be arranged in various arrangements, are not shown. Leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, including the external pins, is a generally flat member. Mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which is substantially planar in the preferred embodiment. Mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes lateral dimensions <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Dimensions <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are typically the dimensions of the semiconductor die to be joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Although shown as being substantially square, mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> may be rectangular or may take on other shapes according to various other exemplary embodiments. Lateral dimensions <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may each range from 16 mils to 1 inch in an exemplary embodiment, but other dimensions may be used alternatively. Leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be formed of various materials and in an exemplary embodiment may be formed of a malleable, bendable material so that the external pins of the leadframe (not shown) may be easily positioned and maneuvered when being joined to printed circuit boards and the like. In an exemplary embodiment, leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be formed of copper, nickel-plated copper, or other materials. According to another exemplary embodiment, leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be formed of a rigid, non-malleable material. Mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes substantially planar surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and in an exemplary embodiment, leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be formed of copper and portions of the leadframe including surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, may have gold or nickel electroplated thereon. Mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes three exemplary pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in the exemplary embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows another exemplary embodiment similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> but in which mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> includes four exemplary pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. According to various other exemplary embodiments, mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> may include various arrangements of at least three pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are arranged within mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> so as to evenly bear the weight of the die which will be joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are arranged to support and balance the die to be mounted in the mounting area and to maintain the die level and parallel to mounting surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, which is substantially flat or planar, when the die is initially joined to leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Since surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is a planar surface and since the semiconductor die to be joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is flat and includes a planar upper surface, pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> include the same pedestal height so that when a semiconductor die is joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and contacts each of pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the upper surface of the semiconductor die will be substantially parallel to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The pedestals may take on various shapes. Exemplary pedestal shapes are shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>C. The pedestals extend above planar surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. According to one exemplary embodiment, the pedestals may be formed separately and joined to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. According to another exemplary embodiment, the pedestals may be formed by stamping the leadframe to cause protrusions to extend from surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and which are therefore integrally formed of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Exemplary pedestal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>A, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A, is substantially cylindrical and includes top surface <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>A. Exemplary pedestal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>B, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, is substantially conical in shape and includes apex <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>A which forms the top surface of exemplary pedestal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>B. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> shows exemplary pedestal <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>C which is an orthogonal polygon. Pedestal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>C includes top surface <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>C. In the preferred embodiment, the three or more pedestals which are formed in mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, will be of the same shape. The three or more pedestals which appear in mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will include the same pedestal height. In an exemplary embodiment, the pedestal height for each of the pedestals which appear in mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, may range from 1-2 mils, but other pedestal heights may be used alternatively. The top surface of the pedestal, which is adapted to contact the lower surface of the mounted semiconductor die, may be substantially a point such as apex <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> B shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>B, or, such as for the embodiments shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, may include top surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>C, respectively, which may include an area ranging from 490 micron<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to 2000 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, but other areas may be used according to various other exemplary embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to one exemplary embodiment, pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may be formed of a non-deformable material and joined to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. According to the exemplary embodiment, pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may be formed and joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> using conventional methods. According to another exemplary embodiment in which mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is formed of a malleable material, the pedestals may be formed by stamping mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Now turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are formed by stamping and extend above planar surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are thus integrally formed of the same malleable material which forms leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are raised above surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and include indentations <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> formed by the stamping process on the opposite side of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The stamping process includes mechanically deforming leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by applying a sudden mechanical force to underside <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In the cross-sectional view shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> include top surface <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and may be box-shaped or cylindrical in shape, but other pedestal configurations may be used according to other exemplary embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a side view of exemplary pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> formed over surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> within mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Each of pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> includes the same pedestal height <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Pedestal <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may be formed as an integral part of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or they may be formed separately and joined to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> illustrate the sequence of process operations which together constitute a method for joining a semiconductor die to leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> such that the semiconductor die contacts top surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of respective pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be formed on leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> using conventional methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the arrangement shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> after adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> has been formed over leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be an epoxy such as Ablestick, a commercially available epoxy, or various other exemplary epoxies and adhesives may be used. Thickness <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is chosen to be at least as great as height <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. According to the preferred embodiment, adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is formed over the entirety of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and average thickness <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is chosen to be sufficient that when a die is mounted in mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, adhesive <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> will be void-free and continuous within mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is also shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> positioned over mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> includes top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, and sides <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> includes width <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> which is substantially the same as the width of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, in the preferred embodiment. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> will advantageously have approximately the same lateral dimensions as mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is substantially flat and includes top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> being substantially parallel to each other. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> will typically be rectangular or square in shape and may include lateral dimensions ranging from 16 mils to 1 inch, but may include other lateral dimensions according to other exemplary embodiments. According to one exemplary embodiment, semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be substantially square and may include lateral dimensions of 16&times;16 mils. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be formed of silicon, gallium arsenide, indium phosphide, or other semiconductor materials. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be formed of various other ceramic materials according to various exemplary embodiments. According to another exemplary embodiment, semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be formed of an insulating material such as sapphire. Top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> includes a semiconductor device formed thereon. In an exemplary embodiment, the semiconductor device may be an integrated circuit. According to other exemplary embodiments, other semiconductor devices such as transistors, resistors, capacitors, and waveguide devices may be formed on top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be polished and finished in preparation for mounting on leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, using conventional methods. Semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is grasped, positioned, and eventually joined to leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> using conventional die attach manufacturing tools. After semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is positioned over mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is joined to mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> by bringing bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> into contact with top surfaces <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> According to an exemplary embodiment, and depending upon the epoxy or other adhesive material used, adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be heated so that it is deformable and contours to the bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> when the components are joined to one another. According to other exemplary embodiments, adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be deformable at room temperature and may not require heating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> According to yet another exemplary embodiment, adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may be a solder material heated to flow and to accommodate semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> being joined to leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, the solder material may be J-alloy, a silver alloy, or it may be a 5/95 tin/lead eutectic, but other tin/lead eutectics may be used alternatively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> After the components are joined, such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is substantially continuous within mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and adheres to each of bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. According to an exemplary embodiment in which a thermally-curable epoxy is used, the epoxy may be heated to thermally cure the epoxy at this stage. The assembly is characterized by an absence of voids in the mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Original thickness <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is chosen such that, when the components are joined, a portion <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> of adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> extends along sides <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, portion <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> of adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may extend upward along 50% to 90% of sides <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, to ensure good bonding. Top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and bottom surface <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are each substantially parallel to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In this manner, bond pads (not shown) formed on top surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are at the same height relative to surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and can be reliably wire-bonded using a wire bonding tool which uses surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> as a reference surface. Because pedestals <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> include the same pedestal height <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is level with surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as mounted, and does not require additional mechanical maneuvering. Since adhesive material <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is continuous and uniform within mounting area <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, good thermal conductivity is achieved between semiconductor die <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and therefore leadframe <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> can reliably act as a heat sink as necessary. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The preceding merely illustrates the principles of the invention. It will thus be appreciated that those skilled in the art will be able to devise various arrangements which, although not explicitly described or shown herein, embody the principles of the invention and are included within its spirit and scope. Furthermore, all examples and conditional language recited herein are principally intended expressly to be only for pedagogical purposes and to aid the reader in understanding the principles of the invention and the concepts contributed by the inventors to furthering the art, and are to be construed as being without limitation to such specifically recited examples and conditions. For example, various numbers of pedestals may be used in the mounting area and they may be arranged in various configurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Moreover, all statements herein reciting principles, aspects, and embodiments of the invention, as well as specific examples thereof, are intended to encompass both structural and functional equivalents thereof. Additionally, it is intended that such equivalents include both currently known equivalents and equivalents described in the future, i.e., any elements developed that perform the same function, regardless of structure. The scope of the present invention, therefore, is not intended to be limited to the exemplary embodiments shown and described herein. Rather, the scope and spirit of the present invention is embodied by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for joining a semiconductor die to a leadframe comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a semiconductor die and a leadframe; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least three pedestals raised above a surface of said leadframe in a mounting area adapted for receiving said semiconductor die attached thereto, each of said pedestals having substantially the same pedestal height; </claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing an adhesive material onto said mounting area, said adhesive material including an average thickness being at least as great as said pedestal height; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>joining said semiconductor die to said mounting area such that said semiconductor die contacts each of said pedestals and said adhesive material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of heating to urge said adhesive material to deform and in which said step of joining includes urging said adhesive material to solidify. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said adhesive material comprises an epoxy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said adhesive material comprises a thermally curable epoxy and said step of joining includes heating to cure said epoxy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said pedestals each include a height within the range of 1-2 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said leadframe is formed of a malleable material and said step of forming comprises mechanically stamping said leadframe to form said pedestals as integral portions of said leadframe which protrude from said surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which each of said pedestals includes a shape being one of cylindrical and conical. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said step of providing includes providing said semiconductor die having a top including a semiconductor device formed thereon, sides, and a bottom for contacting said pedestals, and in which said step of introducing includes introducing a deformable adhesive material to a sufficient thickness such that said step of joining urges portions of said adhesive material to extend at least partially along said sides of said semiconductor die when said bottom contacts said pedestals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said semiconductor die includes an integrated circuit formed on a top surface thereof, and said step of joining includes joining a bottom surface of said die to said leadframe such that said bottom surface contacts each of said pedestals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method for joining a semiconductor chip to a leadframe comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a leadframe and a semiconductor chip; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming at least three pedestals raised above a surface of said leadframe in a mounting area adapted for receiving said semiconductor chip attached thereto, each of said pedestals having substantially the same pedestal height; </claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing a viscous solder material onto said mounting area; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>joining said semiconductor chip to said mounting area of said leadframe such that said semiconductor chip contacts each of said pedestals and said solder. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An assembly comprising a semiconductor die attached to a surface of a leadframe by an adhesive, said leadframe including at least three pedestals one of protruding from and formed over said surface, each of said pedestals having substantially the same pedestal height, and said semiconductor die contacting each of said pedestals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said pedestal height lies within the range of 1-2 mils. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said pedestals each include a top portion which contacts said semiconductor die and said top portion includes an area within the range of 490 micron<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and 2000 micron<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which each of said pedestals are conical in shape and include a base coincident with said surface and an apex which contacts said semiconductor die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said semiconductor die includes an area which lies within the range of 256 mils<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to 1 inch<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedestals each comprise raised portions of said leadframe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said pedestals are discrete members joined to said surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said leadframe is formed of copper. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adhesive comprises an epoxy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedestals are substantially cylindrical in shape and include substantially flat tops which contact said semiconductor die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said semiconductor die includes an integrated circuit formed thereon, an opposed bottom surface contacting said adhesive and said pedestals and facing said leadframe, and sides, and said adhesive extends at least partially up said sides. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said adhesive laterally surrounds each of said pedestals and is interposed between said semiconductor die and said surface, has a thickness substantially equal to said pedestal height, and therefore contacts and adheres to each of said semiconductor die and said leadframe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said semiconductor die includes a top surface including circuitry thereon, an opposed bottom surface contacting said adhesive and said pedestals and facing said leadframe, and sides, and said adhesive extends at least partially up said sides. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The assembly as in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said adhesive is characterized as being void-free between said semiconductor die and said surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003625A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003625A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003625A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
