<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002052A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002052A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002052A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002052A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002052A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002052A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002052A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002052A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002052</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10169149</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>199 63 333.9</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>19991227</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01B011/25</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>356</class>
<subclass>603000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for determining three-dimensional surface coordinates</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Christian</given-name>
<family-name>Hoffmann</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Munich</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>YOUNG &amp; THOMPSON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>745 SOUTH 23RD STREET 2ND FLOOR</address-1>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22202</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/DE00/04417</doc-number>
<document-date>20001212</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The formation of a two-dimensional color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) consisting of colored pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) enables a particularly compact and faultproof color pattern for a coding to be provided. The aim of the invention is to determine the projection angle PHI for a pattern element in the picture record of the two-dimensional color pattern projected onto an object. Three dimensional data of an object point can be calculated by subsequent triangulation at a known position of the projector and a camera. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to a three-dimensional optical measurement of the surface of objects. This plays a special part in construction, for example in reproduction, and a major part in production control, in particular for quality monitoring, in re-engineering, such as repairs, expansions of existing machines and installations. It is also increasingly being employed in the case of non-technical objects, such as, for example, in the quality control of foodstuffs or in the identification and authentication of persons. Further areas of use are three-dimensional modeling of objects for virtual reality and the multimedia and games sectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> For many years, the principle of the &ldquo;coded light approach&rdquo; (CLA) has been used for the three-dimensional measurement of objects. In this case, a projector successively illuminates an object with different light patterns, with structured light. A camera records images of the object thus illuminated. Projector, camera and object point form a triangle in this case. Triangulation is used to calculate the point coordinates on the object surface. A prerequisite for this is that the spatial positions of projector and camera in a fixed coordinate system are known beforehand. Moreover, an angle &PHgr; at which the projector illuminates the object point (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) must be known for each point of the object image. The initially known position data are obtained by a calibration operation, and the camera angle &kgr; of the viewing beam of the camera, which angle is associated with an object point, is known through the pixel coordinates and through the data from the optical camera calibration. The &ldquo;coded light approach&rdquo; achieves the determination of the angle &PHgr; as follows: a series of strip-type light patterns with varying strip width are successively projected onto the stationary object and respective images thereof are recorded, and the bright and dark pixels of the object thus illuminated, separately for each pixel, are combined to form a coding, so that the projection angle &PHgr; can be inferred from the coding. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Since, in this method, each object point must maintain its position during all the image recordings with the different projected patterns, this method is well suited to static, unmoving objects, but is not suited to moving or deforming objects. Accordingly, use is not recommended, in the case of identification of persons, for faces or other body parts or in the case of moving objects on a transport device. Various proposals have been made for improving the method. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The literature reference &lsqb;1&rsqb; proposes that only a single pattern is projected and this pattern is composed of groups of colored vertical strips which comprise subgroups which are unique in the entire pattern and can thus be identified in the image of a color camera. If these subgroups are not disturbed or damaged, the projector light plane can be determined from them for each color strip and the triangulation can be carried out. The longer the subgroups, however, the greater the likelihood of disturbances which arise for example as a result of depth jumps or occlusions on the object. This leads to non-identified or incorrectly identified groups and thus to errors in the three-dimensional coordinate determination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the literature reference &lsqb;2&rsqb;, it was found during investigations with groups of length <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> with four colors during simulated disturbances of the patterns that up to 20% of all the strips could not be determined and up to approximately 8% were decided incorrectly. Therefore, this method of determining the strip number from horizontal groups of vertical color strips must be rated as unsatisfactory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Generally, it can be stated that, in order to determine the projection angle of a surface point of an object, the surroundings thereof must be considered if only a single pattern is intended to be projected. The larger the surroundings of a pixel which are necessary for determining (decoding) the projection angle, the greater the risk of damage to the coding as a result of depth jumps or occlusions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> An overview of known methods for three-dimensional measurement is afforded by the literature reference &lsqb;3&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The invention is based on the object of providing a reliable light coding for the three-dimensional determination of surface coordinates of an object when using only a single projected pattern, whereby corruptions due to erroneous evaluation of the coding or due to a movement of the object are eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> This object is achieved by means of the feature combination in accordance with claim 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Advantageous refinements can be gathered from the subclaims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The invention is based on the fact that two-dimensional color patterns can be composed of individual pattern elements which can differ in terms of color or in terms of their spectral composition in a predetermined manner and in which it is possible to unambiguously reconstruct the projection angle &PHgr; in the recorded image of the object illuminated with the color pattern and assign it to each pattern element. This is done as follows: the color or the spectral composition of a selected pattern element is measured and this color or spectral composition is compared with one of the adjacent pattern elements in a row, which is oriented approximately horizontally, for example, and with one of the adjacent pattern elements situated in an adjacent row. In this case, then, the coding for a pattern element comprises the color of the pattern element itself and the color or spectral difference with respect to one of its neighbors in a preferably horizontal direction and one of its neighbors in a direction which lies approximately perpendicularly thereto. As a result, the local surroundings necessary for the coding are restricted to a minimum, namely to two of the immediate neighbors. The coding is designed in such a way that, in a color pattern, the combination of one pattern element presently under consideration with one of its immediately adjacent elements in the row and with one of its immediately adjacent elements from an adjacent row in the direction of the row is unique. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The geometrical form of the pattern elements may be arbitrary, for example polygonal (triangle, quadrangle, hexagon . . . ) or else circular. The directions of the preferably horizontal adjacency within a row and of the preferably vertical adjacency in the direction of an adjacent row need not be perpendicular to one another, but can differ by 90&deg;. It is advantageous for a color pattern to be composed of pattern elements which represent elongate rectangles. In particular, short, vertically upright strips are used which differ systematically in terms of their colors or in terms of their spectral composition in the horizontal and vertical directions. If e.g. eight different colors are used, for example additively composed of the three primary colors red, green, blue, which are designated by the numbers 0, 1, 2, . . . 7, then one part of the color pattern can comprise the horizontal arrangement of eight vertical strip sections with the colors 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and another part of the color pattern can comprise the arrangement 0, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1. These two parts can be differentiated solely by a comparison with one of the horizontal neighbors, because the difference in the color numbers is ascending in the case of the first group and descending in the case of the second group (modulo 8&excl;). Arranged one beside the other, e.g. the color sequence of length <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is produced: &ldquo;0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 0, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1&rdquo;. This can be repeated periodically a number of times one beside the other, that is to say in a row. In order to be able to differentiate the different periods of the entire color pattern from one another, there is arranged above and below this strip sequence, i.e. in adjacent rows, another strip sequence whose color numbers can be differentiated in the vertical direction by different differences in the color numbers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In order to adapt the number of pattern elements or the size thereof to the surface structure and to the required accuracy of the resolution, the color pattern is constructed with correspondingly long rows with repeated sequences and from a multiplicity of at least two differently formed adjacent rows. From the two-dimensional color pattern, the horizontal position of a surface point within the sequence and thus the projection angle &PHgr; can be determined in the recorded camera image within the sequences, that is to say within a row. The horizontal position of a pattern element can thus be converted directly to the projection angle &PHgr;. Overall, each color can be unambiguously classified and can be distinguished from every other color. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An advantageous refinement of the invention provides for a separating strip having a color or spectral composition that differs from all the pattern colors to be positioned between two rows. The color identity of two directly adjacent pattern elements in adjacent rows is permitted in this variant. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Exemplary embodiments are described below with reference to diagrammatic figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows pattern sequences S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and also a color pattern constructed therefrom, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a diagram for the calculation of three-dimensional coordinates at an object surface with a color pattern projection, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a detail from a color pattern </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a detail from a color pattern, separating strips being present between the rows.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Two pattern sequences S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are illustrated in the upper part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The sequence S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in this case comprises two identical halves <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The sequence S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises two nonidentical parts <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The numbers in each case correspond to a color present in the color pattern, as is illustrated in the lower part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In the color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. illustrated in the central part of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the pattern sequences S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are strung one below the other, as double row, a total of four times. In this pattern sequence, the horizontal difference between two adjacent pattern elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is greater than 1. The vertical difference is either 1 or &minus;7 for the first half (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>), which is equivalent in the case of 8 different colors. The subsequences <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of the pattern sequence S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which are illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> contain all variations, i.e. subsets taking account of the order, of two out of eight numerals with horizontal differences which are &ne;1. The numbers increased by 1, 2 or 3 (modulo 8) in the vertical difference also have the aforementioned properties, so that the pattern sequence S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is suitable as adjacent row with respect to the sequence S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in order that the comparison of a pattern element with immediately adjacent pattern elements from adjacent rows yields a color difference with the aid of which the first half <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> of the sequences S<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and S<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be differentiated from the second half <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, so that, despite the repetition of the subsequence <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, each pattern element can be unambiguously localized by comparison of the elements in the adjacent row in the total sequence in the row direction. The color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> can be extended by further sequences in the row direction which have other vertical color number differences, e.g. 0, 3 and 4. Since different colors in each case adjoin one another in a color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and form boundary regions or boundary zones, what is important is to detect the color differences. If instead of the vertical difference of 1 or &minus;7, for example, the vertical difference is intended to be &equals;0, i.e. the color identity between vertically adjacent pattern elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is permitted, then horizontal separating strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> must advantageously be inserted between the rows <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. These separating strips have a color that differs from all the colors of the pattern element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The color of the separating strips may preferably be black. In this case, by way of example, if the vertical difference between adjacent pattern elements is &equals;0, it is possible to perform the differentiation between the pattern elements of adjacent rows, since black separating strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, for example, represent the boundaries between pattern elements in the vertical direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In order to decode the absolute position of a pattern element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> within a sequence in the camera image, it is necessary firstly to determine its color. The aim is to determine the projection angle &PHgr;. In order to find its neighbors in the image, it is necessary to determine the contours of the pattern element that is projected on the object <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and imaged by the camera optical arrangement. In the image, said pattern element is generally not rectangular and not oriented exactly as in the projected pattern. The contours to be detected are the boundaries with respect to the adjacent pattern elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Through a preceding calibration of projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and camera <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and through the preferably horizontal orientation of the rows in the projection pattern, it is possible to reconstruct the orientation of the pattern elements and sequence rows in the image. If one of the contours of the pattern element is exceeded, the color value or the spectral composition is altered. Said color value or said spectral composition can be measured for comparison of the color numbers with the adjacent element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In the case of disturbances and in cases of uncertain decision, the comparison of the calculated three-dimensional coordinates with those of the surroundings of an object point <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> may also contribute to avoiding or correcting errors. This corresponds to a trimming of the calculated surface in the three-dimensional model. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Instead of a conventional projector with positive transparency, it is also possible to use a controllable image matrix projector which is controlled by a video signal and, with an active matrix of light modulators, generates the pattern image contained in the video signal and projects it onto the object <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by means of an optical arrangement. The light modulators of the image-generating controlled matrix may be LCD elements for transmitted light attenuation or those with reflective layers. It is also possible to use matrices of micromirrors, laser diodes or other light-generating elements. Finally, an areal color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> can also be generated and projected by means of the line-by-line movement, scanning, as in the case of television, of a single light source, over a space sector. The various technologies for light modulation can be subdivided into those with light generation, with light attenuation during the passage of light, with light reflection or by two-dimensional scanning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the pattern generation with a controllable matrix projector in comparison with the projection of a fixed positive transparency is that, after the evaluation of a reference image recorded first, the subsequently generated pattern is controlled in terms of its local brightness, its contrast or in terms of the number or selection of the colors and can thus be optimally adapted to the properties of the object with regard, for example, to its brightness or color. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a diagram for a three-dimensional coordinate measurement by triangulation with color projection. For the triangulation, the projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the camera <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the object <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are arranged at the corners of a triangle. The path between projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and camera <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is referred to as base <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and is known. The projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> images a color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> on the surface of an object <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A multiplicity of surface points <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of the object <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are to be measured, the three-dimensional coordinates of the object point being determined in each case. The method of triangulation is preferably used for the calculation. Firstly the camera angle &kgr; and secondly the projection angle &PHgr; are important in these calculations. Through the angle &PHgr; each object point <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> can be assigned a position relative to projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and camera <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The associated angle &kgr; of the viewing beam of the camera is known through the pixel coordinates and the data from the optical camera calibration. The illumination indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> by a color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> in the form of a successive series of different colors represents a coding which can be used to unambiguously determine the position of a pattern element in this sequence. The letters R-G-B stand for red-green-blue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a detail corresponding to the detail III-III in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The elements of the color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> that are to be brought into reference in accordance with the coding are identified in this case. A pattern element <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> that is presently being considered is adjoined by pattern elements <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which are horizontally adjacent in this rectangular system, and by pattern elements <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which are vertically adjacent, that is to say occur in adjacent rows. The rows <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are approximately perpendicular to columns <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a detail from a color pattern <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with rows <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and columns <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, pattern elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> being marked. The separating strips <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> that are present between the rows <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and have a color that differs from the color elements indicate the variant of the invention which also permits color identity of adjacent pattern elements in columns <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to the invention, a two-dimensional color pattern, comprising colored pattern elements <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, is used which contains information, i.e. is coded, not only in the color of a pattern element but also in the relationships with the immediate neighbors of said pattern element. Through the determination of the colors together with the adjacency relationships, it is possible to infer the position in the color pattern. It is thus possible to produce an extremely compact and therefore faultproof pattern for the coding of the projection angle &PHgr; for the three-dimensional measurement by the active triangulation. Consequently, it is possible to apply a coding for the positional identification of object points <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by means of a single pattern which is projected by a projector <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, usually a transparency projector, onto an object to be measured. This obviates the need to carry out multiple exposures with changing patterns in accordance with the coded light approach. According to the invention, a single illumination with this single pattern is sufficient. If, in order to increase the identification reliability, a reference image is to be recorded with uniformly white or spectrally uniformly distributed object illumination, a maximum of two illuminations would be necessary. The recording of a reference image, a normal color image, which reproduces the inherent colors of the object, is useful for determining the colors in the image in particular in the case of colored objects. In the case of objects with weak color variation, for example in the case of green or white objects, an image recording of the object with projected pattern suffices for the determination of the three-dimensional coordinates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Applications for the invention are, in particular, detection of the facial form of a person, for a recognition or, alternatively, the recognition of gestures. A summary of the advantages reveals the following: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> it is necessary merely to project a single pattern, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> the coding is extremely fault-free through the restriction to the very closest adjacency relationships through comparison in the horizontal and vertical directions, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> the horizontal and vertical coding is done simultaneously, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> the use of the horizontally and vertically adjacent pattern elements of a pattern, element that is presently to be detected furthermore results in a minimization of the location region during coding, since diagonally adjacent elements are not taken into account, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> the coding yields the unambiguous determination of a pattern element in the projected color pattern in the row direction and thus the determination of the projection angle &PHgr;, the three-dimensional coordinates of said object point <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> subsequently being able to be calculated by triangulation, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> the recording of a reference image enables disturbing light compensation, the reference image being recorded without single color pattern with uniform illumination. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">LITERATURE REFERENCES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;1&rsqb; K. L. Boyer, A. C. Kak, &ldquo;Color-Encoded Structured Light for Rapid Active Ranging&rdquo;, IEEE PAMI 9 (1), 1987 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;2&rsqb; H. H{dot over (u)}gli, G. Ma&icirc;tre, &ldquo;Generation and Use of Color Pseudo Random Sequences for Coding Structured Light in Active Ranging&rdquo;, SPIE Vol. 1010 Industrial Inspection, 1988 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;3&rsqb; X. Jiang, H. Bunke, &ldquo;Dreidimensionales Computersehen&rdquo; &lsqb;Three-dimensional computer vision&rsqb;, Springer Verlag 1997 </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for determining three-dimensional surface coordinates comprising 
<claim-text>the illumination of an object (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) with a color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) of known structure by a projector (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and the recording of an object image by a camera (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), color patterns comprising pattern elements having in each case a different color or in each case a different spectral composition of the projected light or a combination thereof, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the single projection of the color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) onto the object (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) for image recording, the color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) having at least two adjacent rows (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) with a multiplicity of pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>), a respective pattern element (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) differing in color terms or in the spectral composition of the projected light both from an adjacent pattern element (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) within the row and from an adjacent pattern element (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) situated in an adjacent row, whereby it is possible to unambiguously determine the position of the pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) in the row (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) in the color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) of the recorded image and this pattern element (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) is assigned a projection angle (&PHgr;), with which, given a known relative position between camera (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and projector (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), it is possible to determine the three-dimensional coordinates of object points considered. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, for each pattern element (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) considered, the combination with one of its immediate neighbors in the row together with one of its immediate neighbors from an adjacent row for the color pattern in the row direction is unique. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein different spectral compositions of the pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) lie in the region of ultraviolet or infrared light. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein pattern elements (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of a row (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are combined in groups to form a sequence. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of identical sequences (<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>) are strung together in a respective row. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plurality of different sequences (<highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>; <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>) are strung together in a respective row. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein the contour of the pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) is polygonal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein pattern elements are embodied in rectangular fashion and the color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>) has rows (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) and columns (<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) oriented perpendicularly to one another. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein the vertically adjacent rows (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) are strung together a number of times vertically in the color pattern (<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein between 3 and 64 different colors or spectral compositions are used in order to differentiate pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein separating strips (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) having a color or spectral composition that differs from all the pattern colors are present in each case between two rows and the color identity of two adjacent pattern elements (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) is permitted in a non-horizontal direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in one of the preceding claims, wherein a reference image with uniformly white or spectrally uniformly distributed illumination is recorded in order to minimize disturbance effects as a result of ambient light or as a result of object colors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the projector used is a raster image projector whose pixels can be controlled in terms of color and brightness, so that, after the evaluation of a reference image recorded first, the subsequently generated color pattern can be controlled in terms of its local brightness, its contrast or in terms of the number or selection of the colors, in order to optimally adapt the pattern to the color and brightness of the object.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002052A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002052A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002052A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002052A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
