<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001340A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001340A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001340</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895052</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F16J015/43</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>277</class>
<subclass>410000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Low power high speed disc drive spindle seal</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ram</given-name>
<middle-name>V.</middle-name>
<family-name>Pazhayannur</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Edina</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Koester</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chanhassen</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Elsing</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Edina</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Moser Patterson &amp; Sheridan LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>350 Cambridge Avenue Suite 250</address-1>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94306</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A stationary ferrofluidic seal for sealing a stationary shaft to a rotating hub. A formed magnetic is attached to the rotating hub, bounded by upper and lower members to form a shaped cavity. A stationary ring is attached to the shaft and extends into the cavity, which is filled with a conductive ferrofluid. The cavity has a uniform, concave cross section over at least part of its surface. The end of the stationary ring distal from the shaft is shaped so that in the region containing the fluid, the ring and cavity surface are equidistant from a set of points defining the seals &ldquo;characteristic contour&rdquo;. The seal&apos;s Power Index is defined as (A&times;R&circ; 2)/(&Dgr;&times;V), where: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="2">A&equals;surface area of the characteristic contour </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0003" lvl="2">R&equals;maximum radius of the contour about the axis of rotation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0004" lvl="2">&Dgr;&equals;average gap between the inner and outer member </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0005" lvl="2">V&equals;total volume of the fluid </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0006" lvl="0">Power loss is minimized by constructing the seal so that the Power Index is less than 700 (more preferably in the range of about 200 to 500). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates generally to the field of disc drives, and more particularly to an apparatus and method for providing a reliable, ferrofluidic seal between a hub and a shaft of a spindle motor in a disc drive. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Disc drives, including magnetic disc drives, optical disc drives and magneto-optical disc drives, are widely used for storing information. A typical disc drive has one or more discs for storing information in a plurality of concentric circular tracks. This information is written to and read from the discs using read/write heads mounted on actuator arms which are moved from track to track across surfaces of the discs by an actuator mechanism. The discs are mounted on a spindle which is turned by a spindle motor to pass the surfaces of the discs under the read/write heads. The spindle motor generally includes a shaft fixed to a baseplate and a hub, to which the spindle is attached, having a sleeve into which the shaft is inserted. Permanent magnets attached to the hub interact with a stator winding on the baseplate to rotate the hub relative to the shaft. Bearings between the hub and the shaft facilitate rotation of the hub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The spindle motor also typically includes an exclusion seal to seal interfacial spaces between the hub and shaft. This is necessary, because lubricating fluids or greases used in the bearings tend to give off aerosols or vaporous components that migrate or diffuse out of the spindle motor and into a disc chamber in which the discs are maintained. This vapor often transports other particles, such as material abraded from the bearings or other components of the spindle motor, into the disc chamber. These vapors and particles deposit on the read/write heads and the surfaces of the discs, causing damage to the discs and the read/write heads as they pass over the discs. Thus, the migration of these contaminants into the disc chamber must be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> To prevent the migration of these contaminants into the disc chamber, the latest generation of spindle motors utilize a ferrofluidic seal between the shaft and the hub. Ferrofluidic seals are described in, for example, U.S. Pat. No. 5,473,484, which is incorporated herein by reference. A typical ferrofluidic seal consists of ferrofluid, an axially polarized annular magnet and two magnetically permeable annular pole pieces attached to opposing faces of the magnet. The ferrofluid is conventionally composed of a suspension of magnetically permeable particles suspended in a fluid carrier. Generally, the magnet and the pole pieces are fixed to the hub and extend close to but do not touch the shaft. Magnetic flux generated by the magnet passes through the pole pieces and the shaft, which is also magnetically permeable, to magnetically hold the ferrofluid in gaps between the pole pieces and the shaft, thereby forming a seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As noted above, current ferrofluidic seals use a rotating design in which the magnet and pole pieces are affixed to the hub, and a ferrofluid seal is found between the rotating pole pieces and the fixed shaft. Although this design has worked well for conventional spindle motors, the latest generation of motors rotate at high speeds, often exceeding 10,000 revolutions per minute (rpm). The centrifugal forces developed at such high speeds often exceed the ability of the ferrofluidic seal&apos;s magnetic flux to hold the ferrofluid against the shaft due to the velocity gradient across the ferrofluid, resulting in the failure of the ferrofluidic seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there is a need for a ferrofluidic seal that is reliable at high rotational speeds. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a solution to these and other problems, and offers other advantages over the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an apparatus for sealing the outer surface of a shaft to a face of a hub disposed about the shaft that solves the above problems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In yet another aspect, the present invention is directed to a ferrofluidic seal for sealing a stationary shaft to a rotating hub. A formed magnet is attached to the rotating hub, bounded by upper and lower members to form a shaped cavity. A stationary ring is attached to the shaft and extends into the cavity, which is filled with a conductive ferrofluid. The cavity has a uniform, concave cross section over at least part of its surface. The end of the stationary ring distal from the shaft is shaped so that in the region containing the fluid, the ring and cavity surface are equidistant from a set of points defining the seals &ldquo;characteristic contour&rdquo;. The seal&apos;s Power Index is defined as (A&times;R&circ; 2)/(&Dgr;&times;V), where: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A&equals;surface area of the characteristic contour </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> R&equals;maximum radius of the contour about the axis of rotation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> &Dgr;&equals;average gap between the inner and outer member </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> V&equals;total volume of the fluid </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Power loss is minimized by constructing the seal so that the Power Index is less than 700 (more preferably in the range of about 200 to 500). This differs from prior systems by allowing very high rotation rates with acceptable power consumption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The current invention enables seals to be operated at high rotational velocities at acceptable power levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention is particularly useful in a spindle motor such as used in a disc drive. A spindle motor generally has a base supporting a shaft, and a hub having an inner surface disposed about an outer surface of the shaft. An embodiment of a seal according to the present invention is positioned between the shaft and the hub to seal the outer surface of the shaft to the inner surface of the hub and to electrically couple the shaft to the hub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> These and various other features as well as advantages which characterize the present invention will be apparent upon reading of the following detailed description and review of the associate drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> (prior art) is a plan view of a disc drive in which a spindle motor incorporating a ferrofluidic seal according to the embodiment of the present invention is useful. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> (prior art) is a sectional side view of an embodiment of a spindle motor in which the present invention is useful, illustrating a ferrofluidic seal according to the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a sectional view of one exemplary embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> is a vertical section of one element of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>D are partial sectional views illustrating alternative embodiments of this invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of a magnetic disc drive for which a spindle motor having a ferrofluidic seal according to the present invention is particularly useful. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> disc drive <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> typically includes a housing <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> having a base <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> joined to a cover <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight>. One or more of discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> having surfaces <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> covered with a magnetic media (not shown) for magnetically storing information are attached to a spindle <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. A spindle motor (not shown in this figure) turns the spindle <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> to rotate the discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> past read/write heads <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> which are suspended above surfaces <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> of the discs by a suspension arm assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. In operation, the discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are rotated at high speed past the read/write <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> while the suspension arm assembly <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> moves the read/write heads in an arc over a number of radially spaced tracks (not shown) on the surfaces <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> of the disc <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. This enables the read/write heads <highlight><bold>145</bold></highlight> to read and write magnetically encoded information to the magnetic media on the surfaces <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> of the discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> at selected locations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a sectional side view of a spindle motor <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> of a type which is especially useful in disc drives <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Typically the spindle motor <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> includes a rotatable hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> having an inner surface <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> disposed about an outer surface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of a shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>. A ferrofluidic seal <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> seals the outer surface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> to the inner surface <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> of the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. One or more magnets <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> attached to a periphery <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> of the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> interact with a stator winding <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> attached to the base <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to cause the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to rotate. The hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is supported on the shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> by one or more bearings <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, such as fluid dynamic bearings (not shown) or ball bearings <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. A ball-bearing generally balls <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> loosely held by a retainer <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> between an inner race <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and an outer race <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>. Interfacial spaces (not shown) between the balls <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the retainer <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> and the inner and outer races <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, can be filled with a lubricating fluid or grease to facilitate movement of the balls <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. The structure of the bearing <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> is not material to the invention. What is significant is that the ferrofluidic seal <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> must maintain a seal between the outer surface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> and the inner surface <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> of the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> so that the fluid, grease and other loose particles associated with the bearing <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight> cannot reach the discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A typical ferrofluidic seal <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>, such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, includes a laminate <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> consisting of an annular magnet <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>, with top and bottom pole pieces <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>, coupled to opposite poles thereof. The magnet <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> and pole pieces <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>, are attached and sealed, using an epoxy or solder, to the inner surface <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> of the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> or the outer surface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>. A ferrofluidic fluid (ferrofluid <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>) is magnetically held in a gap <highlight><bold>275</bold></highlight> between the pole pieces <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight>, and the outer surface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the shaft <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> or the inner surface <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> of the hub <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to seal the shaft to the inner surface of the hub. The ferrofluid <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> typically includes ferromagnetic particles, such as Fe<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>O or magnetite, colloidally suspended in a carrier fluid, such as a hydrocarbon or synthetic ester based fluid. In a conventional ferrofluidic seal <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>, the ferrofluid <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> forms a top meniscus <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, that during dynamic operations, especially operation at the high speeds which are becoming increasingly common, can cause splashing and migration of the ferrofluid due centrifugal force exerted on the ferrofluid of the rapidly rotating ferrofluidic seal. This splashing and migration can cause contamination of the discs <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and loss of the hermetic seal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Turning next to the details of the seal of the present invention, the invention herein identifies two critical components for a spindle seal used in applications such as disc drives, and especially those where the spindle motor shaft or hub is rotating faster than 10,000 RPM. The first of these is to maintain the seal integrity at these and higher rotational velocities. The second of these is to consume very low power while satisfying the first requirement. In the field of spindle seals, such as are required to prevent particles, gasses and other undesirable elements from moving from the ball bearing or shaft region out into the region of the rotating discs, some prior systems operated successfully at low rotational velocities. However, these were typically unsuccessful in maintaining seal integrity at high RPMs. Other designs, overcame the speed limitations, but consumed excessive power. Therefore, the designs of the present invention were developed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The basic elements of the present invention can be seen in the detailed cutaway view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> showing a disc drive stator and rotor and one embodiment is the seal of the present invention. In this example, the seal is shown adjacent a ball bearing <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> comprising an inner race <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> which is supported from or attached to a shaft <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and an outer race <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> which will support a hub when the motor is used in a disc drive or similar mechanical supported element for rotation relative to the shaft <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. In order to prevent any lubricants, gasses, particles, or the like which are generated by the balls <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of the ball bearing rolling in the races <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, from reaching the interior of the HDD, it is already well-known to provide a magnetic seal generally indicated at <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> immediately adjacent the ball bearing and intervening between the ball bearing and the air space surrounding the discs of the disc drive. In this embodiment, where the shaft <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is fixed to the inner race <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, and the outer race <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> rotates, a magnet is provided supported atop the outer race <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> and rotating with that race in this particular fixed shaft embodiment, and axially spaced from the ball bearing along the shaft. In this way, the magnet forms a basic element of the structure of the magnetic seal, and one of these is provided at either end of the system supported about the shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Adjacent the magnet <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> are two plates <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> formed of a magnetic material. These cooperate with the magnet <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> to define a recess <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in which the magnetic fluid is placed. The seal is completed by providing a stationary ring <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> typically in the form of a plate with a shaped pole piece on the distal end thereof supported from the shaft <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> and extending radially out from the shaft to the recess defined between the upper and lower plates <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and the magnet <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. This ring <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> extends close to the interior of the recess where the conductive ferrofluid <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> is retained and includes on an end thereof as shown most clearly in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> a shaped pole piece <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>. The pole piece <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> is shaped in this instance and the other embodiments to be described below to have a substantially uniform spacing between at least a part of the outer surface <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> of the pole piece and a portion of the inner surface <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight> of the recess <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The pole piece may be formed, for example, of plastic or nylon with a magnetic material covering such as Ni plating; this may also be used to form ring <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. The recess <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> has at least in a part of its interior a substantially uniform concave cross-section (herein also called pocket) that contains the conductive ferrofluid <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. In order to optimize the sealing ability of the seal, it has a characteristic contour which is defined as the center points within the sealed fluid that are equidistant between the inner member, i.e., the surface <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> of the pole piece, and the outer member, i.e., the surface of the concave cross-sectional recess defined by the upper and lower plates <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and the inner surface of the magnet <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Given this characteristic contour, the seal&apos;s Power Index is defined as (A&times;R&circ; 2)/(&Dgr;&times;V), where: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A&equals;surface area of the characteristic contour </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> R&equals;maximum radius of the contour about the axis of rotation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> &Dgr;&equals;average gap between the inner and outer member </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> V&equals;total volume of the fluid </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Power loss is minimized by constructing the seal so that the Power Index is less than 700 (more preferably in the range of about 200 to 500). This differs from prior systems by allowing very high rotation rates with acceptable power consumption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The current invention enables seals to be operated at high rotational velocities at acceptable power of levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Considering in further detail the example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, it shows that the stationary ring which is supported from the shaft is, in this example, held in place by a conductive adhesive <highlight><bold>290</bold></highlight>. Obviously, other means of supporting the stationary ring may be provided so that the ring is held stable relative to the recess which is rotating around the end of the ring and the pole piece <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> that it supports. The fluid <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> is held in place by the rotating outer members centrifugal force, by the rotating member being comprised of the upper and lower plates <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> and the magnet <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, as well as by surface tension, wetting, and by the magnets attractive for the magnetic fluid <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. Providing the shaped surface which is defined herein for both the outer surface of the recess and the outer surface of the pole piece provides a larger wetted surface. Further, the pole piece occupies the substantial portion of the recess, which means that the centrifugal force is more effective in holding the fluid in place within the recess since the space between the inner surface of the rotating member and the outer surface of the pole piece can be defined to be relatively narrow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The first preferred configuration of the present invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. In this figure, the pole piece <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight>, which forms the inner member, has a flat upper and lower surfaces and a smoothly curved end surface <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight>. The inner surface of the rotating outer member <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> also has a smoothly rounded curvature curved inner surface <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> ending in flat axially radially extending upper and lower surfaces <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. In this configuration, any current losses and edge effects, which would be created with the sharp corners and edges of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, are prevented or minimized by providing the smoothly curved surface which is shown. Preferably, the radii of curvature are below 0.01R everywhere that the fluid <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight> touches. Therefore, the seals Power Index and its effectiveness can be measured by applying example K from Table 4. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> L is the length of the characteristic contour, and A is generally approximated by 2*pi*R*L. Example &ldquo;I&rdquo; is modeled with a textured surface, however, so that A is slightly larger than this approximation, increasing the Power Index from 212 to 225. It is also apparent that the magnet <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> has a greater axial dimension than the pole piece, and that has a curved cross-section at the end facing the pole piece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> A more easily manufactured seal configuration is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference>. In this figure, the recess is generally rectangular, as also shown in the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, and the pole piece <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> has a generally flat outer surface and a generally rectangular cross-section looked at in a side view. In this case, the characteristic contour is represented by the line <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>; and it can be seen that the spacing between the outer surface of the pole piece and the inner surface of the recess may be somewhat greater between the axially upper and lower surfaces <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> of the pole piece and the inner axial surfaces <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight>, than it is between the outer surface of the pole piece facing in the axially direction <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> and the corresponding surface of the recess <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight>. Also, in this case, the lower pole plate is somewhat extended in the radial direction to prevent loss of fluid due to splashing. This is because gravitational effects will draw somewhat more of the fluid down toward this lower ledge surface. According to the preferred embodiment which has dimensions consistent with examples A, E, S, or T of Table 4, the ledge <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight> which desirably exceeds 0.1R to 0.2R to reduce loss of fluid due to the splashing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> A variation of the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> where both the recess <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> and the pole piece <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> are similar in configuration to what appears in FIG. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>B, but with some variation especially in that the interior corners of the pocket or recess <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> are rounded as are the exterior corners of the pole piece <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. Further, in addition to the magnet <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, which is incorporated in the recess <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, in a preferred embodiment, a further magnet <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> is incorporated in the pole piece having preferably an axial length which is the same as or less than magnet <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. This additional magnet <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> carried in the pole piece which is of less radial extent preferably than the magnet <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> which is incorporated in the outer member, or hub, or spindle, serves to concentrate the fluid <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> in the desired region of the gap, diminishing the need for an extended ledge as appears in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference>. It can be seen that the gap <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> between the outer member and the pole piece is substantially the same over the entire region of interest, although it may widen some in the gap in the axial direction gaps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> A further preferred embodiment of the present invention is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, again shown in vertical cross-section so that it can be easily visualized as incorporated into the overall embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, yet a further embodiment is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3D</cross-reference> which has the benefit, at least in certain embodiments, with certain measurements, of achieving operation in the desired range of the power index. In this embodiment, the recess has a dramatically modified shape from the other embodiments, comprising a tapered wall <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> extending generally in the axial direction, but being inclined from its point of maximum distance from the shaft which is adjacent the pole piece to a point which is less distant from the shaft as the wall moves away from the pole piece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The design further comprises a ledge <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> which is somewhat inclined toward the center of the shaft and away from the end of the shaft as the wall extends toward the shaft. In the region <highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight> where the walls meet, they meet in a curved region. The pole piece itself is tapered so that its walls <highlight><bold>642</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>644</bold></highlight> as viewed in vertical or axial cross-section gradually extend toward each other, meeting at or near a point <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>, which does form a somewhat curved nose. The gap, which must be measured to define the characteristic &Dgr; should be measured in the region where the tapered walls of the pole piece are near to the tapered walls <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> of the outer member. The magnet <highlight><bold>660</bold></highlight> must be of reasonable strength in order to maintain the fluid at or near this defined gap region, and a further magnet <highlight><bold>670</bold></highlight> may be incorporated in the pole piece to aid in maintaining the fluid in the gap region even when there is no relative rotation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> At rest, the seal fluid <highlight><bold>680</bold></highlight> flows to a lower position in which L is the length of the characteristic contour is about five times &Dgr; which is the average gap. As the seal begins to rotate, that is, as the pole piece and outer member achieve relative rotation, the fluid flows quickly to a dynamic position in which the ratio of L/&Dgr; decreases by at least 5-10%. At speed, this embodiment has dimensions, such as examples B, H or K or Table 4. Therefore, at least with examples H or K, the desired power index can be achieved with this embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Other features and advantages of this invention will become apparent to a person of skill in the art who studies this invention disclosure. Therefore, the scope of the present invention is to be limited only by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A seal for sealing an outer surface of a magnetically permeable shaft to an inner surface of a hub disposed about the shaft, the seal comprising and outer member including: 
<claim-text>an annular magnet positioned between the shaft and the hub; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a top pole piece and a bottom pole piece coupled to opposite poles of the magnet, the top and bottom pole pieces comprising a material which is magnetically permeable, and having annular shapes with interior radii that are larger than the radius of the outer surface of the shaft to define a concave region in which a ferrofluid is held, an inner member including an annular ring supported from the shaft and extending into the concave region and supporting a short, axially extended pole piece at an end thereof to define a contoured gap in the concave region where the ferrofluid is held, the surface of the pole piece having a relatively uniform spacing from an inner surface of the recess. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the contoured gap includes a characteristic contour defined as a set of points within the seal ferrofluid that are equidistant between a surface of the concave region and an outer surface of the pole piece, and usable to define a Power Index (PI)&equals;(A&times;R&circ; 2)/&Dgr;&times;V) wherein 
<claim-text>A&equals;surface area of the characteristic contour </claim-text>
<claim-text>R&equals;maximum radius of the contour about the axis of rotation &Dgr;&equals;average gap between the inner and outer member </claim-text>
<claim-text>V&equals;total volume of the fluid </claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein the seal is optimized for PI&lt;700. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the concave region interior surface of the outer member is smooth, having radii of curvature below 0.01R everywhere the ferrofluid touches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece of the inner member has a substantially constant spacing from the inner, contoured surface of the outer member in the fluid region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece comprises nylon coated with a magnetic material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece is coated with a nickel plating. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece which comprises an inner member of the seal has flat upper and lower surfaces and a smoothly curved end surface, and the inner surface of the outer member has a smoothly rounded curved inner surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one of the surfaces is slightly textured. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the axially extent of the magnet is at least equal to or greater than the axially extent of the pole piece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer surface of the pole piece and the inner surface of the recess are both substantially rectangular in cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gap between the radially outer end of the pole piece and the inner surface of the recess is slightly greater than the axially gap between the pole piece and the recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the axially inner surface of the recess is of greater radial extent than the axially outer surface, in order to further diminish fluid loss due to splashing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the axially inner surface of the recess is of a dimension of about 0.1 R to 0.2 R, where R is the distance from the center line between the pole piece and the recess to the axis of the shaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the corners of the recess and of the pole piece are rounded. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece includes a magnet whose axially radially outer surface faces the inner surface of the recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the axial dimension of the pole piece magnet is less than the axial extent of the magnet which defines a part of the recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the gap between the outer surface of the pole piece and the inner surface of the recess is substantially uniform over the entire region where the fluid may be found. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the pole piece comprises two generally axially services which generally taper each other to meet at the axially distal end of the pole piece from the shaft, and wherein the axially lower surface of the recess maintains a substantially constant spacing from the axially lower surface of the pole piece. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A seal as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the axially upper surface of the recess inclines gradually away from the upper surface of the pole piece, and wherein the fluid is maintained in the recess primarily in the region from the axially end point of the pole piece and extending radially between the axial lower surface of the pole piece and the axial upper surface of the recess. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A seal for sealing an outer surface of a magnetically permeable shaft to an inner surface of a hub disposed about the shaft, the seal comprising and outer member including: 
<claim-text>an annular magnet positioned between the shaft and the hub; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a top pole piece and a bottom pole piece coupled to opposite poles of the magnet, the top and bottom pole pieces comprising a material which is magnetically permeable, and having annular shapes with interior radii that are larger than the radius of the outer surface of the shaft to define a concave region in which a ferrofluid is held, an inner member including an annular ring supported from the shaft and extending into the concave region and means for maintaining the fluid in the recess in the seal while minimizing the power required to maintain constant speed rotation of the annular ring and pole piece through the recess of the seal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001340A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
