<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001039A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001039A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001039</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10183645</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-198937</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B023/107</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>242</class>
<subclass>348000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Cartridge engaging mechanism</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Toshimitsu</given-name>
<family-name>Kawasaki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yonezawa-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>NEC Corporation</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>YOUNG &amp; THOMPSON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>745 SOUTH 23RD STREET 2ND FLOOR</address-1>
<city>ARLINGTON</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22202</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A cartridge gear (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) which is formed in an annular shape around the rotational center (CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) and secured to a reel of a tape cartridge (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) loaded in a drive device (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) has a tapered shape having a first inclination angle which is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach to the innermost peripheral edge. A drive gear (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) which is formed in an annular shape around the rotational center (CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and connected to a reel motor (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) of the drive device (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) has a tapered shape having a second inclination angle which is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach to the outermost peripheral edge, the second inclination angle being smaller than the first inclination angle. The tapered shape of the drive gear (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) is formed in an area which extends outwardly from the radially-innermost position of the drive gear (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) at which lock pads (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) abut against the drive gear (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) under the state that the drive gear (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) and the cartridge gear (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) are in proper engagement with each other. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a cartridge engaging mechanism for the engagement between a tape cartridge and a tape drive device when the tape cartridge is loaded into the tape drive device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A single reel cartridge magnetic tape is used as one of storage media for computers. The magnetic tape is wound around a reel while one end thereof is fixed to the core of the reel, and the reel is supported in a case of a cartridge so as to be rotatable relatively to the case. The other end of the magnetic tape is drawn out from the case of the cartridge followed by rotation of the reel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> When the cartridge is loaded in the magnetic tape drive device, the rotational driving force can be transmitted from the driving motor (reel motor) of the drive device to the reel of the cartridge by a cartridge engaging mechanism. In order to construct the cartridge engaging mechanism, a plane-type cartridge gear exposed to the outside from the outer surface of the case is equipped to the reel at the cartridge side, and a plane-type drive gear for receiving the rotational force transmitted from the reel motor is disposed at the drive device side, and the cartridge gear and the drive gear are disposed so as to come into contact with each other and separate from each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The cartridge is equipped with a reel lock mechanism for preventing the reel from being rotated relatively to the case of the cartridge when the cartridge is unloaded from the drive device (that is, the engagement of the cartridge engaging mechanism is canceled). With the reel lock mechanism, the reel can be prevented from being rotated relatively to the case of the cartridge under states other than the loading state of the cartridge in the drive device, thereby preventing rewinding of the magnetic tape and occurrence of slack of the magnetic tape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The reel lock mechanism is designed so that brake is released only when the cartridge gear is engaged with the drive gear. In order to satisfy this operation, a movable member called as a lock pad which abuts against the gear tooth tops of the drive gear is secured to each portion at which some gear teeth are removed from the cartridge gear. The lock pad is disposed so as to be reciprocatively movable between an advance position at which the lock pad is projected forwardly from the gear surface and a retraction position at which the lock pad is retracted backwardly from the gear surface. The lock pad is forwardly urged to the advance position by a spring. The brake acts at the advance position, and the lock pad is backwardly moved to the retraction position against the urging force of the spring to release the brake. Therefore, the lock pad is required to have a proper reciprocative movement stroke. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematically partially cross-sectional view showing the drive gear and the cartridge gear of a conventional cartridge engaging mechanism as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is designed in an annular form so as to surround the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extending in the up-and-down direction, and three lock pads <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are disposed so as to be spaced at an equal angular interval in the circumferential direction of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Each lock pad <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is movable in the up-and-down direction over a required stroke with the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> as the lower limit position. A non-tooth portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>at which three gear teeth of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are removed is formed in the neighborhood of the formation position of each lock pad <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> has such a shape that it is fit to the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and it is designed in an annular form so as to surround the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> extending in the up-and-down direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Each tooth top of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided with a tapered portion having a gradually-lowered taper angle of &thgr;a in an area extending inwardly from each lock pad <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and each tooth top of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is provided with a tapered portion having a gradually-lowered taper angle of &thgr;b in an area extending inwardly from the center of each lock pad <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. Accordingly, under the state that the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are properly engaged with each other with the rotational centers CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> thereof being common to each other, the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> abut against and pushes the lock pads <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at the highest position of the tooth tops, so that the lock pads <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can be moved by a distance enough to release the brake. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> However, if the precision of the positioning of the cartridge case to the drive device when the cartridge is loaded into the drive device and the positional precision of the cartridge gear to the cartridge case are not sufficient, there occurs a positional error between the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, there is a case where the positional error described above occurs so that the positional error direction of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with respect to the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is substantially coincident with the direction of the lock pad <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>relative to the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in the circumferential direction showing the neighborhood of the position corresponding to the lock pads <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>at the outermost peripheral position at which the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are highest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As is apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, when a slight inclination occurs between the rotational axis direction of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and the rotational axis direction of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the tooth tops at both sides of each non-tooth portion <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>intrude in each portion having the largest tooth top pitch in the neighborhood of the outermost peripheral portion of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Firstly, this is because the tooth top pitch of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is smaller than the tooth top pitch of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> within the cross section shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, and secondly this is because the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are formed to be highest in height in order to achieve a required lock pad movement stroke, so that the width W&prime; of the flat portion of each tooth top of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is small and thus there is little margin in receiving the tooth tops of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>by the flat portions of the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Under such a situation, the relative rotation between both the gears is impossible, and thus it is impossible to properly engage both the gears with each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Therefore, in the conventional cartridge engaging mechanism, the permissible dimension for the error or displacement S&prime; between the rotational centers CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the gears which enables the proper engagement between both the gears is reduced, and thus it is required to enhance the precision of the positioning of the cartridge case to the drive device and also enhance the positional precision of the cartridge reel to the cartridge case. This is an obstacle to reduce the cost of the cartridge engaging mechanism and the cartridge and drive device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to enhance the tolerance level of the positional error between a cartridge gear and a drive gear to be engaged with each other in a cartridge engaging mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to enhance the tolerance level of the positional error between a cartridge gear and a drive gear to be engaged with each other in a cartridge engaging mechanism while keeping a required movement stroke of a lock pad of a reel lock mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In order to attain the above object, according to the present invention, there is provided a cartridge engaging mechanism for engaging a plane-type cartridge gear secured to a reel of a tape cartridge loaded in a tape drive device with a plate-type drive gear connected to a reel motor of the tape drive device, characterized in that the cartridge gear has a tapered shape having a first inclination angle that is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach to the innermost peripheral edge, and the drive gear has a tapered shape having a second inclination angle that is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach the outermost peripheral edge, the second inclination angle being set to be smaller than the first inclination angle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, each of a face of the cartridge gear and a face of the drive gear is formed in an annular shape in a peripheral direction around a rotational center thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, the cartridge is equipped with a reel lock mechanism for preventing rotation of the reel with respect to a case of the cartridge, and the reel lock mechanism has a lock pad that is reciprocatively movable between an advance position and a retract position at a part of the face of the cartridge gear and urged toward the advance position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, the tapered shape of the drive gear is formed in an area which extends outwardly from the radially-innermost position of the drive gear at which the lock pad abuts against the drive gear under the state that the drive gear and the cartridge gear are in proper engagement with each other. In an aspect of the present invention, a width of a flat portion of each of the tooth tops of the drive gear is gradually larger in the outward direction from the radially-innermost position of the drive gear at which the lock pad abuts against the drive gear under the state that the drive gear and the cartridge gear are in proper engagement with each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, the tapered shape of the cartridge gear is formed in an area which extends inwardly from the innermost position of the lock pad in the radial direction of the cartridge gear. In an aspect of the present invention, the cartridge gear has a non-tooth portion having no tooth in an area in the neighborhood of the lock pad. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, the cartridge engaging mechanism further comprises urging means for urging the cartridge gear toward said drive gear. In an aspect of the present invention, the urging means comprises a magnet equipped to the drive gear and a magnetic member equipped to the cartridge gear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In an aspect of the present invention, a case of the tape cartridge is equipped with a positioning hole, and the tape drive device is equipped with a support pin which is inserted into the positioning hole when the cartridge gear is engaged with the drive gear to position the case to the tape drive device. In an aspect of the present invention, the support pin has such a sufficient length as to be inserted into the positioning hole before contact between the cartridge gear and the drive gear is started when the cartridge gear is engaged with the drive gear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the tolerance level of the positional displacement between the cartridge gear and the drive gear to be engaged with each other in the cartridge engaging mechanism can be enhanced by the specific shape of the teeth of the drive gear, and particularly the tolerance level of the positional displacement between the cartridge gear and the drive gear can be enhanced while keeping the required movement stroke of the lock pads of the reel lock mechanism.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional exploded front view showing the relationship between a drive device and a cartridge in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a partially enlarged view showing the relationship between the drive device and the cartridge in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a bottom view showing the cartridge in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional front view showing the cartridge in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional view showing the cartridge in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view showing a positionally displaced state of a cartridge gear from a drive gear in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in the circumferential direction at the outermost peripheral position of the drive gear in the neighborhood of the position corresponding to a lock pad in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side view showing a loading mechanism portion of the drive device in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is partially exploded perspective view showing the loading mechanism portion of the drive device in the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional exploded front view showing the relationship between the drive device and the cartridge to explain the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic partial cross-sectional view showing a drive gear and a cartridge gear of a conventional cartridge engaging mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view showing a positionally displaced state of the cartridge gear from the drive gear in the conventional cartridge engaging mechanism; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in the circumferential direction at the outermost peripheral position of the drive gear in the neighborhood of the position corresponding to a lock pad in the conventional cartridge engaging mechanism.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Preferred embodiments according to the present invention will be described hereunder with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view showing an embodiment of a cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> are shown a deck base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of a magnetic tape drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and a cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which is loaded at a predetermined position by a loading mechanism (not shown) of the magnetic tape drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is disposed a machine reel <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> for winding up a magnetic tape which is rewound and reeled out from the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> thus loaded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional exploded front view showing the relationship between the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a partially enlarged view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. A reel motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is secured to the deck base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the rotating shaft of the reel motor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the drive gear extends in the up-and-down direction. The drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is equipped with a magnet <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a yoke <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which constitute urging means for urging the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> toward the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Plural support pins <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> for positioning the case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>of the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are provided to the deck base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so as to project upwardly. The support pins <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are designed so that the upper end portion of each support pin <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> has a substantially conical shape. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a bottom diagram showing the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> are partially cross-sectional front view and partially cross-sectional view thereof. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has the case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d, </italic></highlight>a reel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>disposed in the case so as to be rotatable around the up-and-down direction, and a magnetic tape <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>wound around the reel. The case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>has a circular opening formed at the center of the lower plate portion thereof, and a cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is exposed to the outside from the opening. Positioning holes <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in which the support pins <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> are respectively fit are formed at the positions corresponding to the respective support pins <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is equipped at the lower side of the center portion of the reel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f, </italic></highlight>and the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> thereof extends in the up-and-down direction. The face of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed to be annular in the circumferential direction around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The face of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is likewise formed to be annular in the circumferential direction around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is shaped so as to be engageable with the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is equipped with three lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>disposed at an equal angular interval in the circumferential direction around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the three lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>extend upwardly while penetrating through the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and intercommunicate with a common base plate portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; in the case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight>The shape of the base plate portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; in plan is a substantially triangular shape in which the three lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are located substantially at the apexes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Further, a lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>is secured to the lower side of the center of the upper plate portion of the case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>while it is slidable in the up-and-down direction and prevented from being rotated around the up-and-down direction. The lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>is pressed downwardly by a coil spring <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i, </italic></highlight>and the center portion of the lower portion thereof abuts against the base plate portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; of the lock pads. Accordingly, the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are urged downwardly. Further, first latch gears <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j </italic></highlight>arranged in an annular shape around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are formed at the upper surface side of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and second latch gears arranged arcuately around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in an area other than the area corresponding to the triangular shape of the lock pad base plate portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; are formed at the outer peripheral portion of the lower surface of the lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>in connection with the first latch gears <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>j. </italic></highlight>Further, the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is equipped with an iron plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>serving as a magnetic member constituting the above urging means together with the magnet <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the yoke <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which is located at the position corresponding to the magnet <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the yoke <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 5</cross-reference> show a state that the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are downwardly pressed by the coil spring <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>and located at such an advance position that it is projected from the gear face. On the other hand, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a state that through the engagement with the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are pressed upwardly against the urging force of the coil spring <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i </italic></highlight>and located at a retract position. Since the lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>is upwardly pressed at the retract position, the engagement between the first and second latch gears are released (that is, the brake is released), so that the reel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>is allowed to be rotated. When the reel is rotated, the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are integrally rotated, and the center portion of the upper surface of the lock pad base plate portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>&prime; is relatively rotated to the lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>while brought into point contact with the center portion of the lower portion of the lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h. </italic></highlight>When the engagement with the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is released, the lock member <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>h </italic></highlight>and the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are downwardly moved by the urging force of the coil spring <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i, </italic></highlight>and finally the first and second latch gears are engaged with each other, so that the brake is applied. The brake is applied to only the rotation in one rotational direction corresponding to the reel-out direction of the magnetic tape <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>from the reel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f, </italic></highlight>and it is never applied to the rotation in the opposite rotational direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In an area in the neighborhood of the lock pad, the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is provided with non-tooth portions <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>which each lack three teeth of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and thus has a flat surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is designed in such a tapered shape having a first inclination angle &thgr;<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that the tooth tops of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are lowered in height as they approach to the inner peripheral edge. On the other hand, the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is designed in such a tapered shape having a second inclination angle &thgr;<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> that the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are lowered in height as they approach to the outer peripheral edge. Here, the second inclination angle &thgr;<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is smaller than the first inclination angle &thgr;<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The tapered shape of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed in an area which extends outwardly from the radially-innermost position (indicated by an arrow <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;) of the drive gear at which the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>abut against the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> under the state that the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are in proper engagement with each other. Accordingly, the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is designed so that in the area shown by the arrow <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime; the width of the flat portion of each tooth top (the dimension in the circumferential direction around the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) is gradually increased in the direction from the radially-innermost position to the outer peripheral edge. On the other hand, the tapered shape of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is formed in an area which extends inwardly from the innermost position of the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the radial direction (indicated by an arrow <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>&prime;). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Next, the operation and action of the cartridge engaging mechanism according to this embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</cross-reference> in addition to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view showing a positionally displaced state of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which may occur when the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is loaded in the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Under the positionally displaced state shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the displacement between the gear rotational centers CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is equal to S, and the positional displacement direction of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with respect to the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is coincident with the direction of one lock pad <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>relative to the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight><cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view in the circumferential direction at the outermost peripheral position of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in the neighborhood of the position corresponding to the lock pad <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>concerned in the above case. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, even when there occurs an inclination of the shaft direction of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>from the shaft direction of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the tooth tops located in the vicinity of both sides of the non-tooth portion <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>never enter the space between the adjacent teeth of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The first reason for this is as follows. Since the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is designed in the tapered shape having the second inclination angle &thgr;<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in which the tooth tops are lower in height toward the outer peripheral edge thereof, the width W of each tooth-top flat portion is largest at the outermost peripheral portion, and thus even when the displacement S between the rotational centers CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the gears is greatly large (for example, even when the displacement S is 1.7 time as large as that of the cartridge engaging mechanism described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>), the tooth tops of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>abut against the tooth-top flat portions of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Further, the second reason for this is that the tooth tops of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>first abut against the outermost peripheral portion of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> because &thgr;2&lt;&thgr;1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Therefore, even when the positioning precision of the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the positional precision of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are not so high, the tooth-top flat portions of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> have large margins for receiving the tooth tops of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>so that the relative rotation between both the gears is possible and a proper engagement can be performed after the relative rotation of a slight angle (for example, several degrees). When this engagement is made, the iron plate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>k </italic></highlight>equipped to the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is attracted to the magnet <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the yoke <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Through this proper engagement, the lock pad <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is pressed upwardly by the tooth tops of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Under this state, the inner edges of the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>nearest to the rotational center CL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> abut against the portions located at the highest position (the innermost position in the radial direction which corresponds to the start point of the arrow <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&prime;) of the teeth of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, so that the movement stroke of the lock pads <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>can be secured even when the height of the teeth is low at the outermost peripheral position of the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This engagement releases the brake of the reel lock mechanism of the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In the positioning operation of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the cartridge reel <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>to the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as described above, the support pin <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is fitted into the positioning hole <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>at the same time, thereby completing the positioning of the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>to the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the amount of the upward and downward movement when the engagement of the cartridge is made can be reduced, and thus the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be designed in compact size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Next, the cartridge loading mechanism portion constituting the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> according to this embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>. The loading mechanism portion feeds the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> inserted in the direction of an arrow X in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference> and moves it to a predetermined position at which the magnetic tape in the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be reeled out and rewound. In addition, the loading mechanism portion feeds the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> containing the rewound magnetic tape from the predetermined position in the direction of an arrow Y and moves it to a predetermined position at which the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be discharged in the direction of the arrow Y. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> A loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> which is positionally fixed with respect to the deck base <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is disposed in the loading mechanism portion, a loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is disposed inside the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and a cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is disposed inside the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a partially exploded perspective view showing the relationship of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is inserted into the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the direction of X. A pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed on one side surface of the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so as to project outwardly from the side surface of the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed in the side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a slant portion <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is designed to be higher at the front portion thereof and lower at the rear portion thereof with respect to the X direction, and a horizontal portion <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>connected to the Y-direction end of the slant portion <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight>Loader guide grooves <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are formed in the side surface of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> extends through the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a roller <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which is movable in and along the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and a roller <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which is movable in and along the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> are rotatably secured to the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. These rollers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are equipped with flanges for the spacing between the side surface of the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the spacing between the side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the side surface of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, respectively. A pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is provided to the side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> so as-to project outwardly from the side surface, and a roller <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which is movable in and along the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The relationship of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> with respect to one side surface side, and the same construction is provided at the other side surface side. However, in addition to the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; similar to the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided to the other side surface of the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so as to project outwardly as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. In connection with the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime;, a loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; similar to the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed in the other side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in addition to the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; extends through the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; and the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a roller <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&prime; which is movable in and along the loader drive groove <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; and a roller <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; which is movable in and along the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are rotatably secured to the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; in analogous manner to the case of the pin <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Further, in addition to the pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&prime; is provided to the other side surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> so as to project outwardly, and a roller <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; which is movable in and along the loader guide groove <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is rotatably secured to the pin <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&prime; as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, each of the loader guide grooves <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises a horizontal portion extending in the direction of X and a vertical portion extending downwardly substantially in the vertical direction from the X-direction end of the horizontal portion. The shapes of the loader guide grooves <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the positions of the pins <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; are set so that the rollers <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>&prime; reaches the vertical portions of the loader guide grooves <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> at the same time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> With this construction, the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be supported so as to be movable in the XY direction and the up-and-down direction perpendicular to the XY direction with respect to the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> A loader drive roller <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is secured to the top surface of the loader drive plate <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the loader drive roller <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> extends through a groove formed along the XY direction on the upper surface of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the upper side of the loader guide plate <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is equipped with an engaging member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> at the position where the engaging member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is engaged with an engaging projection <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> provided to the door <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The cartridge door <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is opened through the engagement between the engaging projection <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the engaging member <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> when the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is inserted to a predetermined position of the tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is inserted into the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the direction X manually or by using a proper handling machine and a loader drive gear <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is rotated around the up-and-down direction by driving means (not shown) to thereby move the loader drive roller <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> engaged with a cam groove formed in the loader drive gear in the X direction. In connection with this movement, the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is first moved in the X direction together with the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and then moved downwardly to a predetermined position. The downward movement of the cartridge tray <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> starts the engaging operation of the above cartridge engaging mechanism. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime; represents a machine reel motor for rotating a machine reel <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, reference numeral <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> represents a threader drive gear having outer teeth which are engaged with the loader drive gear <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> represents a threading cam. The threading cam <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a threading cam groove engaged with a pin which is equipped to a threading arm (not shown) fitted in a cam groove formed in the threader drive gear <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Thereby, by moving the pin of the threading arm along the threading cam groove, the leading edge of the magnetic tape in the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> loaded can be drawn out and guided to the machine reel <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> along a predetermined route. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a partially cross-sectional exploded front view showing the relationship between the drive device and the cartridge to explain another embodiment of the cartridge engaging mechanism according to the present invention. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the members having the same functions as those of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> are represented by the same reference numerals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> This embodiment is different from the embodiment described with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the length of the support pin <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> provided to the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. That is, the length of the support pin <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of this embodiment is set to such a sufficient value that it is inserted into the positioning hole <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>before the contact between the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is started when the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is engaged with the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The depth of the positioning hole <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>may be set to a larger value than that of the embodiment of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> According to this embodiment, the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>is first positioned to the drive device <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> when the cartridge <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is loaded. Therefore, when the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is engaged with the drive gear <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, it is sufficient to correct only the positional displacement amount of the cartridge gear with respect to the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d. </italic></highlight>Therefore, the tolerance level of the positional displacement of the cartridge gear <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with respect to the cartridge case <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>can be further enhanced, and thus the cost can be further reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiments, the magnetic tape cartridge is used as the tape cartridge, however, the same action and effect can be also achieved when the present invention is applied to tape cartridges other than the magnetic tape cartridge, for example, an optical tape cartridge or other types of tape cartridges. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A cartridge engaging mechanism for engaging a plane-type cartridge gear secured to a reel of a tape cartridge loaded in a tape drive device with a plate-type drive gear connected to a reel motor of the tape drive device, characterized in that said cartridge gear has a tapered shape having a first inclination angle that is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach to the innermost peripheral edge, and said drive gear has a tapered shape having a second inclination angle that is lower in height as the tooth tops thereof approach the outermost peripheral edge, the second inclination angle being set to be smaller than the first inclination angle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of a face of said cartridge gear and a face of said drive gear is formed in an annular shape in a peripheral direction around a rotational center thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cartridge is equipped with a reel lock mechanism for preventing rotation of said reel with respect to a case of said cartridge, and said reel lock mechanism has a lock pad that is reciprocatively movable between an advance position and a retract position at a part of the face of said cartridge gear and urged toward the advance position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tapered shape of said drive gear is formed in an area which extends outwardly from the radially-innermost position of said drive gear at which said lock pad abuts against said drive gear under the state that said drive gear and said cartridge gear are in proper engagement with each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a width of a flat portion of each of the tooth tops of said drive gear is gradually larger in the outward direction from the radially-innermost position of said drive gear at which said lock pad abuts against said drive gear under the state that said drive gear and said cartridge gear are in proper engagement with each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tapered shape of said cartridge gear is formed in an area which extends inwardly from the innermost position of said lock pad in the radial direction of said cartridge gear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cartridge gear has a non-tooth portion having no tooth in an area in the neighborhood of said lock pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising urging means for urging said cartridge gear toward said drive gear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said urging means comprises a magnet equipped to said drive gear and a magnetic member equipped to said cartridge gear. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a case of said tape cartridge is equipped with a positioning hole, and said tape drive device is equipped with a support pin which is inserted into said positioning hole when said cartridge gear is engaged with said drive gear to position said case to said tape drive device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The cartridge engaging mechanism as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said support pin has such a sufficient length as to be inserted into said positioning hole before contact between said cartridge gear and said drive gear is started when said cartridge gear is engaged with the drive gear.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001039A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
