<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000243A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000243A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000243</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10143936</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020514</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>90112039</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010518</filing-date>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F25B015/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>F25B015/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>F25B037/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>062</class>
<subclass>484000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>062</class>
<subclass>490000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>062</class>
<subclass>494000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hao</given-name>
<family-name>Pai</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hsintien City</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ru</given-name>
<middle-name>He</middle-name>
<family-name>Jan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hsintien City</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chin</given-name>
<middle-name>Hung</middle-name>
<family-name>Kuo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Hsintien City</city>
<country-code>TW</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>ROSENBERG, KLEIN &amp; LEE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3458 ELLICOTT CENTER DRIVE-SUITE 101</address-1>
<city>ELLICOTT CITY</city>
<state>MD</state>
<postalcode>21043</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure comprises a generator, a rectifier, a condenser, an evaporator, a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, and an absorber. The absorber is vertical. A spiral device is disposed in the absorber to lengthen the flow path of diluted ammonia aqueous solution, to extend the time of diluted ammonia aqueous solution in the absorber, and to expand the reaction area of diluted ammonia solution in the absorber, thereby reducing the whole weight, shrinking the volume, and enhancing the refrigerating speed. An ammonia liquid pipe and a hydrogen pipe are arranged in the evaporator. The evaporator has a simple and symmetrical shape, and can be processed and assembled easily, hence saving the space thereof. Moreover, because the ammonia liquid pipe and the hydrogen pipe are arranged in the evaporator, the effect of heat exchange thereof is better, and the refrigerating temperature is lower. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure and, more particularly, to a refrigerating structure of largely shrunk volume and reduced weight. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A conventional refrigerating circulation system of an air conditioner comprises mainly a titanium heat pipe generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a hydrogen chest <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a separator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a liquid heat exchanger <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, an absorber <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, a dehydrator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, a condenser <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, an evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, an air heat exchanger <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, a filter pipe <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, an analyzer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a U-shaped pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a fan <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and a mineral wool plate <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Ammonia aqueous solution has a high latent heat to be used as a refrigerant. Because water can absorb a large amount of ammonia at room temperature and pressure, and the absorbed ammonia will divagate from water when water is heated, water is used as an absorbent in reverse process. Moreover, hydrogen will accelerate the evaporation rate of ammonia to provide pressure equilibrium for the system. For a system achieving absorption refrigerating circulation through gravity and heat, the whole system is non-mechanical. There will be no action of revolution of compressor, not to mention sound of revolution of compressor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, heat is added to the generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to let ammonia divagate from the solution after the titanium heat pipe is electrified. The ammonia vapor at high temperature will rise along the filter pipe <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and carry part solution to enter the separator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, where the vapor and the liquid will separately flow along pipeline <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. The liquid flows into the liquid heat exchanger <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> from the pipeline <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>by gravity, and then reaches the absorber <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The vapor in the separator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> descends and diverts to the analyzer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from the central pipeline <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Because the vapor is lighter, after it rises to the dehydrator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, if there is still any water or condensed liquid, they will flow downwards to the analyzer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and then back into the generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The dehydrator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> has a plurality of annular baffle plates <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to block the vapor from carrying liquid upwards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> After passing the dehydrator <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, pure ammonia is obtained to enter the condenser <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, which is divided into a condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>has fins capable of condensing part of the vapor. Heat in the system is only utilized in upward circulation and only up to the condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Subsequent circulation relies only on gravity to let pure ammonia flow to the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the vapor not condensing at the condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>rises to the condensing pipe <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and then condenses there. The U-shaped pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> between the condenser <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is used for storing ammonia liquid. When the storage of ammonia liquid exceeds a predetermined level, the ammonia liquid will flow into the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. Because the liquid is affected by gravity, horizontal equilibrium is accomplished. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> After the liquid brims the U-shaped pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, it will flow into the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. When the ammonia liquid enters the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and forms a thin film of ammonia liquid on a series of horizontal baffle plates <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, hydrogen gas will fill into the U-shaped pipe <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to decrease the pressure of the ammonia liquid to a designed standard so that the ammonia liquid can evaporate at low temperatures. When the ammonia liquid evaporates, it will absorb heat, hence accomplishing the effect of condensation. The vapor will be discharged by the fan <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and be isolated by the mineral wool plate <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The more the hydrogen, the less the ammonia, and the lower the temperature thereof. When the ammonia liquid is evaporated and mixed with the hydrogen gas, the mixed gas will be heavier than the hydrogen gas, and will descends into the absorber <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> along an inner pipe <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the vapor heat exchanger <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Simultaneously, the hydrogen gas rising from an outer pipe <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is refrigerated. Diluted ammonia aqueous solution flowing from the separator <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via the liquid heat exchanger <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> into the top of the absorber <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will absorb ammonia vapor once contacting the mixed gas coming from the vapor heat exchanger <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. Therefore, only the hydrogen gas remains. Because the hydrogen gas is insoluble in water and is lighter, it will rise into the evaporator <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> along the outer pipe <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the vapor heat exchanger <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> to mix with the ammonia vapor again. The absorber <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> has fins <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>outside cooled by air. This will refrigerate diluted ammonia aqueous solution and enhance its capability of absorption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Simultaneously, when diluted ammonia aqueous solution absorbs ammonia vapor, it will also generate heat. Therefore, using the air-cooled fins <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>to remove heat will enhance continual circulation of the system. When the solution absorbs a large amount of ammonia vapor, it becomes concentrated ammonia aqueous solution and descends to the bottom of the absorber <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and continually descends back into the generator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> via the liquid heat exchanger <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the analyzer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to start another circulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The prior art has the following drawbacks. The pipeline of the evaporator is very long and complicated, and the vapor and liquid separator also occupy much space. Moreover, the condenser has a curved loop, which requires more space. Mutual flow between ammonia liquid, ammonia vapor, and hydrogen gas in the evaporator affects the whole stability, and requires a very long pipeline, which is very uneconomic. Furthermore, the vapor heat exchanger, the liquid heat exchanger, and the absorber also have very long pipelines, respectively, hence increasing the flow path of pipeline and the whole volume. Therefore, the prior art has a very large volume, which cannot be reduced. The present invention aims to resolve the above problems in the prior art. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> One object of the present invention is to provide an absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure, wherein a capillary device is arranged in a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank to increase the surface of absorption reaction for enhancing extra absorption reaction. The absorber is vertical. The absorber has a spiral device therein to lengthen the flow path of diluted ammonia aqueous solution, to extend the time of diluted ammonia aqueous solution in the absorber, and to expand the reaction surface area of diluted ammonia aqueous solution in the absorber, hence reducing the whole weight, shrinking the volume, simultaneously increasing the refrigerating speed, and simplifying the shape and structure of the evaporator. An ammonia liquid pipe and a hydrogen pipe are arranged in the evaporator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The evaporator has a simple and symmetrical shape, and can be processed and assembled easily, hence saving the space thereof. Moreover, because the ammonia liquid pipe and the hydrogen pipe penetrate into the evaporator, the heat exchange thereof is better, the refrigerating temperature is lower, hence further reducing the system weight and shrinking the volume. Therefore, the present invention can produce smaller refrigerating structures with better operational characteristics, letting portable refrigerating structures be feasible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The structure of the present invention has a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank to receive concentrated ammonia aqueous solution. The concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank is led out via a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe to penetrate into a diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe to perform heat exchange. The diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe passes through a generator, which joins a heater outside. After being heated, ammonia in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe evaporates to be separated out, and mixed vapor and liquid bubble flow of diluted ammonia aqueous solution and ammonia vapor passes through a separator and then rises to a pipeline of a rectifier. The diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflows from the separator, through the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe to be near the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, and is then guided to an absorber via a diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe. Water steam condenses into water in the rectifier and reflows to the separator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The ammonia vapor enters a condenser pipeline and condenses into ammonia liquid, which is then guided by an ammonia liquid pipe to penetrate into an evaporator pipeline. The absorber pipeline is connected with the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank to let concentrated ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas pass through the absorber. At this time, the concentrated ammonia vapor reacts with the reflowing diluted ammonia aqueous solution to become concentrated ammonia aqueous solution, which then reflows to the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank. Diluted ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas pass through an airway to the hydrogen pipe. The distal end of the airway is connected to the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank via a condensing ammonia liquid guide pipe. The hydrogen pipe penetrates into one end of the evaporator pipeline. Ammonia liquid and hydrogen gas are simultaneously released out from the other closed end of the evaporator pipeline to let the ammonia liquid evaporate and absorb heat, hence performing the reaction of heat exchange to absorb heat and refrigerate. The mixed gas of generated ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas will together flow back into the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank via a guide-in pipe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The various objects and advantages of the present invention will be more readily understood from the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the appended drawing, in which:</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the arrangement of the prior art pipeline; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a longitudinal cross-sectional view of an evaporator of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a lateral cross-sectional view of an evaporator of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partly enlarged view of the part A shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a lateral cross-sectional view of a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a position diagram of the test points of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows measurement graphs of part of the test points of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the present invention provides an absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure having a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> to receive concentrated ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is led out by a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A pipe mouth <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is situated in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and protrudes out to prevent residue from entering the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Residue will accumulate on the bottom face of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and will not choke the pipe mouth <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can also be connected out from the end face of a horizontal pipe type concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> penetrates into a diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, which passes through a generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The inserted end of the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is closed. The generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> joins a heater <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> outside to heat the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Part surface of the generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is sheathed by a constricting tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and an adiabatic body <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The adiabatic body is situated outside the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The constricting tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is situated outside the adiabatic body <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> capillary device <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> can be added in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Part of the capillary device <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> is situated below the liquid face to absorb the liquid, preventing the liquid face in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> from generating jolts. The capillary device <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> is porous. Part of the capillary device <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> is situated above the liquid face to absorb liquid, letting part ammonia of passing vapor be absorbed. That is, the surface of absorption reaction can be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The heater <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> heats ammonia aqueous solution in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to separate out ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and generate vapor and liquid mixed bubble flow of diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The mixed bubble flow in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> further includes the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and water steam <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. They together rise to a pipeline of a rectifier <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> through a separator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> flows out from a separator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, i.e., the distal end of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, reflows vertically downwards from the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> through the action of gravity, passed through the generator <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and then reflows to near the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> along the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> An enlarged pipe or the periphery of the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> joins a diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, which is connected to an absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The distal end of the diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is lower than the separator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> so that the diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> can naturally flow back into the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> through the action of gravity. The outer surface of the distal end of the diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> can have a plurality of dissipating fins <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> to cool the diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in advance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The pipeline at the rectifier <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> forms a curved pipe shape. Because the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> in this section also contains water steam <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, which is detrimental to the reaction of evaporation, the pipeline of the rectifier <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is used to refrigerate the water steam <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and the ammonia <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> to let the water steam <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> condense into water liquid <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and part of the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> condense into ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which then reflow to the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> along the rectifier <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> High purity ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> enters a condenser <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which comprises a first pipeline <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of condenser and a second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of condenser. A plurality of first fins <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and second fins <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are disposed outside the first pipeline <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of condenser and the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of condenser, respectively. An adapting block <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of condenser is connected between the two pipelines <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to save the occupied space. The first fins <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and the second fins <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> are respectively disposed on the first pipeline <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> to more quickly condense the pure ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> into the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Because the pipelines <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are slantingly disposed and are of reflected shape, the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> will flow to the distal end of the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The distal end of the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> joins a first ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The front section of the first ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> has a plurality of third fins <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to enhance refrigerating effect. The first ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> then penetrates into a pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of an evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> via a second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> A liquid-shutting loop is formed between two ends of the ammonia liquid pipe comprising the first ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> and the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The liquid-shutting loop can be U-shaped or spiral. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the whole ammonia liquid pipe is U-shaped to directly form a liquid-shutting loop. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the other end of the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> is open. The open end is of downwards curved shape to form a outflow mouth for guidance, hence guiding out ammonia liquid and preventing ammonia liquid from creeping on the outer pipe wall of the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Therefore, the outflow ammonia liquid will expand so that the refrigerating capability will not be affected because the ammonia liquid pipe is arranged in the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> After the first ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> passes through a bearing block <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> is contained in the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. In fact, the first ammonia liquid pipeline <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> and the second ammonia liquid pipeline <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> are the same pipeline. Similarly, the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, the pipeline of the rectifier <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the first pipeline <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of condenser, and the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of condenser are the same pipeline. These designs can facilitate manufacturing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> One end of the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> joins the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has the reflowing diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> therein. The absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> has a plurality of absorber fins <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> outside. The inner wall of the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> has a wick spiral device <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> so that the diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> can go around downwards along the inner peripheral wall of the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. Mixed gas formed of hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> and ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> flowing in from the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> exists above the liquid face in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> When the mixed gas passes by the liquid face of concentrated ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, it performs a first absorption reaction to absorb the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> from the mix gas to the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The mixed gas is then guided into the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to perform a second absorption reaction. The ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> enters the pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> of the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and reacts with the diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> to become gradually into the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, which then reflows to the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> along the wick spiral device <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In addition, a pressing region <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is formed near the other end of the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The pressing region <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is situated above the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and the diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The pressing region <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> utilizes gravity to press the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> flowing into the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The other end of the absorber pipeline <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> joins an absorber guide block <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, which is connected with an airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> has a plurality of refrigerating fins <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> outside to further cool not wholly absorbed ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> into the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the absorber is of vertical pipe type, but it can also be replaced with a coiled pipe type absorber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Because the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is bent downwards, after the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> of the mix gas are absorbed by the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, part of the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and the reflowing diluted ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> will react in the absorber <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to become the reflowing concentrated ammonia aqueous solution <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, hence further reducing the amount of ammonia vapor in the mixed gas. The diluted mixed gas of the diluted ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and the hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> then flows through the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. Because the distal end of the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is largely pure hydrogen <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> joins an upward hydrogen pipe <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> to guide the hydrogen <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> upwards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The distal end of the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is connected to the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> via an ammonia liquid guide pipe <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The ammonia liquid guide pipe <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> can have a capillary device <highlight><bold>481</bold></highlight> to avoid liquid-shutting phenomenon due to a too-small caliber or condensation and to prevent condensing ammonia liquid from accumulating in the ammonia liquid guide pipe <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The other end of the ammonia liquid guide pipe <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to a position below the liquid face of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The hydrogen pipe <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> also passes through the bearing block <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> to penetrate into the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference>, the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is simultaneously abreast of the hydrogen pipe <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> and the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The hydrogen pipe <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> has a capillary device <highlight><bold>491</bold></highlight> of hydrogen pipe to prevent liquid-shutting phenomenon. The pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> can be of bent sideward-U shape. The hydrogen pipe <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> and the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> form exits near inside the other end of the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to simultaneously release the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Therefore, the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and the hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> can perform evaporation reaction of heat exchange to absorb heat and refrigerate. After being evaporated, the generated mixed gas of the ammonia vapor <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> and the hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> will reflow together from the other end to be near one end of the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> along the internal space of the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is connected to a guide-in pipe <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to let the concentrated ammonia <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> and the hydrogen gas <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> be discharged into the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> via the guide-in pipe <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The other end of the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is not higher than the distal end of the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, and forms a U-shaped connected pipe to let the ammonia liquid <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> flow naturally through the action of gravity and flow out from the other end of the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The speed of heat exchange at this position is high to facilitate the outflow of the ammonia liquid. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the distal end of the second ammonia liquid pipe <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> has a capillary device <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of evaporator to achieve very better effect of guidance. Simultaneously, the capillary device <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of evaporator is utilized to expand the evaporation area of ammonia liquid to facilitate evaporation of ammonia liquid into ammonia vapor, hence enhancing the refrigerating efficiency and speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Through the help of forward guidance, the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> of the present invention can achieve very fast heat exchange. A pressure equilibrium pipe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> can further be disposed between the top face of the distal end of the second pipeline <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of the condenser <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the top face of the bent section of the airway <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> to achieve equilibrium of pressure of the system. Furthermore, a capillary device <highlight><bold>651</bold></highlight> can be disposed in the pressure equilibrium pipe <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to avoid liquid shutting phenomenon due to condensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Additionally, a spiral device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of evaporator is disposed on the inner pipe wall of the pipeline <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of the evaporator <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The spiral device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is a spiral groove or concentrically circular grooves formed on the inner pipe wall, a spiral spring or fiber bundles arranged therein, or a capillary device, all of which can facilitate the expansion of the liquid face of ammonia liquid and thus enhance the refrigerating performance. The capillary device is made of knitted net, sintered powder, fiber bundle, or foaming metal. The above spiral device <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> of absorber can be similar to or the same as the spiral device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> of evaporator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Therefore, all of the capillary device of the pressure equilibrium pipe, the capillary device of the hydrogen pipe, the capillary device of the evaporator, the capillary device of the spiral device of evaporator, the capillary device of the spiral device of absorber, and the capillary device of the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank are made of any one or any combination of knitted net, fiber bundle, sintered powder, and foaming metal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiment, fins are utilized for heat radiation on the outer surface of the condenser and the absorber. The main function of the fins is to generate heat exchange. Therefore, heat exchangers can be disposed outside the condenser and the absorber, respectively. The heat exchanger comprises the above sheet heat-radiating fins and an integrally formed heat radiator or cooling water sleeve. For an embodiment of the present invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a position diagram of test points, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows measurement graphs of part of the test points of the present invention, and Table 1 shows test temperatures of the test points. The ammonia aqueous solution has a weight percentage of 25%. The pressure of filled-in hydrogen is 15 kgf/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. The average room temperature is 24.9&deg; C. A heater of 110VAC and 45W is used. Both the generator and the evaporator are sheathed by ceramic cotton.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>All the set positions</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Test point</entry>
<entry>Temperature &deg; C.</entry>
<entry>are on the outer surface</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>65.4</entry>
<entry>initial point of the concentrated</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ammonia aqueous solution pipe</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>122.8</entry>
<entry>middle point of the concentrated</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>ammonia aqueous solution pipe</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>191.8</entry>
<entry>initial point of the generator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>188.4</entry>
<entry>middle point of the generator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>167.2</entry>
<entry>final point of the generator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>157.9</entry>
<entry>the vapor and liquid separator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>104.8</entry>
<entry>initial point of the condenser</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>41.8</entry>
<entry>final point of the condenser</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>41.6</entry>
<entry>final point of the diluted ammonia</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>aqueous solution reflow pipe</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>47.3</entry>
<entry>initial point of the absorber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
<entry>51.4</entry>
<entry>middle point of the absorber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>55.2</entry>
<entry>final point of the absorber</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>44.8</entry>
<entry>above the liquid face of the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>concentrated ammonia aqueous</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>solution tank</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>14</entry>
<entry>44.4</entry>
<entry>below the liquid face of the</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>concentrated ammonia aqueous</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>solution tank</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>15</entry>
<entry>&minus;29.9</entry>
<entry>initial point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>&minus;29.1</entry>
<entry>second point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>17</entry>
<entry>&minus;28.4</entry>
<entry>third point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>&minus;26.5</entry>
<entry>fourth point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>19</entry>
<entry>&minus;24.0</entry>
<entry>fifth point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>&minus;19.2</entry>
<entry>sixth point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>21</entry>
<entry>&minus;0.2</entry>
<entry>seventh point of reaction in the evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>22</entry>
<entry>10.0</entry>
<entry>final point of reaction in evaporator</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> From the above measurements matched with the graphs in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, for a 3-hour measurement, operation of equilibrium is approached at about 15 minutes. Therefore, the present invention exactly can quickly achieve the effect of operation. Moreover, about half of the volume can be shrunk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The present invention utilizes a twin-bushing structure at the generator to generate vapor and to further guide the separation of vapor and liquid. Usage of space is enhanced. Moreover, energy for heating the reflowing diluted ammonia aqueous solution is used again to heat the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe, hence lessening the burden of the heater. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the condenser disposed forwards down is different from the prior art coiled pipe type. A thicker pipeline is connected to the diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe to facilitate manufacturing and flow of liquid and vapor in the pipeline. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The condensed ammonia liquid is guided into the pipeline of the evaporator in special way. A common pipe type evaporator is used to let the condensed ammonia liquid and hydrogen be guided into the evaporator together. Moreover, the open end of the ammonia liquid pipe has a capillary device and forms a curved shape to facilitate the action of guidance. In other words, the capillary device is used to guide the expansion of the ammonia liquid and to prevent the ammonia liquid from only creeping along the outer surface of the ammonia liquid pipe. The disposition of the capillary device can greatly improve the cold status of evaporation. Furthermore, a spiral device for resisting flow and expanding the surface area of evaporation of the ammonia liquid is disposed in the pipeline of the evaporator. Therefore, the present invention can use the most economic pipeline of the evaporator to form the best flow path. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Additionally, there is no independent hydrogen chest structure in the present invention. Appropriate quantity of hydrogen is filled into the system loop for circulatory flow. The concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank also facilitates the flow of ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas, and is a storage space of ammonia aqueous solution. Moreover, a capillary device is disposed in the concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank to absorb ammonia aqueous solution and to also provide larger absorption reaction area of ammonia aqueous solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A vertical absorber is used so that the absorber can generate concentrated ammonia aqueous solution with a special structure. The path is very short, totally different from the prior art long coiled pipe type. Therefore, the present invention can utilize the most economic pipeline to form the best flow path, thereby greatly shrinking the whole structure, generating better action of heat exchange, reducing the volume and weight of the refrigerating structure, and obtaining better refrigerating effect as compared to the prior art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described with reference to the preferred embodiment thereof, it will be understood that the invention is not limited to the details thereof. Various substitutions and modifications have been suggested in the foregoing description, and other will occur to those of ordinary skill in the art. Therefore, all such substitutions and modifications are intended to be embraced within the scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure, comprising: 
<claim-text>a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank for receiving concentrated ammonia aqueous solution; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe for guiding out concentrated ammonia aqueous solution from said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, the other end of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pips being an opening; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe sleeved outside said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe and passing across the other end of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a generator having a heater, said heater abutting on said diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe so that said diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe can conduct heat to said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe to let said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe generate vapor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a separator for separating vapor and liquid, said separator being formed between the open end of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe and said diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a rectifier connected with said diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe to let part of the vapor leaving said separator condense into liquid and then flow back; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a condenser connected with said rectifier to let vapor condense into liquid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an ammonia liquid pipe, one end thereof being joined at the distal end of said condenser, and the other end thereof being an opening, a liquid-shutting loop forming between the two ends of said ammonia liquid pipe; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe led out from said diluted ammonia aqueous solution pipe near said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an absorber, the lower end thereof being connected with said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank and said diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe, the joining position of said absorber with said diluted ammonia aqueous solution reflow pipe being lower than said opening of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe in said separator, said absorber being used to let diluted ammonia aqueous solution react to become into concentrated ammonia aqueous solution, said absorber being connected with an airway, said airway being disposed downwards, ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas passing through said absorber entering said airway to let ammonia vapor condense into ammonia liquid, said airway being connected with an ammonia liquid guide pipe, the other end of said ammonia liquid guide pipe being connected to a region below the liquid face of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a hydrogen pipe, one end thereof being connected to the other end of said airway and disposed upwards, the other end thereof being an opening; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an evaporator having a pipeline, the upper end of said pipeline being closed, the lower end of said pipeline being connected with said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, the rear section of said hydrogen pipe and said ammonia liquid pipe being inserted into said pipeline of said evaporator from near the lower end and extending to the closed end along said pipeline, the open end of said ammonia liquid pipe being lower than the position where said ammonia liquid pipe joins the distal end of said condenser, ammonia liquid and hydrogen gas being simultaneously released out from the closed end of said evaporator to let ammonia liquid absorb heat and perform reaction of heat exchange, the generated ammonia vapor and hydrogen gas then flowing back to be discharged into said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a pipe mouth of said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution pipe is situated in said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, and protrudes out to prevent residue flowing into said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank from choking said pipe mouth. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a pressure equilibrium pipe is further disposed between said condenser pipeline and said airway. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a capillary device is further disposed in said pressure equilibrium pipe to avoid liquid-shutting phenomenon due to condensation, said capillary device being made of knitted net, fiber bundle, sintered powder, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said liquid-shutting loop of said ammonia liquid pipe is U-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said absorber is of coiled pipe type. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said absorber is of vertical pipe type. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a spiral device of absorber is further disposed in said absorber to guide the flow of diluted ammonia aqueous solution. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spiral device of absorber is a spiral groove, concentric grooves, a spiral spring, or a spiral fiber bundle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spiral device of absorber is a capillary device, and said capillary device is made of knitted net, sintered powder, fiber bundle, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a capillary device is further disposed between said ammonia liquid guide pipe and said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank to prevent condensed ammonia liquid from accumulating in said ammonia liquid guide pipe. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a capillary device is further disposed in said hydrogen pipe to avoid liquid-shutting phenomenon, and said capillary device is made of knitted net, sintered powder, fiber buddle, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a capillary device is further disposed in said evaporator pipeline, said capillary device being situated at the open end of said ammonia liquid pipe to let ammonia liquid steadily flow out and to facilitate the expansion of the liquid face, said capillary device being made of knitted net, sintered powder, fiber bundle, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a spiral device of evaporator is further disposed in said evaporator pipeline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spiral device of evaporator is a spiral groove, concentric grooves, a spiral spring, or a spiral fiber bundle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said spiral device of evaporator is a capillary device, and said capillary device is made of knitted net, sintered powder, fiber bundle, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a capillary device is further disposed in said concentrated ammonia aqueous solution tank, and said capillary device is made of porous knitted net, sintered powder, fiber bundle, or foaming metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein part of said capillary device is above the liquid face, while the other part thereof is below the liquid face. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein heat exchangers are further disposed outside said condenser and said absorber, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The absorption diffusion type refrigerating structure as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said heat exchanger is a heat radiator, heat-radiating fins, or a cooling water sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030000243A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
