<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001221A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001221A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001221</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10066851</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020204</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>1 01 04 868.8-33</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010203</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L029/82</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>417000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Micromechanical component as well as a method for producing a micromechanical component</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frank</given-name>
<family-name>Fischer</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gomaringen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Peter</given-name>
<family-name>Hein</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Reutlingen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Eckhard</given-name>
<family-name>Graf</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Gomaringen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KENYON &amp; KENYON</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>ONE BROADWAY</address-1>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A micromechanical component having a substrate beneath at least one structured layer, in the structured layer at least one functional structure being formed, a cap which covers the functional structure, between the cap and the functional structure at least one cavity being formed, and a connecting layer which connects the cap to structured layer, as well as a method for producing the micromechanical component. To obtain a compact and robust component, the connecting layer is formed from an anodically bondable glass, i.e. a bond glass, which has a thickness in the range of 300 nm to 100 &mgr;m, which may in particular be in the range of 300 nm to 50 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a micromechanical component, and a method for producing a micromechanical component. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> German Published Patent Application No. 195 37 814 describes the construction of a sensor layer system and a method for the hermetic encapsulation of sensors in surface micromechanics. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A cost-effectively produced compact and long-term stable micromechanical component characterized by a robust layer construction and by a clear reduction of the area needed for the encapsulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The present invention concerns a cap that covers functional structures, the cap being connected with the structured layer with the aid of an anodically bondable glass or a bond glass. According to one exemplary embodiment and/or exemplary method of the present invention, the connecting layer may be formed by the anodically bondable glass having a thickness in the range of 300 nm to 100 &mgr;m, especially a thickness in the range of 300 nm to 50 &mgr;m. By the use of the anodically bondable glass, a mechanically stable connection may be produced in a simple manner between the cap and the structured layer using a small connecting area. A considerable savings in area or a considerably improved wafer utilization may be achieved, particularly in mass production where the micromechanical component may be formed more than one thousandfold on one wafer or substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> According to another exemplary embodiment and/or exemplary method according to the present invention, by choosing an anodically bondable glass having a thickness in the range of 300 nm to 100 &mgr;m, or especially making it from a thicker glass wafer, one may cut the micromechanical components formed on a wafer into single pieces, using one single saw cut through the entire layer construction of the micromechanical component. This is possible because a customary saw blade for cutting out micromechanical components from the wafer may also cut through the anodically bondable glass of the noted thickness without damaging the saw blade or the component. Without the present invention, it may be necessary to make a saw cut down to the connecting layer using a first saw blade, to cut through the connecting layer using a second saw blade, and after that, to cut completely through the micromechanical component, or rather cut it into individual pieces, using the first saw blade again. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> According to another exemplary embodiment and/or exemplary method of the present invention, a bond glass may be used, which has a specified ion concentration so as to be anodically bondable. Glasses which may be used as bond glasses include ones which have alkali silicate and/or borosilicate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to yet another exemplary embodiment and/or exemplary method of the present invention, a terminal area may be provided for external contacting of the functional structures in the substrate of the micromechanical component. The terminal area may be electrically insulated from the substrate by an insulating frame formed by trenches. The terminal area may be provided directly next to or even under a supporting element in the substrate, in order to minimize, especially for reasons of cost, the substrate area or volume required for the micromechanical component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> External contacting of the functional structures is achieved via a funnel-shaped opening, provided in the cap, which expands away from the functional structures. In such an external contacting, the sawing sludge created during sawing, or rather the cutting into individual pieces of the micromechanical components from the wafer, may get into the funnel-shaped access opening. Considerable effort may be needed to clean the funnel-shaped access opening of the sawing sludge. Any remains of sawing sludge that are not washed out may lead to shunting, which may lead to the malfunctioning of the respective micromechanical component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> By dint of the terminal area for the external contacting of the functional structures being created in an exemplary manner according to the present invention in the substrate, a method of plasma etching or trench etching may be used, particularly with a substrate thickness in the range of ca 80 &mgr;m to 150 &mgr;m, for example, ca 80 &mgr;m to 100 &mgr;m. Hereby, narrow, deep trenches may be produced for the formation of an insulating frame, which may extend largely perpendicularly from the underside of the substrate up to the functional layer. Selection of the substrate&apos;s thickness may be oriented to the required stability of the micromechanical component and to the maximum possible depth of the trenches, down to which narrow trenches may be produced, for example, by trench etching. These trenches, or rather the insulating frame formed by the trenches, may be closed by a dielectric in the area on the underside of the substrate, which electrically insulates the terminal area from the substrate while forming a part of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to another exemplary embodiment and/or exemplary method of the present invention, a blind hole may be formed by etching, which proceeds largely vertically through the substrate, the structured layer, and the connecting layer right up to the cap, where the floor of the blind hole is in the region of the cap, and the opening of the blind hole is on the side of the substrate opposite the functional structures. The blind hole or the passage at its floor area and on its wall areas may be provided with a conducting layer, so that an electrical connection may be made between the cap, the structured layer, and the substrate. The blind hole or the passage may be completely filled with a filler layer after production of the conducting layer. By putting the conducting layer at a definite electrical potential, at ground for example, potential differences between the cap, the structured layer, and the substrate, and thus, potential interference voltages, may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> If the mechanical stability of the micromechanical component is not sufficient, at least one supporting element may be provided between the substrate and the cap, the supporting element may be formed by etching of the functional layer, and may be largely at the center of the cavity covered by the cap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> An exemplary method according to the present invention may be used to produce a micromechanical component in which the structured layer, which has functional structures, may be connected to a cap via a connecting layer. The material of the connecting layer may be selected in such a way that chemical bonding is brought about, by the application of an electrical voltage between the substrate and the cap of the micromechanical component, between the connecting layer and the structured layer, as well as between the connecting layer and the cap where a bond may be formed at the edge region of the cavity formed between the cap and the functional structures (anodic bonding). For this, at least the bonding region may be heated. The bonding of the cap and the side of the bonding layer facing the cap may take place in a first step, and the bonding between the structured layer and the side of the connecting layer facing the structured layer may take place in a second step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The bonding locations may be pretreated chemically and/or mechanically before anodic bonding in such a way that they have a slight surface roughness quantifiable as approximately 40 nm or less. Finally, the component may posses a low topography, whereby, for example, the component may be installed using the so-called flip-chip technique.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DIAGRAMS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a cross section of an exemplary embodiment of a component according to the present invention having a substrate, a structured layer, and a cap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 10</cross-reference> show an exemplary method according to the present invention for producing the component illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an exemplary embodiment of a component according to the present invention, such as an acceleration sensor, in cross section. A structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, in which functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and supporting structures are formed, is positioned on a substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary embodiment, the functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are formed in the structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> as meshing combs or interdigital structures having fixed and deflectable electrodes. The supporting structures are formed by a frame <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, which surrounds functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and a supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, which is positioned inside frame <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> in the area of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and may contribute to the mechanical stability of the layer system. In the exemplary embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, only a supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is illustrated, which is positioned between the two functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> shown. However, depending on the required mechanical stability of the component, provision may also be made, in the region of the functional structures, for no supporting element, a single supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, or a plurality of supporting elements spaced at a distance from one another. Expediently, the supporting element or supporting elements may be positioned in such a way that the freedom of motion of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is not impaired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> An approximately planar cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> via a connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and overlaps functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are developed raised in comparison with functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> (cf <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>), and project above functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, for example, by about 4-10 &mgr;m, so that cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>form in the region of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, or open up between functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Alternatively or supplementary to the exemplary embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> depression may be provided in the region of the functional structures on the underside of the cap, i.e. on the side of the cap facing functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, so that the depression forms the cavity or cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>above functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in whole or in part (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is removed in the region of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, so that the height of the gap H of cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>becomes correspondingly greater. Expediently, the height of the gap H of cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be such that a destructive deflection of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in the vertical direction, i.e. in the z direction, is prevented. The total gap range of cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>in the lateral direction may lie between about 100 and 500 &mgr;m. However, gap widths up to several mm are also possible. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> At first ends <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, of supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and of frame <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, associated with cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, connecting areas <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for connecting <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are formed. Connecting areas <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may have a width of less than 150 &mgr;m and a high surface quality or rather, a low surface roughness, which may amount to approximately 40 nm or less. Supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and frame <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are connected at their other ends <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>to substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Between substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are provided which may be used for the external contacting of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are placed closely underneath functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> run through duct areas <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, two sacrificial layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) insulating printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> from supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In addition, for external contacting of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, a terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is formed in substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, for the most part directly next to functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, which is located at upper side <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> facing structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, in direct contact with contact reed <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is completely surrounded by trenches <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which form an insulating frame. Trenches <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>extend from the substrate&apos;s underside to the substrate&apos;s upper side, so that terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed thereby may be electrically insulated from substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Trenches <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may have a high aspect ratio, i.e. great depth and a slight lateral dimension size. A metallic coating <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is applied to terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on its backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> facing away from structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, which may form a printed circuit trace and a contact pad for fastening bonding wire, via which an external electrical connection to functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is produced. Metallic coating <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is insulated from substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by a dialectric layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Metal coating <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and thus the printed circuit trace and the contact pad may extend from terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> horizontally in the direction of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, whereby the wafer area and substrate area, respectively, required for the production of the component may be reduced in a cost-saving manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to one exemplary embodiment (not shown), terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for external contacting of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> may be produced largely centrically below supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. This may lead to savings in wafer area and substrate area required for producing the component, which is consistent with a cost-saving reduction in volume of the component. Packing density may also be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, between substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, a conductive connection <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is provided, in order to avoid differences in potential between the substrate and cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Conductive connection <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> includes a blind hole or rather, a passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, which extends outside the region of printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> through substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, frame <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and into a part of cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A conductive layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, for example a metallic layer, which is positioned on the bottom and the wall surfaces <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, connects substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A filler layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> closes passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> on the backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and evens out the topography. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 10</cross-reference> describe an exemplary method for producing the component illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The layer construction of the component is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> as it looks before the depth structuring of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. On substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, which may be made of monocrystalline silicon, a first sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is applied which may be made, for instance, of one or more SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>layers. On first sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are deposited, made of polycrystalline silicon, which may be sufficiently strongly doped for the purpose of achieving as high as possible a conductivity. First sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is prestructured before the application of the printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a contact opening for correspondingly formed contact reed <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> being etched into first sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for each of the printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Each of contact reeds <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> borders directly on substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and is directly connected to terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> formed later in each case in substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The production of the terminal areas described and their respective external contacting (not illustrated) may be carried out in the same way as the production and external contacting of the explicitly illustrated terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A second sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, similarly made of of SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, is deposited on printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and functions as an insulating layer. CVD &lsqb;chemical vapor deposition&rsqb; methods may be used for the production of the second sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, such as when using tetraethyl orthosilicate (TEOS). Then, on second sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, a thin polysilicon starter layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is deposited, i.e. a polycrystalline silicon layer having the function of a seeding or nucleating layer. On starting polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>a polycrystalline silicon layer, which represents the subsequently formed structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, is deposited, using an epitaxial method, the starting polycrystalline layer merging into the upper polycrystalline layer. The surface of upper polycrystalline layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is leveled in a further process step. A chemical-mechanical polishing process (CMP) may be used to achieve a surface roughness which allows the surfaces to connect or anodically bond well with connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by the application of a voltage difference. The surface roughness in this case may amount to ca 2 nm to ca 50 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Sacrificial layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are expediently structured before the deposition of starting polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In this case, first and second sacrificial layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are partially or completely removed in regions <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, in which supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are formed in a later process step, so that supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are directly connected to the substrate. In second sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, contact openings <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are formed for contacting functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> to printed circuit traces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, an oxide mask <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is deposited on connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> by a CVD method, connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> being located in the area of supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> which are formed later. Oxide mask <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, precipitated from the gas phase, is used as a passivating layer on account of its good Si/SiO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>selectivity, and ensures that connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are not attacked by a later plasma etching step or a chemical-mechanical polishing process (CMP). Using a dry etching method or an additional CMP step, planar recesses are etched or formed in regions <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, in which functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are structured later. Oxide mask <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is subsequently removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Alternatively or in supplement to the exemplary method of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, one or more recesses (not illustrated) may be produced at the underside of the cap, for the complete or partial formation of the cavity above the functional structures, for example, by plasma etching. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In the exemplary process step described above, supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are prestructured opposite functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, with respect to their height (and possibly with respect to their width), by thinning structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the areas of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> by a specified quantity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, in order to make supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> higher, a connecting layer may be used having a correspondingly greater thickness dimension (case not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> If one or more recesses may be provided at the underside of the cap, they may be structured in such a way that the recess(es) has(have) one or more supporting elements, which complement(s) one or more supporting elements of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> (not illustrated). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In a further exemplary process step shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and supporting element <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are structured using trench etching. Second sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and in part also first sacrificial layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are removed below functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> using a gas phase etching method, so that deflectable structures are created. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The hermetically sealed encapsulation of the component or rather, the sensor layer system, is performed in an exemplary central step, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which may be made of monocrystalline silicon, is here chemically bonded to connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of supporting structures <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, via connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be made of a silicate glass about 10-50 &mgr;m thick, which may be produced by chemical and/or mechanical treatment from a thicker silicate glass wafer, for example, 500 &mgr;m in thickness. The silicate glass has a specified concentration of monovalent or higher-valent cations, such as Na<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> or B<highlight><superscript>3&plus;</superscript></highlight>, and a corresponding concentration of weakly bound oxygen atoms. Alkali silicates and borosilicates may be particularly suitable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In order to be able to produce a high surface quality for the purpose of an optimum joint between cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is chemically-mechanically polished on its side facing connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. After the CMP step, the surface roughness is typically under 2 nm. Then, cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected in a planar manner to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by the application of a voltage difference between the cap and connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, typically ca &minus;150 to&minus;1000 V, cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> being grounded. During the connecting step, a raised temperature of about 350-450&deg; C. may additionally act on connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in order to increase the mobility of the metal or boron cations. The reduced cation concentration may be compensated for by a supplementary temperature action. Alternatively or in supplement, after connecting cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the supply voltage is reversed so as to compensate for the reduced concentration of cations that has been created at the boundary between connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be deposited on cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in fused form, the melting or softening temperature, respectively, being in a range of 600-800&deg; C., depending on the kind of silicate glass used. At this temperature range, chemical bonding between cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may also take place. After solidification, connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be processed as described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> After the bonding of cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is ground down roughly mechanically, or rather thinned down according to the above first or second alternative on the side facing connecting surface <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and is subsequently polished in a CMP step in order to produce a good joint with connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> After this processing, connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a thickness of about 10-50 &mgr;m, and a surface roughness of 2 nm or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the Connecting layer may be deposited by sputtering of silicate glass, particularly using electron beam sputtering. Before that, the cap is oxidized thermally, whereby a ca 1 to 2 &mgr;m layer of silicon oxide layer is formed on which the connecting layer is deposited by sputtering. The silicon oxide layer improves the electrical voltage resistance during anodic bonding. For a connecting layer (alkali or borosilicate) formed by sputtering, layer thicknesses may be in the range of about 300 nm to 2 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is removed in the area of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in all three alternatives recited above, or is structured so as to increase the size of gap height H of cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is also removed in the region of connecting passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, formed later, of conductive connection <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In a further process step, the bonding of connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> takes place. Connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are adjusted to each other and chemically connected (anodic bonding) by the supply voltage applied and/or under the action of temperature. For this step, a lower voltage is applied to cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> compared to that of the bonding of cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, to prevent excessive deflection of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> as a result of the bonding voltage. Typically, this may be &minus;100 V at cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> being grounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> During the encapsulation, a gas having a pressure between <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> mbar and 1 bar may be enclosed in cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the damping of functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>&apos;s movement being determined by the pressure. In a supplementary way, after encapsulation, a liquid may also be conveyed into cavities <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>via an opening that may be closed again, its viscosity determining the degree of the damping, or also a gas, or even a further gas. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The basic doping Of n-doped substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be typically greater than 5&starf;10<highlight><superscript>15</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, and the ohmic resistance less than ca 1 Ohm&starf;cm (low-resistance). The doping of n-doped function layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is approximately 10<highlight><superscript>17</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>19</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, which makes possible a low-resistance external contact to functional structures <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Using the anodic bonding method described above, a hermetically sealed connection is produced, on the one hand, between cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and, on the other hand, between connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In this manner, relatively small connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are needed. For example, the width of the connecting surfaces is only about 30 to 150 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> After the connection of cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to connecting surfaces <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, there follows mechanical grinding back of backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (cf <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). This may take place in several steps: First backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is ground down coarsely abrasively, using a diamond grinding disk of large grain size, and subsequently using a diamond grinding disk of smaller grain size having correspondingly less material removal. Alternatively, the grinding down may also be performed in a single step. After finishing, the surface roughness amounts to about 0.1-1 &mgr;m, and the depth of crystal dislocation comes to about 3-5 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The crystal dislocations are removed by a CMP process and the surface quality is thereby further improved. The material removal here amounts to about 10 &mgr;m. The crystal dislocations in substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may alternatively be removed by so-called spin etching. The material removal here typically amounts to 5 to 10 &mgr;m. After subsequent CMP leveling there may still be a material removal of typically 3 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The residual thickness K of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is selected in such a way that the static stability of the layer system is ensured, supporting elements <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> considerably improving the static stability. One may do without the supporting elements particularly when the gap widths are small. Typically, residual thickness K of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> may be about 80-150 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In a further process step (cf <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) trenches <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are formed for contact area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by trench etching. Furthermore, passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is formed by a deep-etching method, passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> extending through substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and partially into cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, conductive layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is applied to bottom surface and wall surfaces <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, or rather, blind hole, by being deposited on the backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Conductive layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which may be a metallic layer, for example, produces a low ohmic connection of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, a filler layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is introduced into passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, or the blind hole, which closes passage <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and evens out the surface topography. Filler layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be a silicon oxide layer which may be produced by a so-called spin-on method or by introducing and hardening a filler material containing silicon dioxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, filler layer <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is etched back using a plasma etching method. Subsequently, on backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is removed by a wet-chemical process. Here care should be taken that conductive layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is completely removed in the region of trenches <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and that in the region of passage <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> there is not excessively much overetching, so that no undesired topographies form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> According to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, dielectric layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is deposited on backside <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> by a CVD method. Dielectric layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is used as insulating layer and insulates subsequently deposited metallic coating <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> from substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Near terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a contact opening <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is formed in dielectric layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, for the external contacting of terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Subsequently, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, metallic layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is deposited on dielectric layer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and on terminal area <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> via contact opening <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and may be structured wet-chemically to a printed circuit trace or to a terminal, the terminal pad extending, for example, in the direction of the center of the component. Thereby the substrate area needed for the production of the component and the latter&apos;s volume may be reduced, at savings in cost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The sensor or actuator structures may be integrated together with an electronic evaluation circuit (not shown) into cap <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and/or into structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The exemplary component described above may stand out as having a compact and robust design, which may permit the integration of a plurality of functional structures, and, at the same time, may permit adequate freedom of movement of the functional structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The exemplary method described above makes possible the production of a plurality of components requiring hermetically sealed encapsulation. In this manner, the effort or expenditure required for encapsulation and connecting surfaces may be reduced to a minimum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The list of reference numerals is as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> Cap </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> connecting layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> substrate </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>backside of substrate </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>upper side of substrate </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> connecting surface </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> structured layer having functional structures of a sensor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>starting polysilicon layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> supporting element </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>first end of supporting element (supporting element) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>second end of supporting element </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>passage of supporting element </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> deflectable functional structures of the sensor in structured layer <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>cavity </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> conductive connection </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> passage </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>wall surface </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> conductive layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> filler layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> metallic layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> printed circuit traces made of low-resistance polysilicon </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> terminal area </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>trenches or insulating trenches </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> frame </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>first end of frame </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>second end of frame </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>passage in frame </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> first sacrificial layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>areas of first sacrificial layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> second sacrificial layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>contact openings of second sacrificial layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> contact reed </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> oxide mask </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> recess forming a part of cavity <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> dielectric layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> contact opening of dielectric layer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> H gap height determined by total thickness of connecting layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and depth of recess <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> K remaining thickness of substrate <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A micromechanical component comprising: 
<claim-text>a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one structured layer on the substrate, wherein at least one functional structure is formed in the at least one structured layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap covering the functional structure, wherein at least one cavity is formed between the cap and the at least one functional structure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting layer to connect the cap with the structured layer, wherein the connecting layer is formed by an anodically bondable glass having a thickness in a range of 300 nm to 100 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anodically bondable glass has a defined ion concentration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least one terminal area is formed in the substrate to externally contact the at least one functional structure, the at least one terminal area being electrically insulated from the substrate by an insulating frame formed by trenches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the terminal area is formed by a part of the substrate, the substrate being doped such that the terminal area is low-resistance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein, between the substrate and the cap, at least one supporting element is provided in the at least one structured layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate has a thickness between ca 80 &mgr;m and 150 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the terminal area is positioned one of next to the at least one functional structure and below the at least one supporting element in the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the micromechanical component includes the substrate and the at least one structured layer, which is provided on at least one part of the substrate and is covered at least partly by the cap, and a conductive connection is provided between the cap and the substrate which extends all the way through the at least one structured layer and is positioned near a frame structure of the at least one structured layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive connection is formed by a passage on whose bottom surface and wall surfaces a conductive layer is deposited, the at least one of the passage and the conductive layer being covered by at least one insulating layer on a side of the substrate opposite the at least one structured layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the terminal area is in contact with at least one printed circuit trace on a side of the substrate facing the at least one structured layer, and is furnished with a metallic layer on a side of the substrate opposite the at least one structured layer, at least one insulating layer being provided between the metallic layer and the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cap, the substrate, and the at least one structured layer are made at least partially of a same material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method for producing a micromechanical component having at least one structured layer, in which at least one cap is connected to regions of the at least one structured layer and covers the at least one structured layer at least partially, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>bonding the cap to the regions of the at least one structured layer using a connecting layer that produces a chemical bond when at least one of an electrical voltage and a temperature is applied to it, the chemical bond occurring between the connecting layer and at least one of the regions of the at least one structured layer and the cap. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bonding of the cap with the regions of the at least one structured layer includes: 
<claim-text>chemically bonding the cap to the connecting layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>chemically bonding the regions of the at least one structured layer to a side of the connecting layer facing the at least one structured layer while, at approximately the same time, enclosing at least one of a gas and vacuum in at least one cavity formed between the cap and the at least one structured layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connecting layer includes at least one of a glass and a glass-type material having a specified ion concentration. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regions of the at least one structured layer have connecting surfaces, the connecting surfaces and a side of the cap facing the connecting layer being at least one of chemically and mechanically treated before the bonding, so that they have a comparatively slight surface roughness. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connecting layer is treated at least one of chemically and mechanically before bonding to the connecting surfaces of the at least one structured layer, so that it has a slight surface roughness. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connecting layer is formed from at least one of: a glass wafer by reducing its thickness to about 10 to 50 &mgr;m; a silicate glass fusion; and by sputtering on a glass layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the silicate glass fusion includes at least one of alkali silicate and borosilicate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the glass layer is in the range of 300 nm to 2 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the thickness of the anodically bondable glass is in the range of 300 nm to 50 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The micromechancial component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the anodically bondable glass includes at least one of alkali silicate and borosilicate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one supporting element is positioned largely in a center of the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substrate has a thickness of ca 80 &mgr;m to 100 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one of the passage and the conductive layer is covered by at least one insulating layer on a side of the substrate opposite the at least one structured layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the same material is silicon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The micromechanical component of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cap and the substrate are made of monocrystalline silicon and the at least one structured layer is made of polycrystalline silicon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connecting layer includes at least one of an alkali silicate or a borosilicate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the slight surface roughness is 2 to 40 nm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the slight surface roughness amounts to 2 nm or less.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001221A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
