<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000803A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000803A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000803</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894157</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65G013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>198</class>
<subclass>361000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>UNLOADING APPARATUS</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ruben</given-name>
<family-name>Luevano</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fontana</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TIMOTHY M. KELLEY</name-1>
<name-2>MICHAEL BEST &amp; FRIEDRICH LLP.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 EAST WISCONSIN AVENUE</address-1>
<city>MILWAUKEE</city>
<state>WI</state>
<postalcode>53202-4108</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A mobile unloading apparatus for unloading items from a variety of heights is disclosed wherein the apparatus has a frame supporting a ramp for movement between a first position spaced above a conveyor for permitting items to be placed directly on the conveyor and a second, downwardly sloping ramp position for moving items down the ramp to the conveyor. The apparatus includes a first walkway section supported by the frame on a first conveyor side above a supporting surface, a second walkway section supported by the frame on a second conveyor side above the supporting surface and a third walkway section. The third walkway section can be moved from a first, use position bridging the first and second walkway sections to a second, storage position. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates generally to an apparatus for unloading objects and, more specifically, to an apparatus to assist in unloading bulky objects onto conveyors. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The movement of goods efficiently through commerce is of great importance to the modem economy of today. More and more manufacturers attempt to save costs by maintaining a minimal inventory of parts, relying on the just in time delivery of parts to maintain production and of goods to restock the shelves in stores, thereby limiting the expense of maintaining a large inventory of parts and goods. As a result, rapid and efficient loading and unloading of vehicles has become more and more important in the modem economy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Current methods and apparatus for unloading vehicles are not as efficient as possible. For example, mobile conveyors exist that can be rolled into vehicles which facilitate moving boxes outside the vehicle. Some conveyors are even powered, thereby assisting the removal of items from the vehicles. However, items still must be manually loaded onto the conveyor and the conveyor is maintained at a single height. Accordingly, unloading boxes from the upper reaches of a vehicle can require a great amount of physical effort and time to safely remove the object from the upper reaches of the vehicle and safely bring the object down to the height of the conveyor. Such stretching and reaching often causes injuries to the people unloading the vehicle. Further, large and bulky items often are damaged when they are unloaded from the upper reaches of the vehicle. Setting the height of the conveyor at a higher level develops its own problems, making those unloading a vehicle lift the large and bulky boxes up and onto the elevated conveyor which puts great physical stress on the unloaders and significantly increases the probability of a box being dropped thereby damaging the goods in the box. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A mobile unloading apparatus for unloading items from a variety of heights is disclosed. The apparatus has a ramp movable between a first ramp position and a second ramp position. The ramp is centered over a central opening and a conveyor. The apparatus has a first walkway section on a first conveyor side above a supporting surface, a second walkway section on a second conveyor side above the supporting surface and a third walkway section above the supporting surface wherein the third walkway section can be moved from a first walkway position to a second walkway position. Optionally, the third walkway section is made up of a first pivoting platform section and a second pivoting platform section. In some embodiments, the first walkway section and second walkway section are on opposite sides of the conveyor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, the ramp is connected to a transfer platform by a pivot. In another aspect of the invention, the first ramp position has the loading end of the ramp and the unloading end of the ramp raised by a spring above the conveyor such that items can flow on the conveyor beneath the ramp. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect of the invention, the second ramp position has a loading ramp end positioned above an unloading ramp end and the unloading ramp end positioned in close proximity to the conveyor allowing items to flow down the ramp from the loading ramp end to the unloading ramp end onto the conveyor. The ramp may rest on a support when the ramp is in the second position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the invention, the first walkway position has the third walkway section suspended virtually horizontal and parallel to the conveyor in close proximity to the first and second walkway sections allowing a user to travel continuously on the first, second and third walkway. In addition, the second walkway position may have the third walkway section virtually vertical creating the central opening allowing the conveyor to project through and beyond the apparatus. Optionally, the ramp may be at least twenty-four inches above the conveyor when the ramp is in the first ramp position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In accordance with yet another aspect of the invention, items can be passed through the apparatus on the conveyor when the ramp is in the first ramp position and the third walkway section is in the second position. Other features and advantages are inherent in the apparatus claimed and disclosed or will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description and its accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an illustration of one embodiment of a mobile bulk unloading apparatus in accordance with the claims of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are illustrations of one embodiment of walkway sections for the mobile bulk unloading apparatus in accordance with the claims of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are illustrations of another embodiment of the walkway sections for the mobile bulk unloading apparatus in accordance with the claims of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are illustrations of one embodiment of a ramp attached to the mobile bulk unloading apparatus in accordance with the claims of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, one embodiment of a unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated. The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a first walkway section <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a second walkway section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, all of which are raised above a supporting surface. When the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is in a first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), the first <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, second <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and third walkway sections <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are on virtually the same horizontal plane allowing a user to walk around the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> using the walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which are all spaced above the supporting surface. The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also has a ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with a spring <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> that is connected to a loading platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> through a hinge or pivot <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Advantageously, a first position <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> allows objects lower in a vehicle to be easily unloaded by placing them directly onto a conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) and a second position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) allows objects high in a vehicle to be easily unloaded using the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> itself is made of a sturdy metal frame <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment, the frame <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is made of stainless steel welded together at any junction points. However, any other metal can be substituted such as an aluminum alloy or even a resin composite so long as the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> continues to be as strong and stable as necessary to handle the loads and wear that come with moving the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in and out of various vehicles and using it to unload heavy, bulky objects. The unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is preferably constructed to have a width and height such that it can comfortably fit into most commonly unloaded vehicles such as a tractor trailer, railroad car, ship or other vehicles where moving large, heavy boxes from a variety of heights may be difficult. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has wheels <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> on its four corners which makes the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> mobile but sturdy so that users can walk on the walkways <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> without being concerned about instability or tipping. Further, the wheels <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may preferably have locks which will provide further stability to the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> without limiting its mobility and usefulness. In addition, more or less wheels <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be used as required by the particular environment in which the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be used taking into account the heft of the objects to be unloaded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, the first walkway section <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is secured to the frame <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> on a first conveyor side <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the second walkway section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is secured to the frame <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> on a second conveyor side <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The first conveyor side <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is directly opposite and parallel to the second conveyor side <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Also in the preferred embodiment, the first and second walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> preferably have steps such as <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on the end of the walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> opposite the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which assist a user in climbing onto the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and, for safety, the first and second walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may advantageously have safety rails <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>on a second side of the walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, for example, on the outside edges of the walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> parallel to the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The supporting surface upon which the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is positioned could be, by way of example, the floor of a vehicle or a floor in a warehouse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, a third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be described in greater detail. In the preferred embodiment, the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is made up of a first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and a second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> connected through the use of a hinge to the first walkway section <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> connected through the use of a hinge to the second walkway section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can be placed in the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and it can also be moved to a second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> (compare <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). In the preferred embodiment, in the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are virtually horizontal, with the first, second and third walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> being on the same virtual plane allowing a user to walk unimpeded around the walkway above the supporting surface. The first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> has a support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> attached via a hinge to the end <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>opposite the pivoting end <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> that is attached to the first walkway section <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for pivoting movement between the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. In the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are virtually vertical creating a central opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>) allowing a worker to step through the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to place items directly onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> or allowing the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to be placed around the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extending through the central opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and beyond the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> so that users can easily unload items stacked lower in a vehicle by placing them on the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. While the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is in the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> hangs virtually vertical and out of the way of items placed on the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and workers working around the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, when the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is moved from the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in which both the first and the second pivoting platform sections <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are virtually vertical to the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in which both the first and second pivoting platform sections <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are virtually horizontal, the support stand <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> on the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> will be disposed virtually vertical and will touch the surface below the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> providing support to the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, in addition to support of the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by the support stand <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has a threshold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the form of an extending flange on the end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>opposite the pivoting end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that is attached to the second walkway section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for pivoting movement between the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The threshold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> will lay across and rest on the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> when the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is in the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and will provide support to the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> through the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> that is vertically disposed in contact with the supporting surface. Accordingly, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, in the preferred embodiment, moving the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> entails moving the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> from a nearly vertical orientation to a horizontal orientation whereby the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> will remain vertical and come to rest on the supporting surface and moving the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from a nearly vertical orientation to a horizontal orientation and allowing the threshold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to rest on the first pivoting platform section over the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> thereby creating a single, relatively flat supported third walkway above the supporting surface. Advantageously, because the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be pivoted to the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> to create the central opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be moved completely through the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and items can be placed directly on the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at appropriate times without concern of interference by the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Of course, it will be understood that the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> could be attached to the second pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the threshold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> could be attached to the first pivoting platform section <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Further, it will be appreciated that any of a number of conventional means which are well known by those skilled in the art may be provided to lock the support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> in a vertical position when the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is in the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and to lock the first and second pivoting platform sections <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in a nearly vertical position when the third walkway section is in a second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, in an alternative embodiment, the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; is a single pivoting platform attached via a hinge to either the first walkway section <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> or to the second walkway section <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; can then be pivoted on a hinge to a vertical position such that the central opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is created in the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; can be pivoted to a horizontal position where a threshold <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the form of an extending flange or the like rests on the opposite walkway section and creates a continuous walkway around the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, for added stability, the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can also have a support stand <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime; which can pivot down from an intermediate point along the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; to rest on the support surface to provide support when the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; is moved to the use position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In the preferred embodiment, the first, second and third walkways <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are advantageously made from stainless steel with the walkways <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> having ridges cut in the stainless steel to allow better traction. In alternate embodiments, the walkways <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> could be made from steel, aluminum or other alloys or resins. In fact, the only requirement is that the walkways <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> have the strength necessary to uphold a worker and the weight associated with the object to be moved and to withstand the wear and tear associated with moving objects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, as previously mentioned, the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> connected by a hinge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the loading platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> which is attached to the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> via pivots at rear support members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> of the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is made up of parallel side rails <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with a number of rollers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>connecting the two rails. The rollers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>are spaced such that items such as boxes which are placed on the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> will move smoothly down the ramp. In addition, the rollers <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>which are commercially available from numerous industrial supply catalogs are advantageously selected to be sufficiently strong to withstand the weight of the items placed on them and to withstand the repeated wear and tear that is inherent in unloading operations. The transfer platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is virtually horizontal and has rollers leading to the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may have a first section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and a second section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>connected by a hinge <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>such that the second section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>may be folded via the hinge <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>on top of the first section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>such that the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> will not extend beyond the unloading apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> When the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is in the second position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), it rests on supports <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and an unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is located in close proximity to the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in this position has a downward slope, sloping downward from a loading end <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> to the unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. Advantageously, the slope of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> allows items that are stacked high in a vehicle to be loaded onto the transfer platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and conveyed down the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> without much lifting and lowering of the item. Further, this unloading is made even easier by having the first, second and third walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> be on the same virtual horizontal plane above the supporting surface, allowing unloaders to walk around the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and not be forced to reach excessively to obtain items stored high in a vehicle. Advantageously, an unloader can stand on and walk around the first, second and third walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to easily reach bulky items and the unloaders will only have to carry each item to the transfer platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a small distance, making unloading significantly easier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may rest in the first position or raised position <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> where the force of the spring <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> holds the loading end <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at virtually the same height as an unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, such that the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is virtually parallel to a conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> or the like, thereby creating a gap or space under the raised ramp where objects can move along on the conveyor under the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). When sufficient weight is placed on the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> will pivot to the second position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or lowered position where the loading end <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be higher than an unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with the unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> resting in close proximity to the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> allowing objects to move from a loading platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with the loading end <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> higher than the unloading end <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, and onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). The spring <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> exerts sufficient force to hold the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> virtually horizontal when no weight is on the ramp, but will allow the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to pivot to the second position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> when a sufficient amount of weight is placed on the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In the first position, the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is held above the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at a sufficient height to allow items to be unloaded and to move along the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> under the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing, it will be appreciated that the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> allows unloaders to unload items from a variety of heights in a vehicle in a less stressful and more efficient manner. When items high in a vehicle are to be unloaded, the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be in the first ramp position <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will be moved to the first, use position <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, allowing an unloader to stand on and walk around the first, second and third walkway sections <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> above the supporting surface and carry each item a short distance from its location within the vehicle to the loading end <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> of the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, where the item will be placed on the transfer platform <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, will move down the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, pushing the ramp from the first, raised position <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to the second or lowered position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>), where the item will move onto the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. When items low in a vehicle are to be unloaded, the ramp <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> will be in the first ramp position <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), and the third walkway section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> will be moved to the second, storage position <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> allowing the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to be moved through the central opening <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> so that items can then be moved from the lower part of the vehicle directly to the conveyor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with a small amount of lifting and moving. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Numerous modifications and alternative embodiments of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art in view of the foregoing description. Accordingly, this description is to be construed as illustrative only and is not to be limiting of the invention. Thus, the details herein given may be varied substantially without departing from the spirit of the invention. Accordingly, the exclusive use of all modifications which are within the scope of the appended claims is reserved. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An unloading apparatus for unloading items from a variety of heights comprising: 
<claim-text>a frame supporting a ramp for movement between a first ramp position where the ramp is held above the separate conveyor, creating a space that permits items to be placed directly on the separate conveyor and a second, downwardly sloping ramp position for moving items down the ramp to a separate conveyor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first walkway section supported by the frame on a first conveyor side above a supporting surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second walkway section supported by the frame on a second conveyor side above the supporting surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third walkway section movable from a first, use position bridging the first and second walkway sections to a second, storage position defining a central opening accommodating direct access to the separate conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ramp is held in the first position by a spring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third walkway section includes a first pivoting platform section and a second pivoting platform section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first, second and third walkway sections are supported in a virtually horizontal plane allowing a user to walk about the first, second and third walkway sections when the third walkway section is in the first, use position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third walkway section is movable to a substantially vertical orientation in the second, storage position whereby the central opening allows the separate conveyor to project through the apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ramp can be positioned to have a loading ramp end positioned above an unloading ramp end in the second, downwardly sloping ramp position with the unloading ramp end positioned in close proximity to the conveyor allowing items to move down the ramp from the loading ramp end to the unloading ramp end onto the conveyor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ramp can be positioned to have both a loading ramp end and an unloading end spaced above the conveyor for permitting items to be placed directly on the conveyor beneath the ramp. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a loading platform wherein a loading end of the ramp is connected to the loading platform through a hinge. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ramp further comprises a first section and a second section with a hinge connecting the first section and the second section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the third walkway section is a single pivoting section with a threshold on a non-pivoting end. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The unloading apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the ramp is centered over a central opening in the apparatus and centered over the separate conveyor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000803A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
