<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002169A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002169A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002169</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09897514</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B001/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B003/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>666000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>739000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>FLEXIBLE LENS</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>K.</middle-name>
<family-name>Guy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Mesa</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Mark D. Elchuk</name-1>
<name-2>Harness, Dickey &amp; Pierce, P.L.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 828</address-1>
<city>Bloomfield Hills</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48303</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A flexible lens is provided that comprises at least two chambers encased by a flexible membrane and separated by a partition, wherein pressure within the chambers is regulated such that when one chamber receives positive pressure, the other chamber receives negative pressure. Accordingly, a first lens portion and a second lens portion of the flexible membrane flex in the same relative direction when the pressure is regulated. In addition, a variable optical input such as an iris diaphragm is provided that operates in concert with the flexible membrane. As a result, the flexible lens generates a constant spot size output having a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution. Similarly, the flexible lens generates a variable spot size output having a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution when the optical input is constant. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to optical lenses and more particularly to flexible lenses for controlling optical properties by varying the pressure of a fluid within a chamber of the flexible lens. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Flexible optical lenses of the known art have largely been employed to provide a variable focal length for a given optical input. Generally, known art flexible lenses comprise a single chamber encapsulated by a flexible transparent membrane and filled with a gas, liquid, or other fluid. By changing the pressure of the fluid in the chamber, the shape of the flexible membrane also changes, thereby changing the focal length of the lens. With the single chamber, however, the flexible membrane is limited to providing a concave lens on both ends or a convex lens on both ends of the chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Other known flexible lenses provide two independent chambers rather than a single chamber, such that a flexible membrane on each side of the lens flexes independent of the other flexible membrane. Therefore, one side of the lens may be concave and while the other is convex, and vice versa, along with various combinations thereof. For example, U.S. Pat. No. 3,161,718 to De Luca discloses a variable lens that has two fluid tight lens compartments enclosed by a flexible diaphragm on each end and separated by a clear separator disc. The variable lens further comprises two pressure actuators that independently control the amount of pressure in each compartment, and thus the amount of flex of each diaphragm. As a result, a variety of flexible lens combinations may be produced, as set forth in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A through 7H</cross-reference>, to control the focal length of an optical input. Additionally, De Luca and other known flexible lenses are limited to a constant optical input wherein optical properties are exclusively controlled by the flexible membrane and/or the substance within the compartments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> With many optical applications, and more specifically with regard to fiber optic applications, a terminated bundle of fibers receives light from an optical input such as a collimated beam for subsequent transmission of the light in an optical system. An important aspect of transmitting light to the bundle involves providing a constant spot size output of the light to the face of the fibers such that each fiber receives approximately the same amount of light. In addition, the intensity distribution of the output must be substantially flat such that all of the fibers receive approximately the same intensity of light. Moreover, the angular distribution of the light must similarly be substantially uniform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> At times, the intensity of the optical input must be varied while still maintaining a constant spot size output, a substantially flat intensity, and a substantially uniform angular distribution in order to accommodate different fiber bundle sizes and different operating requirements of the fiber bundle. Unfortunately, flat intensity distributions and uniform angular distributions are difficult to produce with optical systems of the known art, primarily because an iris that adjusts the optical input has a limited minimum size. If the minimum size of the iris becomes smaller than the face of the fiber bundle, the fibers around the periphery of the bundle cannot receive the same amount of light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, using a focused beam of light, i.e. output from a flexible lens of the known art, an approximate gaussian intensity distribution results across the face of a fiber bundle, which is not a flat intensity distribution. The intensity may be controlled using an iris, for example, or by changing the power output of a lamp. However, changing the power output of the lamp alters the intensity distribution and also the color temperature of the light. Accordingly, the color temperature may be maintained while the power output of the lamp is held constant by employing an iris with a variable aperture to control intensity. As a result, however, the spot size of the output changes and not all of the fibers in the bundle may receive an equal distribution of light or a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there remains a need in the art for a flexible lens that provides a constant spot size output, a substantially flat intensity distribution, and a substantially uniform angular distribution across a target area while changing the intensity of an optical input. The flexible lens should operate without changing the color temperature of the light and should further be capable of enlarging or reducing the spot size output while maintaining a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially constant angular distribution. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In one preferred form, the present invention provides a flexible lens that comprises at least two chambers separated by a partition and encased in a flexible membrane. The flexible lens further comprises a regulator in communication with the chambers that controls the pressure therein. Further, an optical input is provided, which may be variable or constant depending on the desired output characteristics as further described below, which results in a constant or variable spot size output, respectfully, with a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially constant angular distribution across a target surface, e.g., the face of a fiber bundle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The flexible membrane that encases the chambers further comprises a first lens portion adjacent the optical input and a second lens portion adjacent the target surface. In one form, the flexible membrane is one piece that encases both chambers. In another form, two separate membranes are used to cover each chamber, wherein the membranes are secured to a support structure or other similar device as may be contemplated by one of ordinary skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The regulator that controls the pressure within the chambers causes the first lens portion and the second lens portion to flex in the same relative direction as one chamber receives positive pressure and the other chamber receives negative pressure. Accordingly, the pressure within one chamber is dependent on the pressure within the other chamber, wherein when one chamber receives positive pressure, the other chamber receives approximately the same amount of negative pressure, and vice versa. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In one form, a constant spot size output is generated with a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution using a variable optical input that operates in concert with the flexible membrane. Preferably, the optical input is varied using an iris diaphragm that defines a variable aperture. The iris diaphragm is disposed adjacent the first lens portion such that light from the optical input, e.g. a parabolic reflector, may be varied to the first lens portion. As the iris diaphragm closes to form a smaller aperture, the pressure in the chamber encased by the first lens portion is decreased and the pressure in the chamber encased by the second lens portion is increased. Accordingly, the first lens portion flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward to maintain a constant spot size output on the target area. Further, the intensity distribution is substantially flat, in addition to a substantially constant angular distribution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another form, the optical input remains constant while the pressure in the chambers is varied in order to produce a variable spot size output with a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially constant angular distribution. Accordingly, the pressure in the chamber encased by the first lens portion is decreased and the pressure in the chamber encased by the second lens portion is increased, wherein the first lens portion flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward, to increase the spot size. Similarly, the pressure in the chamber encased by the first lens portion is increased and the pressure in the chamber encased by the second lens portion is decreased, wherein the first lens portion flexes outward and the second lens portion flexes inward, to decrease the spot size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The partition that separates the chambers is preferably a solid transparent material in order to maximize light transmission. Alternately, the partition may comprise a filter such that light may be filtered to a particular spectrum. Furthermore, the chambers may be filled with air, a liquid, or other substance as required in order to achieve the desired set of optical properties. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The regulator that controls pressure within the chamber in one form is a hydraulic cylinder that is vented to one chamber on one side of a piston and vented to the other chamber on the other side of the piston. When the piston moves within the hydraulic cylinder from one side to the other, one chamber receives negative pressure while the other chamber receives positive pressure. Alternately, the pressure may be regulated using drive mechanism such as a magnetic ring that is operable with the partition, wherein the partition slides laterally to cause negative pressure in one chamber and positive pressure in the other chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Further areas of applicability of the present invention will become apparent from the detailed description provided hereinafter. It should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples, while indicating the preferred embodiment of the invention, are intended for purposes of illustration only and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention will become more fully understood from the detailed description and the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a side view of a flexible lens in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a side view of a flexible lens with an iris fully open and a corresponding intensity distribution, angular distribution, and spot size in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a side view of a flexible lens with an iris 25 percent closed and a corresponding intensity distribution, angular distribution, and spot size in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference> is a side view of a flexible lens with an iris 50 percent closed and a corresponding intensity distribution, angular distribution, and spot size in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</cross-reference> is a side view of a flexible lens with an iris 95 percent closed and a corresponding intensity distribution, angular distribution, and spot size in accordance with the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a side view of a hydraulic cylinder regulator in communication with chambers of a flexible lens in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side view of a magnetic ring regulator in communication with chambers of a flexible lens in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The following description of the preferred embodiments is merely exemplary in nature and is in no way intended to limit the invention, its application, or uses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings, the flexible lens of the present invention is illustrated and generally indicated by reference numeral <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown, the flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> generally comprises a first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> that are separated by a partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and encased by a flexible membrane <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The flexible membrane <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> further comprises a first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and a second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which flex inward or outward as indicated by the dashed lines when a regulator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> controls the pressure within the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As used herein, the terms &ldquo;inward&rdquo; and &ldquo;outward&rdquo; are defined as a direction from an approximate center of the flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is flexed inward as indicated by the letter A and outward as indicated by the letter B. Similarly, the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is flexed outward as indicated by the letter A&prime; and inward as indicated by the letter B&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> When the regulator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> controls the pressure within the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, one chamber receives positive pressure while the other chamber receives negative pressure. Accordingly, the pressure in first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is dependent on the pressure in second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and vice versa. For example, when the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is negative and the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is positive, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexes inward as indicated by the letter A and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flexes outward as indicated by the letter A&prime;. Similarly, when the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is positive and the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is negative, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexes outward as indicated by the letter B and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flexes inward as indicated by the letter B&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises an optical input <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which is varied using, for example, an iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having a variable aperture <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In one form, the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is operable with the flexible membrane <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> such that when the aperture <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is closed or opened, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flex inward and/or outward to produce an output with a desired set of optical properties as described in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>D, the operation of the flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a variable optical input is illustrated in greater detail. As shown, the optical input <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is varied using the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which generally closes to form a smaller aperture and opens to form a larger aperture. As further shown, the optical input is preferably distributed to the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> using a parabolic reflector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. It shall be appreciated by those skilled in the art that other forms of optical input may be employed, and the use of the parabolic reflector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> shall not be construed as limiting the scope of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Generally, light travels in the direction of arrow X from the optical input <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, through the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, through the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and finally through the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> onto a target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As a result, a constant spot size output is generated with a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially constant angular distribution as described in greater detail below. The target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may be, for example, a fiber bundle, a glass rod, or other device to which light is being transmitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is fully open and the first and second lens portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> remain in an unflexed position. Accordingly, a theoretical intensity distribution <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A for the light that is transmitted to the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is shown along with a spot size <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, the spot size <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> covers the entire width of the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> such that, for example, all of the fibers at the face of a fiber bundle receive approximately the same amount of light. Furthermore, the intensity distribution <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A is substantially flat and an angular distribution <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>A is substantially constant across the width of the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, the aperture <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is approximately 25 percent closed, and accordingly, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is flexed inward and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is flexed outward. As shown, the spot size <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> remains constant while the optical input <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is varied. Additionally, the theoretical intensity distribution <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B remains substantially flat and the angular distribution <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>B also remains substantially constant across the width of the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The aperture <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is further closed to approximately 50 percent as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</cross-reference>. Accordingly, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexes further inward and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flexes further outward. As a result of the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> moving in concert with the flexing of the first and second lens portions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the spot size <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> remains constant while the theoretical intensity distribution <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>C remains substantially flat and the angular distribution <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>C also remains substantially constant across the width of the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>D, the aperture <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is further closed to approximately 95 percent, wherein the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is flexed even further inward and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is flexed even further outward in concert with the movement of the iris diaphragm <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Similarly, the spot size <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> remains constant while the theoretical intensity distribution <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>D remains substantially flat and the angular distribution <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>D remains substantially constant across the width of the target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In another form, (not shown), a variable spot size output is generated when the optical input <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> remains constant and the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are flexed in the same relative direction. When the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is flexed inward and the second lens portion is flexed outward, the spot size increases. Similarly, when the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is flexed outward and the second lens portion is flexed inward, the spot size decreases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the regulator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> that controls the pressure within the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is preferably a hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as shown. The hydraulic cylinder <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> houses a piston <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, which operates between a first vent <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a second vent <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> to the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. When the piston <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> moves in the direction of arrow Y, the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> decreases and the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> correspondingly increases. Accordingly, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward. (Not shown). Similarly, when the piston <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> moves in the direction of arrow Z, the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> increases and the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> correspondingly decreases, which results in the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexing outward and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flexing inward. (Not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In yet another preferred form, the regulator <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is a drive mechanism such as a magnetic ring <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. The magnetic ring <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is operable with the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> such that the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> slides laterally in the direction of arrows Y&prime; and Z&prime; to cause negative pressure in one chamber and positive pressure in the other chamber. For example, movement of the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow Y&prime; decreases the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and increases the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward. (Not shown). Similarly, when the magnetic ring <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> causes movement of the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the direction of arrow Z&prime;, the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> increases and the pressure in the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> correspondingly decreases, which results in the first lens portion <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> flexing outward and the second lens portion <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> flexing inward. (Not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> It shall be appreciated by those skilled in the art that other devices and methods to control the pressure in the first chamber <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the second chamber <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may also be employed in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. Furthermore, the first and second chambers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> may be filled with air, liquid, or other substance in order to control the output according to a desired set of optical properties. Additionally, the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is preferably a solid transparent material to maximize light transmission. Alternately, the partition <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may comprise a filter in order to filter light to a particular spectrum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention provides a constant spot size output to a target area <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, wherein, for example, all fibers within a fiber bundle receive approximately the same amount of light. Furthermore, the flexible lens <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> also provides a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially constant angular distribution, thereby increasing the performance of a variety of optical systems. Moreover, a variable spot size output is provided with a constant optical input through the operation of the flexible membrane <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in accordance with the teachings of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The description of the invention is merely exemplary in nature and, thus, variations that do not depart from the gist of the invention are intended to be within the scope of the invention. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A flexible lens comprising: 
<claim-text>at least two chambers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a partition disposed between the two chambers; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one flexible membrane encasing the chambers, the flexible membrane comprising a first lens portion and a second lens portion; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator in communication with the two chambers; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical input disposed adjacent the first lens portion, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the regulator is activated, one chamber receives negative pressure and the other chamber receives positive pressure such that the first lens portion and the second lens portion flex in the same relative direction, thereby providing: 
<claim-text>a constant spot size output comprising a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution when the optical input is variable; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a variable spot size output comprising a flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution when the optical input is constant. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical input is varied with an iris diaphragm, such that the iris diaphragm is moved from open to closed and from closed to open in concert with the flexing of the first lens portion and the second lens portion to generate the constant spot size output. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regulator further comprises a hydraulic actuator operatively engaged with the two chambers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regulator further comprises a drive mechanism operatively engaged with the partition, such that the partition slides laterally to cause the negative pressure in one chamber and the positive pressure in the other chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the drive mechanism further comprises a magnetic ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partition comprises a solid transparent material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partition further comprises a filter, such that the optical input is filtered to a predetermined spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical input further comprises a parabolic reflector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a support structure, wherein the flexible membrane, the partition, and the regulator are secured to the support structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of generating a constant spot size optical output having a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution using a variable optical input, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a flexible lens comprising at least two chambers divided by a partition and encased by a flexible membrane comprising a first lens portion and a second lens portion, and a regulator that controls pressure within the two chambers such that one chamber receives positive pressure and the other chamber receives negative pressure; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) regulating the pressure in the chambers such that the first lens portion and the second lens portion flex in the same relative direction; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) varying the size of the optical input in concert with the flexing of the first lens portion and the second lens portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the size of the optical input is varied from open to closed and the first lens portion flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the size of the optical input is varied from closed to open and the first lens portion flexes outward and the second lens portion flexes inward. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of generating a variable spot size optical output having a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution using a constant optical input, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) providing a flexible lens comprising at least two chambers divided by a partition and encased by a flexible membrane comprising a first lens portion and a second lens portion, and a regulator that controls pressure within the two chambers such that one chamber receives positive pressure and the other chamber receives negative pressure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) regulating the pressure in the chambers such that the first lens portion and the second lens portion flex in the same relative direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the pressure in the chambers is regulated, the first lens portion flexes inward and the second lens portion flexes outward, such that the spot size of the optical output increases. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the pressure in the chambers is regulated, first lens portion flexes outward and the second lens portion flexes inward, such that the spot size of the optical output decreases. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A flexible lens comprising: 
<claim-text>a first chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first lens portion encasing the first chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second lens portion encasing the second chamber; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a partition disposed between the first chamber and the second chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a regulator in communication with the first chamber and the second chamber, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the regulator is activated, one chamber receives negative pressure and the other chamber receives positive pressure such that the first lens portion and the second lens portion flex in the same relative direction, thereby providing: 
<claim-text>a constant spot size output comprising a substantially flat intensity distribution and substantially uniform angular distribution with a variable optical input; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a variable spot size output comprising a substantially flat intensity distribution and a substantially uniform angular distribution with a constant optical input. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical input is varied with an iris diaphragm, such that the iris diaphragm is moved from open to closed and from closed to open in concert with the flexing of the first lens portion and the second lens portion to generate the constant spot size output. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regulator further comprises a hydraulic actuator operatively engaged with the two chambers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regulator further comprises a drive mechanism operatively engaged with the partition, such that the partition slides laterally to cause the negative pressure in one chamber and the positive pressure in the other chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the drive mechanism further comprises a magnetic ring. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partition comprises a solid transparent material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partition further comprises a filter, such that the optical input is filtered to a predetermined spectrum. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical input further comprises a parabolic reflector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The flexible lens of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a support structure, wherein the first lens portion, the second lens portion, the partition, and the regulator are secured to the support structure.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002169A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
