<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001822</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896693</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G09G005/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>168000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Keyboard with integrated mouse/pointer device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Brian</given-name>
<family-name>Davidson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Surrey</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nikolaj</given-name>
<middle-name>Helberg</middle-name>
<family-name>Bestle</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Calabasas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>JERALD J. GNUSCHKE</name-1>
<name-2>NOKIA INC.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>6000 CONNECTION DRIVE</address-1>
<address-2>MD 1-4-755</address-2>
<city>IRVING</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75039</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A data input device for use with portable electronic devices. The data input device has a motion-sensing device disposed within it that detects movement of the input device. In the presently preferred embodiment, the data input device has at least a keypad and an integral mouse-ball system. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to input devices and, more particularly, to keyboards with integrated positioning devices. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Mobile communication devices generally have a data input device such as a keyboard. The data input device is typically an integral part of the mobile communication device. For example, in a conventional mobile cellular telephone, the keypad is physically a part of the cellular telephone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Due to the small size of most mobile communication devices, integral data input devices are generally small and difficult to use. For example, the typical cellular telephone keypad is constrained by the size of the cellular telephone. As future cellular telephones continue to get smaller, so too must their integral keypads. As the keypads become ever smaller, they become more difficult to manipulate. Thus, it would be advantageous to have an external keypad/keyboard to function as a remote data entry device for small mobile communication devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a conventional keyboard <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and mouse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as they are typically used with a personal computer <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The mouse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and the keyboard <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are physically separate devices. Using both devices can be difficult in constrained areas, such as in coach class passenger seating aboard the typical commercial airplane. Thus, it would be advantageous to combine the two devices in order to save space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Past efforts to combine the keyboard with a device for use with graphical interfaces have resulted in inventions such as the keyboard/trackball and the keyboard/trackpoint (a type of joystick found in the keyboard of IBM laptop computers). Both of these solutions suffer from the disadvantage that the user must move his fingers from the keys to operate the trackball or trackpoint, which slows typing. Thus, it would be an advantage to combine a keyboard with a device for navigating graphical user interfaces so that the user does not have to remove his fingers from the keys of the keyboard when navigating the graphical user interface. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Various embodiments of the invention disclose a data input device with an integral motion-sensing device. The motion-sensing device detects movement of the data input device and generates data that, among other uses, can be used to navigate a graphical user interface on a remote data processing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The presently preferred embodiment of the invention is a keyboard for use with a mobile communication device such as a cellular mobile phone, the keyboard having an integral mouse-like motion-sensing device. The motion-sensing device is disposed within the keyboard and senses movement of the keyboard (unlike a trackball or trackpoint, which are unable to detect movement of the keyboard). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the disclosed invention advantageously function as a remote data input device with a mouse disposed primarily within the remote data input device. Embodiments of the disclosed invention are also beneficial for users who wish to avoid the distraction of removing their fingers from the keys to manipulate a device that operates a graphical user interface.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The disclosed inventions will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings, which show important sample embodiments of the invention and which are incorporated in the specification hereof by reference, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a prior art situation in which a keyboard and a separate mouse are used with a computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> depicts a top view of the presently preferred embodiment of a data input device capable of implementing the disclosed innovations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> depicts a side view of the presently preferred embodiment of a data input device capable of implementing the disclosed innovations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts an embodiment of the innovative data input device as it might be used with a remote device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts an internal block diagram of the presently preferred embodiment of a data input device capable of implementing the disclosed innovations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a block diagram of a mobile station capable of interacting with the presently preferred embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an embodiment of the present invention in use with a mobile communication device.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PRESENTLY PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The numerous innovative teachings of the present application will be described with particular reference to the presently preferred embodiment. However, it should be understood that this class of embodiments provides only a few examples of the many advantageous uses of the innovative teachings herein. In general, statements made in the specification of the present application do not necessarily delimit any of the various claimed inventions. Moreover, some statements may apply to some inventive features but not to others. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> depict the top and side views, respectively, of the presently preferred embodiment <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of the invention. A keyboard <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, having at least one key <highlight><bold>215</bold></highlight>, has an integral motion-sensing device <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> that senses movement of the keyboard. In the preferred embodiment shown, the motion-sensing device <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is a mouse-ball system such as that found in a conventional computer mouse. However, the motion-sensing device <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> could be a mechanical device, such as tilt-switches or a mouse system, an optical device, such as an optical mouse system or an infrared (IR) ranging/positioning system, or a radio-frequency (RF) ranging/positioning system. Some conventional mechanical mouse systems use a ball and x-y potentiometer or a ball and x-y optical sensor to sense movement in the x-y plane. One skilled in the art understands that motion-sensing device <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> could output data in analog and/or digital form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the preferred embodiment of the innovative data input device as it might be used in a typical configuration. The innovative keyboard <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> functions as a remote data input terminal and is linked to a remote data-processing device <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>, such as a mobile phone, personal digital assistant (PDA), or portable computer, via a communication link <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. The communication link <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be low power RF technology, such as Bluetooth, optical technology, such as infra-red (IR) communications, or a direct physical connection, such as a cable. When the keyboard <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is moved, the motion-sensing device <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> generates data about the movement. The keyboard movement data <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may then be transmitted over the communication link <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to the remote data-processing device <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight>. The remote data-processing device <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> may use the keyboard movement data <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> to re-position an onscreen cursor <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight>, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts a block diagram of the presently preferred embodiment of the innovative data input device <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. A keypad assembly <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is coupled to an input/output device <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the input/output device <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is a low power RF transceiver. The input/output device <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is further coupled to an antenna <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>. A mouse assembly <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> may be coupled directly to the input/output device <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> or, alternatively, it may be coupled indirectly to the input/output device <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> via a coupling to the keypad <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> depicts a block diagram of a mobile station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> that can make use of the disclosed embodiments. Although the invention is discussed in the context of a mobile station for exemplary purposes, any suitable electronic device, such as a portable computer or PDA, may interact with the innovative data input device disclosed herein. The mobile station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> includes, in this example: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A control head <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> containing an audio interface, i.e. a speaker <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> and microphone <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. The control head <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> generally includes a display assembly <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> allowing a user to see dialed digits, stored information, messages, calling status information, including signal strength, etc. The control head generally includes a keypad <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, or other user control device, allowing a user to dial numbers, answer incoming calls, enter stored information, and perform other mobile station functions. In the context of the disclosed invention, display assembly <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> is a graphical user interface. The control head also has a controller unit <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight> that interfaces with a logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> responsible, from the control unit perspective, for receiving commands from the keypad <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> or other control devices, such as the disclosed invention, and providing status information, alerts, and other information to the display assembly <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A transceiver unit <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter unit <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, receiver unit <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight>, and the logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>. The transmitter unit <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight> converts low-level audio signals from the microphone <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> to digital coding using a codec (a data coder/decoder) <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. The digitally encoded audio is represented by modulated shifts, for example, in the frequency domain, using a shift key modulator/demodulator <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>. Other data received from the logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight>, such as station parameters and control information, may also be encoded for transmission. The modulated signal is then amplified by RF amplifier <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> and transmitted via an antenna assembly <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The antenna assembly <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> contains a TR (transmitter/receiver) switch <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> to prevent simultaneous reception and transmission of a signal by the mobile station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. The transceiver unit <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight> is connected to the antenna assembly <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> through the TR switch <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. The antenna assembly contains at least one antenna <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> coupled to TR switch <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight> by coupler <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> A receiver unit <highlight><bold>516</bold></highlight> receives a transmitted signal via the antenna assembly <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. The signal is amplified by receiver/amplifier <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> and demodulated by shift-key demodulator <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>. If the signal is an audio signal, it is decoded using the codec <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight>. The audio signal is then reproduced by the speaker <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. Other signals, such as remote data input from the present invention are handled by the logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> after demodulation by demodulator <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> usually containing an application specific integrated circuit (or ASIC) combining many functions, such as a general purpose microprocessor, digital signal processor, and other functions, into one integrated circuit. The logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> coordinates the overall operation of the transmitter and receiver using control messages. The various disclosed embodiments would make use of the logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> to update the display <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>. Generally, the logic control assembly <highlight><bold>518</bold></highlight> operates from a program that is stored in flash memory <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> of the mobile station. Flash memory <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> allows upgrading of operating software, software correction or addition of new features. Flash memory <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> is also used to hold user information such as speed dialing names and stored numbers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In addition to flash memory <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight>, the mobile station <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> will typically contain read only memory (ROM) <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> for storing information that should not change, such as startup procedures, and random access memory (RAM) <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight> to hold temporary information such as channel number and system identifier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a keypad <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> embodiment of the present invention as it might be used with a mobile station <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. Mobile station <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> has a display <highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight>. A cursor <highlight><bold>640</bold></highlight> can be navigated around the display <highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight> by moving the entire keypad <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. Keys <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> on the keypad can be used to enter text or to select icons <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight> on the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As will be recognized by those skilled in the art, the innovative concepts described in the present application can be modified and varied over a tremendous range of applications, and accordingly the scope of patented subject matter is not limited by any of the specific exemplary teachings given. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> For example, the various embodiments have generally been discussed in the context of keypads or keyboards. One skilled in the art understands that the invention is equally applicable to keypads and keyboards. Therefore, for purposes of this application, the terms keypad and keyboard are considered synonymous. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> For example, the invention has primarily been discussed in the context of a keyboard with an integral motion-sensing device. In one variation, a touchpad could be used rather than a keyboard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> For example, the integral motion-sensing device has primarily been discussed in the context of a mouse-like device that mechanically sense motion of the input device. In one variation, motion of the input device could be electronically sensed by triangulation of electromagnetic signals, similar to Global Positioning systems but with low-power RF, rather than by a mechanical mouse-like device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As another example, the invention has been discussed primarily in the context of a remote data entry device for use with a mobile station. One skilled in the art realizes that the invention could be used with a mobile computer, PDA, a conventional desktop personal computer, and a multitude of other electronic devices. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A data input device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a keypad; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an integral motion-sensing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said integral motion-sensing device is configured to generate data relating to the movement of said keypad. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The data input device of claim <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, wherein said integral motion-sensing device is a mouse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The data input device of claim <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, wherein said integral motion-sensing device is configured to generate said data by signal triangulation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The data input device of claim <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, wherein said integral motion-sensing device is configured to transmit said data to a remote electronic device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A data input system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a data input device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motion-sensing device, for sensing motion of said data input device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a remote data processing device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication link coupling said data input device, said motion-sensing device, and said remote data processing device, whereby data may be transferred from said data input device or said motion-sensing device to said remote data processing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said motion-sensing device is disposed within said data input device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said data input device is a keyboard, said keyboard having at least one key. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said remote data processing device further comprises: 
<claim-text>a display; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a logic control assembly coupled to said communication link; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said logic control assembly is configured to update said display in response to receiving data from said motion-sensing device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said communication link is an IR link. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said communication link is a low-power RF link. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said remote data processing device is a mobile communication device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said remote data processing device is a portable computer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The data input system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said communication link is a cable comprising at least one wire. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A data input device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a keypad device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a mouse, for sensing motion of said keypad device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said mouse is primarily disposed within said keypad device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said mouse senses motion of said keypad device and generates data related to said motion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said keypad device comprises at least one key. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said keypad device further comprises: 
<claim-text>a top side having keys; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom side; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said mouse is disposed toward said bottom side of said keypad device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said mouse is an optical mouse. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an input/output device coupled to said mouse; 
<claim-text>whereby data from said mouse may be transmitted by said input/output device to a remote device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said input/output device is configurable to transmit data to a remote device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The data input device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said input/output device is configurable to transmit said data in digital form.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001822A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001822A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001822A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001822A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001822A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
