<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005429</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894387</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04N007/173</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06F003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04N007/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04N005/445</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06F013/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>008000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>039000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>091000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>098000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>117000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>118000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>042000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>725</class>
<subclass>051000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>EPG with video previews</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Nicholas</given-name>
<family-name>Colsey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Del Mar</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MILLER PATENT SERVICES</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2500 DOCKERY LANE</address-1>
<city>RALEIGH</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>27606</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method an apparatus for providing a video preview as part of an electronic program guide in a Set-Top Box or other television receiver device. A listing of television programs is presented to a viewer, for example, in the form of a grid showing television programming as a function of time. When a command is transmitted by the viewer from a remote commander to initiate a preview of a specified program, the program is mapped to a video file containing a preview of the specified program. The video file may be stored in a local disc drive or at a service provider head end. The video file can then be played in a window of the electronic program guide to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">COPYRIGHT NOTICE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> A portion of the disclosure of this patent document contains material which is subject to copyright protection. The copyright owner has no objection to the facsimile reproduction of the patent document or the patent disclosure, as it appears in the Patent and Trademark Office patent file or records, but otherwise reserves all copyright rights whatsoever. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the field of electronic program guides (EPG). More particularly, this invention relates to an electronic program guide that permits the user to access video information relating to a program selection. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Cable and satellite television (TV) systems often provide a channel that is used for displaying an electronic programming guide (EPG). The EPG provides a listing of the programs that are available on the cable or satellite system. Typically, the listing includes a plurality of time slots arranged in a column, wherein each time slot has associated with it a row of program information to thus form a grid pattern. The program information may include, for example, the name of the program, the cable channel on which the program may be found, names of actors, whether the program is broadcast in stereo, whether closed captioning is available and other associated information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The data carrying capacity, or bandwidth, of cable systems continues to rapidly increase. This enables much more information to be transmitted, from more sources, over that which was possible just a short time ago. As such, it is desirable that EPGs be provided that are capable of displaying additional information in a manner that facilitates human interaction with TVs and cable systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to electronic program guides. Objects, advantages and features of the invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon consideration of the following detailed description of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention a method and apparatus for providing a video preview as part of an electronic program guide in a Set-Top Box or other television receiver device is provided. A listing of television programs is presented to a viewer, for example, in the form of a grid showing television programming as a function of time. When a command is transmitted by the viewer from a remote commander to initiate a preview of a specified program, the program is mapped to a video file containing a preview of the specified program. The video file may be stored in a local disc drive or at a service provider head end. The video file can then be played in a window of the electronic program guide to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A method of providing an electronic programming guide, consistent with an embodiment of the present invention includes presenting a listing of television programs to a viewer; receiving a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program; mapping the specified program to a video file containing a preview of the specified program; and playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A television Set-Top Box, or other television receiver device, consistent with an embodiment of the present invention has a programmed processor having access to a plurality of video files. An electronic program guide is provided to a display for display to a user. A receiver receives a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program. A computer program running on the programmed processor that maps the command to one of the plurality of files stored on the video device and plays the video file to the display to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An electronic storage medium, consistent with an embodiment of the present invention, stores instructions which, when executed on a programmed processor, carry out a method of providing an electronic programming guide including presenting a listing of television programs to a viewer; receiving a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program; mapping the specified program to a video file containing a preview of the specified program; and playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A method of providing program previews to a viewer, consistent with an embodiment of the present invention includes receiving a program preview file from a server; storing the program preview file in a storage device; receiving a program guide from the server; determining from the program guide that the program preview file does not correspond to a program to be available at a future time; and deleting the program preview file from the storage device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The above summaries are intended to illustrate exemplary embodiments of the invention, which will be best understood in conjunction with the detailed description to follow, and are not intended to limit the scope of the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The features of the invention believed to be novel are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention itself however, both as to organization and method of operation, together with objects and advantages thereof, may be best understood by reference to the following detailed description of the invention, which describes certain exemplary embodiments of the invention, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a system block diagram of a system using a set-top box. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a functional block diagram of a digital set-top box suitable for use with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a screen illustrating an exemplary electronic program guide consistent with an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating a process consistent with an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating a variation of the process of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> consistent with an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> While this invention is susceptible of embodiment in many different forms, there is shown in the drawings and will herein be described in detail specific embodiments, with the understanding that the present disclosure is to be considered as an example of the principles of the invention and not intended to limit the invention to the specific embodiments shown and described. In the description below, like reference numerals are used to describe the same, similar or corresponding parts in the several views of the drawings. The term &ldquo;preview&rdquo; as used herein is intended to embrace any type of moving video information relating to a particular program selection including, without limitation, an MPEG video segment of a movie trailer or television program preview. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> block diagram for an exemplary interactive cable or satellite television (TV) system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is shown. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes, at a head end of the service provider <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, a media server <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> for providing, on demand, movies and other programming obtained from a media database <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The media server <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> might also provide additional content such as interviews with the actors, games, advertisements, available merchandise, associated Web pages, interactive games and other related content. The system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> also includes an electronic programming guide (EPG) server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a program listing database <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for generating an EPG. Set-Top Box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can generally provide for bidirectional communication over a transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the case of a cable STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments, bidirectional communication can be effected using asymmetrical communication techniques possibly using dual communication media&mdash;one for the uplink and one for the downlink. In any event, the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can have its own Universal Resource Locator (URL) or IP address or other unique identifier assigned thereto to provide for addressability by the head end and users of the Internet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The media server <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are operatively coupled by transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to a set-top box (STB) <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may include, for example, a conventional coaxial cable network, a fiber optic cable network, telephone system, twisted pair, a satellite communication system, a radio frequency (RF) system, a microwave system, other wireless systems, a combination of wired and wireless systems or any of a variety of known electronic transmission mediums. In the case of a cable television network, transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is commonly realized at the subscriber&apos;s premises as a coaxial cable that is connected to a suitable cable connector at the rear panel of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In the case of a Direct Satellite System (DSS), the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is often referred to as an Integrated Receiver Decoder (IRD). In the case of a DSS system, the transmission medium is a satellite transmission at an appropriate microwave band. Such transmissions are typically received by a satellite dish antenna with an integral Low Noise Block (LNB) that serves as a down-converter to convert the signal to a lower frequency for processing by the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The exemplary system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> further includes a TV <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, such as a digital television, having a display <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for displaying programming, an EPG, etc. The STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be coupled to the TV <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and various other audio/visual devices <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (such as audio systems, Personal Video Recorders (PVRs), Video Tape Recorders (VTRs), Video Cassette Recorders (VCRs) and the like), storage devices (e.g., hard disc drives) and Internet Appliances <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (such as email devices, home appliances, storage devices, network devices, and other Internet Enabled Appliances) by an appropriate interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which can be any suitable analog or digital interface. In one embodiment, interface <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> conforms to an interface standard such as the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) 1394 standard, but could also be wholly or partially supported by a DVI interface (Digital Visual Interface Digital Display Working Group, www.ddwg.org) or other suitable interface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may include a Central Processing Unit (CPU) such as a microprocessor and memory such as Random Access Memory (RAM), Read Only Memory (ROM), flash memory, mass storage such as a hard disc drive, floppy disc drive, optical disc drive or may accommodate other electronic storage media, etc. Such memory and storage media is suitable for storing data as well as instructions for programmed processes for execution on the CPU, as will be discussed later. Information and programs stored on the electronic storage media or memory may also be transported over any suitable transmission medium such as that illustrated as <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may include circuitry suitable for audio decoding and processing, the decoding of video data compressed in accordance with a compression standard such as the Moving Pictures Experts Group (MPEG) standard and other processing to form a controller or central hub. Alternatively, components of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be incorporated into the TV <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> itself, thus eliminating the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Further, a computer having a tuner device and modem may be equivalently substituted for the TV <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> By way of example, the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be coupled to devices such as a personal computer, video cassette recorder, camcorder, digital camera, personal digital assistant and other audio/visual or Internet related devices. In addition, a data transport architecture, such as that set forth by an industry group which includes Sony Corporation and known as the Home Audio-Video Interoperability (HAVi) architecture may be utilized to enable interoperability among devices on a network regardless of the manufacturer of the device. This forms a home network system wherein electronic devices and Internet appliances are compatible with each other. The STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> runs an operating system suitable for a home network system such as Sony Corporation&apos;s Aperios&trade; real time operating system. Other operating systems could also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes an infrared (IR) receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for receiving IR signals from an input device such as remote control <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, it is noted that many other control communication methods may be utilized besides IR, such as wired or wireless radio frequency, etc. In addition, it can be readily appreciated that the input device <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be any device suitable for controlling the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> such as a remote control, personal digital assistant, laptop computer, keyboard or computer mouse. In addition, an input device in the form of a control panel located on the TV <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> or the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also be coupled to an independent service provider (ISP) host <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> by a suitable connection including dial-up connections, DSL (Digital Subscriber Line) or the same transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> described above (e.g., using a cable modem) to, thus, provide access to services and content from the ISP and the Internet. The ISP host <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> provides various content to the user that is obtained from a content database <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also be used as an Internet access device to obtain information and content from remote servers such as remote server <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> via the Internet <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> using host <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> operating as an Internet portal, for example. In certain satellite STB environments, the data can be downloaded at very high speed from a satellite link, with asymmetrical upload speed from the set-top box provided via a dial-up or DSL connection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In accordance with embodiments of the present invention, the program listing database <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes not only conventional program listing data that can be presented to the viewer as a grid showing programs by channel and time, but also includes information that links certain of the programs (perhaps all) to video files containing previews of the program. These previews are routinely generated for use as commercials or, in the case of movies, advertisement trailer shown at other theater presentations of the movie. The previews can also be stored in the program listing database or otherwise in the EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. In certain embodiments, these previews are delivered by streaming video to the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, while in other embodiments, the previews are delivered as file downloads for storage at the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> or a storage device accessible by the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> While the arrangement illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a plurality of servers and databases depicted as independent devices, any one or more of the servers can operate as server software residing on a single computer. Moreover, although not explicitly illustrated, the servers may operate in a coordinated manner under centralized or distributed control to provide multiple services as a Multiple Service Operator (MSO) in a known manner. Additionally, the services provided by the servers shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> may actually reside in other locations, but from the perspective of the user of STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the service provider <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> serves as a portal to the services shown. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the illustration of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> represents a simplified depiction of a cable system configuration shown simply as service provider <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The actual configuration of the service provider&apos;s equipment is more likely to follow a configuration defined by the CableLabs OpenCable&trade; specification. The simplified illustration shown is intended to simplify the discussion of the service provider <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&apos;s operation without unnecessarily burdening the discussion with architectural details that will be evident to those skilled in the art. Those details can be found in the publicly available CableLabs OpenCable&trade; specification or in the text &ldquo;OpenCable Architecture (Fundamentals)&rdquo; by Michael Adams, Cisco Press, November 1999. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> typical system configuration for a digital Set-Top Box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is illustrated. In this exemplary Set-Top Box, the transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, such as a coaxial cable, is coupled by a suitable interface through a diplexer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to a tuner <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Tuner <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may, for example, include a broadcast in-band tuner for receiving content, an out-of-band (OOB) tuner for receiving data transmissions. A return path through diplexer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> provides an OOB return path for outbound data (destined for example for the head end). A separate tuner (not shown) may be provided to receive conventional RF broadcast television channels. Modulated information formatted, for example, as MPEG-2 information is then demodulated at a demodulator <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The demodulated information at the output of demodulator <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is provided to a demultiplexer and descrambler circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> where the information is separated into discrete channels of programming. The programming is divided into packets, each packet bearing an identifier called a Packet ID (PID) that identifies the packet as containing a particular type of data (e.g., audio, video, data). The demodulator and descrambler circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also decrypts encrypted information in accordance with a decryption algorithm to prevent unauthorized access to programming content, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Audio packets from the demultiplexer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (those identified with an audio PID) are decrypted and forwarded to an audio decoder <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> where they may be converted to analog audio to drive a speaker system (e.g., stereo or home theater multiple channel audio systems) or other audio system <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> (e.g., stereo or home theater multiple channel amplifier and speaker systems) or may simply provide decoded audio out at <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Video packets from the demultiplexer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (those identified with a video PID) are decrypted and forwarded to a video decoder <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. In a similar manner, data packets from the demultiplexer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (those identified with a data PID) are decrypted and forwarded to a data decoder <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Decoded data packets from data decoder <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> are sent to the set-top box&apos;s computer system via the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. A Central Processing Unit (CPU) <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> can thus access the decoded data from data decoder <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> via the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> (or a separate video bus). Video data decoded by video decoder <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is passed to a graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, which is a computer optimized to processes graphics information rapidly. Graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is particularly useful in processing graphics intensive data associated with Internet browsing, gaming and multimedia applications such as those associated with MHEG (Multimedia and Hypermedia information coding Experts Group) Set-Top Box applications. It should be noted, however, that the function of graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may be unnecessary in some set-top box designs having lower capabilities, and the function of the graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> may be handled by the CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> in some applications where the decoded video is passed directly from the demultiplexer <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to a video encoder. Graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> is also coupled to the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and operates under the control of CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Many Set-Top Boxes such as STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may incorporate a smart card reader <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> for communicating with a so called &ldquo;smart card,&rdquo; often serving as a Conditional Access Module (CAM). The CAM typically includes a central processor unit (CPU) of its own along with associated RAM and ROM memory. Smart card reader <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is used to couple the system bus of STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to the smart card serving as a CAM (not shown). Such smart card based CAMs are conventionally utilized for authentication of the user and authentication of transactions carried out by the user as well as authorization of services and storage of authorized cryptography keys. For example, the CAM can be used to provide the key for decoding incoming cryptographic data for content that the CAM determines the user is authorized to receive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can operate in a bidirectional communication mode so that data and other information can be transmitted not only from the system&apos;s head end to the end user, or from a service provider to the end user of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, but also, from the end user upstream using an out-of-band channel. In one embodiment, such data passes through the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to a modulator <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> through the diplexer <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and out through the transmission medium <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. This capability is used to provide a mechanism for the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and/or its user to send information to the head end (e.g., service requests or changes, registration information, etc.) as well as to provide fast outbound communication with the Internet or other services provided at the head end to the end user. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Set-Top Box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may include any of a plurality of I/O (Input/Output) interfaces represented by I/O interfaces <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> that permit interconnection of I/O devices to the set-top box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. By way of example, and not limitation, a serial RS-232 port <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> can be provided to enable interconnection to any suitable serial device supported by the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&apos;s internal software. Similarly, communication with appropriately compatible devices can be provided via an Ethernet port <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, a USB (Universal Serial Bus) port <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, an IEEE 1394 (so-called firewire&trade; or i-link&trade;) or IEEE 1394 wide port <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, S-video port <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> or infrared port <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Such interfaces can be utilized to interconnect the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with any of a variety of accessory devices such as storage devices, audio/visual devices <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, gaming devices (not shown), Internet Appliances <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> I/O interfaces <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> can include a modem (be it dial-up, cable, DSL or other technology modem) having a modem port <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> to facilitate high speed or alternative access to the Internet or other data communication functions. In one preferred embodiment, modem port <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is that of a DOCSIS (Data Over Cable System Interface Specification) cable modem to facilitate high speed network access over a cable system, and port <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> is appropriately coupled to the transmission medium embodied as a coaxial cable. Thus, the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can carry out bidirectional communication via the DOCSIS cable modem with the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> being identified by a unique IP address. The DOCSIS specification is publically available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> A PS/2 or other keyboard mouse/joystick interface such as <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> can be provided to permit ease of data entry to the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Such inputs provide the user with the ability to easily enter data and/or navigate using pointing devices. Pointing devices such as a mouse or joystick may be used in gaming applications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Of course, STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> also may incorporate basic video outputs <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> that can be used for direct connection to a television set such as <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> instead of (or in addition to) an IEEE 1394 connection such as that illustrated as <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, Video output <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> can provide composite video formatted as NTSC (National Television System Committee) video. In some embodiments, the video output <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> can be provided by a direct connection to the graphics processor <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> or the demultiplexer/descrambler <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> rather than passing through the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> as illustrated in the exemplary block diagram. S-Video signals from output <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> can be similarly provided without passing through the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> if desired in other embodiments. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The infrared port <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> can be embodied as an infrared receiver <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, to receive commands from an infrared remote control <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, infrared keyboard or other infrared control device. Although not explicitly shown, front panel controls may be used in some embodiments to directly control the operation of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> through a front panel control interface as one of interfaces <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. Selected interfaces such as those described above and others can be provided in STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in various combinations as required or desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> will more commonly, as time goes on, include a disc drive interface <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and disc drive mass storage <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> for user storage of content and data as well as providing storage of programs operating on CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may also include floppy disc drives, CD ROM drives, CD R/W drives, DVD drives, etc. CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, in order to operate as a computer, is coupled through the system bus <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> (or through a multiple bus architecture) to memory <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. Memory <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> may include a combination any suitable memory technology including Random Access Memory (RAM), Read Only Memory (ROM), Flash memory, Electrically Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory (EEPROM), etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> While the above exemplary system including STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is illustrative of the basic components of a digital Set-Top Box suitable for use with the present invention, the architecture shown should not be considered limiting since many variations of the hardware configuration are possible without departing from the present invention. The present invention could, for example, also be implemented in more advanced architectures such as that disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/473,625, filed Dec. 29, 1999, Docket No. SONY-50N3508 entitled &ldquo;Improved Internet Set-Top Box Having and In-Band Tuner and Cable Modem&rdquo; to Jun Maruo and Atsushi Kagami. This application describes a set-top box using a multiple bus architecture with a high level of encryption between components for added security. This application is hereby incorporated by reference as though disclosed fully herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In general, during operation of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an appropriate operating system <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> such as, for example, Sony Corporation&apos;s Aperios&trade; real time operating system is loaded into, or is permanently stored in, active memory along with the appropriate drivers for communication with the various interfaces. In other embodiments, other operating systems such as Microsoft Corporation&apos;s Windows CE&trade; could be used without departing from the present invention. Along with the operating system and associated drivers, the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> usually operates using browser software <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> in active memory or may permanently reside in ROM, EEPROM or Flash memory, for example. The browser software <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> typically operates as the mechanism for viewing not only web pages on the Internet, but also serves as the mechanism for viewing an Electronic Program Guide (EPG) formatted as an HTML document. The browser <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> can also provide the mechanism for viewing normal programming (wherein normal programming is viewed as an HTML video window&mdash;often occupying the entire area of screen <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> STB software architectures vary depending upon the operating system. However, in general, all such architectures generally include, at the lowest layer, various hardware interface layers. Next is an operating system layer as previously described. The software architectures of modern STB have generally evolved to include a next layer referred to as &ldquo;middleware.&rdquo; Such middleware permits applications to run on multiple platforms with little regard for the actual operating system in place. Middleware standards are still evolving at this writing, but are commonly based upon Javascript and HTML (hypertext Markup Language) virtual machines. At the top layer is the application layer where user applications and the like reside (e.g., browsing, email, EPG, Video On Demand (VOD), rich multimedia applications, pay per view, etc.). The current invention can be utilized with any suitable set-top box software and hardware architecture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, an exemplary EPG screen <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is illustrated showing one implementation of the present electronic program guide. In this exemplary guide, television channels are displayed in a grid arrangement with a column <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> to the left listing the available channel number and an identifier for the network or channel associated with the various rows. A time line <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is shown at the top of the grid. The remainder of the grid, shown as <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, presents the programming available in the particular time slots and channels shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> EPG screen <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> also has a region <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> that identifies the currently selected program as well as a region <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> that provides descriptive information about the currently playing program selection. The currently selected program <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> may be shown in reverse video, a distinct color, bolding, outlining or using some other visual clue to readily identify the currently selected program. Exemplary EPG screen <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> also has a video window <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> that can be used to display a still image associated with the currently selected program, an advertisement or other still image. Trademarks shown (e.g., 20<highlight><superscript>th </superscript></highlight>Century Fox, TBS, TNT, A&amp;E, CNN, etc.) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> are the property of their respective owners, and are used for exemplary purposes only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an embodiment of the present invention, a viewer may wish to find out more information about a future program. For example, the user may wish to find out more about program <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>. In some systems, selecting program <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> using commands from remote commander <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> cause information about the program (stored as system information from an MPEG transport stream) is displayed as <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. In accordance with the present invention, selection of the program <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> from the program grid using a specified &ldquo;preview&rdquo; command issued from the remote commander <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> causes the CPU <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to retrieve a video file (e.g., an MPEG video file) and play the moving video file in video window <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. For example, the video file may be a movie trailer or a television commercial spot advertising the particular program. In some embodiments, the video file may also contain advertising content for products, services or programming, providing an additional source of advertising revenue for the content provider or producer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the present invention, the video file is stored locally within disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. The preview file content of this disc drive. Many such preview files can be stored on disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> without sacrifice of large amounts of storage. For example, 35 movie previews lasting 30 seconds each can be stored in approximately 15 MB of storage assuming each 30 second preview is played at 114 Kbps (e.g., using MPEG 1 video and Audio Layer2). Additional storage (e.g., 750 KB) may be needed for an MPEG 1 player and an audio player implemented in software, but hardware alternatives can also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an embodiment of the invention, upon selecting a program and receiving a preview command, the CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> generates a menu window <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> of options that the user can select after initiating a preview. These options can include any number of functions with four exemplary options illustrated. The &ldquo;Return to Guide&rdquo; option halts the preview and returns the viewer to the previous state of the EPG. The &ldquo;Record&rdquo; option activates a personal video recorder (PVR) or PVR function of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (or activates a video tape recorder or PVR) to record the program being previewed. The &ldquo;Timer&rdquo; option instructs the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to select this program for viewing when it starts. The &ldquo;Info&rdquo; option takes the user to a screen having additional information about the selection (e.g., reviews, notes about the program, actors, etc.). Those skilled in the art will appreciate that many other options (or fewer options) may be implemented without departing from the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the program selected for preview can only be previewed if it is scheduled for a time in the future or the present. Previews of programs that have already been presented can thus be removed from the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to preserve storage space. The previews are thus downloaded from the EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> via cable modem or other communication media and stored in the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> until no longer potentially needed. Thus, the program preview files are provided to the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and stored on the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. The EPG is also sent from the server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and stored on the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> or other storage mechanism. Once the last presentation of a particular program has been made, the CPU <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> determines from the program guide that the program preview file does not correspond to a program to be available at a future time and deletes the program preview file from the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. The available previews are preferably mapped to the program in a table stored within the disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>. Whenever a new preview is received, the table is updated to reflect the availability of a new preview. Similarly, whenever a preview is no longer needed, it is deleted from the table. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, the program previewfiles are stored at the service provider head end <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> within EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Whenever a viewer issues a preview command, the EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is contacted by the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with a request to send the preview file. The EPG server <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> can then either download the file to the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>&apos;s disc drive <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, or can stream the video file to the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> for playback. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> An overview of the process just described is illustrated as process <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> starting at <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>. When the user activates the EPG by issuing a command from the remote commander <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> at <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, the system is placed in an EPG navigation mode at <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. If the user elects to preview a selection at <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>, the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> links to the appropriate preview file at <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> associated with the program selected by the user (as determined by a stored table mapping the preview file to the program). The preview file is then played in the video window <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> within the EPG at <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight>. When the preview is done at <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight>, control returns to <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> to await the next activation of the EPG. If in the meantime, at <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight>, the user issues a command, the video is halted at <highlight><bold>436</bold></highlight> so that the user command can be acted upon. If the command is a channel selection at <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>, the tuner <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> within the Set-Top Box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is directed to tune to a specified channel at <highlight><bold>444</bold></highlight> and control returns to <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. If the command is not a channel selection at <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>, but is another command at <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight>, the other command is acted on at <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> and control returns to <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a variation of this process shown as process <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>. In process <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, when the user elects to preview a program at <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>, the Set-Top Box <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> determines if the selected program time is prior to the current time at <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>. If so, an error message is issued at <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> and control returns to <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, the user is only permitted to view a preview of a program that will be appearing in the future. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been described in terms of a television Set-Top Box, the relevant workings of the STB <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be incorporated within the housing of a television set or other television receiver device without departing from the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will recognize that the present invention has been described in terms of exemplary embodiments based upon use of a programmed processor. However, the invention should not be so limited, since the present invention could be implemented using hardware component equivalents such as special purpose hardware and/or dedicated processors which are equivalents to the invention as described and claimed. Similarly, general purpose computers, microprocessor based computers, micro-controllers, optical computers, analog computers, multi-processor systems, dedicated processors and/or dedicated hard wired logic may be used to construct alternative equivalent embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the program steps and associated data used to implement the embodiments described above can be implemented using disc storage as well as other forms of storage including Read Only Memory (ROM) devices, Random Access Memory (RAM) devices; optical storage elements, magnetic storage elements, magneto-optical storage elements, flash memory, core memory and/or other equivalent storage technologies without departing from the present invention. Such alternative storage devices should be considered equivalents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The present invention is preferably implemented using a programmed processor executing programming instructions that are broadly described above in flow chart form that can be stored on any suitable electronic storage medium or transmitted over any suitable electronic communication medium. However, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the processes described above can be implemented in any number of variations and in many suitable programming languages without departing from the present invention. For example, the order of certain operations carried out can often be varied, additional operations can be added, or operations can be omitted without departing from the invention. Error trapping can be added and/or enhanced and variations can be made in user interface and information presentation without departing from the present invention. Such variations are contemplated and considered equivalent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in conjunction with specific embodiments, it is evident that many alternatives, modifications, permutations and variations will become apparent to those skilled in the art in light of the foregoing description. Accordingly, it is intended that the present invention embrace all such alternatives, modifications and variations as fall within the scope of the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of providing an electronic programming guide, comprising: 
<claim-text>presenting a listing of television programs to a viewer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping the specified program to a video file containing a preview of the specified program; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the command is transmitted from a remote commander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file comprises an MPEG video file containing video complying with an MPEG video standard. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the listing is presented to the user in the form of a grid showing television programming as a function of time. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, carried out in a television Set-Top Box, and wherein the video file is stored in a local disc drive accessible by the Set-Top Box. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file is stored at content provider site. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, carried out in a television Set-Top Box, and wherein the video file is sent to the Set-Top Box as a streaming video file in response to the command. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the video file is played, the video is displayed in a window of the electronic program guide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the window comprises an active video window displayed by a browser. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the playing comprises playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user only if at least a portion of the specified program is scheduled for airing at a time in the future. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the playing further comprises playing an advertisement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A television apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a programmed processor having access to a plurality of video files; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for presenting an electronic program guide to a display for display to a user; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiver that receives a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer program running on the programmed processor that maps the command to one of the plurality of files stored on the video device and plays the video file to the display to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the command is received from a remote commander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file comprises an MPEG video file containing video complying with an MPEG video standard. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the electronic program guide is presented to the user in the form of a grid showing television programming as a function of time. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file is stored in a local disc drive accessible by a television Set-Top Box. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file is stored at content provider site. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the video file is sent to the Set-Top Box as a streaming video file in response to the command. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein when the video file is played, the video is displayed in a window of the electronic program guide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the window comprises an active video window displayed by a browser. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the playing comprises playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user only if at least a portion of the specified program is scheduled for airing at a time in the future. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the playing further comprises playing an advertisement. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of providing an electronic programming guide from a television Set-Top Box, comprising: 
<claim-text>presenting a listing of television programs to a viewer in the form of a grid showing television programming as a function of time; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a command transmitted by the viewer from a remote commander for initiating a preview of a specified program; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping the specified program to a video file containing a preview of the specified program, the video file comprising an MPEG video file containing video complying with an MPEG video standard; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the video file is stored in a local disc drive accessible by the Set-Top Box; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining if at least a portion of the specified program is scheduled for airing at a time in the future; </claim-text>
<claim-text>if so, playing the video file in a window of the electronic program guide to provide a preview of the specified program to the user by displaying the video in an active video window displayed by a browser running on the programmed processor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>if not, displaying an error message. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. An electronic storage medium storing instructions which, when executed on a programmed processor, carry out a method of providing an electronic programming guide, comprising: 
<claim-text>presenting a listing of television programs to a viewer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a command from the viewer for initiating a preview of a specified program; </claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping the specified program to a video file containing a preview of the specified program; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>playing the video file to provide a preview of the specified program to the user. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A method of providing program previews to a viewer, comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving a program preview file from a server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the program preview file in a storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving a program guide from the server; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining from the program guide that the program preview file does not correspond to a program to be available at a future time; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>deleting the program preview file from the storage device.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030005429A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
