<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001362A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001362A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001362</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09974035</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011010</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B62D053/06</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B60D001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>441200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>280</class>
<subclass>490100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Adjustable height gooseneck coupler</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301688</doc-number>
<document-date>20010628</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Edward</given-name>
<middle-name>Wayne</middle-name>
<family-name>Ebey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Delavan</city>
<state>WI</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Edgar A. Zarins</name-1>
<name-2>Masco Corporation</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>21001 Van Born Road</address-1>
<city>Taylor</city>
<state>MI</state>
<postalcode>48180</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An adjustable gooseneck coupler for connecting a trailer to a towing vehicle. The trailer includes a front overhang from which the gooseneck coupler depends. The towing vehicle includes a bed having a ball selectively received within a ball housing of the coupler. The gooseneck coupler includes telescopingly adjustable inner and outer tubes to adjust the length of the gooseneck and therefore the height of the trailer overhang relative to the truck bed. The adjustable inner and outer tubes are locked against relative movement by clamping screws. The clamping screws are arranged on the outer tube in longitudinal pairs at a triangular orientation to maximize the clamping force. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/301,688 filed on Jun. 28, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> I. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a coupler for securing a trailer to a towing vehicle and, in particular, to a coupler of a trailer which engages a ball within a truck bed and includes a system for adjusting the length of the coupler to form a level load. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> II. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> With the increased popularity of recreational vehicles, manufacturers are designing and building vehicles of varying proportions and features. While many recreational vehicles, or trailers, continue to be hitched to the rear end of a towing vehicle through a coupler on the trailer and a hitch on the towing vehicle, larger vehicles have been developed which include a portion extending over the back of the towing vehicle. Examples of such large vehicles include fifth wheel trailers which couple to a specialized hitch mounted within the bed of a pick-up truck and trailers incorporating a gooseneck coupler which is secured to a ball mounted inside the pickup truck bed, usually directly over the rear axle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, the over-bed towed vehicles are dependent upon the position or height of the bed of the pick-up truck. Larger pick-up trucks will have a rear bed which is higher than the bed of small trucks. Including four wheel drive capacity to a truck raises the vehicle, and therefore the bed, even further. While these differences are less of a concern in unoccupied recreational vehicles, horse trailers and equipment trailers require a level ride to prevent injury to the animals and prevent shifting of cargo. Even with unoccupied trailers, adjustment may be desirable to ensure the trailer will be towed at the correct towing angle for uniform weight distribution. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention overcomes the disadvantages of the prior couplers by providing a gooseneck coupler which can be adjusted in length to adjust the height of the towed vehicle when coupled to the towing vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The adjustable gooseneck coupler of the present invention is adapted for use with trailers having a portion or front end which is designed to extend over the cargo bed of a towing vehicle. The rear of the trailer is supported by one or more axles such that the trailer will be towed or pulled down the road by the towing vehicle. Extending downwardly from the front overhang of the trailer is a gooseneck coupler embodying the present invention. The gooseneck coupler is fixedly secured at its upper end to the trailer and includes a coupler assembly at its lower end for releasably engaging a ball mounted within the cargo bed of the towing vehicle. The coupler assembly includes a housing for rotatably receiving the ball allowing the truck and trailer to pivot during turns. A lock selectively secures the ball within the housing to prevent separation of the gooseneck coupler from the ball mounted within the truck. The lock is releasable to facilitate separation of the trailer from the towing vehicle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The gooseneck coupler of the present invention is adjustable so as to vary its length and therefore the distance between the trailer overhang and the coupler assembly which must be secured to the truck bed. The coupler includes telescoping inner and outer tubes. The inner and outer tubes are locked at the desired length by a plurality of clamping screws which extend through the wall of the outer tube to selectively engage the inner tube. Tightening of the clamping screws pushes the inner tube against the opposite side of the outer tube to prevent telescoping movement of the inner tube relative to the outer tube. In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, two pairs of longitudinally aligned clamping screws are employed to form a triangular clamping in conjunction with the opposite wall of the outer tube. The two sets of screws are spaced approximately 120&deg; apart to create the triangulation. This orientation of the clamping screws provides improved retention and less deformation of the inner tube and screws. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The length of the coupler may be adjusted by loosening the clamping screws allowing the inner tube to move freely within the outer tube. At the desired position, the screws are tightened to prevent relative movement. This adjustment allows the trailer overhang to be leveled no matter what the height of the truck bed may be to ensure level towing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Other objects, features and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following detailed description taken in accordance with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be more fully understood by reference to the following detailed description of a preferred embodiment of the present invention when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawing, in which like reference characters refer to like parts throughout the views and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a towing vehicle connected to a trailer incorporating an adjustable gooseneck coupler embodying the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a partial perspective view of the adjustable gooseneck coupler; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the outer tube carrying the clamping screws; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a transverse cross-sectional view taken along lines <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a side view of the outer tube; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a first side view of the inner tube; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a second side view of the inner tube; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a transverse cross-sectional view taken along lines <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF A PREFERRED EMBODIMENT OF THE PRESENT INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, three is shown a towing vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as a pick-up truck having a cargo bed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and a passenger cab <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and a trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> adapted to be towed by the vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes a housing compartment <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> supported on at least one set of wheel axles <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to roll along the road <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> of the present invention has an overhanging portion <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> which extends above the truck cargo bed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> when the vehicles <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are coupled. The truck bed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a hitch ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or similar structure for detachably receiving a gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in accordance with the present invention. It is desirable that the towed vehicle <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> be maintained level to the road <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> when coupled to truck beds <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of different heights and the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is adjustable in length to achieve this purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 8</cross-reference>, the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the present invention includes a pair of telescoping tubes&mdash;inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is fixedly attached to the underside of the trailer overhang <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> received within the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes a coupler assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> at the lower end of inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The coupler assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is utilized to detachably couple the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the towing vehicle <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as will be subsequently described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In order to secure the telescoping gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at a predetermined length, a series of clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are mounted to the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The prior art telescoping couplers would utilize only a single clamping screw to prevent relative movement of the tubes. The present invention contemplates clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> at offset orientation to create a triangular clamping force. In a preferred embodiment, the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> carries two pairs of clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> offset on the periphery of the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to create the triangulation. One such orientation is a 120&deg; offset to form an equilateral triangulation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes a corresponding number of apertures <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with threaded nuts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> welded in alignment therewith. The clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are threadably received within the nuts <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for movement into and out of the apertures <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> include heads <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for manipulation by an appropriate tool (not shown). Rotation of the screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in a first direction will cause the screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to move radially inwardly into locking engagement within the inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Rotation of the screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in a second opposite direction will cause the screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to move radially outwardly freeing the inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> for movement relative to the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and adjustment of the length of the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. To prevent relative movement of the tubes, the clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> should be moved radially inwardly to engage and push on the inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The clamping screws <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> are tightened sufficiently to push the inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> against the opposite side of the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> creating the triangular clamping force depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this manner, the inner tube <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the outer tube <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be locked together at the desired position to form a gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the required length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the present invention connects the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to the towing vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> such that the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is maintained in a substantially level position. The length of the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is adjusted so that it spans the distance between the underside of the trailer overhang <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the normal position of the truck bed <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The truck <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is backed beneath the overhang <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> until the hitch ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> aligns with the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment of the coupler assembly <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is positioned within a housing <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> having a semi-spherical configuration. Once the ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is nested within the coupler housing <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a coupler handle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is pivoted to deploy a latch member <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> against the hitch ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and prevent its withdrawal from the housing <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Movement of the handle <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction will release the hitch ball <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> for withdrawal of the gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and separation of the towing vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> from the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Thus, the adjustable gooseneck coupler <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of the present invention facilitates towing of the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> at a level position while also providing simple disconnection of the trailer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from the towing vehicle <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The foregoing detailed description has been given for clearness of understanding only and no unnecessary limitations should be understood therefrom as some modifications will be obvious to those skilled in the art without departing from the scope and spirit of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An adjustable gooseneck coupler adapted to be fixedly secured to a trailer for selective coupling engagement with a towing vehicle, said coupler comprising: 
<claim-text>a first elongated member secured to the trailer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second elongated member telescopically engaging said first elongated member for adjustment of the length of said coupler; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for locking said first and second elongated members against telescoping movement to fix said length of said coupler; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a coupler assembly mounted to a lower end of said second elongated member for selective coupling engagement with the towing vehicle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said means for locking said first and second elongated members against telescoping movement includes a plurality of clamping members mounted on one of said first and second elongated members for locking engagement with an other of said first and second elongated members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first elongated member is an outer tubular member and said second elongated member is an inner tubular member telescopically received within said outer tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said means for locking includes two pairs of clamping members mounted to said outer tubular member for selective locking engagement with said inner tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said pairs of clamping members are circumferentially spaced along the periphery of said outer tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said pair of clamping members are spaced 120&deg; along the periphery of said outer tubular member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The coupler as defined in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said clamping members are clamping screws extending through a wall of said outer tubular member for selective engagement with said inner tubular member.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001362A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
