<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003757A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003757A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003757</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10140637</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020507</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/461</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/302</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>710000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride in semiconductor structures</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10140637</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020507</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09755522</doc-number>
<document-date>20010105</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09755522</doc-number>
<document-date>20010105</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09614396</doc-number>
<document-date>20000712</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6423644</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Padmapani</given-name>
<family-name>Nallan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hakeem</given-name>
<family-name>Oluseyi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Stanford</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Patent Counsel</name-1>
<name-2>Applied Materials, Inc.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 450 A</address-1>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>95052</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention relates to a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride in semiconductor structures, and particularly to the etching of gate electrodes which require precise control over the etching process. We have discovered a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride which permits precise etch profile control while providing excellent selectivity, of at least 175:1, for example, in favor of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride rather than an adjacent oxide layer. Typically, the oxide is selected from silicon oxide, silicon oxynitride, tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, and combinations thereof. The method appears to be applicable to tungsten or tungsten nitride, whether deposited by physical vapor deposition (PVD) or chemical vapor deposition (CVD). In particular, an initial etch chemistry, used during the majority of the tungsten or tungsten nitride etching process (the main etch), employs the use of a plasma source gas where the chemically functional etchant species are generated from a combination of sulfur hexafluoride (SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>) and nitrogen (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), or in the alternative, from a combination of nitrogen trifluoride (NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>), chlorine (Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), and carbon tetrafluoride (CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). Toward the end of the main etching process, a second chemistry is used in which the chemically functional etchant species are generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. This final portion of the etch process may be referred to as an &ldquo;overetch&rdquo; process, since etching is carried out to at least the surface underlying the tungsten or tungsten nitride. However, this second etch chemistry may optionally be divided into two steps, where the plasma source gas oxygen content and plasma source power are increased in the second step. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. application Ser. No. 09/614,396, filed Jul. 12, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention pertains to a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride electrode gates in semiconductor structures. In particular, one etch chemistry is used during the majority of the etching process and a second etch chemistry is used toward the end of the etching process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Brief Description of the Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor devices as a whole typically include self-aligned contact structures and gate electrodes which are fabricated from multiple film layers of differing compositions. Tungsten nitride films have previously been used as barrier layers, and tungsten has been used as a conductor in various semiconductor device structures. Recently, both tungsten and tungsten nitride have been developing as gate materials, as a result of smaller device geometries. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In many instances, the tungsten or tungsten nitride film (layer) is deposited over a thin (less than about 50 &angst; thick) silicon oxide inorganic dielectric layer. During patterned etching of the multiple film layer structure, it is desired to plasma dry etch through the tungsten or tungsten nitride layer and to stop etching at the surface of the silicon oxide layer. This makes it important that the etch selectivity for etching of tungsten or tungsten nitride (in preference over silicon oxide) be high. (The term &ldquo;selectivity&rdquo; is typically used to refer to a ratio of etch rates of two materials.) Further, as the device geometries become smaller, etching of layers of material must be more precise, providing a profile which permits placement of more devices over a given surface area. In the case of a tungsten gate, for example, the gate may be in the form of a thin line or pad, and the cross-sectional profile of the etched gate feature is preferably one where the sidewalls of the etched feature are essentially perpendicular to an underlying silicon oxide substrate layer, for example. This means the tungsten must be completely etched to the surface of the silicon oxide substrate layer (no residual &ldquo;feet&rdquo; at the bottom of the etched tungsten sidewall). Control of the etch process is critical in providing proper etched tungsten feature profile while avoiding etching away critical thickness of the underlying silicon oxide film substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One reference describes a dry etching method wherein a multilayer film including one selected from tungsten, molybdenum, and a silicide thereof, is etched as the first layer. Underlying the &ldquo;first layer&rdquo; is a second layer of polycrystalline silicon, which overlies a silicon oxide insulation film. The etching step for the first layer uses a plasma etchant source gas made up of a first gas selected from fluorine, sulfur hexafluoride, and nitrogen trifluoride, or a mixture gas containing the first gas and a second gas selected from hydrogen chloride, hydrogen bromide, chlorine, bromine, and carbon tetrachloride. Etching of the second layer of polycrystalline silicon is carried out using a plasma etchant source gas made up of the second gas and a third gas selected from an inert gas, nitrogen gas, oxygen gas, silicon tetrachloride gas, and carbon monoxide gas. In the second etch step, the amount of the third gas added to the second gas should preferably be in the range between 0 and 10 volume % of the total etching gas mixture. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Another reference discloses a method for fabricating a silicon-based MOS transistor having an inverse-T refractory metal gate structure. The gate fabricated comprises a main CVD tungsten portion and a lower sputtered tungsten portion outwardly extending from the bottom of the CVD portion. A Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>plasma etch is used to etch the CVD tungsten layer and a chemical etch (KH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>/KOH/K<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>Fe(CN)<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>) is used to etch the sputtered tungsten portion. The sputtered tungsten layer is said to act as a shield to protect the underlying gate oxide layer from ion damage throughout the fabrication process. In particular, the sputtered tungsten is said to be more resistant to Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>reactive ion etch than is CVD tungsten. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Another reference describes a method of fabricating sidewall spacers for a self-aligned contact hole. A metal, such as tungsten, is RIE etched using a conventional etchback procedure, without the use of a photoresist masking, using a Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>&mdash;BCl<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;Ar etchant gas mixture for plasma generation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> For further background information, the reader is directed to U.S. Pat. No. 5,295,923, to Hori et al.; U.S. Pat. No. 5,599,725, to Dorleans et al.; and U.S. Pat. No. 6,033,962, to Jeng et al. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride in semiconductor structures, and particularly to the etching of gate electrodes which require precise control over the etching process. We have discovered a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride which permits precise etch profile control while providing excellent selectivity in favor of etching tungsten (or tungsten nitride) rather than a thin underlying oxide layer. Typically, the oxide is selected from silicon oxide, silicon oxynitride, tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, and combinations thereof. The method appears to be applicable to tungsten or tungsten nitride, whether deposited by physical vapor deposition (PVD) or chemical vapor deposition (CVD). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In particular, an initial etch chemistry, used during the majority of the tungsten or tungsten nitride etching process (the main etch), employs the use of a plasma source gas where the chemically functional etchant species are typically generated from a combination of sulfur hexafluoride (SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>) and nitrogen (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), or in the alternative, from a combination of nitrogen trifluoride (NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>), chlorine (Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), and carbon tetrafluoride (CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). Toward the end of the main etching process, a second chemistry is used in which the chemically functional etchant species are generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. This final portion of the etch process may be referred to as an &ldquo;overetch&rdquo; process, since etching is carried out to at least the surface underlying the tungsten or tungsten nitride. However, this second etch chemistry may optionally be divided into two steps, where the plasma source gas oxygen content and plasma source power are increased in the second step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> We have discovered that an unexpectedly high etch selectivity for tungsten in preference over an underlying oxide layer (in the range of 175:1, for tungsten:silicon oxide, for example) may be obtained when a sufficiently high concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is used in combination with a sufficiently high plasma density. In particular, when the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>concentration is greater than about 20% by volume in the plasma source gas, further increases in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>content have a limited effect at plasma densities below about 8&times;10<highlight><superscript>10</superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, because there is insufficient power input to energize the active oxygen species. To obtain selectivity in favor of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to an underlying oxide layer, it is necessary to increase both the oxygen content of the plasma source gas and the source power applied to create and maintain the plasma. For example, at a plasma density of about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, and a substrate bias voltage of about &minus;90 V (about 90 W applied bias), an increase in plasma source gas oxygen content from about 30 volume percent to about 40 volume percent produces an increase in selectivity for etching tungsten relative to silicon oxide from about 40:1 to about 75:1. However, at 40 volume percent O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, if the plasma density is increased to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, the selectivity for etching tungsten relative to silicon oxide unexpectedly increases from about 75:1 to about 160:1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Although carrying out the &ldquo;overetch&rdquo; step at the conditions which produce the highest selectivity protects the underlying oxide layer, the etched tungsten or tungsten nitride feature profile may be affected by the rapid tungsten etch rates obtained (about 1800 &angst; per minute at the conditions which produce 175:1 tungsten:silicon oxide selectivity). To enable maintenance of feature profile while removing residual tungsten &ldquo;feet&rdquo; at the base of a feature, it may be advantageous to etch under conditions which provide a lower selectivity, of about 30:1 tungsten:silicon oxide, for example, and a tungsten etch rate of about 1000 &angst; per minute, and then change process conditions to those which provide a selectivity of 175:1 tungsten:silicon oxide and a tungsten etch rate of about 10-15 &angst; per minute for a limited time at the end of the etch, to clean residue off the oxide flat surface surrounding the etched feature in general. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> When the underlying dielectric layer comprises tantalum pentoxide, we have discovered that the source gas composition and process conditions described above provide an almost infinite selectivity for etching tungsten relative to the underlying tantalum pentoxide layer. This extraordinarily high tungsten:tantalum pentoxide etch selectivity allows a thinner tantalum pentoxide dielectric layer to be used (relative to a corresponding silicon oxide layer). The tantalum pentoxide layer typically may have a thickness of less than about 100 &angst;, preferably within the range of about 30 &angst; to about 50 &angst;. The thinness of the oxide layer can be important in terms of increasing a semiconductor device speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> We have discovered that tantalum pentoxide is more resistant to ion bombardment than silicon oxide; this permits a higher substrate bias power to be used during the tungsten overetch step when tantalum pentoxide is used as the underlying oxide layer. The use of a higher bias power (from about 100 W up to about 300 W) during the overetch step provides improved profile control (i.e., a more vertical profile is obtained), while maintaining a high selectivity for etching tungsten relative to the underlying tantalum pentoxide. When a higher bias power is employed, a plasma source gas having a lower oxygen content can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> When the underlying oxide layer comprises tantalum pentoxide, a tungsten etch rate of about 2000 &angst; per minute can be achieved while maintaining a tungsten:tantalum pentoxide etch selectivity of about 75:1 or better. In particular, one etch process includes using a plasma source gas having a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of about 20%, with a plasma density within the range of about 4.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 6.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, a plasma source power within the range of about 400 W to about 600 W, a substrate bias power of about 175 W, and a process chamber pressure of about 4 mTorr, for example. To enable maintenance of feature profile while removing residual tungsten &ldquo;feet&rdquo; at the base of a feature, it may be advantageous to adjust the etch conditions toward the end of the etch. For example, the final etch conditions may provide a selectivity of at least 175:1 tungsten: tantalum pentoxide, where the tungsten etch rate is less than about 1000 &angst; per minute. This etch selectivity and etch rate can be obtained by using a plasma source gas having a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of about 20%, with a plasma density of about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, a plasma source power of about 200 W, a substrate bias power of about 175 W, and a process chamber pressure of about 6 mTorr, for example.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a schematic of the plasma processing apparatus which was used to carry out the etching processes described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> show schematics of photomicrographs of etched tungsten when no overetch step is used, i.e., there is no change in the etch chemistry toward the end of the tungsten etching, and the etch is stopped in sufficient time to avoid etching an underlying silicon oxide substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a schematic of a photomicrograph of etched tungsten where there is a change in the etch chemistry toward the end of the tungsten etching, and etching is permitted to continue to the surface of the silicon oxide substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graph showing that an increase in oxygen content of a plasma source gas has a diminishing effect on the etch rate of a silicon oxide substrate, when all other process variables are held constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a graph showing the effect of increasing the plasma source power on the etch rate of tungsten; the etch rate of silicon oxide; and on the selectivity (in terms of an increase in etch rate of tungsten relative to the etch rate of silicon oxide) during an overetch step, when the oxygen concentration is about 20% by volume. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph showing tungsten etch rate in an overetch step, as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph showing silicon oxide etch rate in an overetch step, as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph showing selectivity (etch rate ratio of W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> shows a beginning semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> for performing an embodiment of the method of the invention for etching tungsten, when the underlying dielectric layer is tantalum pentoxide. The semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> includes, from top to bottom, a patterned silicon nitride hard mask layer <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>, a patterned silicon oxynitride ARC layer <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>, a tungsten layer <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>, a tungsten nitride wetting layer <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>, and a tantalum pentoxide layer <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>, all deposited on a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>. The relative thicknesses of the film stack layers are not shown to scale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> shows the semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> after etching through a major portion of the tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>/tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> during the main etch step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</cross-reference> shows the semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> after performance of the overetch step. The entire thickness of the tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>/tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> has been etched through, exposing the upper surface of the tantalum pentoxide layer <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The present disclosure relates to a method of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride in semiconductor structures. In particular, the method pertains to the etching of feature sizes of less than 0.5 &mgr;m, where control of etch selectivity of tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to a thin layer (typically less than about 50 &angst;) of an underlying oxide is of primary importance. The term &ldquo;feature&rdquo; typically refers to metal lines, trenches and openings in a dielectric layer, as well as other structures which make up the topography of the substrate surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In particular, an initial etch chemistry, used during the majority of the tungsten or tungsten nitride etching process, is typically one employing a plasma source gas comprising at least one halogen-based chemically functional etchant species. The halogen is typically fluorine, chlorine, or combinations thereof. A source gas comprising fluorine species is preferably used, because the fluorine is capable of removing oxides and other residues which may form on the surface of the tungsten if it is exposed to air during processing. If the plasma source gas used during the main tungsten etch step does not include fluorine species (for example, if Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is used), a breakthrough etch step employing a plasma generated from a fluorine-containing gas may be needed in order to remove the tungsten oxide from the substrate surface prior to etching of the tungsten layer. Typical process conditions for the breakthrough etch are as follows: 50-200 sccm CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>; 4-10 mTorr process chamber pressure; 300-1000 W source power; 40-200 W substrate bias power; and 50&deg; C. substrate temperature. Other fluorine-containing gases, such as SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>or NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, for example, can be used in place of, or in combination with, CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. A non-reactive diluent gas, such as, for example, argon, may be used in combination with the fluorine-containing gas. A typical duration for the breakthrough etch is approximately 10 seconds. The tungsten main etch is preferably performed using a plasma source gas where the chemically functional etchant species are generated from sulfur hexafluoride (SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>) and nitrogen (N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>), or from a combination of NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. These etch chemistries provide a rapid tungsten etch rate with excellent etch profile characteristics, and do not require the performance of a breakthrough etch prior to the main tungsten etch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> For example, in one embodiment, the main etch is carried out using a source gas consisting of SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. The volumetric flow rates for SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>typically range from about 30 sccm to about 100 sccm in a CENTURA&reg; DPS&trade; processing chamber. The volumetric flow rates for N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>typically range from about 30 sccm to about 100 sccm as well. The preferred volumetric ratio of SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>:N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>generally ranges from about 20:50 to about 60:10. The process chamber pressure ranges from about 2 mTorr to about 20 mTorr, and is preferably maintained at a pressure within a range of about 2 mTorr to about 10 mTorr. The substrate temperature ranges from about 20&deg; C. to about 100&deg; C., with lower temperatures being preferred, since apparatus costs are lower and the possibility of damage to a gate oxide is reduced. The applied plasma source power ranges from about 200 W to about 2000 W, and the applied substrate biasing power ranges from about 40 W to about 200 W. (The term &ldquo;plasma source power&rdquo; typically refers to the power that is responsible for sustaining the plasma by providing a major portion of the energy to ionize the neutral species in the chamber, while the term &ldquo;substrate bias power&rdquo; typically refers to the power applied to the substrate to attract high energy plasma species toward the substrate.) Using conditions within the ranges just described, adjusted for apparatus variables, a tungsten or tungsten nitride etch rate ranging from about 1500 to about 4000 &angst; per minute is obtained. During the etching of fine (about 0.15 &mgr;m in width) lines, the profile of the line sidewall relative to the underlying substrate surface is vertical at about 88&deg; to 90&deg; (discounting &ldquo;feet&rdquo; which may be formed near the base of the sidewall). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Toward the end of the etching process, a-second chemistry is used in which the chemically functional etchant species are generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. The process during etch of the remaining portion of the tungsten may be referred to as an overetch process, since the etch is carried out to the surface of an underlying film surface and may etch for a limited distance into the underlying film surface. However, this second etch chemistry may optionally be divided into two steps, where the oxygen content and plasma source power are increased during the second step. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> To obtain a satisfactory etch rate for the tungsten or tungsten nitride and the desired selectivity in favor of etching tungsten relative to an underlying silicon oxide gate layer, the volumetric percentage of the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>source gas mixture is controlled to range from greater than 20% up to about 45%. Preferably, the volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>/O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>source gas mixture ranges from about 35% to about 45%. However, to obtain the benefit of the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>content specified above, the plasma density in the etch process chamber must be sufficiently high. We have determined that a plasma density of at least about 8&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(a plasma source power of about 800 W in a CENTURA&reg; DPS&trade; processing chamber available from Applied Materials, Inc., of Santa Clara, Calif.) is required to obtain benefit from increasing the volumetric percentage of oxygen above 20%. (The term &ldquo;decoupled plasma source&rdquo; or &ldquo;DPS&rdquo; as used herein refers to a plasma etch apparatus with separate controls for the inductively coupled RF source power used to generate and maintain a plasma and the bias power applied to a semiconductor substrate to direct high energy species toward the substrate). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> An alternative to using a single overetch step is to use a two-step overetch process. For example, after the main etch step, a first overetch step may be carried out in which the plasma source gas composition is a combination of Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, where the volumetric content of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>ranges from greater than 20% to about 35%. The plasma density typically ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(800 W applied source power and a process chamber pressure of 4-6 mTorr) to about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(1600 W applied source power and a process chamber pressure of 4-6 mTorr). The process chamber pressure may range from about 2 mTorr to about 10 mTorr, and preferably between about 2 mTorr and 6 mTorr. The substrate temperature ranges from about 20&deg; C. to about 1001&deg; C. The applied substrate biasing power ranges from about 40 W to about 200 W. Using conditions within these ranges, adjusted for apparatus variables, a &ldquo;foot&rdquo; which forms at the bottom of the fine line can be removed, while maintaining the line profile at the vertical 88&deg; to 90&deg; profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, a second overetch or finishing step is carried out, to clean etch residue from the surface of an underlying thin oxide film, without significant etching into the film (less than 10% of the thin oxide film thickness is etched). In the second overetch step, the selectivity in favor of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to an underlying oxide film is critical. It is desired to remove tungsten or tungsten nitride residue from the flat surface of the thin oxide layer surrounding the etched feature without etching through the thin oxide layer. Again, the chemical etchants in the plasma source gas are Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, where the volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in the mixture typically ranges from about 36% to about 41%. The plasma density typically ranges from about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, with the other process conditions being the same as those specified above for the first overetch step. A tungsten etch rate under these process conditions is about 1750 &angst; per minute, while the selectivity (W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) is about 175:1. Increased plasma source gas O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>content and increased plasma densities are expected to be useful as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The selectivity of 175:1 obtained using the process conditions just described may be compared with the selectivity obtained using other process conditions which, at first glance, do not appear to be significantly different, but which provide surprisingly different results. For example, a change in the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate to provide a volumetric concentration of of 36%, in combination with a plasma density of 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(1600 W), provides a W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>selectivity of about 75:1; and a volumetric concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of 20%, in combination with a plasma density of 1.5&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>(1500 W), provides a W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>selectivity of about 28:1. As these data indicate, there is an unexpected increase in selectivity in favor of etching tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to silicon oxide which occurs as a result of increasing the oxygen flow rate and the plasma density above particular ranges simultaneously. This is further illustrated in the Examples provided below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The oxide layer underlying the tungsten or tungsten nitride layer may alternatively comprise tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, or silicon oxynitride, instead of silicon oxide. We have discovered that, when the underlying oxide layer comprises tantalum pentoxide, that a higher substrate bias power can be employed during the tungsten overetch step. The use of a higher bias power (about 100 W up to about 300 W) during the overetch step provides improved profile control (i.e., a more vertical profile is obtained), while maintaining a high selectivity (at least 75:1) for etching tungsten relative to the underlying tantalum pentoxide. Typically, a plasma source gas having a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>within the range of about 20% to about 50% is employed, with a plasma density within the range of about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. In the exemplary DPS system, this can be achieved using a plasma source power within the range of about 200 W to about 1800 W, a substrate bias power within the range of about 100 W to about 200 W, and a process chamber pressure within the range of about 2 mTorr to about 10 mTorr. Tungsten etch rates of greater than 1000 &angst; per minute are typically obtained using this process regime to etch tungsten over an underlying tantalum pentoxide layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As a preface to the detailed description of the Examples, it should be noted that, as used in this specification and the appended claims, the singular forms &ldquo;a&rdquo;, &ldquo;an&rdquo;, and &ldquo;the&rdquo; include plural referents, unless the context clearly dictates otherwise. Thus, for example, the term &ldquo;a semiconductor&rdquo; includes a variety of different materials which are known to have the behavioral characteristics of a semiconductor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> 1. An Apparatus for Practicing the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The embodiment etch processes described herein were carried out in a CENTURA&reg; Integrated Processing System, available from Applied Materials, Inc., of Santa Clara, Calif. Although the etch process chamber used in the EXAMPLES presented herein is shown in schematic in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, any of the etch processors available in the industry should be able to take advantage of the etch chemistry described herein, with some adjustment to other process parameters. The equipment shown in schematic in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> includes a Decoupled Plasma Source (DPS) of the kind described by Yan Ye et al. at the Proceedings of the Eleventh International Symposium of Plasma Processing, May 7, 1996, and as published in the Electrochemical Society Proceedings, Volume 96-12, pp. 222-233 (1996). The plasma processing chamber enables the processing of an 8 inch (200 mm) diameter wafer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a schematic of a side view of an individual CENTURA&reg; DPS&trade; polysilicon etch chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The etch chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> consists of an upper chamber <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> having a ceramic dome <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and a lower chamber <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. The lower chamber <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> includes a monopolar electrostatic chuck (ESC) cathode <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Gas is introduced into the chamber via gas injection nozzles <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> for uniform gas distribution. Chamber pressure is controlled by a closed-loop pressure control system (not shown) using a throttle valve <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. During processing, a substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is introduced into the lower chamber <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> through inlet <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is held in place by means of a static charge generated on the surface of electrostatic chuck (ESC) cathode <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> by applying a DC voltage to a conductive layer (not shown) located under a dielectric film (not shown) on the chuck surface. The cathode <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and substrate <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are then raised by means of a wafer lift <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and sealed against the upper chamber <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> in position for processing. Etch gases are introduced into the upper chamber <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> via gas injection nozzles <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. The etch chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> uses an inductively coupled plasma source power <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and matching network <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> operating at 12.56 MHz for generating and sustaining a medium to high density plasma. The wafer is biased with an RF source <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and matching network <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> operating at 13.56 MHz. Plasma source power <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> and substrate biasing means <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are controlled by separate controllers (not shown). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">II. EXAMPLES OF EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> shows a cross-sectional side view schematic of an etched tungsten structure <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, where the etched pattern is lines <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and spaces <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. The line width is approximately 0.165 &mgr;m, and the space width is approximately 0.21 &mgr;m. The structure includes a thin (&ap;45 A) silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> on a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, overlying silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> is a 1650 &angst; thick layer of tungsten <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, a 400 &angst; thick image-focusing antireflective coating (ARC) layer <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, and the residue <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> of a photoresist layer which was used to pattern the etched structure <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The tungsten layer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> includes a thin (&tilde;100 &angst;) wetting layer of tungsten nitride (not shown) which aids in adhesion of the tungsten to the silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. The tungsten nitride is etched during the same etch process as the tungsten. Therefore, as used herein, the term &ldquo;tungsten layer&rdquo; refers to a layer of tungsten, optionally in combination with a thin underlying layer of tungsten nitride. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> shows a more three-dimensional view of the same etched structure <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, showing the surface finish <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> of the etched tungsten in the bottom of a trench (space <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>), and the smoother upper surface <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> of the overlying photoresist layer residue <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Both Figures show a remaining unetched tungsten thickness <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> overlying upper surface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>. The unetched tungsten thickness <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is about 0.023 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The tungsten <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> etch was carried out using only a single etch chemistry, in which the etchant species in the plasma were SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>at 30 sccm and N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at 50 sccm. (There was no second etch chemistry used to etch the final portion of the tungsten layer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> to the surface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight>, i.e., there was no overetch carried out.) Other etch process conditions were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 4 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was about 500 W; the substrate bias power was about 80 W. The etch profile obtained was good, with the sidewall angle of the etched lines <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> from silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> surface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> being about 89&deg;; however, there was some tapering of the profile at the base of the line, since the tungsten was not etched all the way to the surface <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. The tungsten etch rate was about 1500 &angst; per minute. The term &ldquo;tapered&rdquo; profile, with reference to an etched pattern of lines and spaces, refers to a cross-sectional profile where the width of the line is wider at the base of the line than at the top surface of the line. A &ldquo;vertical profile&rdquo; is one where the side walls of the lines are perpendicular to the surface of the silicon oxide substrate. An &ldquo;undercut&rdquo; profile is one where the width of the line is more narrow at the base of the line than at the top surface of the line. A vertical profile is typically preferred, because it enables closer placement of device structures on a given surface area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>B, the etched tungsten surface <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> at the bottom of spaces <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> exhibited a rougher finish than the line <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> upper photoresist residue <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> surface <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a schematic of a photomicrograph of etched tungsten <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> where there is a change in the etch chemistry toward the end of the tungsten <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> etching, and etching is permitted to continue to the surface <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the thin silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>. Again, the etched tungsten structure was a pattern of lines <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> and spaces <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>. The line width is approximately 0.120 &mgr;m, and the space width is approximately 0.165 &mgr;m. The structure included a thin (&ap;45 &angst;) silicon oxide layer <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> on a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, a 1650 &angst; thick overlying layer of tungsten <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> (i.e., tungsten/tungsten nitride, as described above with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), a 400 &angst; thick image-focusing antireflective coating (ARC) layer <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, and a photoresist layer residue <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The tungsten <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> etch was carried out using two etch chemistries. During the first portion of the etching, the chemically reactive etchant species in the plasma were SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>at sccm and N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at 50 sccm (i.e., 37.5 volume % SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>, 62.5 volume % N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). Other etch process conditions were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 4 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was 500 W; the substrate bias power was about 80 W. The etch profile obtained was good, with the sidewall angle of the etched lines <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> from silicon oxide substrate <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> surface <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> being about 89&deg;. The tungsten etch rate was about 1650 &angst; per minute. Approximately 1500 &angst; of the initial 1650 &angst; thickness of the tungsten layer <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> was etched using this first etch chemistry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Etching of the remaining 150 &angst; of tungsten layer <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> was carried out using a plasma in which the chemically reactive etchant species were produced from a source gas of Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at a flow rate of about 70 sccm and O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at a flow rate of about 40 sccm. Other etch process conditions were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 6 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was 600 W; the substrate bias power was about 80 W. The etch profile obtained was excellent, with the sidewall angle of the etched lines <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> from silicon oxide substrate <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> surface <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> being about 89&deg; to 90&deg;. The tungsten etch rate was about 1500 &angst; per minute. The etching was allowed to continue until the upper surface of the silicon oxide substrate <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> was slightly etched. It was determined that the silicon oxide etch rate was about 19 &angst; per minute. The etch rate selectivity of tungsten:silicon oxide was about 79:1. Tungsten residue was cleared off the space <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight> open areas, but there was a slight tungsten &ldquo;foot&rdquo; (not shown) at the bottom of tungsten lines <highlight><bold>303</bold></highlight> in the areas where the spacing between lines was less than that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> (in the more dense areas). Subsequent experimentation demonstrated that adjustment of the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate to 45 sccm, the plasma source power to 1800 W, and the process chamber pressure to 3 mTorr results in removal of the &ldquo;foot&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graph <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> showing the etch rate (shown on axis <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>) of silicon oxide as a function of the plasma source gas oxygen flow rate (shown on axis <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>). The data shown in graph <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> were obtained by etching a layer of silicon oxide only, which was deposited on a silicon wafer. The total flow of Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>used was 110 sccm, and the volume % of oxygen in the plasma source gas may be calculated by dividing the sccm shown on axis <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> by the total gas flow <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> sccm and multiplying by 100. The other etch process conditions used during the silicon oxide etching were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 6 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was about 1600 W; the substrate bias power was about 80 W. Graph <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> indicates that there is a diminishing effect obtained by increasing the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate, with the etch rate leveling out at about 19 &angst; per minute between about 35 sccm and 40 sccm of O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. We later discovered that it was necessary to increase the plasma density (plasma source power) to obtain the full benefit of an increase in the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate over about 35 sccm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a graph <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> showing the effect of increasing the plasma source power (shown in Watts on axis <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>), on the etch rate of tungsten (W) (shown by curve <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>) and on the etch rate of SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>(shown by curve <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>), at a constant O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate of about 20 sccm. The etch rate units in each case are shown on axis <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. Graph <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> also shows the selectivity for W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>as a function of the plasma source power, illustrated by curve <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>, at the constant flow rate of 20 sccm. The nominal selectivity is shown on axis <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. As can be observed from graph <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, an increase in plasma source power results in an increase in tungsten etch rate, a decrease in SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>etch rate, and an increase in selectivity. However, at an O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate of 20 sccm, up to a plasma source power of about 1600 W, the selectivity of W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>is only about 40:1. The process chamber pressure was about 6 mTorr, and the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph <highlight><bold>530</bold></highlight> showing tungsten etch rate in an overetch step, as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. In particular, the wafer etched was a sputtered tungsten layer overlying a silicon wafer. The process chamber pressure was 6 mTorr, and the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C. The tungsten etch rate units (A/min.) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>534</bold></highlight>, the plasma source power units (W) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>532</bold></highlight>, and the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate units (sccm) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>536</bold></highlight>. Curve <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> clearly shows that an increase in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate alone from about 30 sccm to about sccm, with plasma source power held constant at about 1,600 W, increased the tungsten etch rate from about 1170 &angst;/min. to about 1500 &angst;/min. A simultaneous increase in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate from about 30 sccm to about 45 sccm, and increase in plasma source power from about 1600 W to about 1800 W, increased the tungsten etch rate from about 1170 &angst;/min. to about 1750 &angst;/min. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> showing silicon oxide etch rate in an overetch step, as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. In particular, the wafer etched was a silicon substrate having a layer of thermal silicon oxide on its surface. The process chamber pressure was 6 mTorr, and the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C. The silicon oxide etch rate units (&angst;/min.) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>544</bold></highlight>, the plasma source power units (W) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>542</bold></highlight>, and the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate units (sccm) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>546</bold></highlight>. Curve <highlight><bold>538</bold></highlight> shows that an increase in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate alone from about 20 sccm to about 40 sccm, with plasma source power held constant at about 1600 W, decreased the silicon oxide etch rate from about 37 &angst;/min. to about 19 &angst;/min. A simultaneous increase in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate from about 20 sccm to about 45 sccm, and increase in plasma source power from about 1600 W to about 1800 W, decreased the silicon oxide etch rate from about 37 &angst;/min. to about 10 &angst;/min. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> is a three-dimensional graph <highlight><bold>550</bold></highlight> showing selectivity (etch rate ratio of W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) as a function of plasma source power and oxygen flow rate, all other variables held constant. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> is derived from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5B and 5C</cross-reference>, and makes apparent the striking increase in selectivity which can be achieved by increasing both the oxygen flow rate and the plasma source power simultaneously. The selectivity (W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) nominal units are shown on axis <highlight><bold>554</bold></highlight>, the plasma source power units (W) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>552</bold></highlight>, and the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate units (sccm) are shown on axis <highlight><bold>556</bold></highlight>. Curve <highlight><bold>558</bold></highlight> shows that an increase in O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate alone from about 30 sccm to about 40 sccm, with plasma source power held constant at about 1600 W, increased the selectivity from about 50:1 to about 80:1. A simultaneous increase in oxygen flow rate from about 30 sccm to about 45 sccm, and increase in plasma source power from about 1600 W to about 1800 W, increased the selectivity from about 50:1 to about 175:1. For example, a selectivity of about 100:1 is obtained when the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>content is about 40%, and the plasma source power is about 1670 W. A selectivity of about 175:1 is obtained when the O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>content is about 45% and the plasma source power is about 1800 W. An increase in the selectivity to 175:1 was unexpected in view of the much smaller increase in selectivity obtained when only the oxygen flow rate was increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> To better appreciate this surprising increase in selectivity, it is helpful to compare <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</cross-reference> with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> showed that when the oxygen flow rate was held constant at about 20 sccm, and the plasma source power was increased from about 800 W up to about 1600 W, the selectivity of W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x </subscript></highlight>increased from about 19:1 to about 40:1. Further, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>D, an increase in oxygen flow rate from about 30 sccm to about 40 sccm, with the plasma source power held constant at 1600 W, provided a selectivity increase from about 50:1 to about 80:1. It was only with the synergistic combination of increased oxygen flow rate and increased plasma source power that a selectivity of 175:1 was achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Table I, below, provides a summary of various process conditions and the tungsten (or tungsten nitride) etch rate which is expected to be obtained at those process conditions. Table I also shows the selectivity relative to silicon oxide which is expected to be obtained, and the etched sidewall profile angle which is expected to be obtained.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE I</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Typical Process Conditions During Final Portion Etching (Overetch)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>of Tungsten or Tungsten Nitride, With Underlying Silicon Oxide Layer</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="91PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Process Condition</entry>
<entry>Process Condition</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Process Condition and</entry>
<entry>Broad Range</entry>
<entry>Preferred Range</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Result</entry>
<entry>and Results</entry>
<entry>and Results</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Total Gas Flow</entry>
<entry>50-200</entry>
<entry>&ensp;75-125</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>Flow Rate</entry>
<entry>&gt;20-60&emsp;</entry>
<entry>30-50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Vol. % O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in mixt. of O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>&gt;20-50&emsp;</entry>
<entry>30-40</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>and Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate</entry>
<entry>20-100</entry>
<entry>40-60</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Temperature (&deg; C.)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Process Chamber</entry>
<entry>2-20</entry>
<entry>3-6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Pressure (mTorr)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Source Power (W)</entry>
<entry>800-3000</entry>
<entry>1400-1800</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate Bias Power (W)</entry>
<entry>40-200</entry>
<entry>&ensp;80-100</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Etch Rate W or WN<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>1000-3000&ensp;</entry>
<entry>1500-2000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(&angst;/min)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Selectivity</entry>
<entry>10:1 to 200:1</entry>
<entry>100:1 to 175:1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>W:SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Etched Profile, Vertical or</entry>
<entry>88-90&deg;</entry>
<entry>vertical profile</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Tapered or Undercut (&deg;)</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry><highlight><superscript>&ensp;</superscript></highlight>89-90&deg;</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The dielectric layer underlying the tungsten or tungsten nitride layer may alternatively comprise tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, or silicon oxynitride, instead of silicon oxide. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of the method of the invention for etching tungsten, when the underlying dielectric layer is tantalum pentoxide. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> shows a beginning semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> prior to performance of the method of the invention. The structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> includes a thin (50 &angst;) tantalum pentoxide layer <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> on a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, overlying tantalum pentoxide layer <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> is a 300 &angst; thick wetting layer of tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>, a 700 &angst; thick layer of tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>, a 300 &angst; thick image-focusing antireflective coating (ARC) layer <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> (in this case, silicon oxynitride), and a 1500 &angst; thick silicon nitride hard mask layer <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight>, which is used to pattern etch the structure <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight>. The silicon nitride hard mask layer <highlight><bold>612</bold></highlight> and silicon oxynitride ARC layer <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> have been previously patterned using techniques known in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Etching of the tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>/tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> was carried out using two etch chemistries. During the first portion of the etching, the chemically reactive etchant species in the plasma were SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>at 20 sccm and N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at 45 sccm (i.e., 31 volume % SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>, 69 volume % N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>). Other etch process conditions were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 4 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was 200 W; the substrate bias power was about 175 W. The tungsten/tungsten nitride etch rate was about 2000 &angst; per minute. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>B, almost all (at least 950 &angst;) of the initial 1000 &angst; combined thickness of the tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>/tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> was etched using this first etch chemistry, with a small amount of tungsten/tungsten nitride residue remaining at the bottom of the feature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Etching of the remaining tungsten <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>/tungsten nitride <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> was carried out using a plasma in which the chemically reactive etchant species were produced from a source gas of Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at a flow rate of about 72 sccm and O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at a flow rate of about 18 sccm. Other etch process conditions were as follows: The etch process chamber pressure was about 4 mTorr; the substrate temperature was about 50&deg; C.; the plasma source power was 400 W; the substrate bias power was about 175 W. The tungsten/tungsten nitride etch rate was about 1871 per minute. The etching was allowed to continue until the upper surface of the tantalum pentoxide layer <highlight><bold>604</bold></highlight> was slightly etched, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6C</cross-reference>. It was determined that the tantalum pentoxide etch rate was about 20 &angst; per minute. The etch rate selectivity of tungsten tantalum pentoxide was about 94:1. The etch profile obtained was about 89&deg; to 90&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> When the underlying oxide layer comprises tantalum pentoxide, we have discovered that we can use the same source gas composition and process conditions during the tungsten overetch step as those which were used when silicon oxide was used as the underlying layer. Since the tantalum pentoxide is resistant to ion bombardment which occurs during anisotropic etching, we can achieve an almost infinite selectivity for etching tungsten relative to an underlying tantalum pentoxide layer. This extraordinarily high tungsten:tantalum pentoxide etch selectivity allows a thinner tantalum pentoxide layer to be used (relative to a corresponding silicon oxide layer). The tantalum pentoxide layer typically has thickness of less than about 100 &angst;, preferably within the range of about 30 &angst; to about 50 &angst;. The thinness of the oxide layer can be important in terms of increasing a semiconductor device speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Our discovery that tantalum pentoxide is more resistant to ion bombardment than silicon oxide permits a higher substrate bias power to be used during the tungsten overetch step over an underlying tantalum pentoxide layer. The use of a high bias power (from about 100 W up to about 300 W) during the overetch step provides improved profile control (i.e., a more vertical profile is obtained), while maintaining a high selectivity for etching tungsten relative to the underlying tantalum pentoxide. When a higher bias power is employed, a plasma source gas having a lower oxygen content can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> When the underlying oxide layer comprises tantalum pentoxide, a tungsten etch rate of about 2000 &angst; per minute can be achieved while maintaining a tungsten:tantalum pentoxide etch selectivity of about 75:1 or better using a plasma source gas having a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of about 20%, with a plasma density within the range of about 4.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 6.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, which may be achieved in the exemplary DPS chamber using a plasma source power within the range of about 400 W to about 600 W, a substrate bias power of about 175 W, and a process chamber pressure within the range of about 4 mTorr. To enable maintenance of feature profile while removing residual tungsten &ldquo;feet&rdquo; at the base of a feature, it may be advantageous to adjust the etch conditions toward the end of the etch. For example, the final etch conditions may provide a selectivity of at least 175:1 tungsten:tantalum pentoxide, where the tungsten etch rate is less than about 1000 &angst; per minute. This etch selectivity and etch rate can be obtained by using a plasma source gas having a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>of about 20%, with a plasma density of about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, which can be achieved in the exemplary DPS chamber using a plasma source power of about 200 W, a substrate bias power of about 175 W, and a process chamber pressure of about 6 mTorr. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Experimental results obtained by varying particular process parameters (O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>flow rate, process chamber pressure, plasma source power, substrate bias power) during tungsten overetching are presented in Table II, below.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE II</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Tungsten Overetch with Underlying Tantalum Pentoxide Layer,</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Development Data</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="147PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Run &num;</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="7" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="8">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>Flow Rate</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
<entry>72</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>Flow Rate</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>22</entry>
<entry>26</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
<entry>18</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Vol. % O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>23.4</entry>
<entry>26.5</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Process Chamber</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Pressure (mTorr)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Plasma Source</entry>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>200</entry>
<entry>400</entry>
<entry>600</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Power (W)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate Bias</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
<entry>100</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
<entry>175</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Power (W)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
<entry>50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Temperature (&deg; C.)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>W Etch Rate</entry>
<entry>634</entry>
<entry>344</entry>
<entry>1014</entry>
<entry>481</entry>
<entry>42</entry>
<entry>1871</entry>
<entry>2198</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(&angst;/min.)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>Etch Rate</entry>
<entry>22</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>5.7</entry>
<entry>5.3</entry>
<entry>4.7</entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>28</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(&angst;/min.)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>W:Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5 </subscript></highlight>Etch</entry>
<entry>29:1</entry>
<entry>29:1</entry>
<entry>178:1</entry>
<entry>90:1</entry>
<entry>9:1</entry>
<entry>94:1</entry>
<entry>79:1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Selectivity</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="8" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Table III, below, provides a summary of various process conditions and the tungsten (or tungsten nitride) overetch rate which is expected to be obtained at those process conditions. Table III also shows the selectivity for etching tungsten/tungsten nitride relative to tantalum pentoxide which is expected to be obtained, and the etched sidewall profile angle which is expected to be obtained.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE III</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Typical Process Conditions During Final Portion</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Etching (Overetch) of Tungsten or Tungsten Nitride, With</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Underlying Tantalum Pentoxide Layer</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="91PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Process Condition</entry>
<entry>Process Condition</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Process Condition and</entry>
<entry>Broad Range</entry>
<entry>Preferred Range</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Result</entry>
<entry>and Results</entry>
<entry>and Results</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Total Gas Flow</entry>
<entry>30-150</entry>
<entry>&ensp;90-120</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>Flow Rate</entry>
<entry>15-50&ensp;</entry>
<entry>20-50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(sccm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Vol % O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in mixt. of O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>15-50&ensp;</entry>
<entry>20-30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>and Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate</entry>
<entry>40-60&ensp;</entry>
<entry>40-60</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Temperature (&deg; C.)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Process Chamber</entry>
<entry>2-10</entry>
<entry>4-8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Pressure (mTorr)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Source Power (W)</entry>
<entry>200-1800</entry>
<entry>&ensp;400-1800</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Substrate Bias Power (W)</entry>
<entry>60-300</entry>
<entry>&ensp;60-200</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Etch Rate W or WN<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>300-2200</entry>
<entry>1000-2000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(&angst;/min)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Selectivity</entry>
<entry>10:1 to 1000:1</entry>
<entry>30:1 to 600:1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>W:Ta<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Etched Profile, Vertical or</entry>
<entry>Vertical</entry>
<entry>Vertical</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Tapered or Undercut (&deg;)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The above described embodiments are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention, as one skilled in the art can, in view of the present disclosure, expand such embodiments to correspond with the subject matter of the invention claimed below. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of plasma etching tungsten or tungsten nitride, wherein an etch selectivity of greater than about 75:1 is obtained relative to an adjacent silicon oxide layer by using a plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species which are generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, wherein the volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said plasma source gas is at least 35%, and wherein a plasma density is at least 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is obtained by applying a source power of at least 1600 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said etch selectivity is greater than about 100:1, said volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is at least 40%, and said plasma density is at least 1.65&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is obtained by applying a source power of at least 1650 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said etch selectivity is greater than about 175:1, said volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is at least 45%, and said plasma density is at least 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is obtained by applying a source power of at least 1800 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method of selectively etching tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to an underlying oxide layer in semiconductor structures, comprising: 
<claim-text>plasma etching a first majority portion of said tungsten or tungsten nitride using a first plasma source gas comprising at least one halogen-based chemically functional etchant species; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>plasma etching a remaining portion of said tungsten or tungsten nitride using a second plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide is selected from the group consisting of silicon oxide, silicon oxynitride, tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said halogen is selected from the group consisting of fluorine, chlorine, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first majority portion of said plasma etching is carried out using a first plasma source gas selected from the group consisting of a combination of SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and a combination of NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises silicon oxide, and wherein a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said second plasma source gas is greater than 20% by volume. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>volumetric percentage ranges from greater than 20% to about 45%. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises silicon oxide, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma is at least 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power ranges from about 800 W to about 3000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma source power ranges from about 800 W to about 2000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises silicon oxide, and wherein said etching which is carried out using said plasma source gas comprising said chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is carried out in two steps, wherein a volumetric concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a first step ranges from greater than 20% by volume to about 35% by volume, and wherein a volumetric concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a second step ranges from greater than about 35% by volume to about 45% by volume. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and wherein a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said second plasma source gas ranges from about 20% to about 50%. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma ranges from about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power ranges from about 200 W to about 1800 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 300 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of selectively etching tungsten or tungsten nitride relative to an underlying oxide layer in semiconductor structures, comprising: 
<claim-text>plasma etching a first majority portion of said tungsten or tungsten nitride using a first plasma source gas comprising fluorine species; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>plasma etching a remaining portion of said tungsten or tungsten nitride using a second plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide is selected from the group consisting of silicon oxide, silicon oxynitride, tantalum pentoxide, zirconium oxide, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first majority portion of said plasma etching is carried out using a first plasma source gas selected from the group consisting of a combination of SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and a combination of NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first plasma source gas comprises SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and wherein a volumetric ratio of SF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>:N<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said first plasma source gas ranges from about 2:5 to about 6:1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, or <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises silicon oxide, and wherein a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said second plasma source gas is greater than 20% by volume. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>volumetric percentage ranges from greater than 20% to about 45%. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma is at least 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power ranges from about 800 W to about 3000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma source power ranges from about 800 W to about 2000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma is at least 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density ranges from about 8.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power ranges from about 800 W to about 3000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises silicon oxide, and wherein said etching which is carried out using said plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is carried out in two steps, wherein a volumetric concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a first step ranges from greater than 20% by volume to about 35% by volume, and wherein the volumetric concentration of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in a second step ranges from greater than about 35% by volume to about 45% by volume. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma density during said first step ranges from about 8&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>, and wherein a plasma density during said second step ranges from about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 3.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power during said first step ranges from about 800 W to about 1600 W, and wherein a plasma source power during said second step ranges from about 1600 W to about 3000 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and wherein a volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said second plasma source gas ranges from about 20% to about 50%. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma ranges from about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a plasma source power ranges from about 200 W to about 1800 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said underlying oxide comprises tantalum pentoxide, and a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 300 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method of selectively etching tungsten nitride relative to silicon oxide during the etching of semiconductor structures, comprising: 
<claim-text>plasma etching a majority portion of said tungsten nitride using a plasma source gas comprising fluorine species; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>plasma etching a remaining portion of said tungsten nitride using a second plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, wherein said O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>concentration is about 35% by volume or greater, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma is about 1.6&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or greater. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first majority portion of said plasma etching is carried out using a first plasma source gas selected from the group consisting of a combination of SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and a combination of NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is created by application of a plasma source power of 1600 W or greater. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>concentration is about 40% by volume or greater, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma is about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or greater. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 47</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is created by application of a plasma source power of 1800 W or greater. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A method of plasma etching tungsten or tungsten nitride, wherein an etch selectivity of greater than about 75:1 is obtained relative to an adjacent tantalum pentoxide layer by using a plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species which are generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, wherein the volumetric percentage of O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>in said plasma source gas ranges from about 20% to about 50%, and wherein a plasma density ranges from about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is obtained by applying a source power within the range of about 200 W to about 1800 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 300 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 200 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 100 W to about 200 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A method of selectively etching tungsten nitride relative to tantalum pentoxide during the etching of semiconductor structures, comprising: 
<claim-text>plasma etching a majority portion of said tungsten nitride using a plasma source gas comprising fluorine species; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>plasma etching a remaining portion of said tungsten nitride using a second plasma source gas comprising chemically functional etchant species generated from Cl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, wherein said O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>concentration ranges from about 20% to about 50% by volume, and wherein a plasma density of said etchant plasma ranges from about 2.0&times;10<highlight><superscript>10 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to about 1.8&times;10<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>e<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>/cm<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first majority portion of said plasma etching is carried out using a first plasma source gas selected from the group consisting of a combination of SF<highlight><subscript>6 </subscript></highlight>and N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and a combination of NF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, Cl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, and CF<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plasma density is obtained by applying a source power within the range of about 200 W to about 1800 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 200 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 51</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 60 W to about 200 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a substrate bias power ranges from about 100 W to about 200 W. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor gate structure comprising a layer of tungsten and an underlying layer of tantalum pentoxide, deposited on a silicon substrate, wherein said tantalum pentoxide layer has thickness of less than about 100 &angst;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor gate structure of claim <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, wherein said tantalum pentoxide layer has a thickness within the range of about 30 &angst; to about 50 &angst;.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2B</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003757A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
