<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002615A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002615A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002615</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10171953</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020614</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-199040</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C019/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>377</class>
<subclass>064000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Shift register and electronic apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Katsuhiko</given-name>
<family-name>Morosawa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Minoru</given-name>
<family-name>Kanbara</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Casio Computer Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FRISHAUF, HOLTZ, GOODMAN &amp; CHICK, PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>767 THIRD AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>25TH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10017-2023</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A shift register includes stages, outputting an output signal from each stage. The stage includes a first transistor which outputs an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage via the other terminal, when an output signal is inputted into its control terminal. A second transistor has a control terminal connected to the other terminal of the first transistor, accumulates charges in a capacity of a wiring between the control terminal and the other terminal of the first transistor by a clock signal inputted into one terminal and outputs the clock signal from one terminal. A circuit displaces a potential of the wiring to a predetermined level when the output signal is inputted from the subsequent stage, and holds the potential of the wiring at a predetermined level until the output signal is inputted. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is based upon and claims the benefit of priority from the prior Japanese Patent Application No. 2001-199040, filed Jun. 29, 2001, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a shift register which successively outputs an output signal from each stage, and an electronic apparatus which includes the shift register. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As a driver for driving an image pickup element and display element in which pixels are arranged in a matrix form, there has been proposed use of a shift register which shifts an output signal successively to a subsequent stage from a previous stage and which linearly and successively outputs the signal to the image pickup element and display element from each stage. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a shift register which does not cause a malfunction resulting from a parasitic capacity of a transistor, and an electronic apparatus to which the shift register is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To achieve the object, according to one aspect of the present invention, for example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4, 5</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, there is provided a shift register which comprises a plurality of stages, and successively outputs an output signal having a predetermined level from each stage, each stage comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> a first transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage, via the other terminal, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted into the control terminal; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> a second transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal connected to the other terminal of the first transistor, accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with the control terminal of the second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of the second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of the second transistor; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> a potential holding section (TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, or TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) to displace a potential of the wiring to a predetermined level when an output signal having a predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, and to hold the potential of the wiring at the predetermined level until the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the shift register, when there is no stage before a foremost stage, the output signal having the predetermined level from the previous stage in the forefront stage may be an output signal having the predetermined level from the last stage, or an output signal having the predetermined level from an external control apparatus. Moreover, when there is no stage after the last stage, the output signal having the predetermined level from the subsequent stage in the last stage may be an output signal having the predetermined level from the forefront stage, or an output signal having the predetermined level from the external control apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the shift register, when the output signal having the predetermined level from the previous stage is inputted into the control terminal of the first transistor, the output signal is outputted to the other terminal from one terminal of the first transistor. Here, the potential holding section holds the capacity having the wiring with the output signal with the predetermined level inputted therein from the previous stage via the other terminal of the first transistor as one pole, for example, in a state in which charge-up in a positive potential is possible. Therefore, when the output signal from the previous stage is inputted into the wiring, the charges are held in the capacity. In this case, when the clock signal is inputted into one terminal of the second transistor, the clock signal is outputted to the other terminal of the second transistor as the output signal of the corresponding stage. In this case, due to the charge-up of the parasitic capacity of the second transistor, the potential of the wiring rises. In this manner, the potential of the control terminal of the second transistor is held in a relatively high state. Therefore, without lowering the level of the clock signal, the signal can be outputted from the other terminal. Thus, the shift register constituted in this manner securely shifts the output signal with the level of the clock signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, the wiring potential is displaced to a predetermined potential by the potential holding section, and the clock signal inputted into one terminal of the second transistor is not outputted to the other terminal of the second transistor. Before the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage again, the potential of the wiring connected to the control terminal of the second transistor is held by the potential holding section. Therefore, in this case, even if there is an amplitude in the clock signal inputted into one terminal of the second transistor, the wiring potential is synchronized because of the parasitic capacity of the second transistor and can be prevented from being displaced. Thus, a leak current of the second transistor by the clock signal can be prevented. Therefore, the output signal is outputted only when each stage is to output the output signal. The shift register according to the present invention securely shifts the output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The potential holding section may comprise: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> a third transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and displaces the potential of the wiring to a predetermined level in an on state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> a fourth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, outputs the signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage, and stops the output of the on voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> a fifth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage, and stops the output of the off voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The potential holding section may comprise: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> a sixth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of the fourth transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> a seventh transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of the fourth in response to the output signal from the previous stage; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> an eighth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of the fifth transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> a ninth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of the fifth transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> With the potential holding section constituted as described above, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, charges for determining the potential of the control terminal of the fourth transistor are accumulated via the sixth transistor, and the fourth transistor is turned on. Therefore, the signal of the on voltage is outputted to the control terminal of the third transistor via the fourth transistor. Moreover, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, the on voltage of the control terminal of the fifth transistor is displaced to an off potential by the ninth transistor. The fifth transistor is turned off, and by the signal with a constant voltage level outputted from the other terminal of the fourth transistor, the control terminal of the third transistor is set to the on potential. Therefore, the third transistor sets the potential of the wiring connected to the control terminal of the second transistor to a reference voltage Vss. Here, when the clock signal is inputted into one terminal of the second transistor, due to the parasitic capacity of the second transistor, the charges are accumulated in the capacity. However, since the wiring potential of the control terminal of the second transistor is held at the reference voltage Vss, the leak current is not generated from the second transistor. Therefore, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, the output signal is not outputted from the corresponding stage by the clock signal. Thereafter, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage, the potential of the control terminal of the fourth transistor is displaced to the predetermined potential by the seventh transistor. Thereby, the fourth transistor stops the output of the signal having a constant voltage level. Moreover, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage, the potential of the control terminal of the fifth transistor is set to the on potential by the eighth transistor. The wiring potential connected to the control terminal of the third transistor is displaced to the predetermined potential by the fifth transistor, and the third transistor is turned off. Therefore, the wiring potential connected to the control terminal of the second transistor is displaced by the output signal having the predetermined level from the previous stage. In this case, when the clock signal is inputted to one terminal of the second transistor, the clock signal is outputted as the output signal of the stage to the other terminal of the second transistor. In this case, when the clock signal is inputted to one terminal of the second transistor, due to the parasitic capacity of the second transistor, the wiring potential connected to the second transistor is further displaced. Thereby, without lowering the level of the clock signal, the second transistor outputs the signal to the other terminal. Therefore, the shift register constituted in this manner securely shifts the output signal while the level of the output signal is the level of the clock signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the potential holding section may comprise: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> a third transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and displaces the potential of the wiring to a predetermined level in the on state; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> a tenth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal as the on voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor, when the output signal from the subsequent stage is inputted into one terminal and the control terminal of the tenth transistor; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> an eleventh transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal as the off voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In the shift register constituted in this manner, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, the charges are accumulated in the control terminal of the third transistor by the eleventh transistor, for example, so as to apply a positive potential. Therefore, the third transistor is in a state for discharging the charges to determine the wiring potential connected to the control terminal of the second transistor. Here, when the clock signal is inputted into one terminal of the second transistor, due to the parasitic capacity of the second transistor, the charges are accumulated in the capacity having the wiring connected to the control terminal of the second transistor as one pole. However, the third transistor can set the wiring potential to the constant voltage. Therefore, the leak current is not generated from the second transistor from when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage until the output signal is inputted from the previous stage again. Thereafter, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage, the third transistor stops the discharge of the charges accumulated in one pole of the parasitic capacity of the second transistor by the tenth transistor, and the charges are accumulated in one pole of the parasitic capacity of the second transistor. In this case, when the clock signal is inputted to one terminal of the second transistor, the clock signal is outputted as the output signal of the stage to the other terminal of the second transistor. In this case, when the clock signal is inputted into one terminal of the second transistor, due to the parasitic capacity of the second transistor, the charges are accumulated in the wiring capacity, and the wiring potential is further displaced. Therefore, without lowering the level of the clock signal, the second transistor outputs the signal to the other terminal. Therefore, the shift register having this constitution securely shifts the output signal with the level of the clock signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, for example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4, 12</cross-reference>, there is provided a shift register which is constituted of a plurality of stages (stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n)), and successively outputs an output signal having a predetermined level from each stage, each stage comprising: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> a first transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>) which outputs an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage, when the output signal having a predetermined level is inputted into a control terminal from the previous stage; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> a second transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>) whose control terminal is connected to the other terminal of the first transistor, and which accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with the control terminal of the second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of the second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of the second transistor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> a third transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) which has a control terminal, and outputs a second voltage as the output signal of the stage, when a first voltage is supplied to the control terminal of the third transistor from a first voltage wiring; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> a fourth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>) which outputs an off voltage to the control terminal of the third transistor in response to the output signal outputted to the wiring from the other terminal of the first transistor; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> a fifth transistor (TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>) which displaces the potential of the wiring to a predetermined level in response to the output signal having the predetermined level from the subsequent stage; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> a capacitor (capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>) disposed between the wiring and the other terminal of the second transistor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Here, for example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, each stage may include a second capacitor (capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>) disposed between the wiring and a second constant voltage wiring which supplies the second constant voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16, 18</cross-reference>, each stage may include a third capacitor (capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>) disposed between the wiring and the first constant voltage wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17, 19</cross-reference>, each stage may include a fourth capacitor (capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>) in which one pole is grounded and the other pole is connected to the wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In the shift register, when there is no stage before the forefront stage, the output signal having the predetermined level from the previous stage in the forefront stage may be an output signal having the predetermined level from the last stage, or an output signal having the predetermined level from an external control apparatus. Moreover, when there is no stage after the last stage, the output signal having the predetermined level from the subsequent stage in the last stage may be an output signal having the predetermined level from the forefront stage, or an output signal having the predetermined level from the external control apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The above-described respective shift registers are stabilized and the leak current of the second transistor by the amplitude by the clock signal can be suppressed, when the capacitor having the wiring connected to the control terminal of the second transistor as one pole. Particularly in the shift register according to the another aspect, when the second transistor has n channels, the potential of the control terminal of the second transistor can be prevented from dropping. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objects and advantages of the invention may be realized and obtained by means of the instrumentalities and combinations particularly pointed out hereinafter.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a concrete constitution of an image pickup apparatus to which an electronic apparatus according to the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a plan view showing a concrete mode of a double gate type transistor constituting an image pickup element array disposed in the image pickup apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view cut along a III-III line in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, in which the concrete mode of the double gate type transistor shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a whole concrete constitution of a top gate driver or a bottom gate driver disposed in the image pickup apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagram showing a concrete mode of a circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a timing chart showing an operation of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>I are schematic diagrams showing the operation of the image pickup apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver as a comparative example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a timing chart showing the operation of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver to which a shift register according to one embodiment of the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a timing chart showing the operation of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver to which the shift register according to the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a timing chart showing the operation of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver as the comparative example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a diagram showing another concrete mode of the circuit constitution of each stage of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing the concrete mode of a liquid crystal display to which the electronic apparatus according to the present invention is applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate presently preferred embodiments of the invention, and together with the general description given above and the detailed description of the preferred embodiments given below, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Concrete modes of a shift register and electronic apparatus according to an embodiment of the present invention will be described hereinafter with reference to the drawings. Additionally, the scope of the present invention is not limited to shown examples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> First Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, an image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to which the electronic apparatus according to one embodiment of the present invention is applied is basically constituted of: an image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for optically sensing and picking up (acquiring) an image; a controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> for controlling the whole image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; a top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> for driving the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in response to a control signal from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>; a bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>; and a detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> are connected to the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> so that data can be inputted/outputted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is basically constituted of a large number of double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> arranged in a matrix form on a transparent substrate. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, each double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> includes a bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, bottom gate insulation film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>impurity doped layers (semiconductor layers doped with impurities) <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and protective insulation film <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is formed on a transparent substrate <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The transparent substrate <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a permeability to a visible light and an electric insulating property. The bottom gate insulation film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is disposed on the bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and transparent substrate <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> so that the bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and transparent substrate <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are coated. The semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is disposed opposite to the bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> on the bottom gate insulation film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is formed of amorphous silicon. When the visible light is incident upon the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, electron-positive hole pairs are generated in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are disposed apart from each other and in the same plane. The impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is disposed on one end of the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in a channel longitudinal direction, and the impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is disposed on the other end thereof. The impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is disposed on a middle of the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> between the block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is apart from the pair of impurity doped layers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Therefore, the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is entirely coated with the impurity doped layers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>A portion of the impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>overlaps one end of a portion of the block insulation film <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>and the impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>overlaps one end of the block insulation film <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The impurity doped layers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are formed of amorphous silicon doped with n-type impurities. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are disposed on the impurity doped layers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>respectively, and the drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is disposed on the impurity doped layer <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. One source electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>a overlaps a portion of the block insulation film <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>the other source electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>overlaps a portion of the block insulation film <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and the drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> overlaps portions of the block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are apart from the drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is formed so that the bottom gate insulation film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are coated. The top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> disposed opposite to the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is mounted on the top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The protective insulation film <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> covers the top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Each double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> constituted as described above has both photo sense function and photoelectric conversion function. That is, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> has the photo sense function of accumulating the positive holes of the electron-positive hole pairs having an amount generated in accordance with a light amount incident upon the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by a portion constituted of the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the transistor has the photoelectric conversion function of displacing a voltage of a drain line DL in accordance with the amount of positive holes accumulated by the photo sense function by the transistor portion constituted of the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, bottom gate insulation film <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is connected to a top gate line TGL, the bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is connected to a bottom gate line BGL, the drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is connected to the drain line DL, and the source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are connected to a grounded ground line GL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The block insulation films <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>top gate insulation film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and protective insulation film <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are formed of materials having translucency and insulating property, such as silicon nitride. The top gate electrode <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and top gate line TGL are formed of materials having translucency and conductivity such as indium-tin-oxide (ITO). The source electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>drain electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, bottom gate electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and bottom gate line BGL are formed of materials which are selected from chromium, chromium alloy, aluminum, and aluminum alloy, and which cut off the transmission of the visible light and have conductivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Here, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to each top gate line TGL of the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, successively and selectively outputs a driving signal (i.e., the output signal) to each top gate line TGL, and appropriately applies a reset voltage (&plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) or a carrier accumulated voltage (&minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) as the driving signal to the top gate line TGL in accordance with a control signal group Tcnt outputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> The bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is connected to the bottom gate line BGL of the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, successively and selectively outputs the driving signal (i.e., the output signal) to each bottom gate line BGL, and appropriately applies a channel forming voltage (&plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) or a channel non-forming voltage (&plusmn;0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) as the driving signal to the bottom gate line BGL in accordance with a control signal group Bcnt outputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected to each data line DL of the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, applies a reference voltage (&plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) to all the data lines DL in response to a control signal group Dcnt outputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in a predetermined period, and precharges electric charges. The detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> detects a potential of the data line DL which changes in accordance with the light amount incident upon each double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> or a drain current flowing between a source and drain of the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in a predetermined period after the precharge, and outputs a data signal DATA to the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Details of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will next be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a shift register according to the present invention. The shift register according to the embodiment of the present invention is applied to the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. When the number of rows of double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> (i.e., the number of top gate lines TGL) arranged in the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is n, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> have the shift register constituted of n stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n) for outputting output signals to gate lines and dummy stages RS(n&plus;1) to RS(n&plus;2) not outputting the output signals to the gate lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A stage RS(k) has an input signal terminal IN, output signal terminal OUT, reference voltage applied terminal SS, constant voltage applied terminal DD, clock signal input terminal clk (clk<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or clk<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) and reset signal input terminal RST. Here, k denotes integers of 1 to n, a stage RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) denotes a first stage, stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) denotes a second stage, and stage RS(n) denotes an n-th stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) is a terminal which outputs an output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k). When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) is connected to the corresponding top gate line TGL (i.e., the top gate line TGL of a k-th row), and the output signal out(k) is outputted to the corresponding top gate line TGL. On the other hand, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) is connected to the corresponding bottom gate line BGL (i.e., the bottom gate line BGL of the k-th row), and the output signal out(k) is outputted to the corresponding bottom gate line BGL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The input signal terminal IN of the first stage RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is a terminal into which a start signal Vst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted. When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, a high level of the start signal Vst is &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and a low level of the start signal Vst is &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Instead, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the bottom gate driver, the high level of the start signal Vst is &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the low level of the start signal Vst is &plusmn;0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. The input signal terminals IN of the stages RS(k) (i.e., k denotes 2 to n) other than the first stage are connected to the output signal terminal OUT of the previous stage RS(k&minus;1), and an output signal out(k&minus;1) of the previous stage RS(k&minus;1) is inputted as an input signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Output signals OUT(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) to OUT(n&plus;2) from subsequent stages RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) to RS(n&plus;2) are inputted as reset signals into the reset signal input terminals RST of the stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n&plus;1) other than the stage RS(n&plus;2), and a reset signal Vrst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted to the reset signal input terminal RST of the stage RS(n&plus;2). When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the high level of the reset signal Vrst is &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the low level of the reset signal Vrst is &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Instead, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the bottom gate driver, the high level of the reset signal Vrst is &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the low level of the reset signal Vrst is &plusmn;0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The reference voltage applied terminal SS of the stage RS(k) is a terminal to which the reference voltage Vss is supplied from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the level of the reference voltage Vss is &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. On the other hand, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the level of the reference voltage Vss is &plusmn;0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. The constant voltage applied terminal DD of the stage RS(k) is a terminal to which a constant voltage Vdd is supplied from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the level of the constant voltage Vdd is &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. On the other hand, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the level of the constant voltage Vdd is &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> A clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted to a clock signal input terminal clk<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of an odd-numbered (i.e., k denotes an odd number) stage RS(k). A clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inputted to a clock signal input terminal clk<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of an even-numbered (i.e., k denotes an even number) stage RS(k). As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, each of the clock signals CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> alternately indicates the high level in a predetermined time of the time slot for shifting the output signal of the shift register every time slot. That is, when the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> indicates the high level for the predetermined time in one time slot, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> indicates the low level in the time slot. In the next time slot, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> indicates the low level and the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> indicates the high level for the predetermined period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> When the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> constitutes the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the clock signals CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> indicate the high level of &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the low level of &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. On the other hand, when the shift register shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is applied to the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the high level is &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the low level is &plusmn;0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, each of the stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n&plus;2) is basically constituted of six thin film transistors (hereinafter referred to as TFT) <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and additionally constituted of six TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Each of the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is an n-channel MOS type field-effect transistor, silicon nitride is used in the gate insulation film, and amorphous silicon is used in the semiconductor layer. Concretely, a sectional structure of the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are transistors in which the top gate electrodes <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are not laminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, gate and drain electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are connected to the input signal terminal IN, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. In a wiring via which the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are respectively connected, parasitic capacities are generated between the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In a node A as an optional point of the wiring, the potential can be displaced in accordance with the charges accumulated in the parasitic capacity generated between the wiring and the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> The drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is connected to the clock signal input terminal clk, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is connected to the output signal terminal OUT. The drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. In the wiring via which the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are respectively connected, the parasitic capacities are generated among the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A node E as an optional point is positioned in the wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> The drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is connected to the output signal terminal OUT, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. The drain and gate electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are connected to the constant voltage applied terminal DD. The gate and drain electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are connected to the input signal terminal IN, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In the wiring connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the parasitic capacities are generated among the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A node C as the optional point is positioned in the wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> The gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to the reset signal input terminal RST, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. The drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. In the wiring via which the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> are connected to one another, the parasitic capacities are generated among the TFTs <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A node D as the optional point is positioned in the wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> The source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. The drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is connected to the constant voltage applied terminal DD, and the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is connected to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In the wiring via which the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are connected to one another, the parasitic capacities are generated among the TFTs <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A node B as the optional point is positioned in the wiring. The drain and gate electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are commonly connected to the reset signal input terminal RST. The gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is connected to the input signal terminal IN, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The output signal out(k&minus;1) from the previous stage RS(k&minus;1) is inputted as the input signal (additionally, k denotes 2 to n), or the start signal Vst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted as the input signal (additionally, k denotes 1) to the gate and drain electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. When the output signal out(k&minus;1) or the start signal Vst has a high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is turned on, the current flows to the source electrode from the drain electrode of the transfer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> outputs the high-level output signal out(k&minus;1) to the source electrode. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has an off state, the node A is set to the high level by the output signal out(k&minus;1) indicating the high level outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, when the output signal out(k&minus;1) or the start signal Vst indicates the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has the off state, and the current does not flow between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> The constant voltage Vdd is supplied to the gate and drain electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> constantly has the on state, the current flows between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> outputs the signal having a substantially constant voltage Vdd level to the source electrode. The TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> has a function of a load for dividing the constant voltage Vdd. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> The TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> has the off state, when the node A indicates the low level. The node E is set to the high level by the signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and having the substantially constant voltage Vdd level. On the other hand, the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> has the on state, when the node A indicates the high level. When the current flows between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> sets the potential of the node E to the reference voltage Vss. The TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> has the off state with the node E indicating the low level, and has the on state with the node E indicating the high level. The TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has the on state with the node A indicating the high level, and has the off state with the node A indicating the low level. Therefore, when the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has the on state. When the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is in the on state, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has the off state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> The reference voltage Vss is supplied to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> in the on state outputs the signal having a reference voltage Vss level (i.e., the low level) to the output signal terminal OUT from the drain electrode, and outputs the signal having the low level as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k). When the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) indicates the level of the signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. When the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the output of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inputted to the drain electrode is cut off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> When the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the on state, and the low-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> outputs the low-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the source electrode. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the on state, the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> has the off state. The low-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the on state, and the high-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the charges are accumulated in the parasitic capacity constituted by the gate and source electrodes and the gate insulation film between the electrodes. In this case, since the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the stage RS(k) has the off state, the potential of the node A rises by a boot strap effect. When the potential of the node A reaches a gate saturated voltage of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a source-drain current of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is saturated. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in the on state outputs the signal indicating substantially the same potential as that of the high-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to the source electrode. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the on state, the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> has the off state. Therefore, the high-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> When the node D is in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has the on state, sets the potential of the node A to the reference voltage Vss, and maintains this state. On the other hand, when the node D is in the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has the off state. Since the period of the off state of the node A does not overlap that of the node D in this manner, the wiring of the node A is not brought to a floating state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> The reset signal is inputted into the drain and gate electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Additionally, with the stages RS(k) other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the reset signal is the output signal out(k&plus;1) of the subsequent stage RS(k&plus;1). With the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the reset signal is a reset signal Vrst outputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> When the high-level reset signal is inputted to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the current flows between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the on state outputs the high-level reset signal inputted into the drain electrode to the source electrode. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the high-level reset signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> brings the node B into the high level. The TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned on/off by the input signal. That is, when the high-level input signal is inputted to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned on, and sets the potential of the node B to the reference voltage Vss. On the other hand, when the low-level input signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned off, and the potential of the node B can be brought into the high level. The constant voltage Vdd is supplied to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. When the node B is in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the current flows between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> outputs the signal with the constant voltage Vdd inputted to the drain electrode, to the source electrode from the drain electrode. On the other hand, when the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> brings the node B into the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is turned off, and the output of the signal with the constant voltage Vdd level to the source electrode is stopped. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Therefore, from when the high-level reset signal is inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST until the high-level input signal is inputted into the input signal terminal IN, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. On the other hand, from when the high-level input signal is inputted into the input signal terminal IN until the high-level reset signal is inputted into the reset signal input terminal, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> maintains the off state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> When the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the off state, by the signal having the constant voltage Vdd level outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, the node D holds the high level, and thus the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on. The TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned on/off by the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. That is, when the high-level input signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is turned on, while the high-level input signal inputted into the drain electrode is outputted to the source electrode. On the other hand, when the low-level input signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is turned off. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the high-level input signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> brings the node C into the high level. When the high-level reset signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the current flows between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> discharges the charges accumulated in the node C, and the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned on. On the other hand, when the low-level reset signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is turned off. When the high-level input signal is inputted into the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, the node C is brought into the high level. Therefore, from when the high-level input signal is inputted into the input signal terminal IN until the high-level reset signal is inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST, the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. On the other hand, from when the high-level reset signal is inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST until the high-level input signal is inputted into the input signal terminal IN, the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> maintains the off state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Thereby, from when the high-level reset signal is inputted until the high-level input signal is inputted, the node D maintains the high level state. In this result, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state, and thus the wiring of the node A does not have the floating state. On the other hand, from when the high-level input signal is inputted until the high-level reset signal is inputted, the node D maintains the low level state, and the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> After the stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n) respectively output the output signals out(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to out(n), the output signal from the dummy stage RS(n&plus;1) is inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST of the stage RS(n), and the potential of the node A of the stage RS(n) indicates the reference potential Vss. Subsequently, the output signal from the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2) is inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST of the dummy stage RS(n&plus;1), and the potential of the node A of the dummy stage RS(n&plus;1) indicates the reference potential Vss. Finally, when the reset signal Vrst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted to the reset signal input terminal RST of the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the potential of the node A of the dummy stage RS(n&plus;1) is the reference potential Vss. The potentials of the nodes A of all the stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n&plus;2) indicate the reference potentials Vss, and one scanning period of the shift register ends. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> An operation of the image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> according to the present embodiment will be described hereinafter. First, the operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. In the figures, a period for it is one selection period. The top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is presumed in the following description. However, since the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is different from the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> only in the level and timing of the inputted/outputted signals, the top gate driver can be replaced by the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. For the operation of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, only the part different from that of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in the following description, the even-numbered stages other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2) will be described as examples. However, when the reset signal Vrst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is inputted as the reset signal (i.e., the output signal out(k&plus;1)), the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2) is the same as the other even-numbered stages. Moreover, even the odd-numbered stage performs the same operation as that of the even-numbered stage, when the inputted clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is replaced with the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The first stage is also the same as the other even-numbered stages except that the input signal (i.e., the output signal out(k&minus;1)) is the start signal Vst from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Additionally, as described above, the level of the reference voltage Vss supplied to the reference voltage applied terminal SS of each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. However, even when the level of the reference voltage Vss is 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, the operation is substantially the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, before a timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the reset signal (i.e., the output signal out(k&plus;1)) inputted to the reset signal input terminal RST of the stage RS(k) from the subsequent stage RS(k&plus;1) indicates the high level (i.e., &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;). While the reset signal is in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the potential of the node B rises. When the potential of the node B rises, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is turned on. Moreover, for this period, the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is turned on, and thereby the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned off. Therefore, the signal having the level of the constant voltage Vdd (i.e., &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) is outputted into the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, and the potential of the node D rises. Thus, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the potential of the node A indicates the reference voltage Vss (i.e., the low level). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Thereafter, the reset signal is brought into the low level, and the TFTs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are turned off. However, since the node B is maintained in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> maintains the on state, and the charges are accumulated in the node D (i.e., the node D is maintained in the high level). Therefore, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. In this case, the input signal inputted into the input signal terminal IN (i.e., the output signal out(k&minus;1) from the previous stage RS(k&minus;1)) does not have the high level. Thus, the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> are in the off state, and the nodes A and C are not in the high level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, at the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the input signal inputted to the input signal terminal IN is brought into the high level, and the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> are turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is turned on, the potential of the node B drops, and the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is turned off. On the other hand, when the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is turned on, the high-level input signal inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode, and the node C indicates the high level. When the potential of the node C rises, the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned on. Therefore, the charges accumulated in the node D are discharged, and the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Moreover, from the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the high-level input signal inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode. Since the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the high-level input signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> allows the potential of the node A to rise. Thus, the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is turned on, the node E indicates the reference voltage Vss, and the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is turned off. In this manner, since the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is in the on state and the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which is to be inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) via the output signal terminal OUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> After the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and immediately before a timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the input signal of the stage RS(k) is brought into the low level by the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of the previous stage RS(k&minus;1), and the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> are turned off. In this time, the node C maintains the high level, and the nodes B, D remain in the low level. Therefore, even when the input signal is brought into the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state, the potential of the node A is held in the high level, and the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> maintain the on state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, when the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is brought into the high level (&plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) at the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a drain current flows in the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, with the rise of the potential of the source electrode, the parasitic capacity constituted of the gate and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the gate insulation film between the electrodes is charged up. When the boot strap effect allows the potential of the node A to further rise and to reach the gate saturated voltage of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the current flowing between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is saturated. Thereby, the output signal out(k) outputted from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) has the high level of &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; which is substantially the same potential as that of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. In a period in which the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is in the high level, the parasitic capacity of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is charged up, and the potential of the node A substantially reaches &plus;45 to &plus;50 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, after the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and immediately before the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is brought into the low level (&minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;). Thereby, the output signal out(k) also has a level of about &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Moreover, the electric charges charged into the parasitic capacity of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are discharged, and the potential of the node A drops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Next, at a timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the reset signal inputted in the reset signal input terminal RST reaches the high level. Thereby, the TFTs <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is turned on, the high-level reset signal inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode. The high-level reset signal outputted to the source electrode brings the node B into the high level, and turns on the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, when the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is turned on, the potential of the node C drops, and the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is turned off. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> When the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is turned on, the signal having the constant voltage Vdd level is outputted to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. Here, since the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the signal outputted to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and having the constant voltage Vdd level brings the node D into the high level. Therefore, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on, the node A is brought into the low level. Thereby, the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are turned off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is turned off, the output of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inputted to the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is cut off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is turned off, the signal having the constant voltage Vdd level is outputted to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the node E is brought into the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is turned on. Thereby, the signal with the reference voltage Vss level is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) via the output signal terminal OUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Immediately before a timing t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> after the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is turned off, and the TFT <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is turned off, but the node B is in the high level. Therefore, since the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> maintains the on state, and the node D remains in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. That is, the node D maintains the high level, until the input signal inputted to the input signal terminal IN reaches the high level at the next timing to. During this time, the node A constantly indicates the reference voltage Vss without being in the floating state. Therefore, from the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> till the next timing tO, the high-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the odd-numbered stage) is outputted to the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the stage RS(k). Even when the potential of the node A is to rise by the parasitic capacity between the gate and source of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the potential is offset by the reference voltage Vss. Therefore, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can maintain the off state. The output signal is not vibrated by the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and can maintain a normal waveform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> When the operation is successively repeated in both the odd-numbered and even-numbered stages, the stage to output the high-level output signal successively shifts to the next stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> The operation of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is substantially the same as the operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. However, the high level of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Therefore, the high level of the output signal out(k) of each stage RS(k) is about &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb;, and the level of the node A in this case is of the order of &plus;18 to &plus;20 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. A period for which the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is in the high level is shorter than a period for which the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is in the high level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> The whole operation for driving the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and picking up an image will next be described with reference to schematic diagrams of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7A</cross-reference> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>I. Additionally, in the following description, a period of 1T has the same length as that of one horizontal period. To simplify the description, first three rows of transistors are considered in a large number of double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> arranged in the image pickup element array <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> First, in the period of 1T from a timing T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> until T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the top gate line TGL of the first row, and supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the top gate lines TGL of the second and third rows (all the other rows). That is, the high-level output signal is outputted from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the low-level output signals are outputted from the output signal terminals OUT of the stages RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), RS(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the bottom gate lines BGL. That is, the low-level output signals are outputted from the output signal terminals OUT of the RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. In this period, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row is brought into a reset state, and the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second and third rows are in a stat in which a read-out state in a previous vertical period ends (a photo sense is not influenced). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 1T from a timing T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>B, the high-level output signal shifts to the stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the top gate line TGL of the second row, and supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the other top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the bottom gate lines BGL. In this period, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row is brought into a photo sense state, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second row is brought into the reset state, and the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of a third row is brought into the state in which the read-out state in the previous vertical period ends (the photo sense is not influenced). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 1T from a timing T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>C, the high-level output signal shifts to the stage RS(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the top gate line TGL of the third row, and supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the other top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the bottom gate lines BGL. In this period, the double gate type transistors of the first and second rows are brought into the photo sense state, and the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row is brought into the reset state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>T from a timing T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>D, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the bottom gate lines BGL. Moreover, the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the data lines DL. In this period, the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of all the rows are brought into the photo sense state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 0.5T from a timing T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>E, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the bottom gate line BGL of the first row, and supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the other bottom gate lines BGL. That is, the high-level output signal is outputted from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the low-level output signals are outputted from the output signal terminals OUT of the stages RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), RS(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>). In this period, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row is brought into the first or second read-out state, and the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second and third rows remain in the photo sense state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Here, in the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is irradiated with a sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the photo sense state, an n-channel is formed in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the second read-out state, and the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are therefore discharged. On the other hand, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not irradiated with the sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the n-channel in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pinched off in the first read-out state, and therefore the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are not discharged. In the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> reads out the potential on each data line DL, and supplies the potential as image data DATA detected by the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row to the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>T from timing T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>F, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> applies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> applies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the bottom gate lines BGL. Moreover, the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> applies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the data lines DL. In this period, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row has ended the read-out, and the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second and third rows are brought into the photo sense state. Between the timings T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the high-level output signal of the stage RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is inputted into the stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), but the clock signal inputted into the stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) does not reach the high level. Since the output signal is not outputted from the stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), 0&lsqb;V&rsqb; is supplied to the bottom gate line BGL of the second row. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 0.5T from a timing T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>G, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the high-level output signal shifts to the stage RS(<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the bottom gate line BGL of the second row, and supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the other bottom gate lines BGL. In this period, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first row is in the state of the ended read-out, the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second row is in the first or second read-out state, and the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row is in the photo sense state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Here, in the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second row, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is irradiated with the sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the photo sense state, the n-channel is formed in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the second read-out state, and the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are therefore discharged. On the other hand, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not irradiated with the sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the n-channel in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pinched off in the first read-out state, and therefore the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are not discharged. In the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> reads out the potential on each data line DL, and supplies the potential as the image data DATA detected by the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the second row to the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 0.5T from timing T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>H, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the data lines DL. In this period, the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first and second rows are brought into the state in which the read-out has ended, and the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row is brought into the photo sense state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, in a period of 0.5T from a timing T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>I, the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> supplies &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to all the top gate lines TGL. On the other hand, the high-level output signal shifts to the stage RS(<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> supplies &plus;10 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the bottom gate line BGL of the third row, and supplies 0 &lsqb;V&rsqb; to the other bottom gate lines BGL. In this period, the double gate type transistors <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the first and second rows are brought into the state in which the read-out has ended, and the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row is brought into the first or second read-out state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> Here, in the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is irradiated with the sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the photo sense state, the n-channel is formed in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the second read-out state, and the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are therefore discharged. On the other hand, when the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is not irradiated with the sufficient light in the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the n-channel in the semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is pinched off in the first read-out state, and therefore the electric charges on the corresponding data line DL are not discharged. In the period of the timing T<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>.<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> till T<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> reads out the potential on each data line DL, and supplies the potential as the image data DATA detected by the double gate type transistor <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the third row to the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> When the image data DATA supplied to each row from the detection driver <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in this manner is subjected to a predetermined processing of the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, image data of an image pick-up object is generated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> An effect of the present invention will next be described. The stage RS(k) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment is constituted by adding the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to the stage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. That is, in the stage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the reset signal input terminal is directly connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, in the stage RS(k) of the present embodiment, the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are disposed between the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the reset signal input terminal RST or the input signal terminal IN. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> In the stage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, when the reset signal turns to the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on and the potential of the node A indicates the reference voltage Vss. Thereafter, when the reset signal turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned off, and maintains the off state as long as the reset signal does not next reach the high level. Therefore, from when the reset signal turns to the low level until the signal reaches the high level, the wiring of the node A is in the floating state. In this case, when the clock signal inputted into the clock signal input terminal reaches the high level, the parasitic capacity constituted of the gate and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the gate insulation film between the electrodes is charged up and the potential of the wiring A rises. Then, the leak current flows between the source and drain electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Therefore, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, in t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, or t<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to t<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, during the driving of another stage, the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the stage is displaced by the high-level clock signal and malfunction of the TFT is caused. Therefore, the driving driver constituted of the stage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, and the image pickup apparatus including the driver sometimes cause the malfunction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in the present embodiment, when the reset signal reaches the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the node A indicates the reference voltage Vss. Thereafter, even when the reset signal turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. Because the TFTs <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are disposed in the stage RS(k). Thereafter, when the input signal reaches the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned off. Even when the input signal turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state. Here, from when the reset signal reaches the high level until the input signal reaches the high level (i.e., between t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>), the clock signal reaches the high level, and then the parasitic capacity constituted of the gate and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the gate insulation film between the electrodes is charged up. However, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state in this period. Therefore, even when the parasitic capacity is charged up, the electric charges are discharged by the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and the potential of the node A does not rise. Therefore, in the present embodiment, the leak current does not flow from the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> by the high level of the clock signal. The level of the output signal terminal OUT is subtle but does not rise. Therefore, power consumptions of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are prevented from being wasted, and the output signals of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> securely shift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> While the node A is in the high level, and when the clock signal inputted into the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> reaches the high level, the potential of the node A rises, and the high-level output signal out(k) is outputted from the output signal terminal OUT. Here, since the node A is not connected to elements such as a resistance and capacitor other than the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the node A securely rises to the gate saturated voltage. Therefore, the drop of the high-level output signal out(k) outputted from the output signal terminal OUT is not caused. Therefore, the output signals of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the present embodiment securely shift. Therefore, the stability of the operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is satisfactory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> In the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the high-level clock signals CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> from the sages RS(k) are outputted as the output signals out(k) of the stages RS(k) at substantially the same level. Therefore, even when a buffer is not disposed in each stage RS(k), the output signal out(k) can successively shift without attenuating the level of the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Second Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a second embodiment will next be described. The constitution of the image pickup apparatus of the second embodiment is substantially the same as the image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment. Additionally, in the second embodiment, the constitution of each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is different from that of the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the circuit constitution of the respective stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the second embodiment. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, each stage includes TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> as the basic constitution, and TFTs <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> as the additional constitution. Similarly as the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the TFTs <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are n-channel MOS type field-effect transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> The connection constitution of the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is substantially the same as that of the first embodiment. Additionally, in the first embodiment, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, in the second embodiment, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In the wiring connected to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the parasitic capacities are generated among the TFTs <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and a node F is positioned as an optional point in the wiring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> The drain and gate electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> are connected to the reset signal input terminal RST. Moreover, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is connected to the input signal terminal IN, and the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> The TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> have the functions similar to those of the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> When the node F is in the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on, the potential of the node A is set to the reference voltage Vss, and the potential state is maintained. On the other hand, when the node F is in the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned off. In a period in which both the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are in the off state, the wiring of the node A is brought into the floating state, and the potential of the node A can fluctuate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> The reset signal is inputted into the drain and gate electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. In the stage RS(k) other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the reset signal is the output signal out(k&plus;1) of the subsequent stage RS(k&plus;1). With the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the reset signal is the reset signal Vrst outputted from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> When the high-level reset signal (i.e., the output signal out(k&plus;1)) is inputted into the embodiment of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the current flows to the source electrode from the drain electrode. Therefore, the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in the on state outputs corresponding high-level reset signal from the source electrode. Here, when the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the node F is brought into the high level by the high-level reset signal outputted from the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The on/off state of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is controlled by the input signal. That is, when the low-level input signal (i.e., the output signal out(k&minus;1)) is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is turned off. The TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the off state obtains a state in which the charges can be accumulated in the wiring of the node F. On the other hand, when the high-level input signal is inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is turned off. The TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the on state sets the potential of the node F to the reference voltage Vss. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The operation of the image pickup apparatus according to the second embodiment will be described hereinafter. Additionally, the operation of the image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the first embodiment is different from the operation of the image pickup apparatus in the second embodiment only in the operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> of the second embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. Additionally, in the following description, the even-numbered stages other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> will be described as examples. Since the operations of the other stages and each stage of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are substantially the same as those of the even-numbered stages of the top gate drivers <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the detailed description thereof is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, at the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the input signal inputted into the input signal terminal IN (i.e., the output signal out(k&minus;1) of the previous stage RS(k&minus;1)) is brought into the high level, and the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is turned on, the node F indicates the reference voltage Vss, and the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned off. Moreover, at the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the high-level input signal inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode. Since the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the high-level input signal raises the potential of the node A, turns on the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and turns off the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> After the timing to and immediately before a timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the input signal turns to the low level, and the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are turned off. In this case, the node F indicates the reference voltage Vss. Therefore, even when the input signal is in the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state, and the accumulated state of the charges in the node A is maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, at the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> reaches the high level. Then, the parasitic capacity constituted of the gate and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the gate insulation film between the electrodes is charged up, and the boot strap effect further raises the potential of the node A. Moreover, when the potential of the node A reaches the gate saturated voltage, the current flowing between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is saturated. Thereby, the output signal out(k) outputted from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) indicates substantially the same potential of &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; as that of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and is in the high level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, after the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and immediately before the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> turns to the low level. Thereby, the level of the output signal out(k) is about &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Moreover, the electric charges charged into the parasitic capacity of the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are discharged, and the potential of the node A drops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, at the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the reset signal inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST (i.e., the output signal out(k&plus;1) of the subsequent stage RS(k&plus;1)) reaches the high level. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is turned on, the high-level reset signal inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode. In response to the high-level reset signal outputted to the source electrode, the charges are accumulated in the node F, and the potential of the node F reaches the high level. When the charges are accumulated in the node F, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is turned on, the node A indicates the reference voltage Vss, and thereby the TFTs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are turned off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is turned off, the output of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inputted into the drain electrode is cut off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is turned off, the signal having the constant voltage Vdd level is outputted to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the node E reaches the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is turned on, and thereby the signal having the reference voltage Vss level is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) from the output signal terminal OUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> After the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and immediately before the timing t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, when the reset signal turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> is turned off. In this case, since the TFT <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the state of the charges accumulated in the node F is maintained, and the node F maintains the high level. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. Moreover, the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state, until the input signal next reaches the high level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> When the operation is successively repeated in both the odd-numbered and even-numbered stages, the stage to output the high-level output signal successively shifts to the next stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> As described above, even in the second embodiment, similarly as the first embodiment, from when the high-level reset signal is inputted until the high-level input signal is inputted, the potential of the node F maintains the high-level state, and thereby the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the on state. On the other hand, from when the high-level input signal is inputted until the high-level reset signal is inputted, the node F maintains the low level, and the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> maintains the off state. Therefore, from when the high-level reset signal is inputted until the high-level input signal is inputted, even with the input of the high-level clock signal into the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the potential of the node A does not rise. Therefore, even in the second embodiment, the leak current is inhibited from flowing from the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> because of the high level of the clock signal. The level of the output signal terminal OUT is slight but does not rise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> Third Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a third embodiment will next be described. The constitution of the image pickup apparatus of the third embodiment is substantially the same as the image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the first embodiment. Additionally, in the third embodiment, the constitution of each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is different from that of the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagram showing the circuit constitution of the respective stages RS(<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to RS(n) of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, each stage includes TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> as the basic constitution, and a capacitor (capacity) <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> as the additional constitution. The TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the first embodiment, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, and the TFT <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> corresponds to the TFT <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Similarly as the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, the TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are n-channel MOS type field-effect transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> The connection constitution of the TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is substantially the same as that of the first embodiment. Additionally, in the first embodiment, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, in the third embodiment, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is connected to the reset signal input terminal RST. Moreover, one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is connected to the output signal terminal OUT, and the other pole thereof is connected to the wiring connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> The functions of the TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are similar to those of the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> When the reset signal inputted into the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> reaches the high level, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is turned on, and the potential of the node A is set to the reference voltage Vss. On the other hand, when the reset signal inputted to the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is turned off, and the node A is brought into the floating state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> Here, when the node A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is in the floating state, a capacity Cp<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on a clock signal potential side having the node A as one end is a sum of the parasitic capacity between the node A and the wiring of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the parasitic capacity between the node A and the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. When the node A is in the floating state, a capacity Cp<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on a reference voltage Vss side having the node A as one end is a sum of the parasitic capacity between the node A and the wiring of the reference voltage Vss, parasitic capacity between the node A and the TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and capacity of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Moreover, a capacity Cp<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on a constant voltage Vdd side having the node A as one end is the parasitic capacity between the node A and the wiring of the constant voltage Vdd. Therefore, when the node A is in the floating state and the high-level clock signal CK<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is inputted to the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, a potential Vf of the node A can be represented in the following equation (1). </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>Vf&equals;&lcub;Ca&times;</italic></highlight>Vdd&plus;(<highlight><italic>Cb&plus;Cc</italic></highlight>)&times;Vss&rcub;/(<highlight><italic>Ca&plus;Cb&plus;Cc</italic></highlight>) &emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> That is, when settings of the TFTs <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the present embodiment are equal to those of the TFTs <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> value Cb of the present embodiment is larger by the capacity of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> as compared with the capacity on the reference voltage Vss side having the node A as one end during the node A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> having the floating state. Therefore, during the floating, the voltage Vf of the node A displaced by the high-level clock signal CK can be lowered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> The operation of the image pickup apparatus according to the third embodiment will be described hereinafter. Additionally, the operation of the image pickup apparatus <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in the first embodiment is different from the operation of the image pickup apparatus in the third embodiment only in the operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The operation of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the third embodiment will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. Additionally, in the following description, the even-numbered stages of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2) will be described as examples. Since the operations of the other stages of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and each stage of the bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are substantially the same as those of the even-numbered stages of the top gate drivers <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> other than the dummy stage RS(n&plus;2), the detailed description thereof is omitted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> At the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the input signal inputted into the input signal terminal IN (i.e., the output signal out(k&minus;1) of the previous stage RS(k&minus;1)) is brought into the high level, and the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is turned on, the high-level input signal inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is outputted to the source electrode. In this case, the reset signal inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST (the output signal out(k&plus;1) of the subsequent stage RS(k&plus;1)) is in the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is in the off state. Therefore, at the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, by the high-level input signal outputted from the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the potential of the node A rises. When the potential of the node A rises, the TFTs <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is turned on, the potential of the node E indicates the reference voltage Vss, and the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is turned off. Since the TFTs <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> are in the on state in this manner, the low-level clock signal inputted into the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) from the output signal terminal OUT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> After the timing t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and before the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the input signal turns to the low level, and the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is turned off. Also in this case, since the reset signal is in the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is in the off state and the charges are accumulated in the wiring of the node A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> reaches the high level in the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Then, the parasitic capacity constituted of the gate and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the gate insulation film between the electrodes is charged up, and the boot strap effect further raises the potential of the node A. Moreover, when the potential of the node A reaches the gate saturated voltage of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the current flowing between the drain and source electrodes of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is saturated. Thereby, the output signal out(k) outputted from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) indicates substantially the same potential of &plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb; as that of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and is in the high level. Furthermore, when the high-level output signal out(k) is outputted from the output signal terminal OUT, the potential of one pole as the output signal terminal OUT of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is the same as the level (&plus;25 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and the potential of the other pole as the wiring side of the node A of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is the same as the potential of the node A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> Next, after the timing t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and immediately before the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> turns to the low level. Thereby, the level of the output signal out(k) is about &minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;. Moreover, the electric charges charged into the parasitic capacity of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are discharged, and the potential of the node A drops. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, at the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the reset signal inputted into the reset signal input terminal RST reaches the high level. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is turned on. When the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is turned on, the potential of the node A indicates the reference voltage Vss, and thereby the TFTs <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are turned off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is turned off, the output of the clock signal CK<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> inputted into the drain electrode is cut off. When the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is turned off, the signal having the constant voltage Vdd level is outputted to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and the potential of the node E rises. When the potential of the node E rises, the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is turned on, and thereby the signal having the reference voltage Vss level is outputted as the output signal out(k) of the stage RS(k) from the output signal terminal OUT. Moreover, since the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is in the on state, the potential of one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> on the output signal terminal OUT side is the same (&minus;15 &lsqb;V&rsqb;) as the level of the reference voltage Vss. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> After the timing t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and immediately before the timing t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, when the reset signal turns to the low level, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is turned off. Thereby, the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is in the off state, and the wiring of the node A is brought into the floating state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> When the operation is successively repeated in both the odd-numbered and even-numbered stages, the stage to output the high-level output signal successively shifts to the next stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> The effect of the third embodiment will next be described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a circuit diagram showing the constitution of one stage of the top gate driver or the bottom gate driver as a comparative example. That is, in each stage of the comparative example, instead of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> of the stage RS(k) in the third embodiment, a capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is disposed. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> and gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> In the stage shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, since the other electrode of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS, the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> has a function of constantly adjusting the amount of charges accumulated in the capacity constantly having the wiring of the node A as one pole, and stabilizing the potential of the node A. Therefore, even when the clock signal reaches the high level (corresponding to t<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to t<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, t<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to t<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>), the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> suppresses the rise of the potential of the node A. However, immediately after the charges are accumulated in the capacity having the wiring of the node A as one pole, the clock signal reaches the high level (corresponding to t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>). Even in this case, the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> suppresses the rise of the potential of the node A. Therefore, between t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the level of the output signal from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage is lower than the high level of the clock signal, and the output signal of the top gate driver or bottom gate driver does not completely shift in some case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, according to the third embodiment, when the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is in the on state (from when the input signal reaches the high level until the reset signal reaches the high level, i.e., between t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>), the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is in the off state. Therefore, the potential of one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> on the output signal terminal OUT side is substantially the same as the level of the clock signal. Therefore, while the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is in the on state, the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> does not act so as to stabilize the potential of the node A. Therefore, in the third embodiment, between t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the level of the output signal from the output signal terminal OUT of the stage RS(k) is substantially the same as the high level of the clock signal. That is, the high level of the output signal out(k) of each stage RS(k) in the third embodiment is higher than the high level of the output signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, and the output signals of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the third embodiment securely shift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> In the third embodiment, while the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is in the off state (from when the reset signal reaches the high level until the input signal reaches the high level, i.e., between t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>), the TFT <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> is in the on state, and therefore the potential of one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is substantially the same as the level of the reference voltage Vss. Therefore, while the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is in the off state, the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> adjusts the amount of the charges accumulated in the capacity having the wiring of the node A as one pole, and acts so as to stabilize the potential of the node A. Therefore, even when the clock signal reaches the high level between t<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and t<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> suppresses the rise of the potential of the node A. Thereby, the leak current does not flow from the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, and the level of the output signal terminal OUT is slight but does not rise. Therefore, the power consumptions of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are prevented from being wasted, and the output signals of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> securely shift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> Fourth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a fourth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> used in the image pickup apparatus of the fourth embodiment includes a capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in addition to the constitution of each stage in the third embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Since one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is connected to the reference voltage applied terminal SS having a constant potential, the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> adjusts the amount of the charges accumulated in the capacity having the wiring of the node A as one pole, and acts so as to stabilize the potential of the node A. Moreover, since the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is disposed, the effect similar to that of the third embodiment is produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> Fifth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a fifth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> included in the image pickup apparatus of the fifth embodiment uses a capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> in addition to the constitution of each stage in the third embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is connected to the constant voltage applied terminal DD. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Since one pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is connected to the constant voltage applied terminal DD having a constant potential, the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> adjusts the amount of the charges accumulated in the capacity having the wiring of the node A as one pole, and acts so as to stabilize the potential of the capacity A. Moreover, since the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is disposed, the effect similar to that of the third embodiment is produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> Sixth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a sixth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the image pickup apparatus of the sixth embodiment includes a capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in addition to the constitution of each stage in the third embodiment as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is grounded. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. Since the one electrode of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is grounded and has a constant potential, the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> adjusts the amount of the charges accumulated in the capacity having the wiring of the node A as one pole, and acts so as to stabilize the potential of the node A. Moreover, since the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is provided, the effect similar to that of the third embodiment is produced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> Seventh Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a seventh embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the image pickup apparatus of the seventh embodiment includes the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>) in addition to the constitution of each stage (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>) in the fourth embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is connected to the constant voltage applied terminal DD. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> Eighth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as an eighth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> included in the image pickup apparatus of the eighth embodiment includes the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>) in addition to the constitution of each stage (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>) in the fourth embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is grounded. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0187" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0187&rsqb;</number> Ninth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0188" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0188&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a ninth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the image pickup apparatus of the ninth embodiment includes the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in addition to the constitution of each stage (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>) in the fifth embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is grounded. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0189" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0189&rsqb;</number> Tenth Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0190" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0190&rsqb;</number> The image pickup apparatus as a tenth embodiment will next be described. Each stage of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> or bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the image pickup apparatus of the tenth embodiment includes the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> in addition to the constitution of each stage (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>) in the seventh embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>. One pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is grounded. The other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is connected to the source electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the gate electrode of the TFT <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and the other pole of the capacitor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0191" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0191&rsqb;</number> For the above-described image pickup apparatuses in the fourth to tenth embodiments, the constitution other than the respective stages of the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is similar to that of the image pickup apparatus in the third embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0192" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0192&rsqb;</number> The present invention is not limited to the aforementioned embodiments, and can variously be improved and changed in design without departing from the scope of the invention. For example, in the embodiments, the electronic apparatus of the present invention is applied to the image pickup apparatus, but may be applied to another device such as a display. For example, when the electronic apparatus according to the present invention is applied to a liquid crystal display, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22, a</cross-reference> liquid crystal display <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> includes a liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> for displaying an image, a gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and drain driver <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> for driving the liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, and a controller <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> for controlling the whole liquid crystal display <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0193" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0193&rsqb;</number> The liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> includes an array substrate, pixel electrodes arranged in a matrix on the array substrate, a large number of TFTs <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> arranged in the matrix on the array substrate and corresponding to the respective pixel electrodes, an opposite substrate disposed opposite to the array substrate, a liquid crystal layer sealed between the array substrate and the opposite substrate, and a common electrode disposed on the surface of the opposite substrate on a side opposite to the array substrate. The gate electrode of each TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is connected to a gate line g<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the drain electrode thereof is connected to a drain line (hereinafter referred to the data line d<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>), and the source electrode thereof is connected to the pixel electrode. A reference voltage is supplied to the common electrode. A pixel capacity <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is formed between each pixel electrode and common electrode. Each TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is used as a switching element for accumulating the charges in the corresponding pixel capacity. In the pixel capacity or capacities in all pixel capacities <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> in which the charges are accumulated, the liquid crystal responds (orientation changes), and the liquid crystal does not respond (the orientation changes) in the pixel capacity or capacities in which the charges are not accumulated. Light is transmitted through the liquid crystal having responded, and is not transmitted through the liquid crystal not having responded. Thereby, the liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> controls the amount of light transmitted through the liquid crystal layer and displays the image. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0194" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0194&rsqb;</number> The gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is any one of the shift registers applied to the top gate driver <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and bottom gate driver <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> in the first to tenth embodiments. The gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> successively supplies a predetermined voltage to g<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> in response to a control signal Gcnt from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0195" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0195&rsqb;</number> The drain driver <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> successively takes image data data from the controller <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in response to a control signal Dcnt from the controller <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. When the image data for one line is accumulated, the drain driver <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> outputs the data to the data line DL in response to the control signal Dcnt from the controller <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, and the TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> connected to the data line gl selected in accordance with the gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is turned on. Thereby, the charges are accumulated in the pixel capacity <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0196" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0196&rsqb;</number> When the image is displayed on the liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in the liquid crystal display <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, first, the gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> outputs the high-level signal from the stage corresponding to the gate line g<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the row into which the image data is to be written, and turns on the TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of the row. In the timing in which the TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> of the row is on, the drain driver <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> outputs the voltage corresponding to the accumulated image data to the data line DL, and accumulates the charges in the pixel capacity <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> via the TFT <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> in the on state. By the repetition of the above operation, the orientation state of the liquid crystal corresponding to each pixel capacity <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> changes, and the image is displayed on the liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0197" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0197&rsqb;</number> In the above-described embodiments, the shift register according to the present invention is applied to the driver for driving the gate driver <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and liquid crystal display element <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, but can also be applied to other uses. For example, the shift register according to the present invention can also be applied, for example, when series data is converted to parallel data in a data processing apparatus. Moreover, the TFTs <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> are transistors, but may be loads such as resistors, other than the transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0198" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0198&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in the above-described embodiments, all the transistors of the respective stages are of the n-channel type, but may be of a p-channel type. In this case, each signal has a reversed potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0199" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0199&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the present invention, from when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted to the stage from the previous stage until the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted to the stage from the subsequent stage, without lowering the level of the clock signal, the clock signal can be outputted as the output signal of the stage. On the other hand, from when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted to the stage from the subsequent stage until the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted to the stage from the previous stage, the output signal having the level raised by the clock signal because of the parasitic capacity of the transistor is not outputted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0200" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0200&rsqb;</number> Additional advantages and modifications will readily occur to those skilled in the art. Therefore, the invention in its broader aspects is not limited to the specific details and representative embodiments shown and described herein. Accordingly, various modifications may be made without departing from the spirit or scope of the general invention concept as defined by the appended claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A shift register which comprises a plurality of stages, and successively outputs an output signal having a predetermined level from each stage, each stage comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage via the other terminal, when the output signal having a predetermined level is inputted into the control terminal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor which has a control terminal connected to the other terminal of said first transistor, accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with the control terminal of said second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of said second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of said second transistor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a potential holding section to displace a potential of said wiring to a predetermined level when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the subsequent stage, and to hold the potential of said wiring at a predetermined level until the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted from the previous stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>a third transistor which has a control terminal, and displaces the potential of said wiring to a predetermined level in an on state; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth transistor which has a control terminal, outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage, and stops the output of the on voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth transistor which has a control terminal, outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage, and stops the output of the off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>a sixth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of said fourth transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>a seventh transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of said fourth transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>an eighth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to the control terminal of said fifth transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>a ninth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of said fifth transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said potential holding section comprises: 
<claim-text>a third transistor which has a control terminal, and displaces the potential of said wiring to a predetermined level in an on state; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tenth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal as an on voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor, when the output signal from the subsequent stage is inputted into one terminal and the control terminal of said tenth transistor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an eleventh transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal as an off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a twelfth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a second voltage as the output signal of the stage, when a first voltage is supplied to the control terminal of said twelfth transistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a thirteenth transistor which outputs an off voltage to the control terminal of said twelfth transistor in response to the output signal outputted to said wiring from the other terminal of said first transistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a fourteenth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs said first voltage inputted into one terminal to said control terminal of said twelfth transistor via the other terminal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An electronic apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a shift register comprising a plurality of stages, said stage comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage via the other terminal, when the output signal having a predetermined level is inputted into the control terminal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor which has a control terminal connected to the other terminal of said first transistor, accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with the control terminal of said second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of said second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of said second transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third transistor which has a control terminal, and displaces the potential of said wiring to a predetermined level in an on state; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an on voltage to said control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the subsequent stage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a signal having a predetermined level as an off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal from the previous stage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven element which is driven by the output signals outputted from the respective stages of said shift register. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The electronic apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said driven element includes an image pickup element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The electronic apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said driven element includes a double gate type transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A shift register which comprises a plurality of stages, and successively outputs an output signal having a predetermined level from each stage, each stage comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor to output the output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage, when the output signal having the predetermined level is inputted into a control terminal from the previous stage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor whose control terminal is connected to the other terminal of said first transistor, and which accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with a control terminal of said second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of said second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of said second transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a second voltage as the output signal of the stage, when a first voltage is supplied to the control terminal of the third transistor from a first voltage wiring; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth transistor which outputs an off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal outputted to said wiring from the other terminal of said first transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth transistor which displaces the potential of said wiring to a predetermined level in response to the output signal having a predetermined level from the subsequent stage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor disposed between said wiring and the other terminal of said second transistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said each stage comprises: 
<claim-text>a second capacitor disposed between said wiring and a second constant voltage wiring which supplies said second constant voltage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The shift register according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said each stage comprises: 
<claim-text>a third capacitor disposed between said wiring and said first constant voltage wiring. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An electronic apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>(i) a shift register which comprises a plurality of stages, each stage comprising: 
<claim-text>a first transistor to output an output signal inputted into one terminal from the previous stage, when the output signal having a predetermined level is inputted into a control terminal from the previous stage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transistor having a control terminal connected to the other terminal of said first transistor, and which accumulates charges in a capacity having a wiring connected with a control terminal of said second transistor as one pole by a clock signal inputted into one terminal of said second transistor and outputs the clock signal as the output signal of the stage via the other terminal of said second transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third transistor which has a control terminal, and outputs a second voltage as the output signal of the stage, when a first voltage is supplied to the control terminal of the third transistor from a first voltage wiring; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth transistor which outputs an off voltage to the control terminal of said third transistor in response to the output signal outputted to said wiring from the other terminal of said first transistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fifth transistor which displaces the potential of said wiring to a predetermined level in response to the output signal having the predetermined level from the subsequent stage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a capacitor disposed between said wiring and the other terminal of said second transistor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a driven element which is driven by the output signals outputted from the respective stages of said shift register.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030002615A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
