<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000074A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000074A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000074</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10217967</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020813</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01M010/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01M004/66</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01M004/52</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>623100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>429</class>
<subclass>245000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>429</class>
<subclass>231300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>429</class>
<subclass>223000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>029</class>
<subclass>623200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method for making a lithium ion battery capable of being discharged to zero volts</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10217967</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020813</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09675287</doc-number>
<document-date>20000929</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60199895</doc-number>
<document-date>20000426</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hisashi</given-name>
<family-name>Tsukamoto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Saugus</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Clay</given-name>
<family-name>Kishiyama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mikito</given-name>
<family-name>Nagata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Nakahara</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Santa Clarita</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tiehua</given-name>
<family-name>Piao</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Valencia</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>QUALLION, LLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 905</address-1>
<city>Santa Clarita</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>91380-9005</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A lithium ion battery particularly configured to be able to discharge to a very low voltage, e.g. zero volts, without causing permanent damage to the battery. More particularly, the battery is configured to define a Zero Volt Crossing Potential (ZCP) which is lower than a Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP) to thus avoid low voltage substrate damage. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/199,895 filed Apr. 26, 2000.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to rechargeable batteries and more particularly to a rechargeable lithium battery capable of discharging to zero volts without causing damage to the battery. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Rechargeable lithium batteries are widely discussed in the literature and are readily commercially available. They typically consist of a positive electrode and a negative electrode spaced by a separator, an electrolyte, a case, and feedthrough pins respectively connected to the electrodes and extending externally of the case. Each electrode is typically formed of a metal substrate that is coated with a mixture of an active material, a binder, and a solvent. In a typical battery design, the electrodes comprise sheets which are rolled together, separated by separator sheets, and then placed in a prismatic case. Positive and/or negative feed through pins (i.e., terminals) are then connected to the respective electrodes and the case is sealed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The negative electrode is typically formed of a copper substrate carrying graphite as the active material. The positive electrode is typically formed of an aluminum substrate carrying lithium cobalt dioxide as the active material. The electrolyte is most commonly a 1.1 mixture of EC:DEC in a 1.0 M salt of LiPF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>. The separator is frequently a micro porous membrane made of a polyolephine, such as a combination of polyethylene and/or polypropylene which can, for example, be approximately 25 &mgr;m thick. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> It is typical to use protection circuitry with lithium ion batteries to avoid potential deleterious effects. Thus, protection circuitry is frequently employed to terminate charging if the voltage or temperature of the battery (or any cell) exceeds a certain level. Moreover, it is common to incorporate a low voltage cutoff to disconnect the battery from its load if the voltage of the battery (or any cell) falls below a certain lower level. This latter precaution is taken to prevent permanent damage to the battery which can occur if a voltage greater than a Damage Potential Threshold (DPT) is applied to one of the electrodes. For example, corrosion or decomposition of the negative electrode substrate can occur if a voltage greater than a Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP) is applied to the negative electrode. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed to a rechargeable lithium ion battery particularly configured to be able to discharge to a very low voltage, e.g. zero volts, without causing permanent damage to the battery. More particularly, a battery in accordance with the invention is configured to define a Zero Volt Crossing Potential (ZCP) which is lower than the battery&apos;s Damage Potential Threshold (DPT) and more specifically its Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP), to thus avoid low voltage substrate damage. The ZCP refers to the voltage of each of the electrodes relative to a lithium reference (Li/Li&plus;) when the battery potential, i.e., the potential between the electrodes, is zero. The SDP refers to the dissolution potential of the negative electrode substrate relative to the lithium reference (Li/Li&plus;). A conventional lithium ion battery typically exhibits a ZCP of about 3.6 volts which can slightly exceed the battery&apos;s SDP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, the material selected for the negative electrode substrate has a dissolution potential greater than the ZCP. Commercially pure titanium and titanium alloys are preferred. Nickel, nickel alloys, and stainless steel can also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In the normal operation of a lithium ion battery, a solid electrolyte interface (SEI) layer, i.e., a passivation layer, is formed on the negative electrode, attributable to a reaction between the negative electrode and the electrolyte. The SEI layer comprises an insulating membrane that tends to inhibit the continuing reaction of the negative electrode and electrolyte. It has been recognized that this SEI layer can dissolve at a voltage above a certain level, i.e., Film Dissolution Potential (FDP), which can lead to permanent damage to the negative electrode. In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention, the battery is configured to assure a ZCP lower than said FDP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A battery&apos;s ZCP level relative to the lithium reference is dependent in part on the materials used for the positive and/or negative electrodes. In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention, a positive electrode active material, e.g., LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(0&lt;x&lE;1), is selected which exhibits a discharge curve appropriate to achieve a relatively low ZCP level. This feature of the preferred embodiment facilitates the implementation of a battery in accordance with the invention characterized by a Zero Crossing Potential (ZCP) less than its Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP) and/or its Film Dissolution Potential (FDP). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Batteries in accordance with the present invention are particularly suited for use in critical applications where physical access to the battery may be difficult. For example, batteries in accordance with the invention find application in medical devices configured to be implanted under the skin in a patient&apos;s body. Such a medical device is typically comprised of a hermetically sealed housing formed of biocompatible material and dimensioned sufficiently small as to be able to be implanted without interfering with normal bodily function. A battery in accordance with the invention includes a case configured for mounting in the device housing. The battery case can be of a variety of shapes, e.g., prismatic or cylindrical, and typically defines a volume of between 0.05 cc and 30 cc. Batteries within this range exhibit capacities between 1.0 milliamp hours and 3 amp hours. An exemplary battery for use in such a device includes a prismatic hermetically sealed battery casing having dimensions of 35 mm&times;17 mm&times;5.5 mm. The device is intended to be implanted in the lower back region to help alleviate back pain using neurostimulation techniques. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The above and other features and uniqueness of the invention will be better visualized from the following drawings and schematics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> schematically depicts positive and negative battery electrodes rolled around a mandrel for placement in a battery case and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> depicts in cross-section a complete battery; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a typical deep discharge curve for a conventional lithium ion battery using copper as the negative electrode substrate and lithium cobalt dioxide LiCoO2 as the positive electrode active material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a typical deep discharge curve for a zero volt battery in accordance with the present invention using titanium as the negative electrode substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a typical deep discharge curve for a zero volt battery in accordance with the present invention using LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(0&lt;x&lE;1) as the positive electrode active material; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a table showing preliminary test results of various battery configurations in accordance with the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> schematically depicts a battery in accordance with the invention contained within an implantable medical device housing.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The following description discloses presently contemplated preferred embodiments for practicing the invention. This description is not to be taken in a limited sense, but is offered for the purpose of describing the preferred modes of the invention. The scope of the invention should be determined with reference to the claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference> schematically depict a typical lithium ion battery construction <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprising a prismatic case <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> containing a positive electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a negative electrode <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, rolled around a mandrel <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Separator sheets <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are incorporated in the rolling to electrically separate the electrodes. The case <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> also typically includes electrolyte material (not shown) and positive and negative feed through pins (i.e., terminals) <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which are respectively connected to the electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and extend externally of the case <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The positive electrode <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is typically comprised of a thin metal substrate, e.g., aluminum, carrying a layer of positive active material, e.g., lithium cobalt dioxide LiCoO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>mixed with a binder, and coated on both faces of the substrate. The negative electrode <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is typically comprised of a thin metal substrate, e.g., copper, carrying a layer of negative active material, e.g., graphite coated on both faces of the substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Two layers of separator <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> electrically separate the electrodes <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> from each other, enabling the electrodes to be rolled around mandrel <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Each separator layer can comprise a micro porous membrane made of a combination of polypropylene and is approximately 25 &mgr;m thick. The electrolyte is most commonly a 1:1 mixture of EC:DEC in a 1.0 M salt of LiPF<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows typical deep discharge performance curves for a conventional lithium ion battery. The y-axis represents voltage relative to a lithium reference (Li/Li&plus;) or counter electrode and the x-axis represents time. Curves <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> respectively depict the discharge curves for the positive and negative electrodes. The battery output voltage is the difference between the positive electrode voltage and the negative electrode voltage. During discharge, the positive electrode voltage decreases relative to Li/Li&plus; and the negative voltage increases, primarily near the end of discharge. Typically, a protection or management circuit stops the discharge when the battery voltage reaches 2.5 Volts. If the management circuit does not stop the discharge, the negative electrode potential will rise until it reaches the potential of the positive electrode which constitutes the Zero Volt Crossing Potential (ZCP) and is typically about 3.6 volts in conventional lithium ion battery constructions. The negative electrode potential at ZCP, relative to Li/Li&plus;, can exceed the dissolution potential of the negative electrode substrate (SDP), e.g., 3.3 volts for copper, and cause dissolution and permanent damage to the substrate. The present invention is directed to battery improvements to assure that the value of SDP is greater than the value of ZCP, as represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts deep discharge performance curves for a lithium ion battery in accordance with the present invention in which the negative electrode substrate is formed of titanium instead of copper. The use of titanium increases the knee of the negative electrode curve <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> to position the SDP above the ZCP. This relationship considerably reduces potential damage to the negative electrode substrate. In addition to commercially pure titanium, i.e., titanium CP, other materials can be used to raise the SDP sufficiently, e.g. titanium alloys, nickel, nickel alloys, and stainless steel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> demonstrates how the SDP level can be increased relative to the ZCP by proper choice of the negative electrode substrate material. Alternatively, or additionally, the ZCP level can be decreased relative to the SDP by proper choice of the positive electrode active material, as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> More particularly, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the discharge curve <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> for a positive electrode using lithium nickel cobalt dioxide LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X </subscript></highlight>(where 0&lt;x&lE;1) as the active material, i.e., as the intercalation compound. Note that the curve of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> exhibits a greater negative slope than the analogous curve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> representing the standard intercalation compound LiCoO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>The effect of the increased negative slope is to lower the ZCP level relative to the lithium reference and the SDP. As was the case in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, this reduces the potential damage to the negative electrode substrate. Additionally, however, the ZCP level also falls below a Film Dissolution Potential (FDP) which is the voltage above which a solid electrolyte interface (SEI) layer begins to dissolve. The SEI, or film, comprises a passivation layer which forms on the negative electrode and functions to inhibit a continuing reaction between the negative electrode active material and the electrolyte. Dissolution of the SEI can noticeably damage the negative electrode active material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Experiments have been performed at two different temperatures employing the aforedescribed techniques depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>. The preliminary results are summarized in the table of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Four different battery configurations were constructed as shown. Configuration (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) corresponds to the conventional arrangement represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> comprising a copper substrate for the negative electrode and LiCoO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>for the positive active material. The battery was built and then recycled once to get an initial capacity measurement. The battery was then shorted between the positive and negative leads to achieve a zero volt state. This zero volt condition was held for one week and then recharged and discharged to get a capacity measurement after zero-volt storage. The capacity retention is calculated by dividing the discharge capacity after zero volt storage by the initial capacity and multiplying by 100%. In this manner, this percentage reflects any damage that had occurred to the battery while in the zero volt state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the capacity retention for battery configuration (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) is below 80%, thus suggesting that damage had been done to the battery. After opening the battery and examining the electrodes, it was seen that copper dissolution had occurred. This battery (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) configuration performed poorly at both temperature settings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The battery configuration (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) used LiCoO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>as the positive active material and a titanium substrate as the negative substrate corresponding to the arrangement represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The results show that at 25&deg; C. the capacity retention was at about 98% after the zero volt condition. However, at a higher temperature (37&deg; C.), performance deteriorates to below 80%. This suggests that perhaps the zero volt crossing potential was sufficiently below SDP to avoid substrate dissolution but still high enough to exceed FDP and cause damage to the negative electrode active material. Accordingly, attempts were made to lower ZCP further to avoid damage both to the negative active material and the negative electrode substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The battery configuration (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) utilizes LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(0&lt;x&lE;1) as the positive active material with copper negative electrode substrate. The results show that at 37&deg; C. the capacity retention is quite high at 90%. However, examination after the test, revealed that some copper dissolution occurred. Battery configuration (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) uses both LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(0&lt;x&lE;1) as the positive active material and the titanium as the negative electrode substrate material. Results show that this configuration gives the best capacity retention after zero volt storage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing table (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>), it appears that a performance gain is achieved by configuration (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) using a titanium negative electrode substrate and by configuration (<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) using lithium nickel cobalt dioxide as the positive active material. However, maximum performance gain appears in configuration (<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) which combines both of these features. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> schematically depicts a battery <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> in accordance with the invention mounted in a housing <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> (shown partially open for the purposes of illustration) of a medical device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> configured for implanting in a patient&apos;s body. The housing <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is preferably formed of biocompatible material and hermetically sealed. The device <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is typically used for monitoring and/or affecting body parameters. For example, the device can be used to electrically stimulate nerves. The casing <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> of battery <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> can, for example, have dimensions of 35 mm&times;17 mm&times;5.5 mm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described with reference to specific exemplary embodiments and applications, it should be recognized that numerous modifications and variations will occur to those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention set forth in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A rechargeable battery comprising: 
<claim-text>a positive electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a negative electrode </claim-text>
<claim-text>said positive electrode comprising a metal substrate having a lithium based active material formed thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative electrode comprising a metal substrate having a lithium based active material formed thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes defining a Zero Volt Crossing Potential (ZCP) relative to a reference level when the voltage between said electrodes is zero; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative electrode substrate being susceptible of permanent damage when a voltage potential exceeding a Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP) is applied thereto; and wherein </claim-text>
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes are configured to establish ZCP at a lower level than SDP. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of a material from the group titanium and titanium alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of stainless steel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of a material from the group nickel and nickel alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positive electrode active material comprises a lithium-nickel-cobalt compound, LiNi<highlight><subscript>X</subscript></highlight>Co<highlight><subscript>1-X</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>where 0&lt;X&lE;1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including an electrolyte; and wherein 
<claim-text>said negative electrode can react to said electrolyte to form a solid electrolyte interface (SEI) layer, said SEI layer being susceptible of permanent damage when a voltage potential exceeding a Film Dissolution Potential (FDP) is applied thereto; and wherein 
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes are configured to establish ZCP at a lower level than FDP. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further including a case for housing said positive and negative electrodes; and wherein 
<claim-text>said case is configured for implanting in a patient&apos;s body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said case is hermetically sealed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said case has a volume of less then 30 cc. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A rechargeable battery capable of discharging to zero volts without damaging the battery, said battery comprising: 
<claim-text>a positive electrode and a negative electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of said electrodes being susceptible of permanent damage when a voltage exceeding a Damage Potential Threshold (DPT) is applied thereto; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes defining a Zero Volt Crossing Potential Threshold when the voltage between said electrodes is zero; and wherein 
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes are configured to define a value of ZCP which is less than the value of DPT. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode comprises a metal substrate having an active material formed thereon, said negative electrode substrate being susceptible of permanent damage when a voltage exceeding a Substrate Dissolution Potential (SDP) is applied thereto; and wherein 
<claim-text>the value of SDP is greater than said value of ZCP. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of a material from the group titanium and titanium alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of stainless steel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said negative electrode substrate is formed of a material from the group nickel and nickel alloy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said positive electrode comprised a metal substrate having a lithium based active material formed thereon; and wherein 
<claim-text>said positive electrode active material comprises a lithium-nickel-cobalt compound. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The battery of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further including an electrolyte; and wherein 
<claim-text>said negative electrode can react to said electrolyte to form a solid electrolyte interface (SEI) layer, said SEI layer being susceptible of permanent damage when a voltage potential exceeding a Film Dissolution Potential (FDP) is applied thereto; and wherein 
<claim-text>said positive and negative electrodes are configured to establish ZCP at a lower level than FDP.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1A</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030000074A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
