<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003018A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003018A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003018</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10115870</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020402</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G01N021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>422</class>
<subclass>082050</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>422</class>
<subclass>082110</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Systems and apparatus for the analysis of molecular interactions</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60281094</doc-number>
<document-date>20010402</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60360798</doc-number>
<document-date>20020301</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mark</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Stolowitz</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Pleasanton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kaiser</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Bothell</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Leslie</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Linkkila</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Kingston</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Charles</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Dubuque</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Menlo Park</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Baum</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Seattle</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Erik</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Engstrom</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Covington</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stephen</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Bailey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Seattle</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Prolinx Incorporated</organization-name>
<address>
<address-1>22322 20th Avenue SE</address-1>
<city>Bothell</city>
<state>WA</state>
<postalcode>98021</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TOWNSEND AND TOWNSEND AND CREW, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>TWO EMBARCADERO CENTER</address-1>
<address-2>EIGHTH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>SAN FRANCISCO</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94111-3834</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Instruments and systems for the analysis of molecular interactions with enhanced throughput and ease-of-use. In certain aspects, the systems and instruments include miniaturized SPR-based sensors and novel sensor surface chemistry to provide high-throughput automated instruments and systems for molecular interaction analysis. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application Serial Nos. 60/281,094, entitled &ldquo;Biosensors&rdquo;, filed Apr. 2, 2001, and 60/360,798, entitled &ldquo;An Apparatus for the Analysis of Molecular Interactions&rdquo;, filed Mar. 1, 2002, each of which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety for all purposes.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to biosensor systems, methods and apparatus, and more particularly to sensing systems, methods and apparatus using surface plasmon resonance (SPR) detection for molecular interaction analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Molecular Interaction Analysis </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Biological processes are governed by the temporal and spatial interactions between molecules. Basic parameters which characterize these interactions include reaction stoichiometry, concentrations of interacting species, equilibrium (affinity) constants, kinetic (rate) constants, and specificity of interaction as functions of temperature and solution composition (pH, ionic strength). The in vitro determination of these parameters for a system of interest can provide important insight into the molecular basis of fundamental metabolic processes, supply essential information for the diagnosis of disease and help identify promising therapeutic candidates. Hence, molecular interaction analysis plays an important role in basic biological science as well as medicine. Table I summarizes the diversity of recently published applications of molecular interaction analysis.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE I</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Diversity of recently published applications of molecular interaction</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>analysis &lsqb;information from (see, Rich, R. L. and Myszka, D. G. Curr.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Opin. Biotechnol. 11, 54-61 (2000))&rsqb;.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="182PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Drug discovery (lead identification, target validation)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Ligand fishing</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Comparative binding specificity</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Mutation studies, structure-function relationships</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Cell signaling</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Replication, transcription, regulation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Multi-molecular complexes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Immune regulation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Immunoassays</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Vaccine development</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Chromatographic process development</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Surface Plasmon Resonance </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Surface plasmon resonance (SPR) is a label-free optical detection technology that has proven extremely useful in the analysis of molecular interactions for over a decade. The technology provides a real-time method for measuring the interaction(s) between two or more molecules, one of which is tethered to a solid surface (see, Schuck, P., Annu. Rev. Biophys. Biomol. Struct. 26, 541-566 (1997)). Molecules used in such studies to date include: proteins, peptides, nucleic acids, carbohydrates, lipids and low molecular weight substances (e.g., hormones, pharmaceuticals) (see, Myszka, D. G., J. Mol. Recognit. 12, 390-48 (1999)). Indeed, interactions between immobilized cells and ligands to cell surface receptors have been studied (see, Myszka, D. G., J. Mol. Recognit. 12, 390-48 (1999)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A surface plasmon is the oscillation of free electrons which is present at the surface of a conductor such as a metal. Surface plasmon resonance occurs under conditions of total internal reflection in a metal film present at the boundary between two substances of different refractive indices, such as water and glass. An incident monochromatic light beam in the first medium creates an evanescent wave at the point of reflection that crosses a short distance beyond the boundary. The evanescent wave couples with the surface plasmons in the metal at a particular angle of incidence that depends on the refractive index of the second medium. Energy is absorbed, with the result that the intensity of the reflected light is attenuated relative to the incident light. Thus, measurement of reflected light intensity as a function of angle of incidence can be used to monitor changes in the refractive index of the medium near the metal surface (see, Liedberg et al., Lab. Sensors and Actuators 4, 299-304 (1983)). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The implementation of SPR as a detection technology for molecular interaction analysis is illustrated by the following simplified example which is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> (see, Nice, E. C. and Catimel, B., BioEssays 21, 339-352 (1999); Salamon et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,991,488 (1999)). A thin film of a conducting metal, typically gold, is deposited on the surface of a glass prism. A molecular recognition element, such as an antibody or other protein receptor, is immobilized in a molecularly thin layer on the surface of the metal film using any of a variety of methods. Monochromatic light is then directed onto the gold film by the prism. The gold film is brought in contact with a stream of flowing solution containing the (putative) binding partner(s) for the immobilized recognition element. As the binding partner interacts with the surface immobilized recognition element, the dielectric value (and thus refractive index) of the material on the metal surface changes. This change in refractive index causes a change in the angle of the incident light beam required for maximal coupling into the surface plasmons. The incident light beam is scanned through a variety of angles and the angle of minimum reflected intensity is measured. If this measurement is made and plotted as a function of time, the result is a curve that characterizes the binding or association process. If the solution with binding partner is now replaced with a solution that is devoid of the binding partner, bound analyte is released yielding a curve that characterizes this dissociation process. Kinetic and equilibrium constants characterizing the interaction can be mathematically extracted from this data based on given binding models. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> With the recent availability of complete genome sequences, the way in which basic biological science is now being and will be performed in the future has been revolutionized. Newly coined terms such as &ldquo;proteomics&rdquo;, &ldquo;cellomics&rdquo; and &ldquo;metabolomics&rdquo; reflect a fundamental shift in biological research from the characterization of isolated molecules or cells to the analysis and understanding of biological systems as integrated and interactive networks. A key to the successful realization of the analysis of complete biological systems and processes is the development of powerful technologies that will enable the interrogation of complex assemblies of molecules with sufficient throughput to match the scope of the endeavor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is therefore desirable to provide novel instruments and systems for the analysis of molecular interactions with increased throughput and ease-of-use. Preferably such systems should use superior surface chemistry to provide improved sample immobilization and SPR detection techniques to take advantage of real-time data acquisition capabilities. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides novel instruments and systems for the analysis of molecular interactions with increased throughput and ease-of-use. In particular, the present invention combines novel miniaturized SPR-based sensors with reliable and easy-to-use surface chemistry to provide high-throughput automated instruments and systems for molecular interaction analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the present invention, a sensor system is provided that typically includes a sensor holding assembly configured to hold a plurality of SPR-based sensors such that the sensing surfaces of two or more inserted sensors are aligned in an array. The sensor system also typically includes a system for delivery and removal of liquids containing samples, a liquid handling system positioned proximal to the sensor holding assembly and having a head including two or more dispensing members, wherein the liquid handling system assembly is configured to automatically move the head proximal the sensor holding assembly such that the ends of the two or more dispensing members are proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, an apparatus is provided for holding two or more SPR-based sensors, each sensor having a sensing surface. The apparatus typically includes a base, a platform coupled to the base, and a sensor holding block configured to removably attach to the platform, the block including two or more sensor receiving locations with each location configured to receive one of the sensors, wherein the receiving locations are arranged so as to present the sensing surfaces in an aligned array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Reference to the remaining portions of the specification, including the drawings and claims, will realize other features and advantages of the present invention. Further features and advantages of the present invention, as well as the structure and operation of various embodiments of the present invention, are described in detail below with respect to the accompanying drawings. In the drawings, like reference numbers indicate identical or functionally similar elements.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. (A and B) One configuration for molecular interaction analysis using SPR detection as described in the text. The drawing in (A) represents the system in the absence of the binding partner for the recognition element; (B) represents the system in the presence of a saturating amount of the binding partner. (C) Raw SPR data. The red curves represent the dependence of the reflected light intensity as a function of angle of incidence &thgr;. Position I is the angle of incidence for minimum reflected light intensity in the absence of binding partner. Position II is the angle of incidence for minimum reflected light intensity in the presence of a saturating amount of binding partner. (D) Plot of the angular position of the minimum of the curve with time. The association and dissociation phases are as described in the text. This curve is typically referred to as a &ldquo;sensorgram&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The Versalinx&trade; Chemical Affinity Tools are based on the specific interaction between phenyl(di)boronic acid (P(D)BA) and salicylhydroxamic acid (SHA). These two molecules form a coordinate covalent complex under variety of conditions, the only byproduct of which is an equivalent of water. The complex can be reversed into its component parts under appropriate conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates the components of the Spreeta&trade; 2000 SPR sensor. The inset photograph provides an indication of the actual size of the device relative to a U.S. dime. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates an isometric view of a molecular interaction analysis system including a modular sensor unit and a robotic liquid handling system according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate top, front, and side views, respectively, of the system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>illustrate various isometric views of a modular sensor unit according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>show various isometric views illustrating the process of removing a thermal block from, or inserting into, the housing of a modular sensor unit according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate detailed cross-sectional views of a modular sensor unit, including a loaded thermal block, taken at sections A-A and B-B as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>g</italic></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates various components of a modular sensor unit according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are isometric views of a thermal block according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates various components of a thermal block according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 </cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate a sensor module assembly (e.g., cartridge) according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 12 and 13</cross-reference> illustrate sensor module assemblies according to embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate a side view of analytical system and a close-up of the liquid handling system in position proximal the sample wells of the sensor unit, respectively, according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates an analytical system including a liquid dispensing mechanism configured for manual delivery of samples to the sensor unit according to an embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows typical SPR data (left-hand plot) and baseline noise (right-hand plot) for a typical Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates a general overview of a computer-based analysis system including a host computer system communicably coupled to a molecular interaction analysis system according to an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides novel molecular interaction analysis systems, instruments and methods. In one embodiment, the systems of the present invention incorporate a known SPR sensor, the Spreeta&trade; 2000, as will be discussed herein, due primarily to its ease of integration with standard technology compatible with microtiter formats (e.g., spacings). Thus, although the following will discuss systems of the present invention with particular reference to Spreeta&trade; 2000 SPR sensor(s), it should be appreciated by one skilled in the art that the present invention is applicable to other SPR-based sensors and even non-SPR-based sensors. Additionally, in one embodiment, the systems of the present invention incorporate specific chemical affinity tools known as Versalinx&trade; Tools, to optimize immobilization of samples on sensor surfaces. It should be appreciated by one skilled in the art, however, that other chemical affinity tools, compounds, etc, that provide sample immobilization may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> I. The Spreeta&trade; 2000 Sensor </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In 1996, Texas Instruments, Inc. demonstrated the first fully integrated miniature technology for refractive index sensing using surface plasmon resonance (see, Melendez et al., Sens. Actuators B 35, 1-5 (1996)). One recent implementation of this technology is a sensor device, trade-named Spreeta&trade; 2000, that includes optics and electronics necessary for the acquisition of SPR data in a miniaturized device. A drawing and a photograph of the sensor device are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The sensor device includes: a printed circuit board upon which are installed a light source (830 nm light emitting diode), a photodetector (128 pixel linear photodiode array), and a memory chip along with some electronic circuitry; an optical plastic &ldquo;sail&rdquo; that acts as a waveguide to focus light on the gold sensing surface (surface plasmon layer); and a mirror atop the optical sail to re-direct the reflected light to the photodetector. The short light path of the device results in excellent detection sensitivity. The card-edge connector allows the device to interface with state-of-the-art digital signal processing (DSP) electronics, allowing the high-speed collection of SPR curves in real-time. A resident memory chip (16 kilobit) can be utilized for storage of sensor identification information, calibration data, use history and the like. Additionally, the Spreeta&trade; 2000 has a footprint that allows multiple sensors to be aligned side-by-side on 9 mm centers. U.S. Pat. No. 6,138,696 discusses aspects of an SPR-based sensor such as the Spreeta&trade; 2000, and is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> II. The Versalinx&trade; Chemical Affinity Tools </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> SPR-based molecular interaction analysis requires that a molecular recognition element be immobilized on the surface of the metal film employed for SPR. Therefore, an immobilization chemistry appropriate to the molecules being studied is a necessity. In certain aspects, the surface chemistry of the present invention is: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> efficient, easy to perform, reproducible and predictable; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> flexible enough to be applicable to a wide variety of molecular species; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> optimally presents the immobilized molecules to the incoming binding partners such that full and specific biological activity is retained; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> minimal non-specific binding of analytes to prevent loss of detection sensitivity and specificity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The Versalinx&trade; Chemical Affinity Tools are a novel system for the immobilization of biological macromolecules. They are based on the highly specific complex formation between two families of small molecules, the simplest representatives of which are phenyl(di)boronic acid (P(D)BA) and salicylhydroxamic acid (SHA) (see, Stolowitz et al., <highlight><italic>Bioconjugate Chem. </italic></highlight>12, 229-239 (2001); Wiley et al., <highlight><italic>Bioconjugate Chem. </italic></highlight>12, 240-250 (2001)). In one aspect, this interaction is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The only byproduct of complex formation is an equivalent of water. The complex can be dissociated into its component parts either at extremes of pH or by using competitive binding reagents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Complex formation occurs readily in aqueous solution in the pH range 5 to 9. It forms in the presence of most buffer systems; monovalent and divalent inorganic salts to 1.5 M; chaotropes such as urea and guanidine hydrochloride; organic solvents such as dimethyl sulfoxide and simple aliphatic alcohols; and detergents such as sodium dodecyl sulfate. In addition, once the complex is formed, it is stable under an even greater range of solution conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The Versalinx&trade; Chemical Affinity Tools include a series of reagents that enable the immobilization of biomolecules on solid surfaces by virtue of, for example, P(D)BA:SHA complex formation. In general, the strategy for biomolecule immobilization is as follows. A solid surface is chemically derivatized with SHA using one of several chemical alternatives. The biomolecule to be immobilized is optimally conjugated with an appropriate P(D)BA reagent. The P(D)BA-conjugated biomolecule is contacted with the SHA-modified surface, and rapid immobilization due to P(D)BA:SHA complex formation occurs. Excess P(D)BA-conjugated biomolecule (if any) is removed by washing, and the surface is ready to use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The Versalinx&trade; Tools approach to biomolecule immobilization has several powerful attributes for SPR-based molecular interaction analysis. First, it provides a single, universal SHA-modified surface that can be used to immobilize any P(D)BA-conjugated biomolecule. Biomolecule conjugation with P(D)BA is very flexible, as P(D)BA derivatives are available for modifying amines (active ester), thiols (maleimide), oxidized carbohydrates (hydrazide), oligonucleotides (phosphoramidite), DNA (dUTP), RNA (UTP) and the like. Analyses can thus be performed using immobilized biomolecules, proteins, carbohydrates, nucleic acids, etc. on a single type of sensor surface using the same immobilization chemistry. Additionally, SHA-modified surfaces typically show very little interaction with non-P(D)BA labeled biomolecules, resulting in very low noise levels due to non-specific binding. Also, the sensor surface may be regenerated for subsequent analyses using the same immobilized recognition element by chemically removing the binding partner, or it may be stripped to the native SHA surface for reconstitution with the same or a different recognition molecule. In some cases, it may be possible to remove intact recognition element/binding partner complexes for further analysis (e.g., mass spectroscopy) using competitive reversal of the P(D)BA:SHA complex. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> It has been empirically observed that immobilization of biomolecules using Versalinx&trade; Tools typically results in a higher retention of biological activity of the surface-bound species relative to alternative methods of surface immobilization. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A. Sensor Surface Chemistry </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Versalinx&trade; reagents have been developed that allow the incorporation of SHA on the surface of a free electron metal, such as a gold film, through the formation of a binary self-assembled monolayer (SAM), a well-characterized process (see, Prime, K. L. and Whitesides, G. M, Science 252, 1164-1167 (1991); Lahiri et al., Anal. Chem. 71, 777-790 (1999)). This SHA-SAM is designed to provide optimal immobilization of P(D)BA-conjugated biomolecules as well as to exhibit extremely low non-specific binding. The molecularly thin, uniform SAM lessens the complicating effects of inefficient or obstructed mass transport during the association and dissociation processes. It also minimizes loss of SPR sensitivity due to its close proximity to the gold surface (SPR sensitivity decreases exponentially with distance from the metal film). Immobilization of P(D)BA-conjugated recognition elements takes place rapidly (e.g., 15 to 60 minutes). The density of immobilized biomolecule can be easily tuned by adjusting the quantity of input material. Degraded or spent surfaces can be stripped of immobilized species and reconstituted with fresh P(D)BA-conjugate. Co-pending U.S. patent Application Ser. Nos. &lsqb; &rsqb; (Attorney docket No. 17635-001610), and &lsqb; &rsqb;, (Attorney docket No.17635-001710), filed on even date herewith, each disclose novel surface chemistries useful for providing improved immobilization of biomolecules in the systems and instruments of the present invention. The foregoing co-pending Patent Applications are each hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> III. Molecular Interaction Analysis System </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The Versalinx&trade; Chemical Affinity Tools coupled with an SPR-based sensor, such as the Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor, enable the development of unique instruments and systems for increased throughput molecular interaction analysis according to embodiments of the present invention as presented herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> A. System Design </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> In preferred aspects, the size and design of the Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor allows for multiple sensors (sensor array) to be aligned side-by-side on 9 mm centers. Such an alignment corresponds with the well-to-well spacing in industry standard multi-well plates, e.g., 8&times;12 multi-well sample plates, commonly used in biological research. Advantageously, a system according to the present invention combines a robotic liquid handling system for manipulating samples stored in multi-well plates with a small, modular sensor unit containing multiple sensors, such as Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensors or other sensors, to achieve high-throughput molecular interaction analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates an isometric view of a molecular interaction analysis system 10 including a modular sensor unit 20 and a robotic liquid handling system 30 according to an embodiment of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate top, front, and side views, respectively, of molecular interaction analysis system 10. Sensor unit 20 is configured, as will be described below, to hold an array of sensors, e.g., up to eight sensor modules, such as modules including Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensors, in an array to allow the liquid dispensing mechanisms of the liquid handling system 30 to deliver desired amounts and types of samples to the active sensing portions of the sensors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> B. Liquid Handling System </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In a preferred aspect, liquid handling is performed automatically using a three axis robot 30 such as a modified Tecan Systems MSP9000, which is a rugged and reliable OEM instrument for liquid handling in multi-well plate format. The footprint of the Tecan Systems MSP9000 robot (minus computer) is approximately 22 inches wide by 19 inches deep, and it is about 20 inches high, so that it occupies a relatively small amount of bench space. It should be understood that other OEM or custom made robotic liquid handling assemblies may be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the deck <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of robot <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is configured to hold modular sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, two multi-well sample plates <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, a wash station <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for washing the liquid handling probes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, up to three solution stations <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, and wash buffer and waste bottles <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Liquids (e.g., samples, solutions, reagents, analytes, etc.) are transferred by three-dimensional translation of the liquid handling head <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. Head <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, in one embodiment, includes eight dual-needle probes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. One needle of each probe is connected to an <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-channel syringe pump for precision transfer of sample solutions, regeneration buffer, and the like among the multi-well plates <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, sensor wells, pre-conditioning wells and solution stations. Additionally, liquid from the wash buffer bottle <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is delivered through these needles. Liquid transfer and wash buffer delivery is controlled by a solenoid valve on each syringe. The other needle is used to aspirate liquids to waste using a diaphragm pump, primarily during probe washing cycles. In one embodiment, all transfers by the liquid head <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> are performed in a row of eight at a time using a single set of transfer parameters. In another embodiment, transfer is performed in individually selected probes (e.g., from only one up to seven, or all eight). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Communication between a control computer (see, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>) and the modular sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> utilizes a USB 1.x interface, although other interface types may be used, e.g., PCI, USB 2.x, FireWire (also known as IEEE 1394), serial port (RS232), Ethernet, etc. Communication with the liquid handling system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> preferably passes through the sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to manage command sequencing and timing more efficiently, although a communication port <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> (e.g., PCI, USB 2.x, FireWire (also known as IEEE 1394), serial port (RS232), Ethernet, etc.) is provided for direct communication with liquid handling system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Data is advantageously acquired and stored from all sensor modules in the sensor unit 20 simultaneously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> C. Modular Sensor Unit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>f </italic></highlight>illustrate various isometric views of a modular sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. In this embodiment, modular sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, a thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, a platform/agitator assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, a base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, an optical shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, control electronics interface <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, and digital signal processing electronics interface <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Cover <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is provided to seal the thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and other components from the ambient environment. Thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> houses multiple sensors, (e.g., up to eight removable sensor modules or cartridges, each including a Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor or other sensors). Each sensor module includes a sensor packaged in an individual cartridge which is easily inserted into and removed from an electrical connector <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) in the thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> as will be described below. Control and data signals provided to and from each sensor module in thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are preferably received through connector <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>. Handle <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> s provided on thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to facilitate removal from platform assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Preferably, thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> slidably mates with platform <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Platform/agitator assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is configured to removably receive thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and provide electrical connections to thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> for control and data acquisition via interface <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a matching interface <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) for mating with interface <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Platform/agitator assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> also provides the means for efficient orbital sample mixing during analysis. In one embodiment, an agitation mechanism, such as rotating member including a motor, a counterbalance affixed to the motor shaft, and a platform affixed to the motor shaft above the counterbalance is provided. In one embodiment, agitation speed is user-programmable, for example, from about 150 to 1000 rpm or more, and the optimal agitation speed is determined by the user. A small radius of orbit (e.g., 0.5 mm) and the shape of the sample wells minimizes vortexing during sample agitation. Thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes a base <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> adapted to slide into slots <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> in the agitator platform <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and lock in place during use. The agitator assembly <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, in one embodiment, includes a magnetic homing mechanism that assures that thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> returns to the same location following each analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Optical shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> opens to allow transfer of samples into the sample and pre-conditioning wells, and closes during sample analysis and data acquisition to minimize background noise due to stray light. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The electronics for temperature (heating and cooling) and agitation control as well as the electronics for digital processing of the sensor signals are preferably implemented on one or more PC boards located in the base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> of the sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. For example, in one embodiment, two highly dense PC boards integrate the required electronics. Interface <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> of platform <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is preferably coupled to electronics interface <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and/or interface <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> either directly or through electronics integrated in base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. In this manner control and data signals to and from thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> are communicated via interface <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. The sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is preferably designed to prevent damage to the electronics by accidental liquid spills. For example, cut-outs are provided in the sides of the sensor unit outer casing to allow liquids to spill down the outside of the sensor unit base, avoiding contact with the electronic assemblies contained in the interior of the base. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>show various isometric views illustrating the process of removing a thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from, or inserting thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> into, housing <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A door <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, e.g., attached via hinges, provides an opening for receiving thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Handle <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> is used to slidably remove thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> from housing <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>also illustrates an isometric view of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in an open state, wherein individual sensor modules <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> may be inserted into or removed from the sensor receiving locations as will be discussed below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate detailed cross-sectional views of sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, including a loaded thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, taken at sections A-A and B-B as indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference><highlight><italic>g</italic></highlight>, respectively. As shown, a sensor <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> is located proximal a well <highlight><bold>1143</bold></highlight>, which is provided for delivery of sample to the sensing region of sensor <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. Optional, pre-conditioning wells <highlight><bold>1144</bold></highlight> are also provided as will be discussed below. Other components include the electronic boards housed in the unit base, agitator assembly (motor, counterbalance and platform), and cooling fans, as well as communications connector/cable <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (e.g., RS<highlight><italic><highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight></italic></highlight>), and communications connector/cable <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (e.g., USB 1.x). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates various components of sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention, including unit casing <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, front cover <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, unit base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, communications connector/cable <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> (e.g., RS<highlight><italic><highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight></italic></highlight>), communications connector/cable <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> (e.g., USB 1.x), and thermal block interface <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. Other components include electronic boards housed in base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>, agitator assembly (motor, counterbalance and platform), cooling fans, and shutter motor and travel rack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are isometric views of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. In this embodiment, thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes an upper portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> that is configured to attach to a lower portion <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. Lower portion <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> includes a sensor location region <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> configured to receive multiple sensor modules <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Preferably region <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> includes multiple sensor module receiving locations (e.g., eight linearly arranged sensor module receiving locations) spaced such that the sensing region of each sensor module is spaced approximately 9 mm apart. It should be understood that other arrangements (e.g., spacings, dimensions) of sensor modules may be implemented, and that the present embodiment is convenient for use with configurations and spacings compatible with microtiter formatted liquid dispensing mechanisms such as the liquid handling system of the Tecan Systems MSP9000 robot. Upper portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> preferably includes a hinged clamp plate provided to secure a well liner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> proximal the sensor modules in region <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates various components of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. As shown, upper portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> includes a frame <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>that couples to a well region member <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, which includes a first plurality of openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and a second plurality of openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>defined therein. First plurality of openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>are arranged such that they are proximal the sensing regions of the sensor modules <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> inserted in region <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of lower portion <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> when upper portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is closed over lower portion <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The second plurality of openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>are optionally provided to define pre-conditioning wells, e.g., for thermal equilibration of samples and solutions prior to and during analysis. Well liner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is configured such that when properly inserted into upper portion <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>are proximal openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and optional wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>are proximal openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. The bottom of each well <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>includes an opening of sufficient dimension to allow samples to contact the sensing regions on the corresponding sensor modules. Optionally, the well openings <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>are covered with rubber septa that can be pierced by the liquid delivery probes of the liquid handling system, and serve to block ambient light from disadvantageously impacting the sensing regions as well as to minimize or eliminate evaporation of analysis solution from the wells during a measurement. An electrical interface module <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> is provided for connecting the card edge connector <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> of each inserted sensor module <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> with processing and control circuitry via interface <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. For example, interface <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> provides for communication with the local signal processing circuitry implemented in base <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> and/or external processing and control circuitry via interfaces <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>. Electrical interface module <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> defines the sensor module receiving locations of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and is preferably configured to securely fit within region <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight> of lower portion <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, e.g., with or without securing mechanisms such as screws, soldering or other connection devices and schemes. Peltier effect temperature control element operates as is well known to control the temperature of wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>and/or wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Referring back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the hinged top of the thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is configured to receive plastic (e.g., polypropylene or other durable material) well liner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, which mates with the silicone gaskets <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> of the array of sensor modules to provide wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>for holding the samples to be analyzed. Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, there is shown additional views of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, including a portion of a cross-sectional view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. The wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>each preferably support a volume from approximately 20 &mgr;L to about 100 &mgr;L or more. Sensor modules with spent sensors are disposable. The well liner <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, in one embodiment, also contains, for example, sixteen &ldquo;pre-conditioning&rdquo; wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>useful for thermal equilibration of samples and solutions prior to and during analysis. Pre-conditioning wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>are preferably arrayed in two side-by-side linear arrays of eight wells each, although other arrangements may be implemented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> provides highly accurate Peltier effect (thermoelectric heating and cooling) control of the sample temperature during analysis. Referring back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, Peltier effect control is provided by two Peltier effect devices <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> optimally affixed to a block <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> (e.g., aluminum) having cooling fins, which is then affixed to block <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> (e.g., aluminum) containing the wells and sensor modules. A rubber (or other insulating material) gasket <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> is fitted around the Peltier effect devices <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> to provide thermal insulation. Alternatively, one or both blocks <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> may be made of materials other than aluminum having excellent thermal conductivity. In certain embodiments, refractive index is sensitive to temperature. Sample temperature is preferably maintained to within &plusmn;0.2&deg; C. of the set-point over the temperature range 15&deg; C. to 40&deg; C. Additionally, well-to-well temperature uniformity is &lE;&plusmn;0.2&deg; C. over the same temperature range. The thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, module <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> and sensor materials as well as the surface chemistry are preferably compatible with temperatures as high as 65&deg; C. A latching device <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> is preferably provided in the base of the thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> to secure the block in place in the sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> during operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> D. Sensor Module </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate a sensor module assembly (e.g., cartridge) <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>illustrates a complete sensor module assembly <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> including protruding connector <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrates separated components of sensor module assembly <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> according to one embodiment, including side portions <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. Side portions <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> are configured to attachably mate with each other and secure a sensor <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> therein. Preferably each portion is made of plastic, but other durable materials may be used. In one embodiment, tabs <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> and corresponding receptors <highlight><bold>187</bold></highlight> are provided on each portion to securely &ldquo;snap&rdquo; portions <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> together. A gasket <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> (e.g., slotted silicone) sits atop the sensing surface of each sensor <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>, and defines the sensing region/area <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> on which the desired sample is contacted. For example, in the case of Spreeta&trade; 2000 and similar SPR-based sensors, gasket <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight> defines the area of the metallic, e.g., gold, film on which the desired sample, e.g., biomolecule, is immobilized (e.g., with an area of about 12.5 mm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>). A slot <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight> is provided in portion <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> to allow connector <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> to be exposed for electrical communication with interface module <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Preferably indents <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> are provided to facilitate manual insertion and removal of sensor modules <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrates a cross-sectional view along the lines A-A of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>(top view) of a closed sensor module (cartridge) <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> including a sensor <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> and gasket <highlight><bold>185</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a sensor module assembly <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> according to another embodiment, wherein portions <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> are securely attached via connectors <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>. Connectors <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> preferably include threaded or unthreaded screws that couple the two portions together via (threaded or unthreaded) receiving holes <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight>. However, it should be appreciated that other connection mechanisms may be implemented, for example, zero insertion force connectors, pins, glue, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> E. General </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>illustrate a side view of analytical system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a close-up of the liquid handling system in position proximal the sample wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>of sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, respectively, according to an embodiment of the invention. Liquid handling system <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is configured with motors as are well known for translating head <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> laterally along the x-y plane and vertically along the z-direction. Thus, for example when positioned above wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, the z-axis motor is activated to move needle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> into position for delivery of the desired liquid into wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. Similarly, when positioned above a microtiter sample well plate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, head <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is lowered to the appropriate level to retrieve the desired sample solution. In one embodiment, needle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> includes a portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> that is wider than that of the tip. A needle receiving member <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> having an orifice substantially complementary in size to needle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is provided to receive needle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and prevent portion <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> from passing, thereby preventing needle <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> from contacting and potentially damaging the sensor surface. Receiving member <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> may be provided, for example, as a portion of shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, or as a separate insert (see, e.g., insert <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates an analytical system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including an insert <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> optimally configured to allow manual delivery of samples to sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the invention. Dispenser <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> in the figure represents any of a large number of commercially available high-accuracy liquid delivery devices or pipettors commonly used in scientific laboratories (e.g., Pipetman or Finnpipette devices). The manual application insert <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> provided in this embodiment is placed over the wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of thermal block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Insert <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is adapted to fit within the opening to sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (with shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> removed or in addition to shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> with shutter <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> retracted) as shown such that guide holes <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> receive the liquid delivery tips of the commercial liquid delivery device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In this manner liquids may be provided manually to sensor surfaces via wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. Portions <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> are preferably larger in diameter than guide holes <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> and needles <highlight><bold>235</bold></highlight>, which are smaller in diameter than guide holes <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the tips of the liquid delivery device are prevented from entering too far into wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> so as to prevent damage due unintended contact of the tips with the sensor surfaces. Optional holes <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> are provided in embodiments including pre-conditioning wells <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>. In some devices, a handle <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> is provided to allow a user to manually grip device <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, and tab <highlight><bold>245</bold></highlight> is provided to contact the index finger of the user when gripping the handle portion <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight>. Button <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> may be depressed, e.g., with the users thumb, to release liquids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> F. Software Applications </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> illustrates a general overview of a computer-based analysis system <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> including a host computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> communicably coupled to a molecular interaction analysis system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. In system <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is preferably directly coupled to sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and/or robot <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as above using PCI, USB 1.x/2.x, FireWire (also known as IEEE 1394), serial port (RS232), Ethernet, etc., interfaces for communicating data and control commands, although host computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be coupled over a network, e.g., over any LAN or WAN connection, to system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. System <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and in particular computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>, are configured according to the present invention to perform automatic molecular interaction assays in response to user input criteria. It should be understood that, although only one computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is shown and discussed herein, any number of computer systems may be communicably coupled to system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, for example, forming a network. The analysis system of the present invention advantageously allows a user to perform molecular interaction analyses and automatically process and display the resulting data in default or user-configured formats. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Several elements in the system shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> include conventional, well-known elements that need not be explained in detail here. For example, each computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> could include a desktop personal computer, workstation, laptop, or any other computing device capable of interfacing directly or indirectly with system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, e.g., directly or over a network. Computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> typically includes one or more user interface devices <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, such as a keyboard, a mouse, touch-screen, pen or the like, for interacting with a graphical user interface (GUI) provided by the software applications on a display <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> (e.g., monitor screen, LCD display, etc.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment, computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> and all of its components are operator-configurable using an application including computer code run using a central processing unit <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight> such as an Intel Pentium processor or the like. Computer code including instructions for operating and configuring computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> to process data content and communicate with, and control, system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as described herein is preferably stored on a hard disk, but the entire program code, or portions thereof, may also be stored in any other volatile or non-volatile memory medium or device as is well known, such as a ROM or RAM, or provided on any media capable of storing program code, such as a compact disk (CD) medium, digital video disk (DVD) medium, a floppy disk, and the like. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, for example, the code, or portions thereof, is included in a portable memory medium <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> (e.g., floppy, CD, DVD, etc. disk medium) that is readable by computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> via an appropriate memory drive (not shown) coupled to, or integrated in, computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the entire program code, or portions thereof, may be transmitted and downloaded from a software source, e.g., from a server system (not shown) to computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> over the Internet as is well known, or transmitted over any other conventional network connection (e.g., extranet, VPN, LAN, etc.) using any communication medium and protocols (e.g., TCP/IP, HTTP, HTTPS, Ethernet, etc.) as are well known. It should be understood that computer code for implementing aspects of the present invention can be implemented in machine language, assembly language, Cobol, C/C&plus;&plus; (and related languages), Pascal, Java, BASIC, etc., which can be executed on computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment, one or more applications (represented as module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>) executing on computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> include instructions for running molecular interaction analysis assays and processing the results based on user input criteria. Application(s) <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> is preferably downloaded and stored in a hard drive <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> (or other memory such as a local or attached RAM or ROM), although application(s) <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> can be provided on any software storage medium such as a floppy disk, CD, DVD, etc. as discussed above. In one embodiment, application module <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight> includes various software modules for processing data content, such as a user interface communication module <highlight><bold>257</bold></highlight> for communicating control commands to system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through a communication port <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>, and for receiving data from system <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. All components of computer system <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> are connected by one or more buses as is well known. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Two software applications are provided in one embodiment: an Instrument Control/Data Acquisition application and a Data Analysis/Modeling application, which are designed to assist users in setting up and performing experiments and in analyzing the resulting data in the context of several mathematical models which describe molecular interactions, as well as to provide expert users with sufficient flexibility to create their own unique methods and analyze data according to non-standard models. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The Instrument Control/Data Acquisition application provides graphical user interface (GUI) functionality, including providing various user-interactive screens, for example, Users, Plate ID, Methods, Sensors, Experiments and Reports screens. The Users screen lists all authorized users of the instrument, along with any permissions or privileges assigned to them (e.g., access to other users&apos; methods, ability to modify instrument parameters). The Plate ID screen provides a graphical and tabular interface for the user to input sample information such as source, location in sample plate, etc. The Methods screen lists all of the methods available to the logged-in user and allows the user to create new methods or edit existing methods. Methods embody a series of commands for controlling the molecular interaction analysis experiment such as opening and closing shutter, setting parameters such a temperature and agitation rate, pick up and dispensing of sample, etc. Method creation and editing utilize a graphical interface, with icons representing fundamental hardware processes that are added to a method using &ldquo;point-and-click&rdquo; functionality. Certain hardware processes (e.g., &ldquo;transfer sample&rdquo;, &ldquo;start acquisition&rdquo;, &ldquo;wash probe&rdquo;) have user-selectable parameters (e.g., volume, from position/to position, data acquisition period). Methods and sequences may be run from this screen as well. The Experiments screen provides a mechanism for experimental design and execution and utilizes data from sensor database, plate ID database and method database. This affords maximum flexibility with respect to how samples in the sample plates are handled such that each column of samples may be analyzed using a different method. This design allows for unattended operation during analysis of all samples on the deck. When an experiment or method is running, the active process is highlighted on screen, and if acquisition is occurring, the data is graphically displayed (both SPR curves as well as calculated curve minimum versus time). The user can select how many channels of data are displayed simultaneously. Data is preferably stored in an SQL-compatible data base, and can optionally be exported as Microsoft Excel spreadsheets or text files. The Sensors screen details information about each of the sensor positions (e.g., sensor installed, sensor initialized, sensor serial number, sensor use history). It also maintains a database of all sensors that have been used in the instrument. The Reports screen provides printable listings of methods, sensors and users. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> Experienced users may access the Instrument screen in the Instrument Control/Data Acquisition software. This allows the user to set various instrument parameters prior to running a method (e.g., data acquisition rate, number of SPR curves averaged per data point, LED brightness, etc.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The Data Analysis/Modeling application assists users in selecting potential models of the interaction under study, fit the acquired data to the models, and assess the &ldquo;goodness-of-fit&rdquo; to each model. Depending on the experimental setup, users can obtain rate constants, equilibrium constants and component concentrations using first or second order interaction models. The user can select from non-linear least squares (see, O&apos;Shannessy et al., Anal. Biochem. 212, 457-468 (1993)) and global analysis (see, Beechem, J. M., Meth. Enzymol. 210, 37-54 (1992)) curve-fitting routines from which to extract the parameters of interest. Residuals for each curve fit are plotted to assist the user in qualitatively assessing the &ldquo;goodness-of-fit&rdquo;. Experienced users can import more complex interaction models if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> F. Examples </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> In certain aspects, a system according to the present invention is able to acquire raw SPR data from the sensors at up to 400 curves per second. In one embodiment, the curves are averaged on-the-fly and the minimum of the each averaged curve is calculated by the DSP electronics before being sent to the host computer. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows sample SPR data from a Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor taken using the sensor unit <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The sample is pure water; the sensor was initialized in air to provide the background blank. The plotted curve represents the average of 200 individual scans acquired in one second. Baseline noise was determined by acquiring averaged SPR curves every second for <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> seconds and calculating the position of the minimum of each curve using a first moment of resonance below baseline algorithm (see, Chinowsky et al., Sens. Actuators B 54, 89-97 (1999)). The plot of the minimum versus time was analyzed using a sliding <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> second window to calculate the RMS noise. The trace shown is a plot of the calculated noise at <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> second intervals, plotted at the endpoint of the time window. The typical average noise value is &lt;1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;7 </superscript></highlight>refractive index units (RIU). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. Nos. &lsqb; &rsqb; (Attorney docket No. 17635-001610), and &lsqb; &rsqb;, (Attorney docket No. 17635-001710), filed on even date herewith, and previously incorporated by reference, each disclose additional examples including sample and sensor surface preparations and experimental data including sensorgrams. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> It is understood that the examples and embodiments described herein are for illustrative purposes only and that various modifications or changes in light thereof will be suggested to persons skilled in the art and are to be included within the spirit and purview of this application and scope of the appended claims. All publications, patents, and patent applications cited herein are hereby incorporated by reference in their entirety for all purposes. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A sensor system comprising: 
<claim-text>a sensor holding assembly configured to receive a plurality of SPR-based sensors such that the sensing surfaces of two or more inserted sensors are aligned in an array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid handling assembly positioned proximal said sensor holding assembly and having a head including two or more dispensing members, wherein said liquid handling assembly is configured to automatically move said head proximal said sensor holding assembly such that the ends of the two or more dispensing members are proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding assembly a includes temperature control device integrated therein for controlling the temperature of substances proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the temperature control device includes a Peltier effect element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding assembly includes a plurality of electrical connectors that define sensor receiving locations within the sensor holding assembly, wherein the electrical connectors provide a communication path to control circuitry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the inserted sensors includes an interface for communicating control and data signals, wherein when inserted into the holding assembly each sensor interface mates with a corresponding electrical connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control circuitry is integrated in the sensor holding assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holder assembly includes a communication interface, and wherein the control circuitry is communicably coupled to a host computer via the communication interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the communication interface includes one of a USB interface, a PCI interface and a FireWire interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control circuitry is coupled to the liquid handling assembly, and wherein the control circuitry provides control signals to the liquid handling assembly for controlling movement of the head. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each inserted sensor is contained in a sensor module configured to hold the sensor and mate with a corresponding receiving location within the sensor holding assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding assembly further includes a removable well liner configured to provide wells for holding samples proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the well liner includes a plurality of secondary wells for holding liquids. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each sensor includes a Spreeta&trade; 2000 sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a control computer communicably coupled to one or both of the sensor holding assembly and the liquid handling assembly, said control computer adapted to provide control signals for controlling operation of the liquid handling assembly and the sensors in the sensor holding assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control computer is further adapted to receive and process data signals received from the sensors in the sensor holding assembly. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the control computer provides a graphical user interface on a display device, the graphical user interface including options for displaying processed data and user selectable control parameters. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensing surfaces are aligned in a linear array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spacing between each of sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors are compatible with microtiter formats. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the spacing between each of sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors is approximately 9 mm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a sample holder including two or more samples, wherein the liquid handling assembly is further configured to automatically move said head proximal the sample holder and retrieve samples with the two or more dispensing members and thereafter automatically deliver the retrieved samples proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the liquid handling assembly includes a base, and wherein the sensor holding assembly and sample holder are attached to said base. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding assembly includes an agitation mechanism configured to agitate the assembly so as to induce mixing of materials proximal the sensing surfaces of the two or more inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for holding two or more SPR-based sensors, each sensor having a sensing surface, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a platform coupled to said base; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor holding block configured to removably attach to said platform, said block including two or more sensor receiving locations, each location configured to receive one of said sensors, wherein said receiving locations are arranged so as to present the sensing surfaces in an aligned array. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding block includes a removable well liner that provides a well proximal the sensing surface of each inserted sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the well liner includes an array of secondary wells for holding liquids. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding block includes eight sensor receiving locations aligned in a linear array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor holding block includes a temperature control element configured to control the temperature of substances proximal the sensing surfaces of inserted sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the temperature control element includes a Peltier effect device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each sensor receiving location includes an electrical connector configured to mate with a corresponding connector on a sensor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each sensor is contained in a module configured to hold the sensor and expose the sensor connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the platform includes an agitation mechanism configured to agitate the sensor holding block so as to induce mixing of materials proximal the sensing surfaces of the sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further including control circuitry integrated in said base for controlling operation of the sensors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a communication interface for communicating with a host computer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the communication interface includes one of a USB interface, a PCI interface and a FireWire interface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor receiving locations are arranged so that the spacing between sensing surfaces of inserted sensors is compatible with microtiter spacing formats. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the sensor receiving locations are arranged so that the spacing between sensing surfaces of inserted sensors is approximately 9 mm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a housing coupled to the base for enclosing the sensor block and platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing includes a door that provides an opening for a user to insert and remove the sensor holding block from the platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing includes an opening proximal the sensor receiving locations so as to provide access to the sensing surfaces of sensors inserted in the sensor holding block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further including a shutter coupled to the housing for selectively closing said opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030003018A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
