<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002178A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002178A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002178</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894207</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B005/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B007/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G02B005/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>838000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>831000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Lateral transfer retroreflector assembly and method of assembling the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Zvi</given-name>
<family-name>Bleier</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Centerport</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>KAPLAN &amp; GILMAN , L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>900NROUTE 9 NORTH</address-1>
<city>WOODBRIDGE</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>07095</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An improved lateral transfer retroreflector assembly is provided. The lateral transfer retroreflector assembly of the invention comprises a first segment comprising a mirror panel housing, a second segment comprising a roof mirror housing, and a third segment comprising an off-the-shelf connecting member between the two housings. The mirror panel housing will have mounted thereto a mirror panel. The roof mirror housing will have mounted thereto a roof mirror assembly, and the connecting member will be mounted between the mirror panel housing and the roof mirror housing. The off-the-shelf aspect of assembling the connecting allows the assembly to be built to customer specifications, thereby allowing for customized creation of lateral transfer retroreflectors, but at a time and cost savings to the customer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to the field of retroreflectors, and more particularly, to lateral transfer retroreflectors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Retroreflectors generally have the property of causing incident and reflected light rays to travel along parallel paths. To achieve this parallelism, a retroreflector normally consists of three optically flat reflecting surfaces, each reflecting surface positioned at a right angle to each of the other reflecting surfaces. Any departure of the reflecting surfaces from their perpendicular orientation will cause the incident and reflected light rays to depart from parallel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Retroreflectors lose accuracy when they are exposed to external stresses. Examples of such external stresses are mass, thermal expansion or contraction of the substrate material from which the retroreflector is made, or deflection caused by curing of the adhesives which join members of the retroreflector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Retroreflectors, and lateral transfer retroreflectors (which translate the reflected beam some calculated distance from the incident light beam), are old in the art. Examples of prior art retroreflectors and lateral transfer retroreflectors are: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 3,977,765 to Morton S. Lipkins, which disclosed a retroreflector mounted to a support structure through means of applying an adhesive into the joints formed between joined members of the retroreflector and to a flat surface of the support structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 4,065,204, also to Morton S. Lipkins, which disclosed a lateral transfer retroreflector consisting of a base, a roof reflector having two reflecting plates and a third reflector. The base acts as an extension of the third reflector by attaching the third reflector to the roof reflector in the manner known to retroreflectors to produce the lateral transfer retroreflector construction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,024,514 to Zvi Bleier and Morton S. Lipkins, which discloses a lateral transfer retroreflector having a tubular member, a roof mirror and a mirror panel. Both the roof mirror and mirror panel are attached to the tubular member by use of three coplanar mounting pads. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> U.S. Pat. No. 5,361,171, also to Zvi Bleier, which discloses a lateral transfer retroreflector having a fixed-length tubular member, a roof mirror secured within a channel portion extending from an end of the tubular member and a mirror panel attached to the tubular member at the opposite end from the roof mirror and roof mirror panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> It would be desirable to provide a high-accuracy lateral transfer retroreflector that is off-the-shelf adjustable as to the displaced length between the mirror panel and the roof mirror and also having a less temperature-deviant assembly and mounting of the roof mirror and mirror panel. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the invention, an improved lateral transfer retroreflector assembly is provided. The lateral transfer retroreflector assembly of the invention is comprised of three separate, attached segments. A first segment comprising a mirror panel housing, a second segment comprising a roof mirror housing, and a third segment comprising a connecting member between the two housings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The mirror panel housing will have mounted thereto a mirror panel. The roof mirror housing will have mounted thereto a roof mirror assembly, and the connecting member will be mounted between the mirror panel housing and the roof mirror housing. In addition, based upon the mounting together of the three separate segments, the connecting member will have the ability of being an off-the-shelf member that is selectively able to be cut to a particular length dimension based upon customer specifications, thereby allowing for customized creation of lateral transfer retroreflectors, but at a time and cost savings to the customer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In addition, the roof mirror assembly and the mirror panel mounting are kinematic structures that are also improvements over earlier constructions. In particular, the roof mirror assembly of the subject invention has at least a pair of mounting members that act also as back supports and are located substantially at opposite ends of the roof mirror. The manner of attachment of the mounting members to the back portions of the mirror panels making up the roof mirror assembly, is such that expansion and contraction of the reflective surfaces of the mirror panels of the roof mirror assembly will only be in a direction substantially perpendicular to the direction of the roof angle axis. Deflection in this direction does not cause displacement (error), of the transmitted light beam traveling through the lateral transfer retroreflector, and therefore such a mounting system is advantageous. Similarly, the mounting of the mirror panel to the mirror panel housing by means of substantially 45&deg; chamfered edges, insures that the forces exerted by thermal expansion or contraction of the bonding material situated along those chamfered edges, will have a canceling effect, and not deflect the reflective surface of the mirror panel. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide an improved lateral transfer retroreflector assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the invention is to provide a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly having a component construction capable of, allowing for off-the-shelf customization for different customer needs based upon differing customer specifications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Yet a further object of the invention is to provide a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly having a roof mirror assembly construction and mounting such that deformations in the reflective surfaces of the mirror panels of the roof mirror assembly due to thermal expansion/contraction are minimized in the direction of the roof angle axis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the invention is to provide a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly, wherein the deflective forces exerted on the mirror panel by thermal expansion or contraction of the joint bonding the mirror panel to the mirror panel housing, are minimized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Other objects of the invention will in part be obvious and will in part be apparent from the following description taken in association with the figures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The invention accordingly comprises an assembly possessing the features, properties and relation of components which will be exemplified in the products hereinafter described, and the scope of the invention will be indicated in the claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> For a fuller understanding of the invention, reference is made to the following description taken in connection with the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly made in accordance with the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the mirror panel of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a left side elevational view of the mirror panel housing of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a partial prespective view of the mounting pad of member <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the mirror panel housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a partial perspective view of the mounting pad of member <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the mirror panel housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a right side elevational view of the mirror panel housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a left side elevational view of the mirror panel housing; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view taken along line <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the roof mirror assembly of the subject invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is an elevational view of one end of the roof mirror assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is an elevational view of the other end of the roof mirror assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a bottom plan view of the roof mirror assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a second embodiment of the roof mirror assembly of the subject invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> lateral transfer retroreflector assembly made in accordance with the invention and generally designated at <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, is illustrated. Lateral Transfer Retroreflector (&ldquo;LTR&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises three components; those being a mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a roof mirror assembly housing <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and a connecting member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</cross-reference>, mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is comprised of first and second side members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, as well as receiving member <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, for receiving connecting member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can also include member <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, to lend extra stability to the structure, as well as aperture receiving member <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, having aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> extending therethrough. Aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be of any geometric configuration, the preferred configurations being in the circle and square families. Aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a first end <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and a second end <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the distance between which will help dictate the inside diameter of connecting member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. It is to be understood herein that member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> does not have to be circular in cross section, but could be of other shapes; particularly square. However, since light beams to be passed through LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are normally themselves circular in cross section, the preferred embodiment shown in the figures and discussed herein, will regard a circular aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and a circular tubular member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Continuing with the above discussion, the dimensional congruity between the size of aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the cross sectional diameter of member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> will insure that a light beam passing through LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will propagate through member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> very close to the inside surface of member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> as the beam approaches either of ends <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to be used with LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is shown. Mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a reflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and two chamfered edges <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is adhered to mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in such a manner as to be oriented with its reflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> below, and in reflective relation with, aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. In practice, and as will be discussed in more detail below, the light beam, if it is entering LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> through aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, will then reflect off of reflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and propagate through member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> into roof mirror assembly housing <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, where it will reflect off of reflective surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to propagate back toward the source of the beam, in a direction substantially parallel to the beam&apos;s incident direction, but at a displaced distance, substantially based upon the length of member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Continuing with FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, it is seen that mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is adhered at three contact surfaces to corresponding mounting pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of edge portions <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of first and second side members <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, respectively. In particular, edge portions of <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, and their corresponding mounting pads <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, onto which mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is adhered, are themselves chamfered, as is best seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</cross-reference>. The construction and mounting of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> of the subject invention is different to that of the prior art in U.S. Patent Nos. 5,024,514 and 5,361,171 (discussed earlier herein), in that the subject connection between mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is chamfered surface to chamfered surface, as opposed to the prior art disclosure of mounting pads oriented perpendicularly to the reflective surface. What is similar, however, between the subject connection of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and the prior art connections, is the adhesion of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at only three distinct areas; two areas along chamfered surface <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and only one area along chamfered surface <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The use of the matching chamfered surfaces <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> helps to reduce the distortional effect of the connection of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to mirror panel housing <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, as well as to help reduce stresses caused by thermal expansion/contraction, as the substantially 45&deg; of the chamfers insures that such distortional forces do not distort rereflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in a way to effect the orientation of the beam passing through LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Specifically, LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention is a highly accurate instrument which can be used in such precise fields as surveying, military and aerospace applications, to name a few. It is usually necessary that instruments used in these areas meet very specific stress and dimensional specifications, and therefore the manner of construction of LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with respect to joining parts thereof together, and the length and depth dimensions of LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, are important. Accordingly, as will be discussed in more detail below, although lateral transfer retroreflectors are old in the art, the particular manners in which mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are made and mounted to their respective housings, will impact the durability and dimensional integrity of LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Turning now to a discussion of roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, this assembly is best seen in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of mirror panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, and a pair of mounting blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Mirror panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> have reflective surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, respectively, which reflective surfaces are in reflective relation with reflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of mirror panel <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as well as member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and aperture <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. In particular, reflective surface <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is substantially perpendicularly oriented to reflective surface <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, and reflective surface <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is itself oriented substantially perpendicularly to both reflective surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. This mutually perpendicular orientation of the three reflective surfaces of LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> essentially duplicates the construction of a standard Hollow&trade; retroreflector as is known in the art. Referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, mirror panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are seen to be adhered together at miter joint <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. In order to create miter joint <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the attachment surfaces of mirror panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> which are joined together to create miter joint <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, are at substantially 45 degree angles to reflective surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, so as to create the perpendicularity between the reflective surfaces upon creation of miter joint <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, and the associated reduction of distortive forces, as earlier discussed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Continuing with a discussion of FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, it is seen that connected together panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> are finally formed into a secure roof mirror assembly through the mounting of back surfaces of panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to portions of surfaces <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of mounting blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. In so mounting panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> to blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, air gaps <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> are created between surfaces of mounting blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of panel <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and surfaces <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> of panel <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As is further seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference>, the back surfaces of panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> that are adhered to mounting blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> as discussed above, are surfaces <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> for panel <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and surfaces <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> for panel <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. In construction, surfaces <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>/<highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are all substantially perpendicular in orientation to miter joint <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. Such a construction ensures that any substantial distortional effects due to thermal expansion/contraction of panels <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and/or block <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> will be in a direction substantially perpendicular to a longitudal axis for roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>; i.e., perpendicular to the planes of reflective surfaces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Turning again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, it is seen that roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is secured to roof mirror assembly housing <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> by way of connection between bottom surfaces <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of blocks <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to member <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. Such a secure connection of roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to housing <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> assists and strengthens the durability of LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Regarding connecting member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, as has been stated, this member can be cut from an off-the-shelf member of standard construction and length. Such an off-the-shelf retro-fit of connecting member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> allows one to stock separate quantities of housings <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and member <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, for construction of an LTR <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to meet any customer specifications, in a quick and cost affective manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Turning now to a discussion of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13, a</cross-reference> second embodiment of the inventive roof mirror assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is shown at <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Assembly <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is constructed identically to that of assembly <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, accept for the addition of back plate member <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, adhered below mounting blocks <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>360</bold></highlight>, to surfaces <highlight><bold>341</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>361</bold></highlight> (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> It will thus be seen that the objects set forth above, among those made apparent from the preceding description, are efficiently attained, and, since certain changes may be made in the above constructions without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention, it is intended that all matter contained in the above description and shown in the accompanying drawings shall be interpreted as illustrative and not in a limiting sense. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> It is also to be understood that the following claims are intended to cover all of the generic and specific features of the invention herein described and all statements of the scope of the invention which, as a matter of language might be said to fall therebetween. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>a mirror panel housing having a first mirror panel mounted thereto, said mirror panel housing located at a first end of said lateral transfer retroreflector assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roof mirror assembly housing having a roof mirror assembly mounted thereto, said roof mirror assembly housing located at an opposite, second end of said lateral transfer retroreflector assembly; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting member, mounted to and between both said mirror panel housing and said roof mirror assembly housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said roof mirror assembly comprising second and third mirror panels having reflective surfaces, wherein said reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels are oriented substantially perpendicularly to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, said first mirror panel having a reflective surface oriented substantially perpendicularly to said reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said mirror panel housing comprising a first side member, a second side member and a receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first mirror panel is mounted to said mirror panel housing along portions of first and second chamfered edges of said first mirror panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said portions of said first and second chamfered edges of said first mirror panel are adhered to edge portions of said first and second side members of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, said first chamfered edge of said first mirror panel is adhered at two said portions to said first side member of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, said second chamfered edge of said first mirror panel is adhered at one said portion to said second side member of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said receiving member for said connecting member, is located along other edge portions of said first and second side members, and said other edge portions are oriented with respect to said edge portions at substantially 45&deg; angles to said edge portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, said mirror panel housing further comprising an aperture member mounted thereto along yet other edge portions of said first and second side members and located substantially between said first mirror panel and said receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said second and third mirror panels of said roof mirror assembly comprise an edge surface adjacent to, and substantially at a 45&deg; angle to, said respective reflective surface of said mirror panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second and third mirror panels of said roof mirror assembly are joined together along said edge surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said joint between said second and third mirror panels of said roof mirror assembly is a miter joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, said roof mirror assembly comprising at least one mounting block extending under said joined second and third mirror panels, said roof mirror assembly mounted to said roof mirror assembly housing along a bottom surface of said at least one mounting block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block is adhered to said joined second and third mirror panels along portions of a first side thereof and along abutting portions of at least one bottom surface of said joined second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one bottom surface of said joined second and third mirror panels lies in a plain extending substantially perpendicularly to both of said reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block does not touch said second and third mirror panels in any other locations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block is a pair of mounting blocks, said roof mirror assembly mounted to said roof mirror assembly housing along a bottom surface of each of said mounting blocks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, said roof mirror assembly housing comprising a first side member, a second side member, a back member and a receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said roof mirror assembly is attached to said roof mirror assembly housing along said back member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>a mirror panel housing having a first mirror panel mounted thereto, said mirror panel housing located at a first end of said lateral transfer retroreflector assembly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a roof mirror assembly housing located at an opposite, second end of said lateral transfer retroreflector assembly, having a roof mirror assembly mounted thereto, said roof mirror assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>second and third mirror panels each having a reflective surface and an adjacent edge surface oriented substantially at a 45&deg; angle to each of said reflective surfaces, said second and third mirror panels being joined together along said edge surfaces so that said reflective surfaces are substantially perpendicular to each other; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting member, mounted to and between both said mirror panel housing and said roof mirror assembly housing. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, said first mirror panel having a reflective surface oriented substantially perpendicularly to said reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, said mirror panel housing comprising a first side member, a second side member and a receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first mirror panel is mounted to said mirror panel housing along portions of first and second chamfered edges of said first mirror panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said portions of said first and second chamfered edges of said first mirror panel are adhered to edge portions of said first and second side members of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, said first chamfered edge of said first mirror panel is adhered at two said portions to said first side member of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, said second chamfered edge of said first mirror panel is adhered at one said portion to said second side member of said mirror panel housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said receiving member for said connecting member, is located along other edge portions of said first and second side members, and said other edge portions are oriented with respect to said edge portions at substantially 45&deg; angles to said edge portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, said mirror panel housing further comprising an aperture member mounted thereto along yet other edge portions of said first and second side members and located substantially between said first mirror panel and said receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said edges of said second and third mirror panels of said roof mirror assembly are joined together in a miter joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, said roof mirror assembly further comprising, at least one mounting block adhered to, and extending under, said joined second and third mirror panels, for mounting said roof mirror assembly to said roof mirror assembly housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said roof mirror assembly is mounted to said roof mirror assembly housing along a bottom surface of said at least one mounting block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block is adhered to said joined second and third mirror panels along portions of a first side thereof and along abutting portions of at least one bottom surface of said joined second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one bottom surface of said joined second and third mirror panels lies in a plain extending substantially perpendicularly to both of said reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block does not touch said second and third mirror panels in any other locations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block is a pair of mounting blocks, said roof mirror assembly mounted to said roof mirror assembly housing along a bottom surface of each of said mounting blocks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, said roof mirror assembly housing comprising a first side member, a second side member, a back member and a receiving member for said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said roof mirror assembly is attached to said roof mirror assembly housing along said back member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A roof mirror assembly, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first mirror panel having a first reflective surface and a first edge surface, said first edge surface lying in a plane oriented substantially at a 45&deg; angle to said first reflective surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second mirror panel having a second reflective surface and a second edge surface, said second edge surface lying in a plane oriented substantially at a 45&deg; angle to said second reflective surface, wherein said first and second edge surfaces are joined together creating a common plane oriented substantially at a 45&deg; angle to both of said reflective surfaces, and further wherein said joining together of said panels along said common plane causes said first and second reflective surfaces of said panels to be oriented substantially perpendicularly to each other; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one mounting block adhered to, and extending under, said joined first and second mirror panels, said at least one mounting block being adhered to said joined mirror panels along portions of at least one back surface extending from at least one of said first or second mirror panels, said at least one back surface lying in a plane oriented substantially perpendicular to said common plane. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. A roof mirror assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first and second edge surfaces are joined together creating a miter joint. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A roof mirror assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one mounting block is two mounting blocks. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. A roof mirror assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one back surface is a first back surface extending from said first mirror panel and a second back surface extending from said second mirror panel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A roof mirror assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a back plate member adhered below said mounting members. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. A method of assembling a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly in order to comply with certain operator mandated specifications, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a mirror panel housing having a first side member, a second side member and a receiving member for a connecting member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering a mirror panel having a first reflective surface to said first and second side members of said mirror panel housing; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a roof mirror assembly housing having a first side member, a second side member, a back member and a receiving member for said connecting member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering to said back member of said roof mirror assembly housing, a roof mirror assembly comprising second and third mirror panels, with said second mirror panel having a second reflective surface in substantially perpendicular alignment with a third reflective surface on said third mirror panel; </claim-text>
<claim-text>cutting from a supply of off-the-shelf connecting members, said connecting member for said lateral transfer retroreflector, to a length prescribed in part by said operator mandated specifications; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adhering said cut connecting member to said members for receiving said connecting member. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. A method of assembling a lateral transfer retroreflector assembly as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the further step of aligning said first reflective surface of said mirror panel housing with said substantially perpendicularly oriented second and third reflective surfaces of said second and third mirror panels of said roof mirror assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030002178A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
