<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001610A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001610A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001610</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895698</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H03K019/003</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>326</class>
<subclass>030000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>BUS TERMINATION SCHEME FOR FLEXIBLE UNI-PROCESSOR AND DUAL PROCESSOR PLATFORMS</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Vijayalakshmi</given-name>
<family-name>Ramachandran</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Usman</given-name>
<middle-name>Azeez</middle-name>
<family-name>Mughal</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Chee</given-name>
<middle-name>How</middle-name>
<family-name>Lim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Hillsboro</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BLAKELY SOKOLOFF TAYLOR &amp; ZAFMAN</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>12400 WILSHIRE BOULEVARD, SEVENTH FLOOR</address-1>
<city>LOS ANGELES</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>90025</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A circuit board has a transmission line. A connector is coupled to the circuit board and electrically coupled to the transmission line. Bus termination circuitry is electrically coupled to the transmission line at or near an end of the transmission line at the connector such that the transmission line is terminated by the bus termination circuitry when the connector is not engaged to support any device for electrical coupling to the transmission line. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to the field of computer systems. More particularly, the present invention relates to the field of bus termination schemes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Transmitting electrical signals over relatively long mismatched bus transmission lines between integrated circuit devices typically creates signal reflections. Signal reflections occur when only a portion of the power of a signal transmitted over a transmission line is output to the load at the end of the transmission line while the remaining portion of the power of the signal is reflected back onto the transmission line. The existence of signal reflections on transmission lines can result in overshoots, undershoots, and/or ringbacks, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> An overshoot typically occurs when the voltage of a received signal rises from a lower value, such as 0 Volts (V) for example, beyond a desired higher value, such as 3.3 Volts (V) for example, before settling near the higher value. An undershoot typically occurs when the voltage of a received signal falls from the higher value beyond the lower value before settling near the lower value. Ringbacks typically occur when a signal overshoot falls back below the higher value before settling near the higher value or when a signal undershoot rises back above the lower value before settling near the lower value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Overshoots, undershoots, and ringbacks increase the amount of time required to read signals because the circuitry receiving each signal must wait relatively longer for the signal to settle near the higher or lower value prior to interpreting the signal as a logical one or zero, respectively. Because signals may be transmitted only as fast as they can be read, overshoots, undershoots, and ringbacks limit the frequency at which signals may be transmitted over a transmission line. Additionally, relatively large overshoots can damage circuitry designed to receive signals at voltage values of only some predetermined amount over the higher value. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To avoid or minimize signal reflections and therefore help maintain signal quality to allow signal transmission at relatively high frequencies, each transmission line may be terminated with a load having an impedance that is approximately equal to the characteristic impedance of the transmission line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of a computer system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> comprising a motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, a first processor card <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> supporting a first processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, a second processor card <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> supporting a second processor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, and a chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. Motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> has a processor bus formed by a plurality of transmission lines on motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. One exemplary transmission line <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Processor cards <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are each mechanically and electrically coupled to the processor bus of motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> by insertion into a respective slot connector on motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is mechanically and electrically coupled to motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. At least one chip of chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is mechanically and electrically coupled to the processor bus of motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> comprises on-die terminating pull-up resistors at or near the end of each transmission line at processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> comprises on-die terminating pull-up resistors at or near the end of each transmission line at processor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The terminating resistors each have an impedance approximately equal to the characteristic impedance of its corresponding transmission line to help avoid or minimize signal reflections at processors <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. As one example, processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> comprises an on-die terminating pull-up resistor <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> at or near its end of transmission line <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, and processor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> comprises an on-die terminating resistor <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> at or near its end of transmission line <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The end of each transmission line at chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is not terminated with a resistor to help reduce design complexity and power dissipation that results from constant current flow through terminating resistors as a result of driving either end of each transmission line low. Because this single-ended termination scheme produces signal reflections at the end of each transmission line at chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the length of each stub for chipset <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, such as stub <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> for example, is relatively short to help minimize such signal reflections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Computer system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be changed to a uni-processor system by removing processor card <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, for example, from its slot connector on motherboard <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Because the end of each transmission line at that slot connector would no longer have terminating resistors following removal of processor card <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, a bus termination card comprising terminating resistors for each such transmission line is typically inserted into the slot connector to avoid or minimize signal reflections. One or more resistors of a bus termination card, however, may not be firmly coupled to bus termination card and/or may become loose, for example, from rough handling by a user. As a result, one or more transmission lines may not be terminated by the bus termination card. A bus termination card also incurs an added expense for computer system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The present invention is illustrated by way of example and not limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings, in which like references indicate similar elements and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a prior art computer system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, an exemplary dual processor computer system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, a circuit board and connectors to help support the dual processor computer system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and allow the computer system to be changed to a uni-processor computer system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, a circuit board for the computer system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with slot connectors each to receive a respective processor card; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, a circuit board for the computer system of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with socket connectors each to receive a respective processor chip package; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, the circuit board and connectors of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> supporting a uni-processor computer system. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The following detailed description sets forth an embodiment or embodiments in accordance with the present invention for bus termination scheme for flexible uni-processor and dual processor platforms. In the following description, details are set forth such as specific circuitry, connectors, packaging technologies, etc. in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. It will be evident, however, that the present invention may be practiced without these details. In other instances, well-known computer devices, etc. have not been described in particular detail so as not to obscure the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Exemplary Computer System </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary dual processor computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Although described in the context of computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, the present invention may be implemented in any suitable computer system comprising any suitable one or more integrated circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> comprises processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, a processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and a chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> are coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may each comprise any suitable processor such as, for example, a processor in the Pentium&reg; or Celeron&trade; family of processors available from Intel&reg; Corporation of Santa Clara, Calif. For one embodiment, processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is removably coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. In this manner, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may optionally serve as a uni-processor computer system by not coupling or removing processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> from processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> provides an interface to processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> over processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and to one or more suitable devices in communication with chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable interface controllers to provide for any suitable communication link to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> and/or to any suitable device in communication with chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment provides suitable arbitration, buffering, and/or coherency management for each interface. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable circuitry formed on any suitable one or more integrated circuit chips. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment provides an interface to a main memory <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and a graphics controller <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> each coupled to chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Main memory <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> stores data and/or instructions, for example, for computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and may comprise any suitable memory, such as a dynamic random access memory (DRAM) for example. Graphics controller <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> controls the display of information on a suitable display <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>, such as a cathode ray tube (CRT) or liquid crystal display (LCD) for example, coupled to graphics controller <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment interfaces with graphics controller <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> through an accelerated graphics port (AGP). Graphics controller <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may alternatively be included in chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> as a separate chip or integrated with a suitable chip of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Also as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment provides an interface to one or more suitable integrated drive electronics (IDE) drives <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, such as a hard disk drive (HDD) or a compact disc read only memory (CD ROM) drive for example, to store data and/or instructions for example, one or more suitable universal serial bus (USB) devices through one or more USB ports <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, an audio coder/decoder (codec) <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>, and a modem codec <highlight><bold>248</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment also provides an interface through a super input/output (I/O) controller <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> to a keyboard <highlight><bold>251</bold></highlight>, a cursor control device <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> such as a mouse or touchpad, for example, one or more suitable devices, such as a printer for example, through one or more parallel ports <highlight><bold>253</bold></highlight>, one or more suitable devices through one or more serial ports <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>, and a floppy disk drive <highlight><bold>255</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment further provides an interface to one or more suitable peripheral component interconnect (PCI) devices coupled to chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> through one or more PCI slots <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> on a PCI bus and an interface to one or more suitable industry standard architecture (ISA) devices coupled to chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> by the PCI bus through an ISA bridge <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight>. ISA bridge <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> interfaces with one or more ISA devices through one or more ISA slots <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> on an ISA bus. ISA bridge <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may alternatively be included in chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> as a separate chip or integrated with a suitable chip of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Also as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment provides an interface to a basic input/output system (BIOS) memory <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> to store suitable system and/or video BIOS software for computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. BIOS memory <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may alternatively be included in chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> as a separate chip or integrated with a suitable chip of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment comprises a circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for one embodiment supports processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> may support processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, and chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for one embodiment supports each of a plurality of transmission lines, such as a transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> for example, forming processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> in one or more layers of circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable number of transmission lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for one embodiment supports processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> with a connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and supports processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> with a connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Each connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is mechanically coupled or mounted to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> such that connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, respectively, is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Each connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may be coupled to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner to electrically couple connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, respectively, to any suitable plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable connector to mechanically couple any suitable device having processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, such as a chip package or a card for example, to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner such that processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. Connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable connector to mechanically couple any suitable device having processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, such as a chip package or a card for example, to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner such that processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be electrically coupled to any suitable plurality of the transmission lines coupled to connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, respectively. Connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may each be used to removably couple processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively, to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may each comprise the same type of connector or may each comprise a different connector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each comprise a slot connector <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, respectively, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Slot connector <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> defines a slot to receive an edge of a processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> supporting processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is mechanically and electrically coupled to processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> such that processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> becomes electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to slot connector <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> as processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is inserted into slot connector <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. Processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may be coupled to slot connector <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner to couple processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> electrically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Slot connector <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> defines a slot to receive an edge of a processor card <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> supporting processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is mechanically and electrically coupled to processor card <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> such that processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> becomes electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to slot connector <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> as processor card <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is inserted into slot connector <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>. Processor card <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may be coupled to slot connector <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner to couple processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> electrically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each comprise a socket connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>, respectively, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Socket connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> receives a plurality of contacts, such as pins or balls for example, on a chip package supporting processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to electrically couple processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to socket connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>. Socket connector <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> receives a plurality of contacts, such as pins or balls for example, on a chip package supporting processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to electrically couple processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to a plurality of the transmission lines coupled to socket connector <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may each comprise a suitable pin grid array (PGA) socket, such as a flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) socket or a micro-PGA socket. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may each be packaged using a suitable PGA package technology, such as a flip chip pin grid array (FC-PGA) or plastic pin grid array (PPGA) technology for example. Connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may each comprise a suitable Zero Insertion Force (ZIF) socket to allow respective processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to be inserted into and removed from connector <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> with relative ease. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for one embodiment also supports chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Each chip of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be mechanically coupled to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner such that at least one chip of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be electrically coupled to any suitable plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> For one embodiment, one or more chips of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may each be inserted into a respective suitable socket mechanically coupled or mounted to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> such that at least one such socket is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. For another embodiment, one or more chips of chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be coupled to a suitable card inserted into a suitable slot connector mechanically coupled to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> such that the slot connector is electrically coupled to a plurality of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may also support any other suitable device of computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> or any suitable connector for any other suitable device of computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in any suitable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has input/output (I/O) circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry electrically coupled at or near the end of each of a plurality of transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have I/O circuitry to transmit and/or receive signals over each of a plurality of transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have bus termination circuitry to help avoid or minimize signal reflections at the end of each of a plurality of transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. Processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may each have any suitable I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to each of any suitable plurality of transmission lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates, for one embodiment, input/output (I/O) circuitry and bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> for each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> For one embodiment, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has an n-channel metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (N-MOSFET) <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> having a source terminal coupled to a relatively low power supply node, such as ground for example, and a drain terminal coupled to a node <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> at or near an end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> also has a resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> coupled between a relatively high power supply node and node <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> to serve as a pull-up resistor. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> drives or transmits signals onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> by applying suitable high and low voltage signals to a gate terminal <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> of transistor <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> to turn transistor <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> on and off. When processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> off, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is pulled up by the high power supply node coupled to resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively high voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. When processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight> on, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is pulled down by the low power supply node coupled to transistor <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively low voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> also has a differential amplifier <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> having one input terminal <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> coupled to node <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and another input terminal <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> coupled to a suitable reference voltage node. By comparing the voltage of signals received over transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to a reference voltage at the reference voltage node, differential amplifier <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> interprets each received signal as a logical one if the voltage of the signal is above the reference voltage and as a logical zero if the voltage of the signal is below the reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> also serves to terminate transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may have any suitable resistance to help avoid or minimize signal reflections caused by receiving signals at the end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any suitable device or component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, for one embodiment, has an n-channel metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (N-MOSFET) <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> having a source terminal coupled to a relatively low power supply node, such as ground for example, and a drain terminal coupled to a node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> at or near an end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> also has a resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> coupled between a relatively high power supply node and node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> to serve as a pull-up resistor. Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> drives or transmits signals onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> by applying suitable high and low voltage signals to a gate terminal <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of transistor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> to turn transistor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> on and off. When processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> off, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> is pulled up by the high power supply node coupled to resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively high voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. When processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> on, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> is pulled down by the low power supply node coupled to transistor <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively low voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> also has a differential amplifier <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight> having one input terminal <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> coupled to node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight> of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and another input terminal <highlight><bold>329</bold></highlight> coupled to a suitable reference voltage node. By comparing the voltage of signals received over transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to a reference voltage at the reference voltage node, differential amplifier <highlight><bold>327</bold></highlight> interprets each received signal as a logical one if the voltage of the signal is above the reference voltage and as a logical zero if the voltage of the signal is below the reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> also serves to terminate transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may have any suitable resistance to help avoid or minimize signal reflections caused by receiving signals at the end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>. Resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any suitable device or component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Although illustrated as having I/O circuitry and bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to only one transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to each of any suitable one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each have I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of address lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each have I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of data lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each have I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of control lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> for one embodiment each have I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to each of all of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have only I/O circuitry to transmit signals over each of one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, only I/O circuitry to receive signals over each of one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, and/or I/O circuitry to both transmit and receive signals over each of one or more transmission lines. Each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have bus termination circuitry at any suitable one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may have the same or different I/O circuitry to transmit signals for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has such I/O circuitry. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may have the same or different I/O circuitry to receive signals for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has such I/O circuitry. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may have the same or different bus termination circuitry for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> has bus termination circuitry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have the same or different I/O circuitry to transmit signals for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> has such I/O circuitry. Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have the same or different I/O circuitry to receive signals for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> has such I/O circuitry. Processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may have the same or different bus termination circuitry for each transmission line at which processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> has bus termination circuitry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry for processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be formed at any suitable location on any suitable device supporting processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. For one embodiment, the I/O circuitry and/or bus termination circuitry for processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are formed on-die with processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. For another embodiment, the bus termination circuitry is formed in the package for processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> between the processor die and one or more external contacts, such as pins or balls for example. For another embodiment where processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are supported by processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, respectively, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, bus termination circuitry may be formed on processor card <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, respectively, external to processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> comprises bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to one or more transmission lines at or near the end of each such transmission line at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> such that the transmission line is terminated by the bus termination circuitry when connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is not engaged to support or occupied by any device, such as processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> or a bus termination device for example. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may then optionally serve as a single processor or uni-processor computer system, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, by not coupling processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> to connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> or by removing processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> from connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> without any need for coupling of any other device, such as a bus termination device for example, to connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> to avoid or minimize signal reflections at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the expense and risk of loose terminating resistors associated with use of typical bus termination cards may be avoided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable bus termination circuitry to allow computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to optionally serve as either a uni-processor or dual processor computer system with no or minimized signal reflections on one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 6</cross-reference>, such bus termination circuitry for one embodiment comprises a resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> coupled between a node <highlight><bold>383</bold></highlight> at or near the end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and a relatively high power supply node to serve as a pull-up resistor. Resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> may have any suitable resistance to help avoid or minimize signal reflections caused by receiving signals at the end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> when connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is not engaged to support or occupied by any device, such as processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> or a bus termination device for example. Resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> may be implemented using any suitable device or component. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is to be coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> with connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> when computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is to serve as a dual processor computer system, the value of the resistance to be used for resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> depends on the bus termination circuitry coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> when processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. For one embodiment where processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> has bus termination circuitry comprising resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> is then terminated with an effective resistance from the parallel combination of resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> and resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The resistance used for each resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> and resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> may depend, for example, on the desired signal timing and/or signal quality for signal transmissions over transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> when computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is to serve as a uni-processor computer system and when computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is to serve as a dual processor computer system. As one example, the resistance used for resistors <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> may be selected to optimize signal timing and/or signal quality for signal transmissions over transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> when computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is to serve as a uni-processor computer system while satisfying one or more signal timing and/or signal quality constraints when computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is to serve as a dual processor computer system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The resistance used for each resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> and resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> may also depend, for example, on the characteristic impedance of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, the trace length of a stub <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> between resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>383</bold></highlight>, the trace length of a stub <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight> between node <highlight><bold>383</bold></highlight> and connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, and the trace length of a stub <highlight><bold>393</bold></highlight> between connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>325</bold></highlight>. For one embodiment, the effective resistance from the parallel combination of resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> and resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> is generally close to the characteristic impedance of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> For one embodiment, transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> has a characteristic impedance of approximately 60 ohms; the trace length of stub <highlight><bold>391</bold></highlight> is less than or equal to approximately one-half inch; processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is less than or equal to approximately one-half inch from node <highlight><bold>383</bold></highlight> through connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and along stub <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight>; processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is less than or equal to approximately 3.5 inches from a node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight> through connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, along stub <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight>, and along a stub <highlight><bold>394</bold></highlight> between node <highlight><bold>383</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight>; processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is less than or equal to approximately 3.5 inches from node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight> through connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and along a stub <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> between connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight>; and the trace length of a stub <highlight><bold>397</bold></highlight> between chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight> is less than or equal to approximately 2 inches. Resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may then have a resistance in the range of approximately 110 to approximately 130 ohms, for example; resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may then have a resistance of approximately 100 ohms, for example; and resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> of processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may then have a resistance of approximately 60 ohms, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> For one embodiment where each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> comprises on-die bus termination circuitry, each processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may comprise suitable circuitry to set the resistance of such bus termination circuitry selectively. In this manner, any processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be coupled to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> using either connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may then selectively set its on-die resistance depending on which connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> uses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Although illustrated as having bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to only one transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may have bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to each of any suitable one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of address lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of data lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has bus termination circuitry for each of a plurality of control lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has bus termination circuitry for each transmission line that would be terminated by bus termination circuitry for processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> if processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> were coupled to processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> with connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to each of all of the transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may have the same or different bus termination circuitry for each transmission line at which computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> has bus termination circuitry at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Suitable bus termination circuitry for one embodiment may be mechanically coupled to or mounted directly to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> at or near where each of one or more transmission lines is coupled to connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> such that the bus termination circuitry is electrically coupled to each such transmission line at or near the end of each such transmission line at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Suitable bus termination circuitry for one embodiment may be mechanically coupled to or mounted directly to the same surface of circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> on which connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is coupled or mounted and/or to the opposite surface of circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight> for mechanical and electrical coupling to one or more transmission lines at or near connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> through circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. Suitable bus termination circuitry for one embodiment may be mounted to or supported by connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> such that the bus termination circuitry is electrically coupled to each of one or more transmission lines at or near the end of each such transmission line at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> when connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is coupled to circuit board <highlight><bold>301</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Although described as comprising resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> that serves as a pull-up resistor, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may comprise other suitable bus termination circuitry, such as a resistor coupled in series or a pull-down resistor for example, at or near the end of any suitable one or more transmission lines at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. The bus termination circuitry used may depend, for example, on the I/O circuitry used by processors <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to transmit and receive signals over each such transmission line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Although described as comprising bus termination circuitry at or near the end of each of one or more transmission lines at only one connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for another embodiment may also comprise bus termination circuitry at or near the end of each of one or more transmission lines at connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. In this manner, computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may serve as a uni-processor computer system using either processor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> or processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> without any need for coupling of any device, such as a bus termination device for example, to connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, respectively, to avoid or minimize signal reflections at connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, respectively. This option may be desired, for example, where connectors <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> are different. Computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may comprise any suitable bus termination circuitry, such as a pull-up resistor for example, at or near the end of each of any suitable one or more transmission lines at connector <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment has input/output (I/O) circuitry electrically coupled at or near the end of each of a plurality of transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may have I/O circuitry to transmit and/or receive signals over each of a plurality of transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may have any suitable I/O circuitry electrically coupled to each of any suitable plurality of transmission lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, for one embodiment, has an n-channel metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (N-MOSFET) <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> having a source terminal coupled to a relatively low power supply node, such as ground for example, and a drain terminal coupled to a node <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> at an end of transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> drives or transmits signals onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> by applying suitable high and low voltage signals to a gate terminal <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> of transistor <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> to turn transistor <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> on and off. When chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> off, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> is pulled up by the high power supply node coupled to resistor <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, resistor <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight>, and resistor <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> when processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is coupled to transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively high voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. When chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> turns transistor <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight> on, the voltage at node <highlight><bold>335</bold></highlight> is pulled down by the low power supply node coupled to transistor <highlight><bold>333</bold></highlight>, thereby driving a relatively low voltage signal onto transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> also has a differential amplifier <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> having one input terminal <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> coupled to transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and another input terminal <highlight><bold>339</bold></highlight> coupled to a suitable reference voltage node. By comparing the voltage of signals received over transmission line <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to the reference voltage at the reference voltage node, differential amplifier <highlight><bold>337</bold></highlight> interprets each received signal as a logical one if the voltage of the signal is above the reference voltage and as a logical zero if the voltage of the signal is below the reference voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> For one embodiment, the end of one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is not terminated with a resistor to help reduce design complexity and power dissipation that results from constant current flow through terminating resistors as a result of driving any end of a transmission line low. Because this single-ended termination scheme produces signal reflections at the end of each such transmission line at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, the trace length of each stub for chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, such as a stub <highlight><bold>397</bold></highlight> between chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> and node <highlight><bold>399</bold></highlight> for example, is relatively short to help minimize such signal reflections. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for one embodiment may have bus termination circuitry electrically coupled at or near the end of each of one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> to help avoid or minimize signal reflections at the end of each such transmission line at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may have any suitable bus termination circuitry at or near the end of any suitable one or more transmission lines of processor bus <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight> at chipset <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Although described in the context of computer system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> where processor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be either coupled to or removed from connector <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, the present invention may be used to couple or remove any suitable device from any suitable connector in any suitable computer system with minimized concern for signal reflections at the connector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing description, the invention has been described with reference to specific exemplary embodiments thereof. It will, however, be evident that various modifications and changes may be made thereto without departing from the broader spirit or scope of the present invention as defined in the appended claims. The specification and drawings are, accordingly, to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a circuit board having a transmission line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector coupled to the circuit board, the connector electrically coupled to the transmission line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to the transmission line at or near an end of the transmission line at the connector such that the transmission line is terminated by the bus termination circuitry when the connector is not engaged to support any device for electrical coupling to the transmission line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bus termination circuitry comprises a resistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises the bus termination circuitry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bus termination circuitry is mounted directly to the circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises a slot connector to receive a card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises a socket connector to receive a chip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A computer system comprising: 
<claim-text>a circuit board having a transmission line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor supported by the circuit board and electrically coupled to the transmission line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector coupled to the circuit board, the connector electrically coupled to the transmission line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to the transmission line at or near an end of the transmission line at the connector such that the transmission line is terminated by the bus termination circuitry when the connector is not engaged to support any device for electrical coupling to the transmission line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bus termination circuitry comprises a resistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises the bus termination circuitry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bus termination circuitry is mounted directly to the circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector defines a slot connector to receive a processor card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises a socket connector to receive a processor chip. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The computer system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a chipset coupled to the circuit board and electrically coupled to the transmission line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a circuit board having a transmission line; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a device having first bus termination circuitry; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector coupled to the circuit board, the connector to electrically couple the device to the transmission line such that the first bus termination circuitry is electrically coupled to the transmission line; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>second bus termination circuitry electrically coupled to the transmission line at or near an end of the transmission line at the connector such that the transmission line is terminated by both the first bus termination circuitry and the second bus termination circuitry when the connector is engaged to support the device and such that the transmission line is terminated by the second bus termination circuitry when the connector is not engaged to support the device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second bus termination circuitry comprises a resistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second bus termination circuitry comprises a resistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the connector comprises the second bus termination circuitry. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second bus termination circuitry is mounted directly to the circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the device comprises a card and the connector comprises a slot connector to receive the card. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the device comprises a chip and the connector comprises a socket connector to receive the chip.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001610A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
