<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001208</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10228732</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020827</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L027/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>347000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Methods, structures, and circuits for transistors with gate-to-body capacitive coupling</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10228732</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020827</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09031960</doc-number>
<document-date>19980226</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6448615</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Leonard</given-name>
<family-name>Forbes</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Corvallis</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Wendell</given-name>
<middle-name>P.</middle-name>
<family-name>Noble</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Milton</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Micron Technology, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>SCHWEGMAN, LUNDBERG, WOESSNER &amp; KLUTH, P.A.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 2938</address-1>
<city>MINNEAPOLIS</city>
<state>MN</state>
<postalcode>55402</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Many integrated circuits, particularly digital memories, include millions of field-effect transistors which operate simultaneously and thus consume considerable power. One way to reduce power consumption is to lower transistor threshold, or turn-on, voltage, and then use lower-voltage power supplies. Although conventional techniques of lowering threshold voltage have enabled use of 2-volt power supplies, even lower voltages are needed. Several proposals involving a dynamic threshold concept have been promising, but have failed, primarily because of circuit-space considerations, to yield practical devices. Accordingly, the present invention provides a space-saving structure for a field-effect transistor having a dynamic threshold voltage. One embodiment includes a vertical gate-to-body coupling capacitor that reduces the surface area required to realize the dynamic threshold concept. Other embodiments include an inverter, voltage sense amplifier, and a memory. Ultimately, the invention facilitates use of half-volt (or lower) power supplies. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a Divisional of U.S. Ser. No. 09/031,960 filed on Feb. 26, 1998, which is incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention concerns integrated circuits that include field-effect transistors, particularly metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Integrated circuits, the key components in thousands of electronic and computer products, are interconnected networks of electrical components fabricated on a common foundation, or substrate. Fabricators typically use various techniques, such as layering, doping, masking, and etching, to build thousands and even millions of microscopic transistors, resistors, and other electrical components on a silicon substrate, known as a wafer. The components are then &ldquo;wired,&rdquo; or interconnected, together to define a specific electric circuit, such as a computer memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Many integrated circuits include a common type of transistor known as a metal-oxide-semiconductor, field-effect transistor, or &ldquo;mosfet&rdquo; for short. A mosfet has four electrodes, or contacts&mdash;specifically, a gate, source, drain, and body. In digital integrated circuits, such as logic circuits, memories, and microprocessors which operate with electrical signals representing ones and zeroes, each mosfet behaves primarily as a switch, with its gate serving to open and close a channel connecting its source and drain. Closing the switch requires applying a certain threshold voltage to the gate, and opening it requires either decreasing or increasing the gate voltage (relative the threshold voltage), depending on whether the channel is made of negatively or positively doped semiconductive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Mosfets are the most common transistors used in integrated-circuit memories, because of their small size and low power requirements. Integrated-circuit memories typically include millions of mosfets operating simultaneously, to store millions of bits of data. With so many mosfets operating simultaneously, the power consumption of each mosfet is an important concern to memory fabricators. Moreover, as fabricators continually strive to pack more and more mosfets into memory circuits to increase data capacity, the need for even lower power and lower voltage mosfets compounds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Conventional mosfets operate with power supply voltages as low as two volts. Although lower supply voltages are desirable, fabricators have reached a technical impasse based on their inability to make millions of mosfets with perfectly identical threshold voltages. Hence, each of the mosfets has its own unique threshold voltage, with some deviating only slightly from the fabricator&apos;s intended threshold voltage and others deviating significantly. The typical range of threshold voltages in memory circuits extends from 0.2 volts above to 0.2 volts below the intended threshold voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Thus, for example, if fabricators build mosfets with an intended threshold of one-quarter volt to accommodate half-volt power supplies, some mosfets will actually have a threshold around 0.4 volts and others around 0.05 volts. In practice, these deviant mosfets are prone not only to turn on and off randomly because of inevitable power-supply fluctuations or electrical noise affecting their gate voltages, but also to turn on and off at widely variant rates. Therefore, to avoid random operation and promote uniform switching rates, fabricators raise the intended threshold to a higher level, which, in turn, forecloses the option of using lower power-supply voltages. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Recently, three approaches involving the concept of a dynamic, or variable threshold voltage, have emerged as potential solutions to this problem. But, unfortunately none has proven very practical. One dynamic-threshold approach directly connects, or shorts, the gate of a mosfet to its body, causing the mosfet to have a lower effective threshold during switching and higher threshold during non-switching periods. (See, Tsuneaki Fuse et al., A 0.5V 200 MHZ 32b ALU Using Body Bias Controlled SOI Pass-Gate Logic, IEEE International Solid State Circuits Conference, San Francisco, pp. 292-93, 1997.) However, this approach forces the mosfet to draw significant power even when turned off, in other words, to run continuously. This poses a particularly serious limitation for battery-powered applications, such as portable computers, data organizers, cellular phones, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Louis Wong et al. disclose another dynamic-threshold approach which capacitively couples an n-channel mosfet&apos;s gate to its body. (See Louis Wong et al., A 1V CMOS Digital Circuits with Double-Gate Driven MOSFET, IEEE International Solid State Circuits Conference, San Francisco, pp. 292-93, 1997.) Implementing this approach requires adding a gate-to-body coupling capacitor to every mosfet in a memory circuit. Unfortunately, conventional integrated-circuit capacitors are planar or horizontal capacitors that consume great amounts of surface area on an integrated-circuit memory, ultimately reducing its data capacity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The third dynamic-threshold approach, referred to as a synchronous-body bias, applies a voltage pulse to the body of a mosfet at the same time, that is, synchronous, with the application of a voltage to the gate, thereby reducing its effective threshold voltage. (See Kenichi Shimomuro et al., A 1V 46 ns 16 Mb SOI-DRAM with Body Control Technique, Digest of the IEEE International Solid-State Circuits Conference, San Francisco, pp. 68-69, 1997.) Unfortunately, implementing the circuitry to apply the synchronous voltage pulse requires adding extra conductors to carry the voltage pulses and possibly even built-in timing circuits to memory circuits. Thus, like the previous approach, this approach also consumes significant surface area and reduces data capacity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, there is a need to develop space-and-power efficient implementations of the dynamic threshold concept and thus enable the practical use of lower power-supply voltages. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> To address these and other needs, embodiments of the present invention provide a space-saving structure and fabrication method for achieving gate-to-body capacitive coupling in n- and p-channel field-effect transistors. Specifically, one embodiment of the invention uses at least one vertical, that is, non-horizontal, capacitive structure, to achieve the gate-to-body capacitive coupling. In contrast to conventional horizontal capacitor structures, the vertical structure requires much less surface area. Moreover, for further space savings, another embodiment not only uses a lateral semiconductive surface of the transistor as a conductive plate of the gate-to-body coupling capacitor, but also places the other conductive plate in a normally empty isolation region between neighboring transistors. The space-saving gate-to-body capacitive coupling of the invention yields practical transistors with superior switching rates at low-operating voltages, ultimately enabling practical half-volt inverters, buffers, sense amplifiers, memory circuits, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the invention concerns a method for making a field-effect transistor having gate-to-body capacitive coupling. One embodiment entails forming an NMOS or PMOS device island and then growing dielectric sidewalls on two opposing sidewalls of the NMOS or PMOS device island. Afterward, the method forms conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls. This method yields two vertical gate-to-body coupling capacitors, one on each of the two opposing sidewalls of the device island. In other embodiments, the method isolates the device island from an underlying substrate to form a silicon-on-insulator structure and forms self-aligned source and drain regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Still other aspects of the invention include circuits for half-volt inverters, voltage-sense amplifiers, and memories. Each incorporates a field-effect transistor having vertical gate-to-body capacitive coupling and thus offers not only space savings but also superior switching rate at low voltages.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an integrated-circuit assembly for complementary field-effect transistors having gate-to-body capacitive coupling; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference> is a top view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> is a front view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing an equivalent circuit for a portion of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference> assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of an integrated-circuit assembly after formation of an n-well; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> assembly after formation of NMOS and PMOS device islands; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> assembly after isolating the device islands from underlying substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> assembly after formation of vertical sidewall capacitors on the NMOS and PMOS device islands; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> assembly after formation of metal gate layers; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> assembly after definition of metal gate members; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> assembly after formation of the source and drain regions; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of an inverter circuit incorporating the integrated-circuit structures of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of a memory circuit incorporating the inverter circuit of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> as part of a voltage-sense amplifier.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The following detailed description, which references and incorporates FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, describes and illustrates specific embodiments of the invention. These embodiments, offered not to limit but only to exemplify and teach the invention, are shown and described in sufficient detail to enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention. Thus, where appropriate to avoid obscuring the invention, the description may omit certain information known to those of skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> More specifically, this description includes four sections, a definition section that defines certain terms used throughout the description and three sections actually describing the invention. The first section describes a preferred embodiment of new structures for n-and p-type dynamic threshold transistors. The second section describes a preferred method of making these structures, and the third section describes several integrated-circuit applications for complementary dynamic threshold transistors. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Definitions </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The description includes many terms with meanings derived from their usage in the art or from their use within the context of the description. As a further aid, the following term definitions are presented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;substrate,&rdquo; as used herein, encompasses semiconductor wafers as well as structures having one or more insulative, semi-insulative, conductive, or semiconductive layers and materials. Thus, for example, the term embraces not only the silicon-on-insulator structure of this preferred embodiment, but also silicon-on-sapphire and other advanced structures. &ldquo;Horizontal,&rdquo; as used herein, refers to a direction substantially parallel to a supporting surface of the substrate, regardless of substrate orientation. &ldquo;Vertical,&rdquo; as used herein, generally refers to any direction that is not horizontal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Preferred Structure for Complementary Dynamic Threshold Transistors </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A, 1B</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C respectively show perspective, top, and side views of a preferred integrated-circuit assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprising complementary n- and p-type dynamic threshold transistors <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P. Both transistors feature gate-to-body capacitive coupling implemented through transistor sidewall capacitors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>(highlighted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference>.) In the preferred embodiment, the capacitance of each sidewall capacitor is approximately equal to the transistor gate capacitance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> More specifically, assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> having two stacked, or superimposed, layers: a p-doped silicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a silicon dioxide insulative layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Supported on substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are respective NMOS and PMOS dynamic threshold transistors <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P. The transistors are separated on substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> by isolation region <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, best illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1B and 1C</cross-reference>. Transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N, which differs from transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P only in terms of semiconductor doping, includes three layers of semiconductive material. The first layer, a p-type semiconductive body (or bulk) <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, contacts substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, specifically insulative layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Atop p-type body <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is a second layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of lightly doped, p-type semiconductive material (P&minus;), and atop layer <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is a third layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of heavily doped n-type semiconductive material (N&plus;). Layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has two regions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>s</italic></highlight>, which respectively serve as drain and source regions of transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N. The drain and source regions are also shown in the top view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N also includes an insulative saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> atop layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, shown best in the side view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, has a middle region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>that connects insulative sidewall regions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Middle region (or section) <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>contacts a region of layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the channel region, between drain and source regions <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. And insulative sidewall regions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>contact opposing lateral semiconductive surfaces of layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Middle region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>functions as a gate insulator. In the preferred embodiment, insulative saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> consists essentially of silicon dioxide or another electrical insulator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Atop insulative saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a conductive saddle structure <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, preferably formed of polysilicon. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference> shows that, like insulative saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, conductive saddle structure <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> has a conductive middle region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connecting conductive sidewalls <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Conductive middle region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which forms a gate region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, contacts middle region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of insulative saddle structure <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Conductive sidewalls <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>contact respective insulative sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>which space the conductive sidewalls from adjacent lateral surfaces of semiconductive layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Conductive sidewalls <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, together with corresponding insulative sidewalls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and the opposing lateral semiconductive surfaces of layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> form respective twin vertical sidewall capacitors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. (In geometric terms, the vertical sidewalls define respective planes that intersect or are non-parallel to the supporting surface of substrate <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>.) In the preferred embodiment, the sidewalls are substantially perpendicular, or normal, to the supporting surface. The conductive sidewalls <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and semiconductive lateral surfaces of layers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> serve not only as parallel conductive plates of the twin vertical sidewall capacitors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, but also as conductive leads, connecting the vertical sidewall capacitors to gate region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and thereby capacitively coupling gate region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of transistor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N to its body layer <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. (Gate region <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, gate insulator <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and semiconductive layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also provide a gate capacitance.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> One advantage of the vertical sidewall construction of capacitor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is its use of space in the normally unused isolation region <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> between transistors <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P. Sidewall conductors <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and respective insulative, or dielectric, layers <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>extend outwardly, or widthwise, from the lateral surfaces of the transistors into the isolation region. This arrangement, which essentially affixes or attaches the vertical capacitors to the sides of the transistors, consumes a minimum of substrate surface area. In contrast, a conventional integrated-circuit capacitor lies horizontally with its two conductive plates essentially parallel to a supporting substrate, and thus typically occupies a greater surface area to provide similar capacitance. Moreover, instead of requiring parallel plates separate from other features of the integrated circuit assembly, the present invention uses the existing lateral semiconductive surfaces of the transistor itself as a plate, providing not only further space savings but also fabrication savings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1D</cross-reference> shows an equivalent circuit for the dynamic threshold transistors <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P. Notably, the gate-to-body coupling capacitance is shown as twin capacitors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>to denote the preferred space-saving structure of the present invention. In operation, capacitors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>appear as short circuits to a switching signal level at gate <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and as open circuits when the signal reaches its steady-state level. As short circuits, the capacitors enable concurrent forward biasing of both the gate <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>(the frontgate) and the backgate formed by layers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Concurrent forward biasing of the frontgate and backgate effectively lowers threshold voltage relative to input voltage and thus accelerates activation of the transistor. In a sense, concurrent forward biasing forms the conductive channel region from front and back directions, thereby amplifying or accelerating the effect of a given gate voltage. Thus, in keeping with the dynamic threshold concept, the transistors <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>P provide effectively lower thresholds during switching episodes and higher thresholds, based on conventional doping techniques, during steady state. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">The Preferred Method of Making </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Complementary Dynamic Threshold Transistors </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> show a number of preferred integrated-circuit assemblies, which taken collectively and sequentially, illustrate a preferred method of making an integrated-circuit assembly substantially similar to space-saving assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Although the preferred method conforms to 0.2-micron CMOS technology, the exemplary dimensions are scalable, both upwardly and downwardly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The first steps of the method form the integrated-circuit assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. These steps, which entail defining NMOS and PMOS device regions in a semiconductor substrate, start with a positively doped silicon substrate or wafer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, form a thermal screen layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, preferably a 10-nanometer-thick layer of silicon dioxide on substrate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and then implant a p-type dopant into substrate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to a depth of about 0.4 microns. The implantation defines a retrograde doping profile, with dopant concentrations increasing with distance from the upper substrate surface. Next, the method defines an N-well device region <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> on p-doped silicon substrate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by applying photo resist mask <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> on thermal screen layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and etching according to conventional techniques. The method then forms an n-well <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> within device region <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> by implanting an n-type dopant, again achieving a retrograde doping profile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The next steps yield the integrated-circuit assembly of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which includes N-channel and P-channel device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the method strips away mask <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and screen layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, exposing n-well <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The method next forms a gate isolation (or insulation) layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, preferably consisting of silicon dioxide. Subsequently, the method forms a heavily positively doped p-type (P&plus;) gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and heavily positively doped n-type (N&plus;) gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N on respective regions <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>P of gate isolation layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Forming the gate regions entails forming a 0.1-micron-thick polysilicon layer over both the device regions, masking and doping gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and then masking and doping gate region <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N. A cap layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> of silicon nitride, approximately 0.1 micron thick, is then formed on the gate regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P, to protect them during subsequent steps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Finally, to form device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, which have respective pairs of opposing vertical sidewalls, the method applies an etch-resistant mask (not shown) defining the perimeter of the islands and then etches through cap layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, polysilicon gate regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N, gate oxide layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and into substrate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> approximately as deep as n-well <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. As <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows, device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are separated by an isolation region <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> (similar to region <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference>.) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the results of the next steps which isolate NMOS and PMOS device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> from underlying substrate <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> with an insulative layer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> of silicon dioxide. Although there are a variety of techniques for achieving this isolation, the inventors prefer the Noble method disclosed in co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/745,708 entitled &ldquo;Silicon-on-Insulator Islands and Methods for Their Formation&rdquo; filed on Nov. 12, 1996. Another method is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,691,230 entitled Technique for Producing Small Islands of Silicon on Insulator&rdquo; issued Nov. 11, 1997 to Leonard Forbes. Both the application and the patent are assigned to the assignee of the present invention and incorporated herein by reference. A by-product of the Noble method is the formation of silicon nitride sidewalls <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> on device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, dielectric (or insulative) sidewalls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>are then formed on the device islands. In the preferred embodiment, forming the dielectric sidewalls entails first removing silicon nitride sidewalls <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> from the device islands and then growing silicon dioxide or other dielectric material on the sidewalls of the device islands. The preferred thickness of the dielectric sidewalls is the same as gate insulation layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is 5-10 nanometers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> After forming the dielectric sidewalls, the method forms respective conductive vertical sidewalls <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>on corresponding dielectric sidewalls <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>In the preferred method, making the vertical sidewalls entails depositing doped polysilicon and directionally etching the doped polysilicon to remove it from undesired areas, thereby leaving it only on the sidewalls of device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The regions between and around device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are then filled with a preferentially etchable material <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, such as intrinsic polysilicon, and subsequently planarized through chemical-mechanical planarization. After planarization, the method removes cap layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> to expose polysilicon gates <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N and top inside edges of vertical conductive sidewalls <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>. In other words, removing cap layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> also entails removing the top most portion of the dielectric sidewalls to allow contact with the inside edges of the conductive sidewalls. Next, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows that the method fills the resulting depressions over gates <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P with a refractory metal, preferably tungsten, to form contacts <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Following removal of excess refractory metal, the method defines drain and source region pairs <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>for respective device islands <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. This entails masking and etching through metal layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, through polysilicon gate regions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N, through underlying gate insulation layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and intrinsic polysilicon <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. After this, the method removes, preferably by gallic acid wet etching, remaining intrinsic polysilicon. The resulting structure is shown in the perspective of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, which for sake of clarity omits intrinsic polysilicon <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows the results of forming source and drain region pairs <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>in self-alignment with respective gates <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>P and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>N, according to conventional procedures. Although not shown, further processing would entail conventional passivation and formation of contact holes and wiring to form a full integrated circuit, such as one or more of those described below. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preferred Circuits For Dynamic Threshold Transistors </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The structure and/or method described above may be used to implement the circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> shows a logic inverter or buffer circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> useful for pass-gate transistor logic or complementary pass-gate transistor logic, as an output driver or driver for an integrated circuit. Circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> comprises respective input and output nodes <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> and voltage supply nodes <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. In the preferred embodiment, voltage supply node <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> provides a nominal voltage of one-half volt, and voltage supply node <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> provides a nominal voltage of zero volts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> also includes respective NMOS and PMOS dynamic threshold transistors <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, which are preferably consistent with the space-saving structures and operating principles of integrated-circuit assembly <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> described above with the aid of FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>D. Transistor <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> includes a field-effect transistor <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>having a gate, drain, source, and body, and twin gate-to-body coupling capacitors <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. Similarly, transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> comprises a field-effect transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and twin gate-to-body coupling capacitors <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. The gates of transistors <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are connected together to form input <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>; and their drains are connected together to form output <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The source of transistor <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connects to supply node <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and the source of transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>connects to supply node <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In operation, circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> performs as an inverter, providing a nominal half-volt output at output <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> in response to a nominal zero-volt input at input <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> and a zero-volt output in response to a half-volt input. However, gate-to-body coupling capacitors <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>-<highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>play a significant role during input-voltage transitions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> More precisely, during positive input transitions (that is, from low to high), these capacitors approximate short circuits between the gates and bodies of transistors <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, thereby forward biasing the backgate of (n-channel) transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and reverse biasing the backgate of (p-channel) transistor <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Forward biasing the backgate of transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>effectively lowers its threshold voltage relative the input voltage, and thus accelerates activation, or turn on, of transistor <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Consequently, the voltage at output <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> begins decreasing more rapidly toward the voltage at supply node <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, zero volts in the preferred embodiment. After switching, the gate-to-body capacitance discharges, thereby reverse biasing the backgate and restoring the threshold voltage. Similarly, a negative voltage transition at input <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> temporarily forward biases the backgate of (p-channel) transistor <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and thus accelerates its activation and the associated increase in the output voltage toward the voltage at upper supply node <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, one-half volt in the preferred embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Estimates are that the gate-to-body capacitive coupling in circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> will yield peak switching currents about five times larger than conventional low-voltage circuits lacking gate-to-body capacitive coupling. Ultimately, such peak-current increases translate into a three-fold increase in switching rates. Moreover, unlike previous efforts that directly shorted the gate and body to permanently forward bias the backgate junctions and thus drew current continuously, circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> only forward biases the backgate junctions temporarily. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> illustrates a dynamic-random-access-memory (DRAM) circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> suitable for one-half-volt (or lower) power-supply voltages. In addition to conventional DRAM features, such as a memory array <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which comprises a number of memory cells <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>, a column address decoder <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, and a row address decoder <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, and associated bit lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and word lines <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, DRAM circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> includes a novel voltage-sense-amplifier circuit <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> coupled in conventional fashion to bit lines <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Voltage-sense-amplifier circuit <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> includes two cross-coupled inverters <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>B, each similar to circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. Thus, the backgates or bodies of each inverter transistor are capacitively coupled to its input, thereby providing the circuit <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> with the peak switching current and switching rates advantages of circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> More specifically, circuit <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> further includes a bit-line node <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> coupled to a first bit-line <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, and a bit-line node <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> coupled to a second bit line <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and two power supply nodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>. Bit-line node <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> connects to input node <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>A of circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A, and output node <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>B of circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>B. Bit-line node <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> connects to input node <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>B of circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>B, and output node <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>A of circuit <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>A. Power supply nodes <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight>, which preferably provide respective nominal voltages of one-half and zero volts, are coupled to corresponding supply nodes <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>B. With the exception of its dynamic thresholding which provides superior switching current and switching rate at low operating voltages, circuit <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> operates according to well-known and understood principles to sense data stored in memory cells <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Conclusions </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a space-saving structure and fabrication method for achieving gate-to-body capacitive coupling in n- and p-channel transistors. Instead of using common horizontal capacitor structures to achieve the capacitive coupling, the invention uses vertical, that is, non-horizontal, capacitors, which require less substrate area. Moreover, the invention places these vertical capacitors in the isolation region between adjacent transistors. And, for even greater savings, the invention uses a lateral semiconductive surface (or sidewall) of the transistor as a conductive plate of the gate-to-body coupling capacitor. Furthermore, transistors incorporating gate-to-body capacitive coupling provide superior switching speed with low-operating voltages, ultimately enabling practical half-volt inverters, buffers, sense amplifiers, memory circuits, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The embodiments described above are intended only to illustrate and teach one or more ways of implementing or practicing the present invention, not to restrict its breadth or scope. The actual scope of the invention, which includes all ways of implementing or practicing the invention, is defined only by the following claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A structure for a transistor having a gate and a body, the structure comprising a vertical gate-to-body coupling capacitor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A structure for a transistor having a gate and a body, the structure comprising two gate-to-body coupling capacitors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A gate-to-body capacitive-coupling structure for a field-effect transistor having a gate and a body, the capacitive coupling structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a semiconductive layer having a lateral surface; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conductive sidewall confronting the lateral surface and connected to the gate, wherein separation of the lateral surface and the conductive sidewall at least partly determines capacitance of the gate-to-body capacitive-coupling structure. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The gate-to-body capacitive coupling structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an insulative sidewall between the lateral surface and conductive sidewall, wherein the insulative and conductive sidewalls and the lateral surface are substantially parallel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An integrated-circuit assembly comprising first and second field-effect transistor structures separated from each other by an isolation region, with one or more of the field-effect transistor structures having a gate-to-body capacitive coupling structure occupying at least a portion of the isolation region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A structure for a field-effect transistor having a body and a gate, the structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an insulative saddle structure having a middle section contacting the gate, and having two opposing insulative sidewalls contacting the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conductive saddle structure having a middle section contacting the middle section of the insulative saddle structure, and having two opposing conductive sidewalls each contacting one of the opposing insulative sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A structure for a field-effect transistors having a body and a gate, the structure comprising: 
<claim-text>an insulative or semiconductive layer positioned between the body and gate, and having first and second opposing lateral surfaces; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second conductive walls connected to the gate, and respectively confronting the first and second opposing lateral surfaces of the insulative or semiconductive layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second dielectric members positioned respectively between the first conductive wall and the first opposing lateral surface and between the second conductive wall and the second opposing lateral surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a substrate surface which supports the body, wherein the first and second conductive walls define planes intersecting the substrate surface, or define planes which form angles of less than 180 degrees with the substrate surface, or define planes which are non-parallel to the substrate surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the conductive sidewall member comprises polysilicon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A field-effect transistor assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a semiconductive body having a first semiconductive sidewall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first conductive sidewall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first dielectric sidewall separating the first conductive sidewall from the first semiconductive sidewall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The field-effect transistor assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the body has an other semiconductive sidewall and the assembly further comprises: 
<claim-text>a second dielectric sidewall adjacent the other semiconductive sidewall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second conductive sidewall adjacent the second dielectric sidewall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The field-effect transistor assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a semiconductive layer contacting the semiconductive body and having source and drain regions; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric layer contacting the semiconductive layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate structure contacting the dielectric layer and electrically connected to the first and second conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of making a field-effect transistor, comprising: 
<claim-text>forming an NMOS or PMOS island having at least two opposing sidewalls and a gate region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of the NMOS or PMOS device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the NMOS or PMOS device island includes a protective cap layer on the gate region, and wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>exposing the gate region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising forming drain and source regions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the NMOS or PMOS device island is formed on a substrate, and the method further comprises isolating the device island from the substrate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein isolating the island from the substrate forms silicon nitride sidewalls on the device island. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A vertical capacitance structure comprising a semiconductive wall, a doped polysilicon wall, and a dielectric material between the semiconductive and polysilicon walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The vertical capacitor of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the semiconductive wall is part of a transistor structure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a field-effect transistor having a gate and a body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second capacitive structures coupled between the gate and the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitive structures are located on opposing sides of the corresponding transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the field-effect transistors has drain or source coupled to supply node having a nominal voltage no greater than one-half volt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>first and second complementary field-effect transistors, having respective first and second gates and bodies; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first capacitance coupled between the first gate and body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second capacitance coupled between the second gate and body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitances each comprise first and second capacitive structures coupled between the gate and the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitive structures are positioned on opposing sides of the corresponding transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An inverter circuit, comprising: 
<claim-text>first and second complementary field-effect transistors having respective first and second gates and bodies, with the first and second gates coupled together; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first capacitance coupled between the first gate and body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second capacitance coupled between the second gate and body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitances each comprise first and second capacitive structures coupled between the gate and the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 30</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitance structures are vertical structures. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference> wherein at least one of the field-effect transistors has a drain or source coupled to a supply node having a nominal voltage no greater than one-half volt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. A voltage-sense-amplifier circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>first and second complementary field-effect transistors, having respective first and second gates, drains, sources, and bodies, with the first drain or source coupled to the second drain or source; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first capacitance coupled between the first gate and body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second capacitance coupled between the second gate and body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitances each comprise first and second capacitive structures coupled between the respective gate and body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second field-effect transistors are coupled between first and second voltage nodes having a voltage differential no greater than one-half volt. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. An integrated dynamic-random-access-memory circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of memory cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an address decoder coupled to the plurality of memory cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second complementary field-effect transistors having respective first and second gates and bodies, with the first and second gates coupled to at least one of the memory cells; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second capacitances coupled respectively between the first gate and body and between the second gate and body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first and second capacitances each comprise first and second capacitive structures coupled between the gate and the body. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A method of making a field-effect transistor, comprising: 
<claim-text>forming an NMOS or PMOS island on a semiconductive substrate, with each island having at least two opposing sidewalls and a gate region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulative layer between the NMOS or PMOS island and the semiconductive substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of the NMOS or PMOS device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls, with the conductive sidewall extending from the gate region of the NMOS or PMOS island to the insulatlive layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the NMOS or PMOS device island includes a protective cap layer on the gate region, and wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>exposing the gate region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. A method of making a field-effect transistor, comprising: 
<claim-text>forming an NMOS or PMOS island on a semiconductive substrate, with each island having at least two opposing sidewalls and a gate region; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulative layer between the NMOS or PMOS island and the semiconductive substrate, wherein forming the insulative layer forms silicon nitride sidewalls on the device island; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of the NMOS or PMOS device island, wherein forming the dielectric includes removing at least a portion of the silicon nitride sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls, with the conductive sidewall extending from the gate region of the NMOS or PMOS island to the insulatlive layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the NMOS or PMOS device island includes a protective cap layer on the gate region, and wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>exposing the gate region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 45</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. A method of making a field-effect transistor, comprising: 
<claim-text>forming an NMOS or PMOS island on a semiconductive substrate, with each island having at least two opposing sidewalls, a gate region, and a layer with a retrograde dopant profile; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulative layer between the NMOS or PMOS island and the semiconductive substrate, wherein forming the insulative layer forms silicon nitride sidewalls on the device island; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of the NMOS or PMOS device island, wherein forming the dielectric includes removing at least a portion of the silicon nitride sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls, with the conductive sidewall extending from the gate region of the NMOS or PMOS island to the insulatlive layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the NMOS or PMOS device island includes a protective cap layer on the gate region, and wherein the method further comprises: 
<claim-text>exposing the gate region; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the layer having the retrograde dopant profile has a dopant concentrations that increases with distance from the gate region in a dimension substantially parallel to the opposing sidewalls of the device island. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a semiconductive layer having a major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>doping the semiconductive layer with a p-type dopant to define a first retrograde dopant profile in a dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an n-well in the semiconductive layer, with the n-well having a second retrograde dopant profile in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first insulative layer over the n-well and a portion of the semiconductive layer adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive layer over the first insulative layer, with the conductive layer having portions overlying the n-well and the portion of the semiconductive surface adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing portions of the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and semiconductive layer to defne at least first and second device islands, with each device island having at least two opposing sidewalls, a gate layer, a doped layer with a retrograde dopant profile, and a portion of the first insulative layer between the gate layer and the doped layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>electrically isolating the first and second device islands from the semiconductive layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of each device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls of each device island, with each conductive sidewall extending at least from the gate layer of the device island to the doped layer with the retrograde dopant profile. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein removing portions of the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and the semiconductive layer to defne at least first and second device islands, comprises: 
<claim-text>forming a protective cap layer on the conductive layer, with the protective cap layer defining a perimeter of each device island: and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and the semiconductive layer to define the first and second device islands, with the gate layer of each device island underlying a portion of the protective cap layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>removing at least the portions of the protective cap layer to expose the gate layer of each device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate layer of each device island. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 57</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each retrograde dopant profile has a dopant concentration that increases with distance from the gate layer in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a semiconductive layer having a major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>doping the semiconductive layer with a p-type dopant to define a first retrograde dopant profile in a dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an n-well in the semiconductive layer, with the n-well having a second retrograde dopant profile in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first insulative layer over the n-well and a portion of the semiconductive layer adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive layer over the first insulative layer, with the conductive layer having portions overlying the n-well and the portion of the semiconductive surface adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing portions of the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and semiconductive layer to defne at least first and second device islands, with each device island having at least two opposing sidewalls, a gate layer, a doped layer with a retrograde dopant profile, and a portion of the first insulative layer between the gate layer and the doped layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>electrically isolating the first and second device islands from the semiconductive layer, wherein electrically isolating the device islands includes forming silicon nitride sidewalls on the device islands; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of each device island, wherein forming the dielectric includes removing at least a portion of the silicon nitride sidewalls on each device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls of each device island, with each conductive sidewall extending at least from the gate layer of the device island to the doped layer with the retrograde dopant profile. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference> wherein removing portions of the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and the semiconductive layer to defne at least first and second device islands, comprises: 
<claim-text>forming a protective cap layer on the conductive layer, with the protective cap layer defining a perimeter of each device island: and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and the semiconductive layer to define the first and second device islands, with the gate layer of each device island underlying a portion of the protective cap layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>removing at least the portions of the protective cap layer to expose the gate layer of each device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing tungsten or another refractory metal on the exposed gate layer of each device island. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 64</dependent-claim-reference> wherein exposing the gate region comprises removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the dielectric sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>removing material from the opposing sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>growing a dielectric on the opposing sidewalls after removing the material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each retrograde dopant profile has a dopant concentration that increases with distance from the gate layer in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing a semiconductive layer having a major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>doping the semiconductive layer with a p-type dopant to define a first retrograde dopant profile in a dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an n-well in the semiconductive layer, with the n-well having a second retrograde dopant profile in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first insulative layer over the n-well and a portion of the semiconductive layer adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive layer over the first insulative layer, with the conductive layer having portions overlying the n-well and the portion of the semiconductive surface adjacent to the n-well; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a protective cap layer on the conductive layer, with the protective cap layer defining at least first and second perimeters; </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the conductive layer, the first insulative layer, and the semiconductive layer to define first and second device islands in accord with the first and second perimeters, with each device island having at least two opposing sidewalls, a gate layer, a doped layer with a retrograde dopant profile, and a portion of the first insulative layer between the gate layer and the doped layer, and with a portion of of the protective cap layer overlying the gate layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second insulative layer between the semiconductive layer and the first and second device islands; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming dielectric sidewalls on the two opposing sidewalls of each device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming conductive sidewalls on the dielectric sidewalls of each device island, with each conductive sidewall extending at least from the gate layer of the device island to the doped layer with the retrograde dopant profile; </claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the portion of the protective cap layer overlying each gate layer to define a recess between the opposing sidewalls of each device island; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a conductive structure in the recess of each device island, with each conductive structure electrically coupling the conductive sidewalls of the device island; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>doping first and second regions of the doped layer of each device island, with the first and second regions on respective sides of the gate layer of the device island. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 68</dependent-claim-reference> wherein forming the conductive sidewalls comprises: 
<claim-text>depositing polysilicon on the dielectric sidewalls; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>directionally etching the deposited polysilicon to form the conductive sidewalls. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 68</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein removing the portion of the protective cap layer overlying each gate layer to define a recess between the opposing sidewalls of each device island, includes removing portions of the dielectric sidewalls extending above an upper surface of the gate layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 68</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each retrograde dopant profile has a dopant concentration that increases with distance from the gate layer in the dimension perpendicular to the major surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 68</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the recited acts are performed in the recited order.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>5</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
