<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002331A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002331A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002331</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895054</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L029/76</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L027/108</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>163000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>296000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>304000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>311000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>PROGRAMMING A PHASE-CHANGE MEMORY WITH SLOW QUENCH TIME</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Eungjoon</given-name>
<family-name>Park</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tyler</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lowrey</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>TROP, PRUNER &amp; HU, P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8554 KATY FREEWAY</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 100</address-2>
<city>HOUSTON</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77024</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A memory array is operated by increasing a number of currents through a number of corresponding cells of the array, where each cell has a structural phase-change material to store data for that cell. Each of the currents are increased to an upper level that is sufficiently high that can cause the corresponding cell to be in a first state. Some of the currents are decreased to lower levels at sufficiently high rates that cause their corresponding cells to be programmed to the first state, while others are decreased at sufficiently low rates that cause their corresponding cells to be programmed to a second state. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention is related to techniques for programming a structural phase-change material solid state memory device such as those that use a chalcogenide material which can be programmed into different resistivity states to store data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Solid state memory devices that use a structural phase-change material as the data storage mechanism (referred to here simply as &lsquo;phase-change memories&rsquo;) offer significant advantages in both cost and performance over conventional charge storage based memories. The phase-change memory is made of an array of constituent cells where each cell has some structural phase-change material to store the cell&apos;s data. This material may be, for instance, a chalcogenide alloy that exhibits a reversible structural phase change from amorphous to crystalline. A small volume of the chalcogenide alloy is integrated into a circuit that allows the cell to act as a fast switching programmable resistor. This programmable resistor can exhibit greater than 40 times dynamic range of resistivity between a relatively crystalline phase (low resistivity) and a relatively amorphous phase (high resistivity). The data stored in the cell is read by measuring the cell&apos;s resistance. The chalcogenide alloy cell is also non-volatile. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A conventional technique for programming a phase-change memory cell is to apply a rectangular pulse of current (having a constant magnitude throughout the pulse) to the cell, at a voltage greater than a switching threshold for the phase-change material, which leaves the cell in the reset state (the material is relatively amorphous and has high resistivity). To change state, this may be followed by the application of a subsequent rectangular lower current pulse, also at a voltage greater than the switching threshold, which programs the cell to a set state (the material is relatively crystalline and has low resistivity). The reset pulse has a higher magnitude of current than the set pulse so that the temperature of the phase change material is raised to T<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>, the amorphizing temperature, before the material is rapidly cooled down or quenched by the very sharp decrease in current at the trailing edge of the reset pulse, thereby leaving the material in the amorphous phase. To change into the crystalline phase, the material can be heated back up to an optimum temperature T<highlight><subscript>opt</subscript></highlight>, which is lower than T<highlight><subscript>m</subscript></highlight>, using a rectangular current pulse of smaller magnitude, and then rapidly cooled down again, this time leaving the material in the crystalline (low resistance) phase.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of part of a phase-change memory array featuring a cell current pulse having a slowly decaying trailing portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts a circuit schematic of circuitry that may be used to generate the slowly decaying cell current pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts a circuit schematic of another embodiment of circuitry used to generate the slowly decaying cell current pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a cell current pulse with a stepped, slowly decaying trailing portion obtained using the circuitry of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a flow diagram of a phase-change memory programming process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of an integrated circuit device having a phase-change material memory array, including waveshaping and driving circuitry that are designed to provide the voltage and current levels needed to program the constituent cells of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> depicts a block diagram of an embodiment of a portable application of a phase-change memory that incorporates the programming process.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to an embodiment of the invention, the conventional rectangular reset pulses that are applied to some of the cells in the phase-change memory array are modified such that their currents decrease at sufficiently low rates, so as to program those cells to another state. For instance, the decay during the trailing portion of such pulses can be slow enough to ensure that the phase-change materials in those cells spend the minimum required time interval at a specified temperature, so as to program those cells to the relatively crystalline phase. Such a modified reset pulse, having slow quench time, may permit faster programming of the entire memory array as a separate set pulse is not needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, what&apos;s shown is a block diagram of part of a phase-change memory array <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> featuring a cell current pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> having a slowly decaying trailing portion. The array <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> has a number of phase-change memory cells <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> each of which has a structural phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> to store data for that cell. Each cell may be accessed by a unique pair of bitlines <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and wordlines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> to apply the needed current pulses to each cell. The cells are arranged in a rectangular array in this embodiment, in which each cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is given an index (i,j) where i&equals;1 . . . N and j&equals;1 . . . M. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Each cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in the array <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> may be subjected to a current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> is rectangular, with rapid increasing and decreasing leading and trailing edges, respectively, as shown. The current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> has a rapidly increasing leading portion followed by a plateau of a given level for a given time interval, and then followed by a rapidly decreasing trailing portion. The current is decreased in the trailing portion at a sufficiently high rate that causes the material <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> in the corresponding cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to be quickly quenched and thereby cause the cell to be programmed to a reset state. The current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> may thus be an entirely conventional reset pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> also illustrates that some of the cells <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> in the array <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are subjected to a different current pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, where this pulse results in a slow quench time for the phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in the corresponding cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. One or more of the cells <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, such as the one with index (2,1), may be subjected to this current pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, at the same time. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the current pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> begins with a relatively low level <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and rapidly rises to an upper level <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. This rise may be effectuated by, for instance, the closing of a solid state switch which causes a rapid rise, or it may be implemented in a more controlled manner to rise more slowly. For faster programming, the rapid rise may be more desirable. This leading portion may be essentially identical to that of the conventional current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> that is applied to the cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> having index (1,1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Once the cell current of the pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> has been increased to the upper level <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, this upper level may be maintained for a predetermined time interval such as one that is sufficient to insure changing the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> into the relatively amorphous phase. This interval has the reference number <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In the trailing portion of the pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the current starts to decrease slowly during an interval <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> towards a lower level <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. This decrease is at a sufficiently low rate as to cause the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in the corresponding cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to program to the relatively crystalline phase. In contrast, the rapid decrease in the trailing edge of the conventional current pulse <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> causes the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> in the cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> having index (1,1) to program to the amorphous phase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The current need not be reduced all the way down to the lower level <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> during the interval <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, but rather may be decreased to an intermediate level <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> at the sufficiently low rate, prior to its rapid decrease down to the lower level <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> as shown in the figure. This may help shorten the total time interval of the pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> in situations where the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> has reached its desired phase by the end of the interval <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment of the pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the slope or decay rate <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> in the trailing portion is linear and as such may be entirely defined by specifying the upper level <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the intermediate level <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>, and the interval <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments, however, the decay rate <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> may be non linear for a variety of reasons, such as improved phase-change performance in the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> or lower cost of implementation using certain types of analog circuitry, as the case may be. In addition, the lower levels <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may be the same and equal to essentially zero current, although different and/or nonzero levels may also be applicable so long as they ensure that the state of the memory cell <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> does not change at those lower levels and power consumption requirements are met. In the embodiments described above, the cell is allowed to exhibit at least two states, a first state in which the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is relatively amorphous and a second state in which the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is relatively crystalline. These two may correspond to the conventional reset and set states, respectively, associated with a phase-change memory cell that can store one bit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, what is shown is a circuit schematic of waveshaping circuitry that can be used to generate a slowly decaying cell current pulse <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. This version of the circuitry is designed to cause a programming current I<highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>, enabled by current source <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> which is coupled to a supply node <highlight><bold>203</bold></highlight>, to be selectively passed through a volume of phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of a given cell, using a switching transistor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The transistor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is under control of a cell select signal so that when the cell has been selected, the transistor is turned on thereby providing a low impedance path between the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and the current source <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> which cause the current through the cell to increase rapidly to an upper level, such as I<highlight><subscript>p</subscript></highlight>. In this embodiment, the cell current I<highlight><subscript>cell </subscript></highlight>happens to pass through the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and is returned to the power supply via a return node <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> that may be at circuit ground/zero volts as illustrated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The circuitry in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> also has a number of current paths that are enabled by a number of switching transistors <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, . . . <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>_K, under control of signals C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, . . . CK. Each of these current paths may be defined by current sources <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, . . . <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>_K. It can be seen that by sequentially enabling these current paths, i.e. by turning on transistors <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> one at a time, the cell current I<highlight><subscript>cell </subscript></highlight>is decreased as some of the programming current I<highlight><subscript>p, </subscript></highlight>is progressively steered into the current paths. This in effect causes the cell current pulse <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to be stepped downwards as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> with each subsequent turning on of a transistor <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, until the cell current has reached an intermediate level <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> as shown. Although the step sizes of the decay rate <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> are shown to be equal, unequal step sizes may alternatively be used, corresponding to unequal current sources I<highlight><subscript>B1</subscript></highlight>, I<highlight><subscript>B2</subscript></highlight>, . . . . </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows another version of the waveshaping circuitry that can create the profile of the cell current pulse <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. In this version, the available programming current I<highlight><subscript>p </subscript></highlight>is sunk from a node to which the phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is connected. Once again, the switching transistor <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> allows the cell to be selected and enables the available programming current through the material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, while a number of bypass current paths are blocked via transistors <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, . . . <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>_K. These transistors are p-channel metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistors (MOSFETs) in contrast to n-channel transistors <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Similar to the version in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the cell current in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> can be progressively decreased by sequentially turning on transistors <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. In both versions of the circuitry shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference>, the control signals C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, . . . CK and cell select may be digital so as to allow for digital control of the decay rate of the cell current in response to, for instance, a digital code that represents the desired decay rate. One of ordinary skill in the art based on this disclosure will be able to design the needed circuitry, in a wide range of different implementations, to achieve the proper timing of the assertion of the control signals so that the pulse <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is generated with the desired levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> flow diagram of a phase-change memory programming process is depicted. This process essentially summarizes the technique described generally above in which operation <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> begins with increasing a number of currents through a number of corresponding cells (such as two or more) of the memory array, where each cell has a structural phase-change material to store data for that cell. Each of these currents is increased to an upper level that is sufficiently high to cause the corresponding cell to be in a first state. This first state may be the reset state in which the phase-change material is relatively amorphous and has relatively high resistivity. Next, operation <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> proceeds with decreasing some of the currents (at least one) to lower levels. These currents are decreased at sufficiently high rates that cause their corresponding cells to be programmed to the reset state. Some others (at least one) of the currents in the memory array are also decreased to the lower levels, however these others are decreased at sufficiently low rates that cause their corresponding cells to be programmed to the second state rather than programmed to the first state (operation <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>). As mentioned above, this second state may be the set state in which the phase-change material is relatively crystalline and has relatively low resistance. The technique thus allows, for instance, two different pulses to be created where each has the same leading portion but different trailing portions. One of the pulses is conventional in that it has a rapidly decreasing trailing portion, whereas the other pulse is modified to have a slowly decaying trailing portion, where the latter pulse will set its cell and the former pulse will reset its cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, what is shown is a block diagram of an integrated circuit phase-change material memory device <highlight><bold>602</bold></highlight>, including waveshaping circuitry <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> that is designed to provide the voltage and current levels needed to program the constituent cells of the device according to some of the embodiments described above. The device features an array of memory cells <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> where each cell <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> can be accessed by a unique pair of vertical conductors <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> (bitlines) and horizontal conductors <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> (wordlines). In this embodiment, the horizontal conductors allow a control signal from timing logic <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> to be provided to each cell to close or open a solid state switch therein. This solid state switch is in series with a volume of the phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> whose other terminal is connected to a power supply or power return node. Current is thus sourced or sunk, in this embodiment through the phase-change material <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, when the switch is closed. This cell current is provided only through the vertical conductors <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. In other embodiments (not shown), however, the cell current passes through both bitlines and wordlines. The sourcing or sinking of the cell current is performed by either the read circuitry <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight> or waveshaping circuitry <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight>, depending upon whether a write or read operation is being performed. The read circuitry <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight> may be entirely conventional and is not described any further here. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The waveshaping circuitry <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> may be designed according to the versions given in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> above, so as to provide the voltage and current levels that are needed to program the cells <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> according to the pulses <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> described above. Alternatively, the waveshaping circuitry can be implemented using conventional analog waveshaping circuits such as integrator/ramp circuits, exponential and logarithmic circuits, as well as others, to provide the non-stepped version of the cell current pulse <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The timing associated with the generation of the pulses may be determined by timing logic <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. In the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the timing logic <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> provides digital control signals to the waveshaping circuitry <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> and the read circuitry <highlight><bold>618</bold></highlight> so that the latter circuits either measure the resistance of the memory cell <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> (read operation) or provide the reset and set pulses at the correct timing and to the selected memory cell <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight>. Accesses to the cell <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> may be in random fashion where each cell can be accessed individually, or it may be orchestrated according to a row by row basis, depending upon the higher level requirements of the memory system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The memory device depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> may be built using a wide range of different fabrication processes, including a slightly modified version of a conventional complimentary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) logic fabrication process. The array of cells <highlight><bold>606</bold></highlight> and the timing logic <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> and waveshaping circuitry <highlight><bold>608</bold></highlight> may be formed in the same integrated circuit (IC) die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a block diagram of a portable application <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> of the phase-change memory programming process described above. A phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> is operated according to an embodiment of the programming process described above. The phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> may include one or more integrated circuit dies where each die has a memory array that is programmed according to the various embodiments of the programming techniques described above in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. These IC dies may be separate, stand alone memory devices that are arranged in modules such as conventional dynamic random access memory (DRAM) modules, or they may be integrated with other on-chip functionalities. In the latter embodiments, the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> may be part of an I/O processor or a microcontroller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The application <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> may be for instance a portable notebook computer, a digital still and/or video camera, a personal digital assistant, or a mobile (cellular) hand-held telephone unit. In all of these applications, an electronic system includes a processor <highlight><bold>710</bold></highlight> that uses the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> as program memory to store code and data for its execution. Alternatively, the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> may be used as a mass storage device for nonvolatile storage of code and data. The portable application <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> communicates with other devices, such as a personal computer or a network of computers via an I/O interface <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight>. This I/O interface <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight> may provide access to a computer peripheral bus, a high speed digital communication transmission line, or an antenna for unguided transmissions. Communications between the processor and the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> and between the processor and the I/O interface <highlight><bold>714</bold></highlight> may be accomplished using conventional computer bus architectures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The above-described components of the portable application <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> are powered by a battery <highlight><bold>718</bold></highlight> via a power supply bus <highlight><bold>716</bold></highlight>. Since the application <highlight><bold>704</bold></highlight> is normally battery powered, its functional components including the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> should be designed to provide the desired performance at low power consumption levels. In addition, due to the restricted size of portable applications, the various components shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> including the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> should provide a relatively high density of functionality. Of course, there are other non-portable applications for the phase-change memory <highlight><bold>708</bold></highlight> that are not shown. These include, for instance, large network servers or other computing devices which may benefit from a non-volatile memory device such as the phase-change memory. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> As an example, the phase-change material may be Ge2Sb2Te5. An exemplary pulse may have a peak current magnitude of Ireset, where Ireset is sufficiently high to allow the cells of the array to be programmed into the reset state. The exemplary pulse may also have a falling edge that decreases from Ireset to zero current in about 200 nsec. These specifics, however, are merely exemplary and the programming technique may work with a wide range of different phase-change materials and pulse shapes having relatively slow falling edges. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> To summarize, various embodiments of a technique for programming a phase-change memory with slow quench time, have been described. In the foregoing specification, the invention has been described with reference to specific exemplary embodiments thereof. It will, however, be evident that various modifications and changes may be made thereto without departing from the broader spirit and scope of the invention as set forth in the appended claims. The specification and drawings are, accordingly, to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for operating a memory array, comprising: 
<claim-text>increasing a plurality of currents through a plurality of corresponding cells of the memory array, each cell having a structural phase-change material to store data for that cell, each of the plurality of currents being increased to an upper level that is sufficiently high that can cause the material in the corresponding cell to be in a first phase; and then </claim-text>
<claim-text>decreasing some of the currents to lower levels, those currents being decreased at sufficiently high rates that cause the materials in their corresponding cells to be programmed to the first phase; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>decreasing some others of the currents to lower levels, those others being decreased at sufficiently low rates that cause the materials in their corresponding cells to be programmed to a second phase. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>after having increased the plurality of currents through the plurality of cells, maintaining the currents relatively constant at said upper levels for a predetermined time interval, prior to decreasing the currents. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein those others of the currents are decreased to intermediate levels at the sufficiently low rates, and then to the lower levels at relatively high rates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lower levels are equal to essentially zero current. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first phase is relatively amorphous and the second phase is relatively crystalline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of those others of the currents is decreased by sequentially enabling a plurality of current paths to progressively steer some of each into the current paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first phase is relatively amorphous and the second phase is relatively crystalline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit device comprising: 
<claim-text>a memory array having a plurality of cells, each cell having a structural phase-change material to store data for that cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>waveshaping and timing logic circuitry coupled to the memory array to (1) increase a plurality of currents through a plurality of corresponding cells of the array, each of the plurality of currents to be increased to an upper level that is sufficiently high that can cause the material in the corresponding cell to be in a first phase, and then (2) decrease some of the currents to lower levels, those currents to be decreased at sufficiently high rates that cause the materials in their corresponding cells to be programmed to the first phase, and (3) decrease some others of the currents to lower levels, those others to be decreased at sufficiently low rates that cause the materials in their corresponding cells to be programmed to a second phase. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the waveshaping and timing logic circuitry is to, after having increased the plurality of currents through the plurality of cells, maintain the currents relatively constant at said upper levels for a predetermined time interval, prior to decreasing the currents. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the waveshaping and timing logic circuitry is to decrease those others of the currents to intermediate levels at the sufficiently low rates, and then to the lower levels at relatively high rates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lower levels are equal to essentially zero current. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the waveshaping and timing logic circuitry is to decrease each of those others of the currents by sequentially enabling a plurality of current paths to progressively steer some of each into the current paths. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first phase is relatively amorphous and the second phase is relatively crystalline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the first phase is relatively amorphous and the second phase is relatively crystalline. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. An integrated circuit device comprising: 
<claim-text>means for storing data according to a first state and a second state; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for increasing a current through the storage means to an upper level that is sufficiently high that can cause the storage means to be in the first state, wherein the storage means programs to the first state if the current is decreased from the upper level to a lower level at a sufficiently high rate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for decreasing the current from the upper level to the lower level at a sufficiently low rate that can cause the storage means to be programmed to the second state. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising: 
<claim-text>means for maintaining the current relatively constant at the upper level for a predetermined time interval prior to decreasing the current at the sufficiently low rate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The integrated circuit device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the decreasing 
<claim-text>means is to decrease the current from the upper level to an intermediate level at the sufficiently low rate, and then to the lower level at a relatively high rate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002331A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
