<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004607A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004607A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004607</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896876</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>700</class>
<subclass>214000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for acquiring replacement products for a printing device or accessory</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sharon Ann</given-name>
<family-name>Whaley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boise</city>
<state>ID</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A printing system includes a staple sensor that senses a low staple condition in a stapling device. A low staple message is generated in response to sensing the low staple condition in the stapling device. The printing system identifies a computing device designated to manage the replacement of staples. The low staple message is then communicated to the identified computing device. The computing device contains an application capable of determining whether replacement staples are in stock and capable of ordering more staples if replacement staples are not in stock. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention relates to devices that handle print media, such as printers, copiers, and facsimile machines. More particularly, the invention relates to a method and system for ordering or requesting replacement products for a printing device or an accessory coupled to a printing device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Printer technology continues to advance, resulting in commercially available printers having faster speed, increased print quality, and improved features. A wide range of printers are commercially available, ranging from relatively inexpensive &ldquo;desktop&rdquo; models with few features to more expensive &ldquo;printing press&rdquo; models that have many features and expandable options. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Many printers offer specific features that are implemented within the printer or implemented by an accessory device that is attached to the input or output of the printer. One or more of these optional accessory devices may be connected serially to perform various functions, such as binding documents, stapling documents, hole-punching documents, or depositing a document into an appropriate mailbox. Additionally, one or more of these functions may be performed within the printer itself (e.g., a printer with a built-in stapling device). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Certain features implemented within a printer or in an accessory device attached to the printer require a refillable (or replaceable) product to perform their designated function. For example, a stapling device requires a supply of staples to staple sheets of media together. Similarly, a device that glues media together requires a supply of glue and a device that binds media along an edge of the media requires a supply of the necessary binding materials used to bind the media together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> If the refillable (or replaceable) product that is required to perform a particular function is depleted, the function cannot be performed. For example, if a staple cartridge that stores staples in a printer or accessory device is empty, sheets of media cannot be stapled together until the staple cartridge is replaced with a full cartridge or refilled with staples. To avoid this condition, it would be desirable to notify a user or administrator of the printer (or accessory device) that the staple cartridge (or other refillable product) is nearly empty, thereby allowing the staples or other product to be refilled or replaced prior to depletion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In some existing printers and accessories, no notification is provided prior to a product being depleted. In this situation, the user learns that the product is depleted when the print jobs are no longer processed using the product (e.g., print jobs are no longer stapled together). This lack of notification is wasteful if the print job must be repeated and frustrating to the user because the user must reprint the job or perform the desired function manually. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Other known printers and accessories display, for example, a &ldquo;low staple&rdquo; or &ldquo;staple out&rdquo; message on the printer&apos;s control panel. If a user doesn&apos;t notice the message on the control panel, the printer or accessory device may deplete its product and result in print jobs that are not processed as desired. Constantly checking the printer&apos;s control panel for such messages can be tedious and time-consuming, especially if users of the printer are located a significant distance from the printer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The embodiments described herein address these and other problems using an improved method and system for acquiring replacement products for a printing device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A printing system includes a staple sensor that monitors a supply of staples in a stapling device. If the supply of staples are running low, a low staple condition is detected by the staple sensors and a low staple message is generated and communicated to an appropriate application, such as a stock management application. The stock management application then determines whether replacement staples are in stock or whether an order for additional staples is required. If replacement staples are in stock, the stock management application generates a work order to have the printing system refilled with staples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a low staple condition is sensed in a stapling device. A low staple message is generated in response to sensing the low staple condition in the stapling device. A computing device designated to manage the replacement of staples is identified. The low staple message is communicated to the computing device. The computing device contains an application that determines whether replacement staples are in stock and is capable of ordering more staples if replacement staples are not in stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to one embodiment, the stapling device is located in a printer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the stapling device is located in an accessory device coupled to a printer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In a described embodiment, the low staple message identifies the type of staples used by the printing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In one implementation, the low staple message identifies the location of the printer.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The configuration methods and systems are illustrated by way of example and not limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings. The same numbers are used throughout the figures to reference like components and/or features. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates various portions of an exemplary printer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a media-handling system including an exemplary printer and a stapling device coupled to the printer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary printer with a built-in stapling device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an example environment in which the method and apparatus described herein may be implemented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating a procedure for detecting a low staple condition and acquiring replacement staples for a printer.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The embodiments described herein provide a method and system that handles the replacement of products (such as staples) in a printing device or an accessory coupled to a printing device. A staple sensor monitors a supply of staples in a stapling device. If the staples are running low, a low staple condition is detected by the system and a low staple message is generated and communicated to an appropriate device, such as a stock management device. The stock management device then determines whether replacement staples are in stock or whether an order for additional staples is required. Alternatively, the recipient of the low staple message may be presented with, for example, a link to a supplier&apos;s web site that allows a user to order replacement staples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram illustrating various portions of an exemplary printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. As used herein, a printer refers to any type of device that can generate an image (e.g., a letter, a picture, a drawing, etc.) on any type of print media, such as paper, cardstock, plastic, or fabric. Example devices include impact printers, non-impact printers, digital copiers, analog copiers, facsimile machines, press machines, silk screen machines, etc. Printers can produce images in any of a wide variety of conventional print media (paper, plastic, fabric, etc.). However, for ease of discussion, printers are discussed herein in the context of printing on paper. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and a pair of input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> also has at least one output device <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. During a printing operation, a sheet of paper is provided to print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> from one of the input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, or from a direct paper feed (e.g., an external direct-feed tray). As the sheet of paper passes through the print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the appropriate information is printed on the paper. The paper can be printed in any of a wide variety of conventional manners, such as a conventional laser printing process or a conventional inkjet printing process. After printing, the sheet of paper is output directly by print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to an output <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, such as an output bin (or output tray), or other device capable of outputting the sheet of paper from the printer. The output <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may be coupled to another device (not shown) that further processes the sheet of paper. This further processing is discussed in greater detail below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> represent a variety of print medium sources and pre-processing devices. Examples of input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> include: a device with one or more paper trays for supplying one or more sizes or types of paper to print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>; a pre-processing device to put a &ldquo;stamp&rdquo; on each sheet of paper prior to printing (such as physically adding a stamp to the sheet of paper or adding a graphical image or text to the information for each page); a paper separating device that separates fan-folded media into separate sheets or to cut a sheet of paper from a roll of paper; a device to affix another piece of paper to the sheet for printing (e.g., a Post-It&reg; Note); a hole punching device to punch hole(s) in each sheet of paper; or a scanning device, such as to obtain a serial number or other identifier from a sheet of paper to verify that pre-printed media is oriented correctly for printing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and output <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> can communicate with one another, transferring control information and data as necessary. Such communication may occur directly between two devices, or may be routed through print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes additional components, such as a print head or other mechanism for producing the data to be printed on the sheet of paper in print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> includes a processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and a memory/storage device <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> controls the transfer of paper through printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, including communication of information to the input devices <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, and the output device <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may also communicate information to other devices coupled to printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be any type of microprocessor or microcontroller capable of performing the operations necessary to control the operation of printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> may be replaced by an ASIC (application specific integrated circuit) or other customized device capable of controlling the printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Memory <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is a volatile and/or nonvolatile memory, such as a RAM (random access memory), a ROM (read only memory), a Flash EEPROM (electronically erasable programmable read only memory), or a magnetic or optical storage device. Memory <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> stores various information generated and/or used during the operation of the printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Although memory <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> is illustrated as being separate from processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, all or part of memory <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> may be incorporated into processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> also includes a web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, which may be stored in memory <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> or a separate storage device. Web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is executed by processor <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> or another processor (not shown) in printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> allows printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to communicate with other devices, such as other printers, computing devices, web servers, and the like. Printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be coupled to a network, thereby allowing other devices on the network to request information regarding the status of printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In an alternate embodiments, web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is not located in print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. For example, web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> may be part of a separate module in the printer that includes a processor and a memory or other storage device. Additional details regarding web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are provided below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A communication interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is coupled to the print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and allows the print engine to communicate with other devices, such as other printers, computers or other media processing devices (e.g., staplers, binders, or sorters) coupled to the printer <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In a particular embodiment, communication interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> includes a network interface that permits communication between print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and other devices coupled to a common network. Although the communication interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> as a separate component, in alternate embodiments, the communication interface <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is integrated into the print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. In a specific embodiment, two communication interfaces are provided in the printer. The first communication interface communicates with other printers and devices directly coupled to the printer. The other communication interface is a network interface that communicates via a network with other printers, computing devices, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a media-handling system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> including an exemplary printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and a stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> coupled to the printer. Although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> coupled to the printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, any type of accessory device that further processes one or more sheets of paper may also be coupled to the printer. Example accessory devices include a paper sorter; a paper folder; a hole punch; a gluing/binding device; a booklet maker to organize, fold, and bind the output as appropriate for a booklet; a device to stuff the paper into an envelope and optionally seal the envelope; a device to add job dividers such as covers or colored paper; a shrink wrap device to wrap the printed sheets; a device to add tabbed section dividers; a perforating device to perforate the printed sheets; a device to cut an arbitrary shape in the printed sheets; a laminator to laminate all or a part of a sheet (e.g., only the tabs); a mailbox device with different locations to receive printed sheets for different individuals; an embosser to emboss the printed sheets; a device to remove pieces of paper affixed to the sheet of paper for printing (e.g., Post-It&reg; Notes); a device to affix ink from a just-printed medium to transfer onto cloth (e.g., iron onto a t-shirt); or a shredder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> includes an input tray <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>, an output bin <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight>, and a print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. Print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> is similar to print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> discussed above with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Additionally, other input devices (not shown) may be coupled to or attached to printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. A paper path <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> in printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> shows the path of a sheet of paper through the printer to a printer output that is coupled to stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. Print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> communicates with stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to indicate whether a particular print job is to be stapled together. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> receives sheets of paper from printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> and passes the paper through a media stapler <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, which is capable of stapling together multiple sheets of paper or other media. Media stapler <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> either staples the sheets of a print job together or allows the sheets to pass without stapling, based on the instructions received from print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>. The sheets are output from media stapler <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> on paper path <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. The sheets are then deposited into an output bin <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> or provided to the output of stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. The output of stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> can be coupled to another accessory device (not shown) for further processing of the printed sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> includes at least one staple cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> that stores multiple staples used by media stapler <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Staple cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> represents one possible staple storage mechanism. Alternate embodiments may use any type of mechanism to store staples. A staple sensor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> in stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> senses the number of staples remaining in staple cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and/or senses when the staple cartridge is empty. Staple sensor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> communicates the staple supply information to print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> in printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>. Additionally, staple sensor <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may detect staple jams (also referred to as a staple misfeed) that prevents media stapler <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> from operating properly. A web application (e.g., web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) or other mechanism in print engine <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> may then communicate the printer&apos;s staple supply information to other devices. Although stapling device <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is shown adjacent to printer <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, other accessory devices (including other stapling devices) may be positioned above or below the printer. Additionally, any number of accessory devices can be coupled to the printer simultaneously. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates an exemplary printer <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> with a built-in stapling device. Printer <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes a print engine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, which is similar to print engine <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> discussed above with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Print engine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is coupled to a media stapler <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and a staple sensor <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. Staple sensor <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> is also coupled to a staple cartridge <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, which provides staples to media stapler <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. Print engine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> communicates with media stapler <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to indicate whether a particular print job is to be stapled together. Printer <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> also includes an output bin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As discussed above with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, staple cartridge <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> stores staples for use by media stapler <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>, which is capable of stapling various types of media. Staple sensor <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> senses the number of staples remaining in staple cartridge <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and/or senses when the cartridge is empty. Staple sensor <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> communicates the staple supply information to print engine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> or another processing device (not shown). Staple sensor <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may also detect staple jams that prevent the proper operation of media stapler <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. A web application (such as web application <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>) or other mechanism in print engine <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> then communicates the printer&apos;s staple supply information to other devices. After processing the print job, the print job may be deposited into an output bin <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of printer <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> or output from printer <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to another printer or accessory device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates an example environment <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> in which the method and apparatus described herein may be implemented. Printers <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> are coupled to a local area network (LAN) <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>, thereby allowing the printers to communicate with other devices coupled to the LAN. In this example, printers <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> have a built-in stapling device, such as the stapling device described above with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> is coupled to LAN <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> and a supplier server <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>. Computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> is used, for example, to manage an inventory of stock items (such as paper, staples, toner cartridges, pens, paper clips, and the like). Computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> includes a stock management application <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> and a web browser application <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight>. The stock management application <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> helps the user manage the inventory of stock items. The web browser application <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> allows the user of computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> to access various web pages (e.g., local web pages available through LAN <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>, and Internet web pages available through the Internet <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight>). Supplier server <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> may be a web server accessible via an internet connection <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight>, or a server that is accessible via a direct connection <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight>, such as a dial-up connection. Supplier server <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> is maintained by a supplier of stock items that are managed by stock management application <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. Thus, stock management application <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> may be used to order stock items from a supplier by communicating an order to supplier server <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> If printer <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> are running low on staples, the printer&apos;s print engine generates a low staple message and communicates that message to computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> across LAN <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight>. Computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> then takes the necessary action to have the staple supply replenished. As discussed below, this action may include requesting that someone refill the staples or ordering more staples if more staples are needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Although <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates two printers, one computer, and one supplier server, a particular environment <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may include any number of printers, any number of computers, and any number of supplier servers coupled together via any number of networks having any topology and using any communication protocol. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow diagram illustrating a procedure <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> for detecting a low staple condition and acquiring replacement staples for a printer. Initially, a staple sensor senses a low staple condition (block <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>). The printer containing the staple sensor (or the printer attached to a device containing the staple sensor) generates a low staple message and transmits the message to an appropriate device (block <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>). The low staple message may indicate the name of the printer or printer accessory that is low on staples, the location of the printer/printer accessory (e.g., printer <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>A&mdash;second floor, outside conference room <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>A), or the type of printer or type of staples required. The appropriate device may be a computer used by a system administrator or other user responsible for maintaining or managing printer operation. For example, the appropriate device may be computer <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, running a stock management application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The procedure <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> then determines whether the correct staples are in stock (block <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>). The correct staples can be identified based on the staple type included in the low staple message or based on the printer type (along with knowledge of staple types used by different printers). The current inventory can be checked, for example, using a stock management application <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>, discussed above. If the correct staples are in stock, the procedure generates a work order (or other work request) to refill staples in the printer. The work order is then provided to the appropriate person or group responsible for completing the work order. Alternatively, the operator of the stock management application may refill the staples themselves without generating a work order. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> If there are no replacement staples available, the procedure <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> continues to block <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight>, where the procedure displays an option to order staples (e.g., through a stock management application). If a user decides to order replacement staples, they may simply approve the purchase and the stock management application automatically places an order (block <highlight><bold>512</bold></highlight>) for the appropriate staples with a supplier (e.g., using supplier server <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>.) or the organization&apos;s purchasing department. Alternatively, the stock management application may collect multiple requests for stock supplies (e.g., staples, paper, and toner cartridges) and consolidate the multiple requests into a single order to the supplier. For example, the stock management application may consolidate all requests received during a day and send a single order to the supplier at the end of the day. Finally, at block <highlight><bold>514</bold></highlight>, a message is provided to the appropriate individuals and/or systems identifying the status of the need to replace staples (e.g., staples replaced, work order generated, or staples ordered). The appropriate individuals and/or systems may include a stock manager and a stock management application. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In an alternate embodiment, additional staples are ordered from a supplier before the inventory is depleted. For example, if fulfilling a request to refill staples will bring the inventory level for that type of staple below a threshold level, additional staples are ordered, even though there are already staples in stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a stock management application is not available for managing staples and other inventory items. In this embodiment, a low staple condition in a printer causes the generation of a low staple message that is sent to one or more designated users (i.e., the user&apos;s computer). The low staple message includes an &ldquo;order staples&rdquo; button (or link or similar indicator) which, when activated by the user, points the user&apos;s web browser application to a web site that allows the user to order the appropriate staples from one or more suppliers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Thus, a system and method for acquiring replacement products for a printing device is described herein. The described embodiments allow, for example, a printer to generate a low staple message in response to sensing a low staple condition. The message is communicated to a device responsible for managing the replacement and/or ordering of replacement staples for the printing device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Although the description above uses language that is specific to structural features and/or methodological acts, it is to be understood that the invention defined in the appended claims is not limited to the specific features or acts described. Rather, the specific features and acts are disclosed as examplary forms of implementing the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>sensing a low staple condition in a stapling device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a low staple message in response to sensing the low staple condition in the stapling device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying a computing device designated to manage the replacement of staples; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>communicating the low staple message to the computing device, wherein the computing device contains an application capable of determining whether replacement staples are in stock and capable of ordering more staples if replacement staples are not in stock. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stapling device is located in a printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stapling device is located in an accessory device coupled to a printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the low staple message identifies the type of staples used by the stapling device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the stapling device is located in a printing device and the low staple message identifies the location of the printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the computing device is a stock management system. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving a low staple message associated with a particular printing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether replacement staples are in stock for the particular printing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a work order to refill staples in the particular printing device if replacement staples are in stock; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>ordering more replacement staples if replacement staples are not in stock. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the low staple message identifies the type of staples used by the particular printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the low staple message identifies the type of printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the low staple message identifies the location of the printing device and wherein the work order includes the location of the printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein ordering more replacement staples includes consolidating a plurality of low staple notices into a single order for replacement staples. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising generating a message indicating a status of the staple replacement process. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising ordering more replacement staples if fulfilling the work order to refill staples will bring the inventory level for the staples below a threshold level. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method comprising: 
<claim-text>receiving a low staple message associated with a particular printing device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>presenting an option to order replacement staples for the particular printing device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the presented option if additional replacement staples are needed, wherein selecting the presented option causes a web browser application to navigate to a web page that allows a user to order replacement staples for the particular printing device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the presented option is a link to a staple supplier web page. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the low staple message identifies the type of staples used by the particular printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a sheet binding device configured to bind a plurality of media sheets together; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a binding sensor coupled to the sheet binding device, the binding sensor configured to detect when the sheet binding device requires additional materials; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a print engine coupled to the binding sensor, the print engine located in a printing device and configured to generate a low binding material message in response to detection that the sheet binding device requires additional materials by the binding sensor, the print engine further configured to communicate the low binding material message to a computing device that includes an application capable of determining whether replacement binding materials are in stock and capable of ordering more binding materials if replacement binding materials are not in stock. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the print engine includes a web application configured to communicate with other devices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sheet binding device and the binding sensor are located in a printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sheet binding device and the binding sensor are located in an accessory device coupled to a printing device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the print engine includes a processor and a memory. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An apparatus as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the sheet binding device is a stapling device.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004607A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
