<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001928A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001928A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001928</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10225702</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020821</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B41J002/05</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>347</class>
<subclass>063000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>021000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>347</class>
<subclass>064000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Fluid-jet printhead and mehod of fabricating a fluid-jet printhead</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10225702</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020821</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09772410</doc-number>
<document-date>20010129</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6457815</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Richard</given-name>
<middle-name>Todd</middle-name>
<family-name>Miller</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Corvallis</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Susanne</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kumpf</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Corvallis</city>
<state>OR</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Intellectual Property Administration</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P. O. Box 272400</address-1>
<city>Fort Collins</city>
<state>CO</state>
<postalcode>80527-2400</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A fluid-jet printhead has a substrate on which at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid is applied. The printhead includes an elevation layer disposed on the substrate and aligned with the fluid chamber. The printhead also includes a resistive layer disposed between the elevation layer and the substrate wherein the resistive layer has a smooth planer surface interfacing with the resistive layer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">THE FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to the manufacturer of printheads used in fluid-jet printers, and more specifically to a fluid-jet printhead used in a fluid-jet print cartridge having improved dimensional control and improved step coverage. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> One type of fluid-jet printing system uses a piezoelectric transducer to produce a pressure pulse that expels a droplet of fluid from a nozzle. A second type of fluid-jet printing system uses thermal energy to produce a vapor bubble in a fluid-filled chamber that expels a droplet of fluid. The second type is referred to as thermal fluid-jet or bubble jet printing systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Conventional thermal fluid-jet printers include a print cartridge in which small droplets of fluid are formed and ejected towards a printing medium. Such print cartridges include fluid-jet printheads with orifice structures having very small nozzles through which the fluid droplets are ejected. Adjacent to the nozzles inside the fluid-jet printhead are fluid chambers, where fluid is stored prior to ejection. Fluid is delivered to fluid chambers through fluid channels that are in fluid communication with a fluid supply. The fluid supply may be, for example, contained in a reservoir part of the print cartridge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Ejection of a fluid droplet, such as ink, through a nozzle may be accomplished by quickly heating a volume of fluid within the adjacent fluid chamber. The rapid expansion of fluid vapor forces a drop of fluid through the nozzle in the orifice structure. This process is commonly known as &ldquo;firing.&rdquo; The fluid in the chamber may be heated with a transducer, such as a resistor, that is disposed and aligned adjacent to the nozzle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In conventional thermal fluid-jet printhead devices, such as ink-jet cartridges, thin film resistors are used as heating elements. In such thin film devices, the resistive heating material is typically deposited on a thermally and electrically insulating substrate. A conductive layer is then deposited over the resistive material. The individual heater element (i.e., resistor) is dimensionally defined by conductive trace patterns that are lithographically formed through numerous steps including conventionally masking, ultraviolet exposure, and etching techniques on the conductive and resistive layers. More specifically, the critical width dimension of an individual resistor is controlled by a dry etch process. For example, an ion assisted plasma etch process is used to etch portions of the conductive and resistive layers not protected by a photoresist mask. The width of the remaining conductive thin film stack (of conductive and resistive layers) defines the final width of the resistor. The resistive width is defined as the width of the exposed resistive layer between the vertical walls of the conductive layer. Conversely, the critical length dimension of an individual resistor is controlled by a subsequent wet etch process. A wet etch process is used to produce a resistor having sloped walls on the conductive layer defining the resistor length. The sloped walls of the conductive layer permit step coverage of later fabricated layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As discussed above, conventional thermal fluid-jet printhead devices require both dry etch and wet etch processes. The dry etch process determines the width dimension of an individual resistor, while the wet etch process defines both the length dimension and the necessary sloped walls commencing from the individual resistor. As is well known in the art, each process requires numerous steps, thereby increasing both the time to manufacture a printhead device and the cost of manufacturing a printhead device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> One or more passivation and cavitation layers are fabricated in a stepped fashion over the conductive and resistive layers and then selectively removed to create a via for electrical connection of a second conductive layer to the conductive traces. The second conductive layer is pattered to define a discrete conductive path from each trace to an exposed bonding pad remote from the resistor. The bonding pad facilitates connection with electrical contacts on the print cartridge. Activation signals are provided from the printer to the resistor via the electrical contacts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Further, the wet etching process for defining the resistor length suffers from uniformity issues and can be highly dependent upon the chemistries used. The first conductive layer may be vulnerable to corrosion through pinholes and cracks in the passivation layers during subsequent wet etches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The printhead substructure is overlaid with at least one orifice layer. Preferably, the at least one orifice layer is etched to define the shape of the desired firing fluid chamber within the at least one orifice layer. The fluid chamber is situated above, and aligned with, the resistor. The at least one orifice layer is preferably formed with a polymer coating or optionally made of an fluid barrier layer and an orifice plate. Other methods of forming the orifice layer(s) are know to those skilled in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In direct drive thermal fluid-jet printer designs, the thin film device is selectively driven by electronics preferably integrated within the thermal electric integrated circuit part of the printhead substructure. The integrated circuit conducts electrical signals directly from the printer microprocessor to the resistor through conductive layers. The resistor increases in temperature and creates super-heated fluid bubbles for ejection of the fluid from the chamber through the nozzle. However, conventional thermal fluid-jet printhead devices can suffer from inconsistent and unreliable fluid drop sizes and inconsistent turn on energy required to fire a fluid droplet, if the resistor dimensions are not tightly controlled. Further, the stepped regions within the fluid chamber can affect drop trajectory and device reliability. The device reliability is affected by the bubble collapsing after the drop ejection thereby wearing down the stepped regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> It is desirous to fabricate a fluid-jet printhead capable of producing fluid droplets having consistent and reliable fluid drop sizes and less susceptible to corrosion. In addition, it is desirous to fabricate a fluid-jet printhead having a consistent turn on energy (TOE) required to fire a fluid droplet, thereby providing greater control of the size of the fluid drops. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A fluid-jet printhead has a substrate on which at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid is applied. The printhead includes an elevation layer disposed on the substrate and aligned with the fluid chamber. The printhead also includes a resistive layer disposed between the elevation layer and the substrate wherein the resistive layer has a smooth planer surface interfacing with the resistive layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides numerous advantages over conventional thin film printheads. First, the present invention provides a structure capable of firing a fluid droplet in a direction substantially perpendicular (normal or orthogonal) to a plane defined by the formed resistive element and ejection surface of the printhead. Second, the dimensions and planarity of the resistive material layer are more precisely controlled, which reduces the variation in the turn on energy required to fire a fluid droplet. Third, the size of a fluid droplet is better controlled due to less variation in resistor size. Fourth, the corrosion resistance and electro-migration resistance of the conductive layers are improved inherently by the design.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an enlarged, cross-sectional, partial view illustrating an exemplary conventional thin film printhead substructure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a flow chart of an exemplary process used to implement the conventional thin film printhead structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating a first embodiment of the invention&apos;s thin film printhead structure showing the resistor length dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating the first embodiment of the invention&apos;s thin film printhead structure showing the resistor width dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating a second embodiment of the invention&apos;s thin film printhead structure showing the resistor length dimension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flowchart of an exemplary process and optional steps used to implement several embodiments of the invention&apos;s thin-film printhead structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a printhead fabricated with the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an exemplary print cartridge that integrates and uses the printhead of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exemplary recoding device, a printer, which uses the print cartridge of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In the following detailed description of the preferred embodiments, reference is made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration specific embodiments in which the invention may be practiced. It is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and structural or logical changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention. The following detailed description, therefore, is not to be taken in a limiting sense, and the scope of the present invention is defined only by the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present invention is a fluid-jet printhead, a method of fabricating the fluid-jet printhead, and use of a fluid-jet printhead. The present invention provides numerous advantages over the conventional fluid-jet or ink-jet printheads. First, the present invention provides a structure capable of firing a fluid droplet in a direction substantially perpendicular (normal or orthogonal) to a plane defined by the formed resistive element and ejection surface of the printhead. Second, the dimensions and planarity of the resistive layer are more precisely controlled, which reduces the variation in the turn on energy required to fire a fluid droplet. Third, the size of a fluid droplet is better controlled due to less variation in resistor size. Fourth, the design inherently provides for improved corrosion resistance and improved electro-migration resistance of the conductive layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an enlarged, cross-sectional, partial view illustrating a conventional thin film printhead <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>. The thicknesses of the individual thin film layers are not drawn to scale and are drawn for illustrative purposes only. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, thin film printhead <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> has affixed to it a fluid barrier layer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, which is shaped along with orifice plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> to define fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to create an orifice layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>). Optionally, the orifice layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and fluid barrier layers <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> may be made of one or more layers of polymer material. Additionally, other methods of forming a fluid chamber and orifice opening are known to those skilled in the art and can be substituted without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention. A fluid droplet within a fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is rapidly heated and fired through nozzle <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> when the printhead is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Thin film printhead substructure <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> includes a substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, an insulating insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, a conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> (including conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B), a passivation layer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a cavitation layer <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and a fluid barrier structure <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> defining fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with orifice plate <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> As diagrammed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, an insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (also referred to as an insulative dielectric) is applied to substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> preferably by deposition. Silicon dioxides are examples of materials that are used to fabricate insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed from tetraethylorthosilicate (TEOS) oxide having a 14,000 Angstrom thickness. In an alternative embodiment, insulative layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fabricated from silicon dioxide. In another alternative embodiment, it is formed of silicon nitride. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> There are numerous ways to fabricate insulation layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, such as through a plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD) or a thermal oxide process. Insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> serves as both a thermal and electrical insulator for the resistive circuit that will be built on its surface. The thickness of the insulator layer can be adjusted to vary the heat transferring or isolating capabilities of the layer depending on a desired turn-on energy and firing frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Next in step <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is applied to uniformly cover the surface of insulation layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Preferably, the resistive layer is tantalum silicon nitride or tungsten silicon nitride of a 1200 Angstrom thickness although tantalum aluminum can also be used. Next in step <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is applied over the surface of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. In conventional structures, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is formed with preferably aluminum copper or alternatively with tantalum aluminum or aluminum gold. Additionally, a metal used to form conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> may also be doped or combined with materials such as copper, gold, or silicon or combinations thereof. A preferable thickness for the conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is 5000 Angstroms. Resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> can be fabricated though various techniques, such as through a physical vapor deposition (PVD). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, the conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is patterned with a photoresist mask to define the resistor&apos;s width dimension. Then in step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is etched to define conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. Fabrication of conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B define the critical length and width dimensions of the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the critical width dimension of the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is controlled by a dry etch process. For example, an ion assisted plasma etch process is used to vertically etch portions of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which are not protected by a photoresist mask, thereby defining a maximum resistor width as being equal to the width of conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. In step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the conductor layer is patterned with photoresist to define the resistor&apos;s length dimension defined as the distance between conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. In step <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the critical length dimension of the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is controlled by a wet etch process. A wet etch process is used since it is desirable to produce conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B having sloped walls, thereby defining the resistor length. The wet etch process used is chosen such that the etch is highly reactive to the conductive layer but minimally reactive to the resistive layer. Sloped walls of conductive layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A enables step coverage of later fabricated layers such as a passivation layer that is applied in step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B serve as the conductive traces that deliver a signal to the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for firing a fluid droplet. Thus, the conductive trace or path for an electrical signal impulse that heats the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is from conductor <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A through the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to conductor <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, passivation layer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is then applied uniformly over the device. There are numerous passivation layer designs incorporating various compositions. In one conventional embodiment, two passivation layers, rather than a single passivation layer are applied. In the conventional printhead example of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the two passivation layers comprise a layer of silicon nitride followed by a layer of silicon carbide. More specifically, the silicon nitride layer is deposited on conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and then a silicon carbide is preferably deposited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> After passivation layer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is deposited, cavitation barrier <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is applied. In the conventional example, the cavitation barrier comprises tantalum. A sputtering process, such as a physical vapor deposition (PVD) or other techniques known in the art deposits the tantalum. Fluid barrier layer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and orifice layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are then applied to the structure, thereby defining fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, fluid barrier layer <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is fabricated from a photosensitive polymer and orifice layer <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> is fabricated from plated metal or organic polymers. Fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is shown as a substantially rectangular or square configuration in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. However, it is understood that fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may include other geometric configurations without varying from the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Thin film printhead <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight>, shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, illustrates one example of a typical conventional printhead. However, printhead <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> requires both a wet and a dry etch process in order to define the functional length and width of the active region of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, as chamber as to create the sloped walls of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> necessary for adequate step coverage of the later fabricated layers, such as the passivation <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and cavitation <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> layers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating the layers for a fluid-jet printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> incorporating the present invention. The thicknesses of the individual thin film layers are not drawn to scale and are drawn for illustrative purposes only. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an enlarged, plan view illustrating a fluid-jet printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> incorporating the present invention. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, in step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, insulative layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fabricated by being deposited through any known means, such as a plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD), a low pressure chemical vapor deposition (LPCVD), an atmosphere pressure chemical vapor deposition (APCVD) or a thermal oxide process onto substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Preferably, insulator layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is formed with field oxide or optionally from tetraethylorthosilicate (TEOS) oxide. In one alternative embodiment, insulative layer <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is fabricated from silicon dioxide. In another embodiment, it is formed of silicon nitride. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, a dielectric material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is deposited onto the insulator layer. Preferably, the dielectric material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed of phosphosilicate glass (PSG). In an alternative embodiment, dielectric material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed from silicon nitride or TEOS. In an alternative embodiment dielectric material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is fabricated from silicon dioxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, before step <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, a polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is deposited on the insulator area in step <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. The purpose of the polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is to provide a step in height to elevate the subsequent conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in the area of the resistor to allow the conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> to make direct contact with the resistive layer without the need for vias. In step <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, the polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> patterned by an appropriate mask. In step <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, the polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is etched and any photomask remaining striped to leave an area of polysilicon between the substrate and the subsequent formation of a fluid chamber. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Alternatively as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>C, after step <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, in step <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> a capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for the conductive layer is deposited on the dielectric layer. In step <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, the capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is patterned preferably by photoresist. In step <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, the capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is etched to define an area between the resistor and the substrate. The capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is preferably formed of dielectric material, such as TEOS or PSG, silicon nitride, or silicon dioxide, to name a few. The capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> allows for maintaining the thin-film interfaces of the conventional art printhead shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. By maintaining the conventional thin-film interfaces, potential problems such as junction spiking and film interface reliability issues are reduced. Optionally, the capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can be used in place of the polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to provide the step in height elevation of a subsequently applied conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is then fabricated on top of previously deposited layers. In one embodiment, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is a layer formed through a physical vapor deposition (PVD) from aluminum and copper. More specifically, in one embodiment, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> includes up to approximately 2% percent copper in aluminum, preferably approximately 0.5 percent copper in aluminum. Utilizing a small percent of copper in aluminum limits electro-migration. In another preferred embodiment, conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is formed from titanium, copper, or tungsten. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, a photoimagable masking material such as a photoresist is deposited on portions of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, thereby exposing other portions of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. These masking and patterning steps are used to define the resistor length and conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B that is determined by the mask detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, the conductor layer is dry etched to create conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B and openings between the traces that define the resistor length. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>, a second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, such as TEOS or spin-on-glass (SOG) is applied on the conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, but preferably SOG. The second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is used to fill between the conductor traces as well as the resistor length gap. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is planarized preferably by using chemical mechanical polishing (CMP) to expose the elevated surface of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. In an alternative embodiment, the surface second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is planarized through use of a resist-etch-back (REB) process. By using the optional polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to elevate conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the amount of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> exposed during the planarization of the Second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is minimized. Further, only the segments of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> necessary for contact with the subsequently applied resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are exposed to the planarization process if an additional cap is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Optionally, in step <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> the second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is baked out to remove moisture that might have an adverse affect on the subsequently applied resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Next in step <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is applied to uniformly cover the surface of second insulating layer <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and the desired resistor area. Preferably, the resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is tantalum aluminum although tungsten silicon nitride or tantalum silicon nitride can also be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, a photoimagable masking material such as a photoresist mask is deposited on resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to define the resistor area, thereby exposing portions of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for removal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In step <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, the exposed portion of resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is removed through either a dry etch process several of which are known to those skilled in the art such as described in step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> or a wet etch process that is reactive to the resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. This etching step <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> defines and forms the resistor width. The photoresist mask is then removed, thereby exposing the resistor element. The passivation <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, cavitation <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, barrier <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and orifice <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> layers are then applied as described for the conventional printhead. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B provide an electrical connection/path between external circuitry and the formed resistive element. Therefore, conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B transmit energy to the formed resistor element to create heat capable of firing a fluid droplet positioned on a top surface of the formed resistive element in a direction perpendicular to the top surface of the formed resistive element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating the first embodiment of the invention&apos;s thin film printhead structure showing the resistor width dimension with respect to the thin-film layers applied to substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> using the process steps of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3A and 3B</cross-reference>, conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B define a resistor element between conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. Preferably, the formed resistive element has a length L equal to the distance between conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. Preferably, the formed resistive element has a width W as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</cross-reference> equal to the width of conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. However, it is understood that the formed resistive element may be fabricated having any one of a variety of configurations, shapes, or sizes, such as a thin trace or a wide trace of conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. The only requirement of the formed resistive element is that it contacts conductive traces <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B to ensure a proper electrical connection. While the actual length L of the formed resistive element is equal to or greater than the distance between the edges of conductor&apos;s <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B, the active portion of the formed resistive element which conducts heat to a droplet of fluid positioned above the formed resistive element corresponds to the distance between the edges of conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, partial view illustrating a second embodiment of the invention in which the capping layer <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is used to elevate the conductor layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> instead of the polysilicon layer <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, each orifice nozzle <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is in fluid communication with respective fluid chambers <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (shown enlarged in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) defined in printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Each fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is constructed in orifice structure <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> adjacent to thin film structure <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> that preferably includes a transistor coupled to the resistive component. The resistive component is selectively driven (heated) with sufficient electrical current to instantly vaporize some of the fluid in fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, thereby forcing a fluid droplet through nozzle <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Exemplary thermal fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The fluid-jet printhead device of the present invention is a portion of thermal fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Thermal fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes body <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>, flexible circuit <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> having circuit pads <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> having orifice nozzles <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Fluid is provided to fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> by the use of body <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> configured in fluid connection using a fluid delivery system <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>, shown as a sponge (preferably closed-cell foam), within fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> or by means of a remote storage source in fluid connection with fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. While flexible circuit <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, it is understood that other electrical circuits known in the art may be utilized in place of flexible circuit <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> without deviating from the present invention. It is only necessary that electrical contacts <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> be in electrical connection with the circuitry of fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> having orifice nozzles <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is attached to the body <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> and controlled for ejection of fluid droplets, typically by a printer but other recording devices such as plotters, and fax machines, to name a couple, can be used. Thermal fluid-jet print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> includes orifice nozzles <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> through which fluid is expelled in a controlled pattern during printing. Conductive drivelines for each resistor component are carried upon flexible circuit <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> mounted to the exterior of print cartridge body <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. Circuit contact pads <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> (shown enlarged in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> for illustration) at the ends of the resistor drive lines engage similar pads carried on a matching circuit attached to a printer (not shown). A signal for firing the transistor is generated by a microprocessor and associated drivers on the printer that apply the signal to the drivelines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exemplary recording device, a printer <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, which uses the exemplary print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. The print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is placed in a carriage mechanism <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight> to transport the print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> across a first direction of medium <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. A medium feed mechanism <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> transports the medium <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> in a second direction across printhead <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. An optional medium tray <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> is used to hold multiple sets of medium <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>. After the medium is recorded by print cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> using printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to eject fluid onto medium <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight>, the medium <highlight><bold>256</bold></highlight> is optionally placed on media tray <highlight><bold>258</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In operation, a droplet of fluid is positioned within fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Electrical current is supplied to the formed resistive element via conductors <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>B such that the formed resistive element rapidly generates energy in the form of heat. The heat from the formed resistive element is transferred to a droplet of fluid within fluid chamber <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> until the droplet of fluid is &ldquo;fired&rdquo; through nozzle <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. This process is repeated several times in order to produce a desired result. During this process, a single dye may be used, producing a single color design, or multiple dyes may be used, producing a multicolor design. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides numerous advantages over the conventional printhead. First, the resistor length of the present invention is defined by the placement of dielectric material <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> that is fabricated during a combined photo process and dry etching process. The accuracy of the present process is considerably more controllable than conventional wet etch processes. More particularly, the present process is more controllable in critical dimension control of the resistor than a conventional process. With the current generation of low drop weight, high-resolution printheads, resistor lengths have decreased from approximately 35 micrometers to less than approximately 10 micrometers. Thus, resistors size variations can significantly affect the performance of a printhead. Resistor size variations translate into drop weight and turn on energy variations across the resistor on a printhead. Thus, the improved length control of the resistive material layer yields a more consistent resistor size and resistance, which thereby improves the consistency in the drop weight of a fluid droplet and the turn on energy necessary to fire a fluid droplet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Second, the resistor structure of the present invention includes a completely flat top surface and does not have the step contour associated with conventional fabrication designs. A flat structure provides consistent bubble nucleation, better scavenging of the fluid chamber, and a flatter topology, thereby improving the adhesion and lamination of the barrier structure to the thin film. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Third, by introducing heat into the floor of the entire fluid chamber, fluid droplet ejection efficiency is improved. Additionally, the passivation and cavitation layers have reduced stress points during thermal cycling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Fourth, due to the encapsulation and cladding of conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by resistive layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, electro-migration of the conductive layer <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is minimized in the resistor area as well as increasing resistance to corrosion during thin-film processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Further, by attaching the printhead <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to the fluid cartridge <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the combination forms a convenient module that can be packaged for sale. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein for purposes of description of the preferred embodiment, it will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art that a wide variety of alternate and/or equivalent implementations calculated to achieve the same purposes may be substituted for the specific embodiments shown and described without departing from the scope of the present invention. Those with skill in the chemical, mechanical, electro-mechanical, electrical, and computer arts will readily appreciate that the present invention may be implemented in a very wide variety of embodiments. This application is intended to cover any adaptations or variations of the preferred embodiments discussed herein. Therefore, it is manifestly intended that this invention be limited only by the claims and the equivalents thereof.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An fluid-jet printhead having a substrate, comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a elevation layer disposed on the substrate and aligned with the fluid chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive layer having a smooth planar surface between the elevation layer and the fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a conductive layer disposed between said resistive layer and said substrate wherein a portion of said conductive layer is elevated by said elevation layer whereby said resistive layer and the elevated conductive layer are in direct contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the elevation layer is comprised of polysilicon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the elevation layer is comprised of a dielectric material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A fluid jet cartridge, comprising: 
<claim-text>the fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 1;</dependent-claim-reference> </claim-text>
<claim-text>a body for containing fluid; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid delivery system in fluidic connection with the fluid-jet printhead and the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A recording device, comprising: 
<claim-text>the fluid-jet cartridge of claim <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transport mechanism for moving a medium in a first and second direction across the fluid-jet printhead of the fluid-jet cartridge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A fluid-jet printhead including a substrate, comprising: 
<claim-text>an elevation layer disposed on the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric layer disposed on said elevated layer and substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a conductive layer disposed on said dielectric layer wherein a portion of the conductive layer is elevated with respect to the elevation layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an insulation layer disposed on and filling voids within the elevated conductive layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive layer disposed on the elevated conductive layer to form a planar resistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a passivation layer disposed on said planar resistor to form a planar passivation layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a cavitation layer disposed on said planar passivation layer to form a planar cavitation layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid, the fluid chamber disposed on said planar cavitation layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said planar resistor has a planar surface interfacing with said fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein electro-migration of the patterned conductive layer onto the planar passivation layer is minimized due to the resistive layer cladding the conductive layer by contacting the elevated conductive layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The fluid-jet printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said planar resistor is electrically attached to said patterned conductive layer without vias thru a dielectric material using the cladding surface contact. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A fluid-jet cartridge, comprising: 
<claim-text>the fluid-jet printhead of claim <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a body for containing fluid; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid delivery system in fluidic connection with the fluid-jet printhead and the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A recording device, comprising: 
<claim-text>the fluid-jet cartridge of claim <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transport mechanism for moving a medium in a first and second direction across the fluid-jet printhead of the fluid-jet cartridge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method for creating a planar resistor on a substrate surface, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>depositing a insulator layer on the substrate surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing an elevated layer on the insulator surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a first dielectric layer on the insulator layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a conductor layer on the first dielectric layer wherein a portion of the conductor layer is elevated over the elevated layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning the conductor layer to define a resistor area within a portion of the elevated conductor layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the patterned conductor layer to form a resistor area, having a resistor length dimension; </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a second dielectric layer to fill the resistor area and cover the patterned conductor layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>planarizing the second dielectric layer to expose the elevated conductor layer to form a planar resistor area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a resistive layer on the planar resistor area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>patterning the resistive layer to define a resistor width dimension; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>etching the resistive layer to form the resistor width. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method for creating a printhead, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>creating a planar resistor of claim <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying at least one layer defining a fluid chamber on the planar resistor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of depositing a planar passivation layer between the planar resistor and the fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of depositing a planar cavitation layer between the planar passivation layer and the fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A resistor for a fluid-jet printhead made with the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A printhead made with the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method for using the planar resistor created by the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>combining at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid on the planar resistor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>supplying fluid into the fluid chamber; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the planar resistor is capable of being activated to thereby heat the fluid and cause it to be ejected from the fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method of using the printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the steps of attaching the printhead to a fluid container having a fluid conduction path that makes fluidic contact with the fluid chamber. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method using the printhead of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of combining the attached printhead and fluid cartridge with a printing mechanism. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. A fluid-jet print cartridge, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid delivery system contained in the body; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a printhead mounted to the body and in fluid communication with the fluid delivery system, the printhead having a substrate including, 
<claim-text>at least one layer defining a fluid chamber for ejecting fluid, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a elevation layer disposed on the substrate and aligned with the fluid chamber, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a resistive layer having a smooth planar surface between the elevation layer and the fluid chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3C</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001928A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
