<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003435</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09815981</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010322</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C12Q001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12Q001/68</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/53</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/567</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12Q001/66</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12N015/87</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>004000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>006000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>007200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>008000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>455000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Methods for delivering nucleic acid molecules into cells and assessment thereof</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<family-name>DeJong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>North Vancouver</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Sandra</given-name>
<middle-name>Louise</middle-name>
<family-name>Vanderbyl</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Burnaby</city>
<country-code>CA</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>CHROMOS MOLECULAR SYSTEMS, INC.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>HELLER EHRMAN WHITE &amp; MCAULIFFE LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>4250 EXECUTIVE SQ</address-1>
<address-2>7TH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>LA JOLLA</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92037</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Methods for delivering nucleic acid molecules into cells and methods for measuring nucleic acid delivery into cells and the expression of the nucleic acids are provided. The methods are designed for introduction of large nucleic acid molecules, including artificial chromosomes, into cells, and are practiced in vitro and in vivo. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a divisional of U.S. application Ser. No. (attorney dkt. no. 24601-416), to de Jong et al., entitled &ldquo;METHODS FOR DELIVERING NUCLEIC ACID MOLECULES INTO CELLS AND ASSESSMENT THEREOF.&rdquo; The subject matter thereof is incorporated in its entirety by reference thereto.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to methods of delivering nucleic acid molecules into cells and methods for measuring nucleic acid delivery into cells and the expression of the nucleic acids therein. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> A number of methods of delivering nucleic acid molecules, particularly plasmid DNA and other small fragments of nucleic acid, into cells have been developed. These methods are not ideal for delivery of larger nucleic acid molecules. Thus, there is a need for methods of delivering nucleic acid molecules of increasing size and complexity, such as artificial chromosomes, into cells. Methods are required for use with in vitro and in vivo procedures such as gene therapy and for production of transgenic animals and pants. Furthermore, there is a need for the ability to rapidly and simply determine and assess the efficiency of delivery of DNA into cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Therefore it is an object herein to provide methods for delivering nucleic acid molecules, particularly larger molecules, including artificial chromosomes, into cells. Methods for assessing delivery are also provided. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Methods for delivery of large nucleic acid molecules into cells are provided. The methods, which can be used to deliver nucleic acid molecules of any size, are suitable for delivery of larger nucleic acid molecules, such as natural and artificial chromosomes and fragments thereof, into cells. The methods are designed for in vitro, ex vivo and in vivo delivery of nucleic acid molecules for applications, including, but limited to, delivery of nucleic acid molecules to cells for cell-based protein production, transgenic protein production and gene therapy. Methods of protein production in cells and in transgenic animals and plants, methods of introducing nucleic acid into cells to produce transgenic animals and plants, and methods for ex vivo and in vivo gene therapy are also provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Methods provided herein are designed for delivering a large nucleic acid molecule into a cell, but may also be used to deliver smaller molecules. The methods include the steps of exposing the nucleic acid molecule to a first delivery agent, typically an agent that increases contact between the nucleic acid molecule and the cell; and exposing the cell to a second delivery agent, which is generally different from the first agent, and is particularly an agent, such as energy, that enhances permeability of the cell. Selected delivery agents and combinations thereof are those that result in delivery of the nucleic acid the cell to a greater extent than in absence of the agent or in the presence of one of the agent alone. In all of these methods, if the permeability enhancing agent is energy, such as electroporation or sonoporation, the cell is contacted therewith in the absence of the nucleic acid molecule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Also provided are methods in which the cells are contacted with a lipid agent, particularly a dendrimer, such as SAINT-<highlight><bold>2&trade; (</bold></highlight>1-methyl-4-(1-octadec-9-enyl-nonadec-10-enylenyl) pyridinium chloride, also designated 1-methyl-4-(1 9-cis,cis-hepatritiaconta-9,28-dienyl) pyridinium chloride), simultaneously with or sequentially with application of energy. The nucleic acid, which is optionally, although preferably not treated with a delivery agent, is contacted with the so-treated cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The selected delivery methods vary depending on the target cells (cells into which nucleic acid is delivered), the nucleic acid molecules, and the type(s) of delivery agent(s) selected. Exemplary methods for delivery of large nucleic acid molecules into cells provided herein include, but are not limited to, methods involving any of the following: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> mixing the nucleic acid molecule with a delivery agent, such as a cationic lipid that neutralizes the charge of the nucleic acid, and contacting the cell with the mixture of nucleic acid and delivery agent; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> contacting a cell with the nucleic acid molecule, and then contacting the cell with a delivery agent or contacting a cell with a delivery agent then contacting the cell with the nucleic acid molecule; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> contacting a cell in the absence of the nucleic acid molecule with a delivery agent, applying ultrasound or electrical energy to the cell contacted with the delivery agent, and contacting the cell with the nucleic acid molecule upon the conclusion of the application of the energy; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> applying ultrasound or electrical energy to a cell, and contacting the cell, upon conclusion of the application of the energy, with a mixture of the nucleic acid molecule and a delivery agent; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> applying ultrasound or electrical energy to a cell, contacting the cell with a delivery agent upon conclusion of the application of the energy and contacting the cell previously contacted with the delivery agent with the nucleic acid molecule; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> applying ultrasound or electrical energy to a cell and contacting the cell with the nucleic acid molecule upon conclusion of the application of the energy; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> contacting a cell in the absence of the nucleic acid molecule with a delivery agent, applying ultrasound or electrical energy to the cell contacted with the delivery agent, and contacting the cell with a mixture of the nucleic acid and a delivery agent upon the conclusion of the application of the energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Although combinations of the above methods may be used, it has been found that any application of energy to the cells must be done prior to introduction of the nucleic acid molecule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The methods provided herein are intended for delivery of large nucleic acid molecules into cells in a variety of environments for a variety of purposes. For example, nucleic acid molecules greater than about 0.5, 0.6. 0.7, 0.8, 0.9, 1, 5, 10, 30, 50 and 100 megabase pairs may be delivered into cells using the methods provided herein. The methods may be used to deliver the large nucleic acid molecules into cells in vitro or in vivo. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In in vivo applications of the delivery methods, such as in in vivo gene therapy, large nucleic acid molecules may be delivered to cells directly in an animal subject, and in particular human subjects. Reagents can be administered locally or systemically (e.g., in the bloodstream) in the subject. For example, local administration of the nucleic acids, and/or delivery agents, may be into areas such as joints, the skin, tissues, tumors and organs. For systemic administration, the nucleic acid molecules may be targeted to cells or tissues of interest. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The delivery methods provided herein may also be used to deliver large nucleic acid molecules to a target cell in vitro which is then introduced into an animal subject, in particular human subjects, such as may be done, for example, in a method of ex vivo gene therapy. Thus, also provided herein are methods of in vivo and ex vivo gene therapy using the methods for delivering large nucleic acid molecules into cells as provided herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In particular embodiments of the methods in which a delivery agent is used, the delivery agent is a cationic compound. Cationic compounds include, but are not limited to, a cationic lipid, a cationic polymer, a mixture of cationic lipids, a mixture of cationic polymers, a mixture of a cationic lipid and a cationic polymer and a mixture of a cationic lipid and a neutral lipid, polycationic lipids, non-liposomal forming lipids, activated dendrimers, ethanolic cationic lipids, cationic amphiphiles and pyridinium chloride surfactants. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Included among the nucleic acid molecules that may be delivered into cells using the methods provided herein are artificial chromosomes, satellite DNA-based artificial chromosomes (SATACs, herein referred to as ACEs) and natural chromosomes or fragments of any of these chromosomes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The ultrasound energy can be applied as one continuous pulse or two or more intermittent pulses. The intermittent pulses of the ultrasound energy can be applied for substantially the same length of time, at substantially the same energy level or can vary in energy level, the length of time applied, or energy level and the length of time applied. Ultrasound energy ranges and number of pulses can vary, from methods provided herein, according to the instrument selected and can be empirically determined. Typically, ultrasound will be applied for about 30 seconds to about 5 minutes. The power used is a function of the sonorporator used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The effects of the ultrasound energy may be enhanced by con-tacting a cell (in vitro) or administering to a subject (in vivo) a cavitation compound prior to the application of ultrasound energy. Thus, the provided methods may include the use of such cavitation compounds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> When electric fields are employed in the methods provided herein, they are preferably applied to the cells in suspension for about 20 to 50 msec, but the timing and voltage is a function of the instrument used and the particular parameters. The electrical energy can be applied as one to five intermittent pulses. As noted, electrical field ranges and number of pulses can vary according to instrument specification and can be determined empirically. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Methods are provided for generating transgenic animals, particularly non-human transgenic animals, by delivering large nucleic acid molecules into animal cells, in particular non-human animal cells, using delivery methods provided herein, and exposing the animal cells into which the large nucleic acid molecules are delivered to conditions whereby a transgenic animal develops therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The methods for delivering large nucleic acid molecules into cells provided herein may also be used in methods of generating transplantable organs and tissues. Exemplary cells for use in methods of generating transgenic animals, particularly non-human transgenic animals, or transplantable organs include, but are not limited to, an embryonic stem cell, a nuclear transfer donor cell, a stem cell and a cell that is capable of the generation of a specific organ. The methods for delivering nucleic acid molecules into cells provided herein may also be used in methods of generating cellular protein production cell lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Further provided are methods for monitoring delivery of nucleic acids into a cell. These methods permit the rapid and accurate measurement of nucleic acid transfer into cells, thus allowing for screening and optimizing the use of various delivery agents and protocols for delivery of any nucleic acid into any cell type, in vitro, ex vivo or in vivo. Further provided are methods to monitor delivery and expression of nucleic acids in a cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In embodiments of the methods for monitoring delivery of nucleic acids into a cell, labeled nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, are delivered into the cell using the delivery agent(s) as described herein, or using any delivery method known to those of skill in the art. A detection method, such as flow cytometry, is then used to determine the number of cells containing the label as an indication of the ability of the delivery method to facilitate or effect delivery of the nucleic acid molecules. Other detection methods that may be used in place of or in addition to flow cytometry include, but are not limited to, fluorimetry, cell imaging, fluorescence spectroscopy and other such methods known to those of skill in the art for such detection and, as needed or desired, for quantitation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In an exemplary embodiment of the methods for monitoring and quantifying delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into cells, the nucleic acid molecule is an artificial chromosome labeled with a nucleoside or ribonucleoside analog, particularly a thymidine analog, such as iododeoxyuridine (IdU or IdUrd) and bromodeoxyuridine (BrdU), and the delivery agent is a cationic compound, which is used alone or in combination with energy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Because of the ease with which numbers of events are collected, the monitoring methods provided herein, particularly those based on flow cytometry techniques, provide a method for collection of nucleic acid molecule delivery data that is statistically superior to previous methods of evaluating nucleic acid molecules transfer. The positive values are instrument derived and therefore are not susceptible to judgement errors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The monitoring methods provided herein permit the rapid, simple and accurate detection of delivery of small numbers of nucleic acid molecules into cells. Such small numbers may be sufficient for purposes of transgenesis, gene therapy, cellular protein production and other goals of gene transfer. The monitoring methods also make it possible to rapidly quantify differences in delivery efficiencies of differing delivery methods and thus facilitate the development and optimization of methods for the delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> These methods can also be used to optimize transfection efficiencies into cells for which no delivery protocol has been established or which are not easily transfected. These methods also permit rapid screening of delivery protocols and agents for their ability to enhance or permit delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, of any size into a cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Methods are also provided that combine methods of monitoring nucleic acid molecule delivery with methods for monitoring expression of nucleic acid molecules. It is possible not only to assess the efficiency of delivery of nucleic acid molecules to cells, but also to monitor the subsequent expression of the delivered nucleic acid molecules in the same cell population. Thus, these methods also provide a method for the mapping of biological events between nucleic acid molecule delivery and early gene expression, using marker genes, such as, but are not limited to, fluorescent proteins, such as red, green or blue fluorescent proteins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In a particular embodiment of these combined methods, delivery and expression of nucleic acid molecules, such as delivery of a chromosome and expression of genes encoded thereon, are monitored by IdU labeling of a nucleic acid molecule that contains sequences encoding a green fluorescent protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In particular embodiments, the methods of monitoring delivery and expression of a nucleic acid molecule include the steps of: introducing labelled nucleic acid molecules that encode a reporter gene into cells; detecting labelled cells as an indication of delivery of the nucleic acid into a cell; and measuring the product of the reporter gene as an indication of DNA expression in the cell, whereby delivery and expression of nucleic acid molecules in the cell is detected or determined. The labelled cells can be detected, for example, by flow d, fluorimetry, cell imaging or fluorescence spectroscopy. The label, for example, can be iododeoxyuridine (IdU or IdUrd) or bromodeoxyuridine (BrdU), the reporter gene, for example, can be one that encodes fluorescent protein, enzyme, such as a luciferase, or antibody. The delivered nucleic acid molecules include, but are not limited to, RNA, including ribozymes, DNA, including naked DNA and chromosomes, plasmids, chromosome fragments, typically containing at least one gene or at least 1 Kb, naked DNA, or natural chromosomes. The method is exemplified herein by determining delivery and expression of artificial chromosome expression systems (Aces). Any types of cells, eukaryotic and prokaryotic, including cell lines, primary cell lines, plant cells, and animal cells, including stem cells, embryonic cells, and other cells into which delivery is contemplated. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A. DEFINITIONS </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Unless defined otherwise, all technical and scientific terms used herein have the same meaning as is commonly understood by one of skill in the art to which this invention belongs. All patents, patent applications and publications referred to herein are incorporated by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;nucleic acid&rdquo; refers to a polynucleotide containing at least two covalently linked nucleotide or nucleotide analog subunits. A nucleic acid can be a deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA), a ribonucleic acid (RNA), or an analog of DNA or RNA. Nucleotide analogs are commercially available and methods of preparing polynucleotides containing such nucleotide analogs are known (Lin et al. (1994) <highlight><italic>Nucl. Acids Res. </italic></highlight>22:5220-5234; Jellinek et al. (1995) <highlight><italic>Biochemistry </italic></highlight>34:11363-11372; Pagratis et al. (1997) <highlight><italic>Nature Biotechnol. </italic></highlight>15:68-73). The nucleic acid can be single-stranded, double-stranded, or a mixture thereof. For purposes herein, unless specified otherwise, the nucleic acid is double-stranded, or it is apparent from the context. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;nucleic acid&rdquo; refers to single-stranded and/or double-stranded polynucleotides, such as deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) and ribonucleic acid (RNA), as well as analogs or derivatives of either RNA or DNA. Also included in the term &ldquo;nucleic acid&rdquo; are analogs of nucleic acids such as peptide nucleic acid (PNA), phosphorothioate DNA, and other such analogs and derivatives. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> As used herein, DNA is meant to include all types and sizes of DNA molecules including cDNA, plasmids and DNA including modified nucleotides and nucleotide analogs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> As used herein, nucleotides include nucleoside mono-, di-, and triphosphates. Nucleotides also include modified nucleotides, such as, but are not limited to, phosphorothioate nucleotides and deazapurine nucleotides and other nucleotide analogs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> As used herein, the term &ldquo;large nucleic acid molecules&rdquo; or &ldquo;large nucleic acids&rdquo; refers to a nucleic acid molecule of at least about 0.5 megabase pairs (Mbase) in size, greater than 0.5 Mbase, including nucleic acid molecules at least about 0.6. 0.7, 0.8, 0.9, 1, 5, 10, 30, 50 and 100, 200, 300, 500 Mbase in size. Large nucleic acid molecules typically may be on the order of about 10 to about 450 or more Mbase, and may be of various sizes, such as, for example, from about 250 to about 400 Mbase, about 150 to about 200 Mbase, about 90 to about 120 Mbase, about 60 to about 100 Mbase and about 15 to 50 Mbase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Examples of large nucleic acid molecules include, but are not limited to, natural chromosomes and fragments thereof, especially mammalian chromosomes and fragments thereof which retain a centromere and telomeres, artificial chromosome expression systems (ACes; also called satellite DNA-based artificial chromosomes (SATACs); see U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,025,155 and 6,077,697), mammalian artificial chromosomes (MACs), plant artificial chromosomes, insect artificial chromosomes, avian artificial chromosomes and minichromosomes (see, e.g., U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,712,134, 5,891,691 and 5,288,625). The large nucleic acid molecules may include a single copy of a desired nucleic acid fragment encoding a particular nucleotide sequence, such as a gene of interest, or may carry multiple copies thereof or multiple genes or different heterologous sequences of nucleotides. For example, ACes can carry 40 or even more copies of a gene of interest. Large nucleic acid molecules may be associated with proteins, for example chromosomal proteins, that typically function to regulate gene expression and/or participate in determining overall structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> As used herein, an artificial chromosome is a nucleic acid molecule that can stably replicate and segregate alongside endogenous chromosomes in a cell. It has the capacity to act as a gene delivery vehicle by accommodating and expressing foreign genes contained therein. A mammalian artificial chromosome (MAC) refers to chromosomes that have an active mammalian centromere(s). Plant artificial chromosomes, insect artificial chromosomes and avian artificial chromosomes refer to chromosomes that include plant, insect and avian centromeres, respectively. A human artificial chromosome (HAC) refers to chromosomes that include human centromeres. For exemplary artificial chromosomes, see, e.g., U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,025,155; 6,077,697; 5,288,625; 5,712,134; 5,695,967; 5,869,294; 5,891,691 and 5,721,118 and published International PCT application Nos, WO 97/40183 and WO 98/08964. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> As used herein, the term &ldquo;satellite DNA-based artificial chromosome (SATAC)&rdquo; is interchangable with the term &ldquo;artificial chromosome expression system (ACes)&rdquo;. These artificial chromosomes are substantially all neutral non-coding sequences (heterochromatin) except for foreign heterologous, typically gene-encoding nucleic acid, that is interspersed within the heterochromatin for the expression therein (see U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,025,155 and 6,077,697 and International PCT application No. WO 97/40183). Foreign genes contained in these artificial chromosome expression systems can include, but are not limited to, nucleic acid that encodes traceable marker proteins (reporter genes), such as fluorescent proteins, such as green, blue or red fluorescent proteins (GFP, BFP and RFP, respectively), other reporter genes, such as &bgr;-galactosidase and proteins that confer drug resistance, such as a gene encoding hygromycin-resistance. Other examples of heterologous DNA include, but are not limited to, DNA that encodes therapeutically effective substances, such as anti-cancer agents, enzymes and hormones, and DNA that encodes other types of proteins, such as antibodies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As used herein, the terms &ldquo;heterologous&rdquo; and &ldquo;foreign&rdquo; with reference to nucleic acids, such as DNA and RNA, are used interchangeably and refer to nucleic acid that does not occur naturally as part of a genome or cell in which it is present or which is found in a location(s) and/or in amounts in a genome or cell that differ from the location(s) and/or amounts in which it occurs in nature. It is nucleic acid that is not endogenous to the cell and has been exogenously introduced into the cell. Examples of heterologous DNA include, but are not limited to, DNA that encodes a gene product or gene product(s) of interest introduced into cells, for example, for purposes of gene therapy, production of transgenic animals or for production of an encoded protein. Other examples of heterologous DNA include, but are not limited to, DNA that encodes traceable marker proteins, such as a protein that confers drug resistance, DNA that encodes therapeutically effective substances, such as anti-cancer agents, enzymes and hormones, and DNA that encodes other types of proteins, such as antibodies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;delivery,&rdquo; which is used interchangeably with &ldquo;transfection,&rdquo; refers to the process by which exogenous nucleic acid molecules are transferred into a cell such that they are located inside the cell. Delivery of nucleic acids is a distinct process from expression of nucleic acids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;expression&rdquo; refers to the process by which nucleic acid is translated into peptides or is transcribed into mRNA and translated into peptides, polypeptides or proteins. If the nucleic acid is derived from genomic DNA, expression may, if an appropriate eukaryotic host cell or organism is selected, include splicing of the mRNA. For heterologous nucleic acid to be expressed in a host cell, it must initially be delivered into the cell and then, once in the cell, ultimately reside in the nucleus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As used herein, cell recovery refers to a &ldquo;total cell yield&rdquo; after a specified time frame, which for purposes herein is twenty-four hours, and when used with reference to calculation of the clonal fraction </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As used herein, cell recovery time refers to a time frame in order for a cell to equilibrate to new conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> As used herein, cell survival refers to cell viability after a cytotoxic event, such as a delivery procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As used herein, control plating efficiency (CPE) refers to the fraction of untreated cells, under standard optimal growth conditions for the particular cells, that survive a plating procedure. Plating efficiency refers to the fraction of treated cells that survive a plating procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As used herein, clonal fraction is a measurement of cell recovery after delivery of exogenous nucleic acids into cells and the plating efficiency of the cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As used herein, transfer efficiency is the percentage of the total number of cells to which nucleic acids are delivered that contain delivered nucleic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As used herein, transfection efficiency is the percentage of the total number of cells to which nucleic acids including a selectable marker are delivered that survive selection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As used herein, index of potential transfection efficiency means the theoretical maximum transfection efficiency for a particular cell type under particular conditions, for example particular concentrations or amounts of particular delivery agents. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> As used herein, the term &ldquo;cell&rdquo; is meant to include cells of all types, of eukaryotes and prokaryotes, including animals and plants. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;delivery agent&rdquo; refers to compositions, conditions or physical treatments to which cells and/or nucleic acids may be exposed in the process of transferring nucleic acids to cells in order to facilitate nucleic acid delivery into cells. Delivery agents include compositions, conditions and physical treatments that enhance contact of nucleic acids with cells and/or increase the permeability of cells to nucleic acids. In all instances, nucleic acids are not directly treated with energy, such as sonoporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> As used herein, cationic compounds are compounds that have polar groups that are positively charged at or around physiological pH. These compounds facilitate delivery of nucleic acid molecules into cells, it is thought this is achieved by virtue of their ability to neutralize the electrical charge of nucleic acids. Exemplary cationic compounds include, but are not limited to, cationic lipids or cationic polymers or mixtures thereof, with or without neutral lipids, polycationic lipids, non-liposomal forming lipids, ethanolic cationic lipids and cationic amphiphiles. Contemplated cationic compounds also include activated dendrimers, which are spherical cationic polyamidoamine polymers with a defined spherical architecture of charged amino groups which branch from a central core and which can interact with the negatively charged phosphate groups of nucleic acids (e.g., starburst dendrimers). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Cationic compounds for use as delivery agents also include mixtures of cationic compounds that include peptides and protein fragments. The additional components may be non-covalently or covalently bound to the cationic compound or otherwise associated with the cationic compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> As used herein, ultrasound energy is meant to include sound waves (for external application) and lithotripter-generated shock waves (for internal application). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As used herein, electrical energy is meant to include the application of electric fields to cells so as to open pores in membranes for the delivery of molecules into the cell, e.g., electroporation techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> As used herein, cavitation compound is meant to include contrast agents that are typically used with ultrasound imaging devices and includes gas encapsulated and nongaseous agents. These cavitation compounds enhance the efficiency of energy delivery of acoustic or shock waves. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;pharmaceutically acceptable&rdquo; as used herein refers to compounds, compositions and dosage forms that are suitable for administration to the subject without causing excessive toxicity, irritation, allergic response or other undesirable complication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As used herein, embryonic stem cells are primitive, immature cells that are precursors to stem cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> As used herein, stem cells are primitive, immature cells that are precursors to mature, tissue specific cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> As used herein, nuclear transfer donor cells are cells that are the source of nuclei, which are transferred to enucleated oocytes during the process of nuclear transfer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As used herein, the term &ldquo;subject&rdquo; refers to animals, plants, insects, and birds into which the large DNA molecules may be introduced. Included are higher organisms, such as mammals and birds, including humans, primates, cattle, pigs, rabbits, goats, sheep, mice, rats, guinea pigs, cats, dogs, horses, chicken and others. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;administering to a subject&rdquo; is a procedure by which one or more delivery agents and/or large nucleic acid molecules, together or separately, are introduced into or applied onto a subject such that target cells which are present in the subject are eventually contacted with the agent and/or the large nucleic acid molecules. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> As used herein, &ldquo;applying to a subject&rdquo; is a procedure by which target cells present in the subject are eventually contacted with energy such as ultrasound or electrical energy. Application is by any process by which energy may be applied. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> As used herein, gene therapy involves the transfer or insertion of nucleic acid molecules, and, in particular, large nucleic acid molecules, into certain cells, which are also referred to as target cells, to produce specific gene products that are involved in correcting or modulating diseases or disorders. The nucleic acid is introduced into the selected target cells in a manner such that the nucleic acid is expressed and a product encoded thereby is produced. Alternatively, the nucleic acid may in some manner mediate expression of DNA that encodes a therapeutic product. This product may be a therapeutic compound, which is produced in therapeutically effective amounts or at a therapeutically useful time. It may also encode a product, such as a peptide or RNA, that in some manner mediates, directly or indirectly, expression of a therapeutic product. Expression of the nucleic acid by the target cells within an organism afflicted with a disease or disorder thereby providing a way to modulate the disease or disorder. The nucleic acid encoding the therapeutic product may be modified prior to introduction into the cells of the afflicted host in order to enhance or otherwise alter the product or expression thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> For use in gene therapy, cells can be transfected in vitro, followed by introduction of the transfected cells into the body of a subject. This is often referred to as ex vivo gene therapy. Alternatively, the cells can be transfected directly in vivo within the body of a subject. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As used herein, flow cytometry refers to processes that use a laser based instrument capable of analyzing and sorting out cells and or chromosomes based on size and fluorescence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> As used herein, a reporter gene includes any gene that expresses a detectable gene product, which may be RNA or protein. Preferred reporter genes are those that are readily detectable. Examples of reporter genes include, but are not limited to nucleic acid encoding a fluroescent protein, CAT (chloramphenicol acetyl transferase) (Alton and Vapnek (1979), <highlight><italic>Nature </italic></highlight>282: 864-869) luciferase, and other enzyme detection systems, such as beta-galactosidase; firefly luciferase (deWet et al. (1987), <highlight><italic>Mol. Cell. Biol. </italic></highlight>7: 725-737); bacterial luciferase (Engebrecht and Silverman (1984), <highlight><italic>PNAS </italic></highlight>1: 4154-4158; Baldwin et al. (1984), <highlight><italic>Biochemistry </italic></highlight>23: 3663-3667); and alkaline phosphatase (Toh et al. (1989) <highlight><italic>Eur. J. Biochem. </italic></highlight>182: 231-238, Hall et al. (1983) <highlight><italic>J. Mol. Appl. Gen. </italic></highlight>2: 101). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> As used herein, a reporter gene construct is a DNA molecule that includes a reporter gene operatively linked to a transcriptional control sequence. The transcriptional control sequences include the promoter and other optional regulatory regions, such as enhancer sequences, that modulate the activity of the promoter, or control sequences that modulate the activity or efficiency of the RNA polymerase that recognizes the promoter, or control sequences are recognized by effector molecules, including those that are specifically induced by interaction of an extracellular signal with a cell surface protein. For example, modulation of the activity of the promoter may be effected by altering the RNA polymerase binding to the promoter region, or, alternatively, by interfering with initiation of transcription or elongation of the mRNA. Such sequences are herein collectively referred to as transcriptional control elements or sequences. In addition, the construct may include sequences of nucleotides that alter translation of the resulting mRNA, thereby altering the amount of reporter gene product. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> As used herein, promoter refers to the region of DNA that is upstream with respect to the direction of transcription of the transcription initiation site. It includes the RNA polymerase binding and transcription imitation sites and any other regions, including, but not limited to repressor or activator protein binding sites, calcium or cAMP responsive sites, and any such sequences of nucleotides known to those of skill in the art to alter the amount of transcription from the promoter, either directly or indirectly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> As used herein, a promoter that is regulated or mediated by the activity of a cell surface protein is a promoter whose activity changes when a cell is exposed to a particular extracellular signal by virtue of the presence of cell surface proteins whose activities are affected by the extracellular protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> B. METHODS FOR THE DELIVERY OF DNA INTO CELLS </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> A variety of methods for delivering nucleic acids, particularly large nucleic acid molecules, such as artificial chromosomes, including ACes (formerly designated SATACs), are provided. The methods generally involve exposing the nucleic acid molecule to an agent that increases contact between the nucleic acid molecule and the cell, and exposing the cell to a permeability enhancing agent. Each of the methods provided herein requires the use of one or both of these agents, which are applied in different orders, with the caveat that agents, such as energy, which increase the permeability of a cell, must be applied before contacting the cell with a nucleic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In methods provided herein, large nucleic acid molecules are delivered using agents, including, but not limited to, delivery agents that enhance contact between the nucleic acid molecules and the cells and/or agents and treatments that increase cell permeability. Generally the nucleic acid molecules are delivered using agents that enhance contact between the nucleic acid and cells by neutralizing the charge of the nucleic acid molecules, and also by using energy to increase permeability of the cells. The agents may be used individually and in various combinations and orders of application, with the caveat that energy, such as sonoporation and electroporation cannot be applied to cells after the nucleic acid molecule is added thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The method selected for delivering particular nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to targeted cells can depend on the particular nucleic acid molecule being transferred and the particular recipient cell. Preferred methods for particular nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, and recipient cells are those that result in the greatest amount of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, transferred into the cell nucleus with an acceptable degree of cell survival. Suitable methods for delivery of particular pairings of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, and recipient cells may be determined using methods of monitoring nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, delivery and methods of screening agents and conditions as provided herein or may be determined empirically using methods known to those of skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The method selected requires consideration of a number of parameters, which are discussed in detail below. A method for detection of delivered nucleic acid is provided. This method, which can be used for assessing delivery of any nucleic acid molecule, can be used as a rapid screening tool to optimize chromosome transfer conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> In particular, delivery methods may first be assessed for the ability to transfer nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into cells and to identify methods that provide a sufficient number of viable cells that express the transferred nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA. Once such methods are identified, they may be optimized using the delivery monitoring methods provided herein and then assessed for the ability to provide for expression of the transferred nucleic acid molecules. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Delivery Agents </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Delivery agents include compositions, conditions and physical treatments that enhance contact of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, with cells and/or increase the permeability of cells to nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA. Such agents include, but are not limited to, cationic compounds, peptides, proteins, energy, for example ultrasound energy and electric fields, and cavitation compounds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Delivery agents for use in the methods provided herein include compositions, conditions or physical treatments to which cells and/or nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, may be exposed in the process of transferring nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to cells in order to facilitate nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, delivery into cells. For example, compounds and chemical compositions, including, but are not limited to, calcium phosphate, DMSO, glycerol, chloroquine, sodium butyrate, polybrene and DEAE-dextran, peptides, proteins, temperature, light, pH, radiation and pressure are all possible delivery agents. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Cationic Compounds </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Cationic compounds for use in the methods provided herein are available commercially or can be synthesized by those of skill in the art. Any cationic compound may used for delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into a particular cell type using the provided methods. One of skill in the art by using the provided screening procedures can readily determine which of the cationic compounds are best suited for delivery of specific nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into a specific target cell type. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">(a) Cationic Lipids </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> Cationic lipid reagents can be classified into two general categories based on the number of positive charges in the lipid headgroup; either a single positive charge or multiple positive charges, usually up to 5. Cationic lipids are often mixed with neutral lipids prior to use as delivery agents. Neutral lipids include, but are not limited to, lecithins; phospho-tidylethanolamine; phosphatidylethanolamines, such as DOPE (dioleoylphosphatidylethanolamine), DPPE (dipalmitoylphosphatidyl-ethanolamine), dipalmiteoylphosphatidylethanolamine, POPE (palmi-toyloleoylphosphatidylethanolamine) and distearoylphosphatidylethano-lamine; phosphotidylcholine; phosphatidylcholines, such as DOPC (dioleoylphosphidylcholine), DPPC (dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine) POPC (palmitoyloleoylphosphatidylcholine) and distearoylphosphatidylcholine; fatty acid esters; glycerol esters; sphingolipids; cardiolipin; cerebrosides; and ceramides; and mixtures thereof. Neutral lipids also include cholesterol and other 3&bgr;OH-sterols. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Other lipids contemplated herein, include: phosphatidylglycerol; phosphatidylglycerols, such as DOPG (dioleoylphosphatidylglycerol), DPPG (dipalmitoylphosphatidylglycerol), and distearoyl-phosphatidylglycerol; phosphatidylserine; phosphatidylserines, such as dioleoyl- or dipalmitoylphosphatidylserine and diphosphatidylglycerols. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Examples of cationic lipid compounds include, but are not limited to: Lipofectin (Life Technologies, Inc., Burlington, Ont.)(1:1 (w/w) formulation of the cationic lipid N-&lsqb;1-(2,3-dioleyloxy)propyl&rsqb;-N,N, N-trimethylammonium chloride (DOTMA) and dioleoylphosphatidylethanol-amine (DOPE)); LipofectAMINE (Life Technologies, Burlington, Ont., see U.S. Pat. No. 5,334,761) (3:1 (w/w) formulation of polycationic lipid 2, 3-dioleyloxy-N-&lsqb;2(spermine-carboxamido)ethyl&rsqb;-N,N-dimethyl-1-propanaminiumtrifluoroacetate (DOSPA) and dioleoyl phosphatidyl-ethanolamine (DOPE)), LipofectAMINE PLUS (Life Technologies, Burlington, Ont. see U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,334,761 and 5,736,392; see, also U.S. Pat. No. 6,051,429) (LipofectAmine and Plus reagent), LipofectAMINE 2000 (Life Technologies, Burlington, Ont.; see also International PCT application No. WO 00/27795) (Cationic lipid), Effectene (Qiagen, Inc., Mississauga, Ontario) (Non liposomal lipid formulation), Metafectene (Biontex, Munich, Germany) (Polycationic lipid), Eu-fectins (Promega Biosciences, Inc., San Luis Obispo, Calif.) (ethanolic cationic lipids numbers 1 through 12:C<highlight><subscript>52</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>106</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>178</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>40</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>84</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>P. CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>103</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>7</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>55</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>116</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.6CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>49</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>102</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>44</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>89</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>100</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>206</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.8CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>162</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>330</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>22</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>9</subscript></highlight>.13CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>41</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>78</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>P); Cytofectene (Bio-Rad, Hercules, Calif.) (mixture of a cationic lipid and a neutral lipid), GenePORTER (Gene Therapy Systems Inc., San Diego, Calif.) (formulation of a neutral lipid (Dope) and a cationic lipid) and FuGENE 6 (Roche Molecular Biochemicals, Indianapolis, Ind.) (Multi-component lipid based non-liposomal reagent). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">(b) Non-Lipid Cationic Compounds </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Non-lipid cationic reagents include, but are not limited to SUPERFECT&trade; (Qiagen, Inc., Mississauga, ON) (Activated dendrimer (cationic polymer:charged amino groups) and CLONfectin&trade; (Cationic amphiphile N-t-butyl-N&prime;-tetradecyl-3-tetradecyl-aminopropionamidine) (Clontech, Palo Alto, Calif.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Pyridinium amphiphiles are double-chained pyridinium compounds, which are essentially nontoxic toward cells and exhibit little cellular preference for the ability to transfect cells. Examples of a pyridinium amphiphiles are the pyridinium chloride surfactants such as SAINT-2 (1-methyl-4-(1-octadec-9-enyl-nonadec-10-enylenyl) pyridinium chloride) (see, e.g., van der Woude et al. (1997) <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>94:11 60). The pyridinium chloride surfactants are typically mixed with neutral helper lipid compounds, such as dioleoylphosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), in a 1:1 molar ratio. Other Saint derivatives of different chain lengths, state of saturation and head groups can be made by those of skill in the art and are within the scope of the present methods. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Energy </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Delivery agents also include treatment or exposure of the cell and/or nucleic acid molecules, but generally the cells, to sources of energy, such as sound and electrical energy. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Ultrasound </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> For in vitro and in vivo transfection, the ultrasound source should be capable of providing frequency and energy outputs suitable for promoting transfection. Preferably, the output device can generate ultrasound energy in the frequency range of 20 kHz to about 1 MHz. The power of the ultrasound energy is preferably in the range from about 0.05 w/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to 2 w/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, more preferably from about 0.1 w/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to about 1 w/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. The ultrasound can be administered in one continuous pulse or can be administered as two or more intermittent pulses, which can be the same or can vary in time and intensity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> Ultrasound energy can be applied to the body locally or ultrasound-based extracorporeal shock wave lithotripsy can be used for &ldquo;in-depth&rdquo; application. The ultrasound energy can be applied to the body of a subject using various ultrasound devices. In general, ultrasound can be administered by direct contact using standard or specially made ultrasound imaging probes or ultrasound needles with or without the use of other medical devices, such as scopes, catheters and surgical tools, or through ultrasound baths with the tissue or organ partially or completely surrounded by a fluid medium. The source of ultrasound can be external to the subject&apos;s body, such as an ultrasound probe applied to the subject&apos;s skin which projects the ultrasound into the subject&apos;s body, or internal, such as a catheter having an ultrasound transducer which is placed inside the subject&apos;s body. Suitable ultrasound systems are known (see, e.g., International PCT application No. WO 99/21584 and U.S. Pat. No. 5,676,151). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> When the cationic compound and nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, are administered systemically, the ultrasound can be applied to one or several organs or tissues simultaneously to promote nucleic acid molecule delivery to multiple areas of the subject&apos;s body. Alternatively, the ultrasound can be applied selectively to specific areas or tissues to promote selective uptake of the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> The transfection efficiency of the ultrasound can also be enhanced by using contrast reagents, which serve as artificial cavitation nuclei, such as Albunex (Molecular Biosystems, San Diego, Calif.), Imagent (Alliance Pharmaceutical, San Diego, Calif.), Levovist-SHU (Schering AG, Berlin, Germany), Definity (E.I. du Pont de Nemour, Wilmington, Del.), STUC (Washington University, St Louis, Mo.) and the introduction of gaseous microbubbles. A contrast reagent can be introduced locally, such as a joint; introduced systematically, with the enhancement of cavitation efficiency by focusing lithotripter shock waves at a defined area; or by targeting a contrast reagent to a particular site and then enhancing cavitation efficiency by focusing lithotripter shock waves. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Electroporation </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Electroporation temporarily opens up pores in a cell&apos;s outer membrane by use of pulsed rotating electric fields. Methods and apparatus used for electroporation in vitro and in vivo are well known (see, e.g., U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,027,488, 5,993,434, 5,944,710, 5,507,724, 5,501,662, 5,389,069, 5,318,515). Standard protocols may be employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> C. TARGET CELLS AND DELIVERY THERETO </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">In Vitro Delivery </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Cationic compounds and nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, can be added to cells in vitro either separately or mixed together and with or without the application of ultrasound or electrical energy, as long as the energy is applied prior to contacting the cells with the nucleic acid molecule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> In general nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, mixed with cationic lipids/compounds can be added to cell as described in the EXAMPLES. Parameters important for optimization of the delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into target cells will be apparent to those of skill in this art. These parameters include, for example, the cationic compound, cationic compound concentration, the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, the concentration of nucleic acid molecules, the cell growth medium, the cell culture conditions, the length of time cells are exposed to the cationic compound, the toxicity of the cationic compound to the target cell type, and the amount and time of use of ultrasound or electroporation among other parameters. It may be necessary to optimize these parameters for different nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, and target cell types. Such optimization is routine employing the guidance provided herein. In addition, the rapid screening method can provide direction as to what parameters may need to be adjusted to optimize delivery (see EXAMPLES). Alteration of culture conditions, time, reagent concentrations and other parameters, for use with different combinations of cationic compounds and target cell types and to optimize delivery, can be empirically determined. If ultrasound energy is required to be used to enhance transfection efficiency, it can be applied as described below and in the EXAMPLES. Electroporation can be performed as described below or by any suitable protocol known to those of skill in this art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> The contacting of cells with cationic compounds and nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, in separate and distinct steps can be generally carried out as described in the EXAMPLES. Those of skill in the art can readily vary the order of the application of the components to the target cell based on the disclosure herein. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Ex Vivo Gene Therapy </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> Delivery of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, is carried out as described above in in vitro delivery. After selection has been completed, cells harboring the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, are introduced into the subject target by a variety of means, including injection, such as subcutaneous, intramuscular, intraperitoneal, intravascular and intralymphatic injection. The cells can be administered with or without the aid of medical devices such as arthroscopes, other scopes or various types of catheters. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">In Vivo Gene Therapy </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> In one method for delivering of the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to target cells in the body of a subject in vivo, the cationic compound is first delivered to the target area (tissue, organ, tumor or joint). After waiting a suitable amount of time, the target area is then subjected to ultrasound frequency at a suitable energy level for a suitable time, which will be dependent on the equipment, tissue type and depth of the target area in the body. Alternatively, electrical energy is delivered to the target area. The nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, is then delivered to the same area. Optionally, this procedure can be repeated so that the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, can be delivered via multiple injections over time or multiple administrations in different areas at the same time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> The cationic compound mixed together with the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, can be delivered to the target area. The target area is then subjected to ultrasound frequency at a suitable energy level for a suitable time. Depending on the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, the in vivo location, the cationic compound used and other variables, it may not be necessary to use ultrasound or electroporation to achieve suitable transfer efficiency to cells at the target area. Prior to the application of ultrasound, contrast reagents can be delivered to the target area to enhance transfer of the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> The nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, can be delivered to organs or tissues of the body such as skin, muscle, stomach, intestine, lung, bladder, ovary, uterus, liver, kidney, pancreas, brain, heart, spleen, prostate and joints (for example the knee, elbow, shoulder, wrist, hip, finger, and others. Molecules can be delivered to primary cell lines, such as fibroblast, muscle, stomach, intestine, lung, bladder, ovary, uterus, liver, kidney, pancreas, brain, heart, spleen, prostate to mimic in vivo systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> The cationic compounds and the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, separately or together can be delivered to the target area of the body by a variety of means, including injection (for example, subcutaneous, intramuscular, intraperitoneal, intravascular and intralymphatic injection), instillation, cannulation, slow infusion, topical application and any other mode of administration. They can be administered by any suitable mode, including systemically (for example by intravenous injection), locally, such as by delivery to a specific target area (tissue or area), using, for example, a catheter or by direct injection. They can be administered with or without the aid of medical devices such as arthroscopes, other scopes or various types of catheters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> The cationic compounds can be administered also by coating a medical device, for example, a catheter, such as an angioplasty balloon catheter, with a cationic compound formulation. Coating may be achieved, for example, by dipping the medical device into a cationic lipid formulation or a mixture of a cationic compound formulation and a suitable solvent, for example, an aqueous-buffer, an aqueous solvent, ethanol, methylene chloride, chloroform and other suitable solvent. An amount of the formulation will naturally adhere to the surface of the device, which is subsequently administered to a subject, as appropriate. Alternatively, a lyophilized mixture of a cationic lipid formulation may be specifically bound to the surface of the device. Such binding techniques are known (see, e.g., Ishihara et al. (1993) <highlight><italic>Journal of Biomedical Materials Research </italic></highlight>27:1309-1314). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> The cationic compounds and nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, can be formulated in pharmaceutically acceptable carriers, such as saline or other pharmaceutically acceptable solutions, for delivery in vivo. The nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, and cationic compounds, regardless of the route of administration, are formulated into pharmaceutically acceptable dosage forms by standard methods known to those of skill in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> For gene therapy, the dosage level of the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, may be varied to achieve optimal therapeutic response for a particular subject. This depends on a variety of factors including mode of administration, activity of the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, characteristics of the protein produced, the transfection efficiency of the target cells (their ability to take up the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA), the route of administration, the location of the target cells and other factors </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The dosage to be administered and the particular mode of adminis-tration will vary depending upon such factors as the age, weight and the particular animal and region thereof to be treated, the particular nucleic acid molecule and cationic compound used, the therapeutic or diagnostic use contemplated, and the form of the formulation, for example, suspension, emulsion, or liposomal, as will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art. Typically, dosage is administered at lower levels and increased until the desirable therapeutic effect is achieved. The amount of cationic compound that is administered can vary and generally depends upon the amount of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, being administered. For example, the weight ratio of cationic compound to nucleic acid molecules is preferably from about 1:1 to about 15:1, with a weight ratio of about 5:1 to about 1:1 being more preferred. Generally, the amount of cationic compound which is administered will vary from between about 0.1 milligram (mg) to about 1 gram (g). By way of general guidance, typically for a bodyweight of 70 kg and a composition with about 1 to 10 million chromosomes per ml, single dose ranging from 1 to 20 ml is administered as a single or repeated dose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> For localized treatment of diseases, such administration to affected joints in rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis and diabetes should be possible, as well as injection into muscle for treatment of diseases, such as hemophilia or other genetic diseases. For other than local treatment a targeted delivery step is needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> D. ASSESSING THE DELIVERY OF NUCLEIC ACID INTO CELLS </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Microscopic and colony formation analysis methods that may be used in evaluating stable nucleic acid molecule delivery rely on manual visualization or measurement of nucleic acid molecules (e.g., a selectable marker gene) expression, which is a distinct process from delivery. Such methods are associated with time delays in obtaining an assessment of the delivery method. Microscopic techniques for visualizing chromosome or plasmid transfer using bromodeoxyuridine (BrdU) (see. e.g., Pittman et al. <highlight><italic>J Immunol Methods </italic></highlight>103:87-92 (1987)) are time consuming, restricted by the large sample size required to detect low levels of transfer and limited by the necessity of manual scoring. Colony-forming transfection analysis may require four-to-six weeks to generate and evaluate marker-expressing transfection colonies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> In contrast, methods provided herein are based on rapid, auto-mated, sensitive and accurate analysis procedures, such as flow cytometry, and thus do not involve any time-consuming, laborious and error-prone steps, such as manual detection of individual transfected cells by microscopic techniques. The methods make possible the analysis of nucleic acid molecule delivery data within 48 hours after transfection. Also, data collected by flow cytometry analysis is statistically superior due to the ease at which large numbers of events, e.g., nucleic acid molecule transfer, are collected. The positive values obtained in these methods are instrument derived and therefore not as susceptible to judgment errors. Thus, these methods provide for greater accuracy in assessing nucleic acid molecule delivery. In contrast, microscopic analysis is limited by the time involved for scoring positive events and sample size is restrictive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Because the methods of monitoring nucleic acid molecule delivery detect labeled nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, and not a reporter gene expression product, it is possible to measure absolute values of nucleic acid molecules transferred, within twenty-four hours, without being hindered by cell autofluorescence and by the problems of differentiating wild-type cells from cells expressing low levels of reporter gene products (see, e.g., Ropp et al. (1995) <highlight><italic>Cytometry </italic></highlight>21:309-317). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> 1. Factors to consider in addressing delivery of nucleic acids </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Delivery of nucleic acids, including DNA, into cells is a process in which nucleic acids are transferred to the interior of a cell. Methods for the delivery of nucleic acids may be assessed in a variety of ways, including the following. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">a. Transfer Efficiency </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> A delivery method may be assessed by determining the percentage of recipient cells in which the nucleic acids, including DNA, is present (i.e., the transfer efficiency). However, when evaluating a delivery method for the ultimate goal of generating cells that express the transferred nucleic acid, there are additional factors beyond mere presence of the nucleic acid in recipient cells that should be considered. Included among these additional factors is cell viability. When assessing a proliferating cell population, clonogenicity is the method of choice to measure viability. When the target cells population is non-dividing or slow growing, metabolic integrity can be monitored. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">b. Clonogenicity </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> Clonogenicity represents a measure of the survivability of cells with respect to a delivery procedure, growth conditions and cell manipulations (e.g., plating). It is important to assess clonogenicity to determine whether a delivery procedure results in a sufficient number of viable cells to achieve a desired number of cells containing the transferred nucleic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Clonogenicity may be expressed as a clonal fraction. The clonal fraction is an index that is calculated by multiplying two separate fractions and normalizing to a control plating efficiency correction factor (CPE). The two separate fractions that are multiplied in this calculation are the fraction of cells that survive a delivery procedure (population cell yield) and the fraction of cells that survive a plating procedure. The calculation is thus as follows:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>Colonal</mi>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mstyle>
      <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
    </mstyle>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mi>Fraction</mi>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <mfrac>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>#</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>viable</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>colonies</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>after</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>plating</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mrow>
        <mi>#</mi>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mi>cells</mi>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mi>plated</mi>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
    <mo>&times;</mo>
    <mfrac>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>#</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>cells</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>post</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>-</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>transfection</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
      <mtable>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>#</mi>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mstyle>
                <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
              </mstyle>
              <mo>&it;</mo>
              <mi>cells</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
        <mtr>
          <mtd>
            <mrow>
              <mi>transfected</mi>
              <mo>&times;</mo>
              <mi>CPE</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mtd>
        </mtr>
      </mtable>
    </mfrac>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="45.1332" file="US20030003435A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> The values used in this calculation for the number of cells post-transfection (i.e., post-delivery) and the number of colonies post-plating is based on cell or colony numbers at certain times in the process. For instance, the value for the number of cells post-transfection is representative of the number of cells at a time after nucleic acid delivery that is sufficient for the delivery process to be completed. This time may be determined empirically. Typically this time ranges from 4-48 hours and generally is about one day after transfection. Likewise, the value of the number of viable colonies post-plating is representative of the number of colonies at a time after nucleic acid delivery that is sufficient for the non-viable cells to be eliminated and the viable cells to be established as colonies. This time may be determined empirically. Typically this time ranges from that in which the average colony is made up of approximately 50 cells or generally is a time at which five cell cycles have passed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> A correction factor is included to take into account the plating efficiency of control wells, which is the ratio determined by the number of colonies counted divided by the number cells initially plated (typically 600-1000 cells). For LM(tk-) and V79-4 cells, the value of the correction factor typically ranges from about 0.7 to about 1.2 and may be, for example, 0.9. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> The number of cells plated should remain constant at 1000 (simplified plating efficiency assay) done in duplicate, except in the case where the CPE is below 0.3, then number of cells seeded should be increased to a range of 5,000-50,000. If the CPE is below 0.1-0.2, then a viable fraction analysis should be considered. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">c. Viable Fraction </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> If the target cells population is non-dividing or slowly dividing then reproductive or clonogenicity assays are not relevant. Less direct measurements of cell viability must be used to measure cell killing that monitor metabolic death rather than loss of reproductive capacity. These procedures include, for example: (1) membrane integrity as measured by dye exclusion, (2) inhibition of nucleic acid synthesis as measured by incorporation of nucleic acid precursors, (3) radioactive chromium release, and (4) MTT ASSAY (3-&lsqb;4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl&rsqb;-2,5-diphenyl-tetrazolium bromide). These methods are different from measurements of loss of proliferative capacity, as they reflect only immediate changes in metabolism, which can be reversed or delayed and hence lead to errors in estimation of cell viability. To minimize these errors, correlation of duplicate procedures is suggested. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">d. Potential Transfection Efficiency (PTE) and Determination of Chromos Index (CI) </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> In assessing a delivery method used to transfer nucleic acids to cells with the goal of expression of the nucleic acids, including DNA, therein, it is desirable to obtain an indication of the theoretical maximum percentage of cells that are viable and contain the nucleic acid out of the total number of cells into which nucleic acids were delivered. This is referred to as the potential transfection efficiency and may be calculated from existing or historical experimental data sets and is determined as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Potential Transfection Efficiency (PTE)&equals;Transfer Efficiency&times;(Clonal Fraction or Viable Fraction)&times;correction factor (CF)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> The Chromos Index (C.I.) is an effective and rapid method to determine the Potential Transfection Efficiency of a proliferating population by using experimental values of % labeled nucleic acid, such as ACes, delivery to measure transfer efficiency and clonal fraction measured using a simplified clonogenicity assay. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Chromos Index (CI)&equals;% labeled ACes delivery&times;estimated Clonal fraction&times;CF</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The values of the transfer efficiency and of the clonal fraction and viable fraction are calculated as described above. The correction factor (CF) takes into account sample size, sample time and control plating efficiency. If all these factors are constant for each variable i.e., sampling time and size then the correction factor will approach the inverse of the value for the C.P.E., i.e., such that the clonal fraction or transfer efficiency can still approach 100% even with a low CF, or in other words, if delivery and viability are 100%, then the maximum potential transfection efficiency will equal the plating efficiency of the control cells. The calculation of C.I. allows for determination of each variable optimization, with the goal being for parameters, such as transfer efficiency, clonal fraction, and CF to approach one (or 100%). If sample size or time varies for either clonal fraction or transfer efficiency, then CF represents the extrapolated value based on slope or rate of change. An application of this assessment is provided in the EXAMPLES. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> A stable transfection efficiency of about 1% is in the range (1-100%) that is considered useful for the introduction of large nucleic acid molecules into target cells. It is possible, using methods provided herein, to predict which delivery methods have to be selected for achieving desired transfection efficiencies without having to grow transfectants for extended times under selective conditions and determine numbers of cells surviving selection marker expression. This analysis involves calculation of the Chromos Index (CI) which integrates a &ldquo;biological&rdquo; value (the clonal fraction) with a measurement of chromosomal &ldquo;uptake&rdquo; or transfer efficiency (percentage of cells containing delivered ACes). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> 2. Labeling of nucleic acid molecules for transfer </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> In the methods for monitoring nucleic acid molecule delivery provided herein, the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to be delivered are labeled to allow for detection of the nucleic acid molecules in recipient cells after transfer into the cells. The nucleic acid molecules may be labeled by incorporation of nucleotide analogs. Any nucleic acid molecule analog that may be detected in a cell may be used in these methods. The analog is either directly detectable, such as by radioactivity, or may be detected upon binding of a detectable molecule to the analog that specifically recognizes the analog and distinguishes it from nucleotides that make up the endogenous nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, within a recipient cell. Analogs that are directly detectable have intrinsic properties that allow them to be detected using standard analytical methods. Analogs may also be detectable upon binding to a detectable molecule, such as a labeled antibody that binds specifically to the analogs. The label on the antibody is one that may be detected using standard analytical methods. For example, the antibody may be fluorescent and be detectable by flow cytometry or microscopy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> In particular embodiments of these methods, the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to be transferred is labeled with thymidine analogs, such as Iododeoxyuridine (IdUrd) or Bromodeoxyuridine (BrdU). In preferred embodiments, IdUrd is used to label the nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, to be transferred. The transferred IdUrd-labeled nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, may be immunologically tagged using an FITC-conjugated anti-BrdU/IdUrd antibody and quantified by flow cytometry. Thus, the transfer of the labeled nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, into recipient cells can be detected within hours after transfection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> E. STABILITY OF NUCLEIC ACID MOLECULES TO BE DELIVERED </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> It is also of interest to evaluate the stability of the nucleic acid molecule, such as DNA, under the selected delivery conditions. Some delivery conditions and agents may have adverse effects on nucleic acid molecule structure. Furthermore, the labeling techniques used in certain methods of monitoring nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, delivery may also impact nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, structure and function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> The effects of delivery conditions on nucleic acid molecules may be assessed in a variety of ways, including microscopic analysis. In a particular exemplary analysis of the stability of artificial chromosomes, e.g., ACes, the chromosomes are exposed to the conditions of interest, e.g., IdU labeling, and analyzed under a fluorescent microscope for the ability to remain intact and condensed after incorporation of nucleotide analogs. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Methods of Monitoring Nucleic Acid Molecule Delivery and Expression </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Methods of monitoring delivery of nucleic acid molecules delivery provided herein may also be combined with an assessment of nucleic acid molecule, such as DNA, expression in recipient cells to provide even further information concerning the overall process of nucleic acid molecule transfer for purposes of expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> For example, to facilitate analysis of nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, expression, it is desirable to include in the transferred nucleic acid molecules, such as DNA, a reporter gene that encodes a readily detected product. For direct detection, such reporter gene products include, but are not limited to green fluorescent proteins (GFP), Red Fluorescent protein (RFP), luciferases, and CAT. For indirect detection, reporter gene products include, but are not limited, to &bgr;-galactosidase and cell surface markers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> By using, for example, artificial chromosomes such as ACes containing a GFP reporter gene, such as, but are not limited to, GFP coding sequences in combination with labeling of the ACes with DNA analogs, such as IdU, delivery and expression can be rapidly and accurately monitored. For example, following the delivery of IdU-labeled GFP gene-containing ACes to target cells by any of the described methods, the cells containing the ACes are split into two populations. One population is fixed and stained for IdU and analyzed by flow cytometry to determine percentage delivery. The other population is allowed to go through 4-5 cell divisions (approximately 72 hours), and the GFP fluorescence is measured as an indication of expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> Such studies have revealed that incorporation of the analog label does not affect GFP protein expression, which indicates that the methods may be combined to monitor delivery and early expression of the ACes, thus providing more information to rapidly evaluate the efficiency of delivery methods. The combined methods can also be used to map the biological events between the initial stages of delivery and early gene expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> The following examples are included for illustrative purposes only and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of Artificial Chromosomes </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> A. GFP Chromosome contained in A9 cell line Plasmids </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Plasmid pIRES-EGFP (see SEQ ID No. 13, plasmid obtained from Clontech, Calif., and is well known, see, e.g., U.S. Pat. Nos. 6,034,228, 6,037,133, 5,985,577, 5,976,849, 5,965,396, 5,976,796, 5,843,884, 5,962,265, 5,965,396; see, also, U.S. Pat. No. 4,937,190). This plasmid contains the internal ribosome entry site (IRES; Jackson (1990) <highlight><italic>Trends Biochem. </italic></highlight>15:477-483; Jang et al. (1988) <highlight><italic>J. Virol. </italic></highlight>62:2636-2643) of the encephalomyocarditis virus (ECMV) between the MCS and the enhanced green fluorescent protein (EGFP) coding region. This permits the gene of interest (cloned into the MCS) and the EGFP gene to be translated from a single bicistronic mRNA transcript. Plasmid plRES2-EGFP is designed for selection, by flow cytometry and other methods, of transiently transfected mammalian cells that express EGFP and the protein of interest. This vector can also be used to express EGFP alone or to obtain stably transfected cell lines without drug and clonal selection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> Enhanced GFP (EGFP) is a mutant of GFP with a 35-fold increase in fluorescence. This variant has mutations of Ser to Thr at amino acid 65 and Phe to Leu at position 64 and is encoded by a gene with optimized human codons (see, e.g., U.S. Pat. No. 6,054,312). EGFP is a red-shifted variant of wild-type GFP (Yang et al. (1996) <highlight><italic>Nucl. Acids Res. </italic></highlight>24:4592-4593; Haas et al. (1996) <highlight><italic>Curr. Biol. </italic></highlight>6:315-324; Jackson et al. (1990) <highlight><italic>Trends Biochem. </italic></highlight>15:477-483) that has been optimized for brighter fluorescence and higher expression in mammalian cells (excitation maximum&equals;488 nm; emission maximum&equals;507 nm). EGFP encodes the GFPmut1 variant (Jackson (1990) <highlight><italic>Trends Biochem. </italic></highlight>15:477-483) which contains the double-amino-acid substitution of Phe-64 to Leu and Ser-65 to Thr. The coding sequence of the EGFP gene contains more than 190 silent base changes which correspond to human codon-usage preferences (Jang et al. (1988) <highlight><italic>J. Virol. </italic></highlight>62:2636-2643). Sequences flanking EGFP have been converted to a Kozak consensus translation initiation site (Huang et al. (1990) <highlight><italic>Nucleic Acids Res. </italic></highlight>18: 937-947) to further increase the translation efficiency in eukaryotic cells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Plasmid plRES-EGFP was dervied from PlRESneo (orignally called pCIN4) by replacing the neo gene downstream of the IRES sequence with the EGFP coding region. The IRES sequence permits translation of two open reading frames from one mRNA transcript. The expression cassette of pIRES-EGFP contains the human cytomegalovirus (CMV) major immediate early promoter/enhancer followed by a multiple clonging site (MCS), a synthetic intron (IVS; Huang et al. (1990) <highlight><italic>Nucleic Acids Res. </italic></highlight>18: 937-947), the EMCV IRES followed by the EGFP coding region and the polyadenylation signal of bovine growth hormone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> Location of Features (with reference to SEQ ID No. 13): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> Human cytomegalovirus (CMV) immediate early promoter: 232-820; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> MCS 909-974; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> IVS 974-1269; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> IRES of ECMV 1299-1884; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> Enhanced green fluorescent protein (EGFP) gene 1905-2621; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> fragment containing the bovine polyA signal 2636-2913; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> Col E1 origin of replication 3343-4016; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> Amplicillin resistance gene 5026-4168 </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Propagation in <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight></heading>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> Suitable host strains: DH5a, HB101, and other general purpose strains. Single-stranded DNA production requires a host containing an F plasmid such as JM101 or XL1-Blue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> Selectable marker: plasmid confers resistance to kanamycin (30 &mgr;g/ml) to <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>hosts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> <highlight><italic>E. coli </italic></highlight>replication origin: pUC </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> Copy number: &tilde;500 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> Plasmid incompatibility group: pMB1/ColE1 </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">pCHEGFP2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> Plasmid pCHEGFP2 was constructed by deletion of the Nsi1/Smal fragment from plRES-EGFP. Plasmid plRES-EGFP contains the coding sequence for a 2.1 kB Nru 1/Xho fragment of pCHEGFP2 containing the CMV promoter, synthetic intron, EGFP coding sequence and bovine growth hormone polyadenylation signal. Digestion of plRES-EGFP with Nru 1 and Sma 1, yielded a 2.1 kb fragment. Digested DNA was fractionated by agarose gel electrophoresis, the separated band was excised and then eluted from the gel using the Qiaex 11 gel purification system (Qiagen, Mississauga, Ontario). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">pFK161 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> Cosmid pFK161 was obtained from Dr. Gyula Hadlaczky and contains a 9 kb Notl insert derived from a murine rDNA repeat (see clone 161 described in PCT Application Publication No. WO97/40183 by Hadlaczky et al. for a description of this cosmid). This cosmid, referred to as clone 161 contains sequence corresponding to nucleotides 10,232-15,000 in SEQ ID NO. 16. It was produced by inserting fragments of the megachromosome (see, U.S. Pat. No. 6,077,697 and International PCT application No. (WO 97/40183); for example, H1D3, which was deposited at the European Collection of Animal Cell Culture (ECACC) under Accession No. 96040929, is a mouse-hamster hybrid cell line carrying this megachromosome) into plasmid pWE15 (Stratagene, La Jolla, Calif.) as follows. Half of a 100 &mgr;l low melting point agarose block (mega-plug) containing isolated SATACs was digested with Notl overnight at 37&deg; C. Plasmid pWE15 was similarly digested with Notl overnight. The mega-plug was then melted and mixed with the digested plasmid, ligation buffer and T4 ligase. Ligation was conducted at 16&deg; C. overnight. Bacterial DH5&agr; cells were transformed with the ligation product and transformed cells were plated onto LB/Amp plates. Fifteen to twenty colonies were grown on each plate for a total of 189 colonies. Plasmid DNA was isolated from colonies that survived growth on LB/Amp medium and was analyzed by Southern blot hybridization for the presence of DNA that hybridized to a pUC19 probe. This screening methodology assured that all clones, even clones lacking an insert but yet containing the pWE15 plasmid, would be detected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Liquid cultures of all 189 transformants were used to generate cosmid minipreps for analysis of restriction sites within the insert DNA. Six of the original 189 cosmid clones contained an insert. These clones were designated as follows: 28 (&tilde;9-kb insert), 30 (&tilde;9-kb insert), 60 (&tilde;4-kb insert), 113 (&tilde;9-kb insert), 157 (&tilde;9-kb insert) and 161 (&tilde;9-kb insert). Restriction enzyme analysis indicated that three of the clones (113, 157 and 161) contained the same insert. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> For sequence analysis the insert of cosmid clone no. 161 was subcloned as follows. To obtain the end fragments of the insert of clone no. 161, the clone was digested with Notl and BamHl and ligated with Notl/BamHl-digested pBluescript KS (Stratagene, La Jolla, Calif.). Two fragments of the insert of clone no. 161 were obtained: a 0.2-kb and a 0.7-kb insert fragment. To subclone the internal fragment of the insert of clone no. 161, the same digest was ligated with BamHl-digested pUC19. Three fragments of the insert of clone no. 161 were obtained: a 0.6-kb, a 1.8-kb and a 4.8-kb insert fragment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> The insert corresponds to an internal section of the mouse ribosomal RNA gene (rDNA) repeat unit between positions 7551-15670 as set forth in GENBANK accession no. X82564, which is provided as SEQ ID NO. 5. The sequence data obtained for the insert of clone no. 161 is set forth in SEQ ID NOS. 6-12. Specifically, the individual subclones corresponded to the following positions in GENBANK accession no. X82564 (i.e., SEQ ID NO. 5) and in SEQ ID NOs. 6-12:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Subclone</entry>
<entry>Start</entry>
<entry>End</entry>
<entry>Site</entry>
<entry>SEQ ID No.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="168PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>in X82564</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="126PT" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>161k1</entry>
<entry>7579</entry>
<entry>7755</entry>
<entry>NotI, BamHI</entry>
<entry>&ensp;6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>161m5</entry>
<entry>7756</entry>
<entry>8494</entry>
<entry>BamHI</entry>
<entry>&ensp;7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>161m7</entry>
<entry>8495</entry>
<entry>10231</entry>
<entry>BamHI</entry>
<entry>&ensp;8 (shows only sequence corresponding to</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>nt. 8495-8950),</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ensp;9 (shows only sequence corresponding to</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>nt. 9851-10231)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>161m12</entry>
<entry>10232</entry>
<entry>15000</entry>
<entry>BamHI</entry>
<entry>10 (shows only sequence corresponding</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>to nt. 10232-10600),</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>11 (shows only sequence corresponding</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>to nt. 14267-15000)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>161k2</entry>
<entry>15001</entry>
<entry>15676</entry>
<entry>NotI, BamHI</entry>
<entry>12</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> The sequence set forth in SEQ ID NOs. 6-12 diverges in some positions from the sequence presented in positions 7551-15670 of GENBANK accession no. X82564. Such divergence may be attributable to random mutations between repeat units of rDNA. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> For use herein, the rDNA insert from the clone was prepared by digesting the cosmid with Notl and Bgl/ll and was purified as described above. Growth and maintenance of bacterial stocks and purification of plasmids were performed using standard well known methods (see, e.g., Sambrook et al. (1989) <highlight><italic>Molecular Cloning: A Laboratory Manual, </italic></highlight>2nd Edition, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press), and plasmids were purified from bacterial cultures using Midi- and Maxi-preps Kits (Qiagen, Mississauga, Ontario). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> B. PREPARATION OF THE GFP, MURINE A9 CELL LINE </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Cell Culture and Transfection </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> The murine A9 cell line was obtained from ATCC and cells were thawed and maintained as described below. Briefly, cells were plated at a density of 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>cells per 15 cm tissue culture dish (Falcon, Becton Dickinson Labware, Franklin Lakes, N.J.) in growth medium containing of 90% DMEM (Canadian Life Technologies Burlington, ON) and 10% FBS (Can Sera, Rexdale ON), and were maintained at 37&deg; C., 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. Cultures were routinely passaged when cells reached 70%-80% confluence. Sub culturing was carried out as follows: medium was removed by aspiration, 10 ml of 1&times; trypsin-EDTA (Canadian Life Technologies Burlington, ON) was dispensed onto the cell monolayer and the dish gently swirled to distribute the trypsin-EDTA. Finally, the bulk of the trypsin-EDTA was removed by aspiration, and the dish placed at 37&deg; C. for 5 minutes. To quench the trypsin-EDTA, 10 ml of growth medium was added to the dish, and the single cell suspension was transferred to a 50 ml conical tube. Cell counts were performed using a cell counting apparatus (Beckman-Coulter, Hialeah Fla.). The cells were diluted and re-plated as described above. For cryo-storage, cultures were harvested by treatment with trypsin-EDTA, counted and the cell suspension then centrifuged at 500&times;g for 5 minutes in a swinging bucket centrifuge. The cell pellet was resuspended in freezing medium containing 90% DMEM, 20% FBS and 10% DMSO (Sigma-Aldrich, Oakville, ON) at a density of 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>7 </superscript></highlight>cells/ml. One ml aliquots of the cell suspension were then dispensed into cryo-vials (Nunc, Rochester N.Y.), frozen over night in an isopropanol filled container (NUNC, Rochester N..Y) and placed at &minus;70&deg; C. and then transferred to the gas phase of a liquid nitrogen freezer for long-term storage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> A9 cells were transfected using the Ca<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>co-precipitation method (see, e.g., Graham et al. (1978) <highlight><italic>Virology </italic></highlight>52:456-457; Wigler et al. (1979) <highlight><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. </italic></highlight>76:1373-1376; and (1990) <highlight><italic>Current Protocols in Molecular Biology</italic></highlight>, Vol. 1, Wiley Inter-Science, Supplement 14, Unit 9.1.1-9.1.9). One day prior to transfection, A9 cells were plated at a density of 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>cells per 10 cm dish and 3 hours before transfection the medium was replaced with fresh growth medium. 140 &mgr;g of the 9 kb rDNA, Notl and 5 &mgr;g of the 2.1 kB CMV-EGFP Xhol/Nrul fragments were mixed, co-precipitated and used to prepare the Ca<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>co-precipitate (Calcium Phosphate Transfection System, (Canadian Life Technologies Burlington, ON) which was distributed onto 2 10-cm dishes of subconfluent A9 cells. The DNA-Ca<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>PO<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>complexes were left on the cells for 18 hours, after which the precipitate was removed by aspiration and cells were subjected to glycerol shock for 1.5 minutes. After glycerol shock, the cell monolayers were gently washed with 2&times;10 ml of dPBS (Canadian Life Technologies Burlington, ON), followed by addition of 10 ml pre-warmed growth medium. Finally dishes were returned to the incubator and were maintained at 37&deg; C., 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. After 3 hours recovery, each dish was passaged onto 3&times;15 cm tissue dishes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> GFP fluorescence of cultures was monitored visually during culture using an inverted microscope equipped with epifluorescence illumination (Axiovert 25; Zeiss, (North York ON) and &num;41017 Endow GFP filter set (Chroma Technologies, Brattleboro, Vt.). Enrichment of GFP expressing populations was carried out as described below. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Enrichment of GFP Expressing Cell Populations by Fluorescence Activated Cell Sorting </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> Cell sorting was carried out using a FACS Vantage flow cytometer (Becton Dickinson Immunocytometry Systems, San Jose, Calif.) equipped with turbo-sort option and 2 Innova 306 lasers (Coherent, Palo Alto Calif.). For cell sorting a 70 &mgr;m nozzle was used. The sheath buffer was changed to PBS (maintained at 20 p.s.i.). GFP was excited with a 488 nm Laser beam and excitation detected in FL1 using a 500 EFLP filter. Forward and side scattering was adjusted to select for viable cells. Only viable cells were then analyzed for GFP fluorescence. Gating parameters were adjusted using wild type A9 cells as negative control and GFP CHO cells as positive control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> For the first round of sorting, A9 cells were harvested 4 days post-transfection, resuspended in 10 ml of growth medium and sorted for GFP expressing populations using parameters described above. GFP positive cells were dispensed into a volume of 5-10 ml of growth medium supplemented with 1&times; penicillin/streptomycin (Canadian Life Technologies Burlington, ON) while non-expressing cells were directed to waste. The expressing cells were further diluted to 50 ml using the same medium, plated onto 2&times;15 cm dishes and cultured as described in the previous section. When the sorted populations reached confluence they were re-sorted to enrich for GFP expressing cells. A total of 4 sequential sorts were carried out, achieving enrichments of as high as 89% GFP expressing cells after the final sort. The final GFP expressing populations were expanded for cryo-preservation and for fluorescence in-situ hybridization screening (see below). Single cell clones were established from populations of interest by using the flow cytometer to direct GFP expressing single cells to individual wells of 96 well plates. These were cultured as described above. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Fluorescence In-Situ Hybridization </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> Fluorescence In-Situ Hybridization (FISH) screening was carried out on GFP enriched populations and single cell clones to detect amplification and/or artificial chromosome formation. Preparation of metaphase spreads and hybridizations were performed (see, Telenius et al. (1999) <highlight><italic>Chromosome Res </italic></highlight>7:3-7). Probes used include pSAT 1, which recognizes the mouse major repeat (see, e.g., Wong et al. (1988) <highlight><italic>Nucl. Acids Res. </italic></highlight>16:11645-11661), pFK161, which hybridizes to the mouse rDNA-containing regions and a PCR generated probe against the mouse minor repeat. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> C. Purification of artificial chromosomes by Flow Cytometry and preparation of DNA from flow sorted chromosomes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> Artificial chromosomes were purified from the host cell by flow cytometry (see de Jong (1999) <highlight><italic>Cytometry </italic></highlight>35:129-133). Briefly, purification was performed on FACS Vantage flow cytometer (Becton Dickinson Immunocytometry Systems, San Jose, Calif.) equipped with a Trubo-Sort Option and two Innova 306 lasers (Coherent, Palo Alto, Calif.). The Turbo Sort Option modification include increasing the maximum system pressure from 20 lb/in<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to 60 lb/in<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, increasing the drop drive frequency from 50,000 drops/s to a maximum of 99,000 drops/s and increasing the deflection plate voltages from a maximum 6,000 V to 8,000 V. Other modifications are made to the instrument to accommodate the higher pressures. Hoechst 35258 was excited with the primary UV laser beam, and excitation detected in FL1 by using 420 nm hand-pass filter. Chromomycin A3 was excited by the second laser set at 458 nm and fluorescence detected in FL 4 by using a 475 nm long-pass filter. Both lasers had an output of 200 mW. Bivariate distributions (1,024&times;1024 channels) were accumulated during each sort. For all chromosome sorts, the sheath pressure was set at 30 lb/in<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and a 50 &mgr;m diameter nozzle was installed. A drop delay profile was performed every morning and repeated after any major plug. Alignment of the instrument was performed daily by using 3.0 &mgr;m diameter Sphero rainbow beads (Spherotech, Libertyville, Ill.). Alignment was considered optimized when a CV of 2.0% or less was achieved for FL1 and FL4. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> Condensing agents (hexylene glycol, spermine and spermidine) were added to the sheath buffer to maintain condensed chromosomes after sorting. The sheath buffer contains 15 nM Tris HCl, 0.1 mM EDTA, 20 mM NaCl, 1% hexylene glycol, 100 mM glycine, 20 &mgr;M spermine and 50 &mgr;M spermidine. The sorted chromosomes were collected in 1.5 ml screw-capped Eppendorf tubes at 4&deg; C. at a concentration of approximately 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>chromosomes/ml, which were then stored at 4&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> For preparation of purified genomic DNA, sorted chromosome samples were brought to 0.5% SDS, 50 mm EDTA and 100 &mgr;g/ml Proteinase K, then incubated for 18 hours at 50&deg; C. 1 &mgr;l of a 20 mg/ml glycogen solution (Boehringer Mannheim) was added to each sample, followed by extraction with an equal volume of Phenol: Chloroform: Isoamyl Alcohol (25:24:1). After centrifugation at 21,000 Xg for 10 min, the aqueous phases were transferred to fresh microfuge tubes and were re-extracted as above. 0.2 volumes of 10 M NH<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>OAC, 1 &mgr;l of 20 mg/ml glycogen and 1 volume of iso-propanol were added to the twice extracted aqueous phases which were then vortexed and centrifuged for 15 minutes at 30,000&times;g (at room temperautre). Pellets were washed with 200 &mgr;l of 70% ethanol and re-centrifuged as above. The washed pellets were air-dried then resuspended in 5mM Tris-Cl, pH 8.0 at 0.5-2&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>chromosome equivalents/&mgr;l. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> PCR was carried out on DNA prepared from sorted chromosome samples essentially as described (see, Co et al. (2000) <highlight><italic>Chromosome Research </italic></highlight>8:183-191) using primers sets specific for EGFP and RAPSYN. Briefly, 50 &mgr;l PCR reactions were carried out on genomic DNA equivalent to 10,000 or 1000 chromosomes in a solution containing 10 mM Tris-CI, pH 8.3, 50 mM KCI, 200 &mgr;M dNTPs, 500 nM of forward and reverse primers, 1.5 mM MgCl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, 1.25 units Taq polymerase (Ampli-Taq, Perkin-Elmer Cetus, Calif.). Separate reactions were carried out for each primer set. The reaction conditions were as follows: one cycle of 10 min. at 95&deg; C., then 35 cycles of 1 min. 94&deg; C., 1 min. 55&deg; C., 1 min 72&deg; C., and finally one cycle of 10 min at 72&deg; C. After completion the samples were held at 4&deg; C. until analyzed by agarose gel electrophoresis using the following primers (SEQ ID Nos. 1-4, respectively): </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> EGFP forward primer 5&prime;-cgtccaggagcgcaccatcttctt-3&prime;; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> EGFP reverse primer 3&prime;-atcgcgcttctcgttggggtcttt-3&prime;; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> RAPSYN forward primer 5&prime;-aggactgggtggcttccaactcccagacac-3&prime;; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> RAPSYN reverse primer 5&prime;-agcttctcattgctgcgcgccaggttcagg-3&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> All primers were obtained from Canadian Life Technologies, Burlington, ON. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of Cationic Vesicles </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> Vesicles were prepared at a lipid concentration of 700 nmoles/ml lipid (cationic lipid/DOPE 1:1) as follows. In a glass tube (10 ml) 350 nmoles cationic lipid (SAINT-2) was mixed with 350 nmoles dioleyl-phosphoethanolamine (DOPE), both solubilized in an organic solvent (Chloroform, Methanol or Chloroform/Methanol 1:1, v/v). Diphosphatidyl-ethanolamine (DOPE; Avanti Polar Lipids, Alabaster, Ala.) forms inverse hexagonal phases in a membrane and weakens the membrane. Other effectors that may be used are cis-unsaturated phosphoethanolamines, cis-unsaturated fatty acids, cholesterol. Cis-unsaturated phosphatidylcholines are less effective. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> The solvent was evaporated under a stream of nitrogen (15 min/250 &mgr;l solvent at room temperature). The remaining solvent was removed totally by drying the lipid for 15 min in an desiccator under high vacuum from a vacuum pump. To the dried mixture was added 1 ml ultrapure water. This was vortexed vigorously for about 5 min. The resulting solution was sonicated in an ultrasonication bath (Laboratory Supplies Inc. N.Y.) until a clear solution was obtained. The resulting suspension contained a population of unilamellar vesicles with a size distribution between 50 to 100 nm. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of Cationic Vesicles via Alcoholic Injection </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> In a glass tube (10 ml) 350 nmoles cationic lipid (Saint-2) was mixed with 350 nmoles DOPE, both solubilized in an organic solvent (chloroform, methanol or chloroform/methanol 1/1). The solvent was evaporated under a stream of nitrogen (15 min/250 &mgr;l solvent at room temperature). The remaining solvent was removed totally by drying the lipid for 15 min under high vacuum. This was then reconstituted in 100 &mgr;l pure ethanol. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Transfection of Beta ACes into V79-4 Cell Line </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Transfection Procedure for Various Transfection Agents </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> All compounds were tested in a Chinese Hamster lung fibroblast line (V79-4, ATCC number CCL-39). Approximately 17 hours (2 cell doublings) prior to transfection, exponentially growing cells were trypsinized and plated at 250,000 cells per well into a 6 well petri dish with Dulbecco&apos;s Modified Eagle Medium (Life Technologies, Burlington, ON) and supplemented with 10% FBS (Can Sera, Rexdale ON)). At the time of transfection, the number of cells per well was estimated to be approximately 1 million. For transfection, each individual manufacturer&apos;s protocol for complexing to naked DNA was followed, with the exception that the amount of transfection agent used was varied, to reflect the different amount and type of DNA present, as well as the different ionic strength of the complexing. One million ACes (in a volume of 800 &mgr;l) were typically combined with the transfection agent in a wide range of concentrations (between 5 times and 100 times the lowest manufacturers suggested concentration). The ACes/transfection mixture was allowed to complex for the time recommended by the manufacturer, in volumes ranging from 0.8 ml to 1.9 ml; some manufacturers recommend adding media to the complexing reaction. The complexed mixture was then applied to the recipient cells and transfection allowed to proceed according to the manufacturer&apos;s protocol. Details on the various conditions used with different agents are presented in Table 1. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Transfection Procedure for Superfect Agent </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> Superfect was tested in a Chinese Hamster lung fibroblast line (V79-4, ATCC number CCL-39). Approximately 17 hours (2 cell doublings) prior to transfection, exponentially growing cells were trypsinized and plated at 250,000 cells per well into a 6 well petri dish with Dulbecco&apos;s Modified Eagle Medium (Life Technologies, Burlington, ON) and supplemented with 10% FBS (Can Sera, Rexdale ON). One million ACes in 800 &mgr;l of sort buffer was complexed to 10 &mgr;l of Superfect reagent. Complex was incubated at room temperature for 10 minutes. At the time of transfection, the number of cells per well was estimated to be approximately 1 million. Media was removed from wells and 600 &mgr;l of DMEM and 10% FBS was added. Superfect:ACes complex was added to the wells drop-wise and allowed to incubate for 3 hours at 37&deg; C. After incubation, transfected cells were trypsinized and transferred to 15 cm dishes with 25 ml DMEM and 10% FBS and allowed to attach for 24 hours. After 24 hours, selection medium containing of 0.7 mg/ml hygromycin B was added to each well. The selection medium was changed every 2-3 days. After 10-12 days colonies were screened for Beta-galactosidase expression and/or FISHed for detection of intact chromosome. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example of Application of the Determination of the Chromos Index </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0187" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0187&rsqb;</number> Approximately 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>V79-4 cells were transfected with 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>IdUrd-labeled ACes complexed with a delivery agent (i.e., Lipofectamine PLUS and Lipofectamine or Superfect). The transfected cells were then fixed in ethanol. Fixed cells were denatured and exposed to FITC-conjugated antibody that specifically binds to BrdU/IdUrd-labeled nucleic acids. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0188" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0188&rsqb;</number> The percentage of transfected cells containing IdUrd-labeled ACes was determined using flow cytometry and collecting FITC fluorescence. Data were accumulated to form bivariate channel distribution showing forward scatter versus green fluorescence (IdUrd-FITC). The fluorescence level at which cells were determined to be positive was established by visual inspection of the histogram of negative control cells such that the gate for the negative cells was set such that 1% appeared in the positive region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0189" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0189&rsqb;</number> The number of cells recovered at 24 hours post-transfection was determined by counting an aliquot using a Coulter Counter. To determine the control plating efficiency of a recipient cell line, the untreated cells were plated at 600-1000 cells per 10 cm petri dish in growth medium and left stationary in a 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>incubator at 37&deg; C. for approximately five cell cycles or until average colony was made up of 50 cells. At this point the number of viable colonies was determined. The treated cells were seeded at 1000 cells if the CPE is above 0.1-0.2. If the CPE is low then the seeding density is increased to 5,000-50,000 cells per dish. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Ultrasound Mediated Transfection of LMTK(-) Cells with Lipofectamine </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0190" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0190&rsqb;</number> LM(tk-) cells were grown at 37&deg; C., 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, in DMEM with 4500 mg/L D-glucose, L-glutamine, pyridoxine hydrochloride and 10% Fetal Bovine Serum. The corner wells of a 12-well dish were seeded with 200,000 cells per well (this is to ensure no interference from the ultrasound waves from other wells) 24 hours before use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0191" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0191&rsqb;</number> The GFP chromosomes were counted to verify approximately 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>ACes per ml. The chromosomes were resuspended in the tube by flicking. Ten &mgr;l of chromosome suspension was removed and mixed with an equal volume of 30 mg/ml PI (propidium iodide) stain. Eight &mgr;l of the stained chromosomes was loaded onto a Petroff Hausser counting chamber and the chromosomes were counted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0192" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0192&rsqb;</number> The medium was removed from the cells, and the cells were washed twice with HBSS (without phenol red, Gibco BRL) warmed to 37&deg; C. 500 &mgr;l of the warmed HBSS was added to each well of cells (1 &mgr;l) LipofectAMINE (Gibco BRL) was added to each well. The plates were then sealed with parafilm tape and shaken gently at 20 rpm at room temperature for 30 minutes (Stagger plates&mdash;10 minutes for ease of handling). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0193" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0193&rsqb;</number> After incubation Ultrasound gel (Other-Sonic Generic Ultra sound transmission gel, Pharmaceutical Innovations, Inc., Newark, N.J.) was applied to the 2.5 cm sonoporator head. Ultrasound was applied with an ImaRX Sonoporator 100 at an output energy of 2.0 Watt/cm2, for 60 seconds, through the bottom of the plate of cells. After ultrasound of the well one chromosome per seeded cell (2&times;10<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight>) or 200 &mgr;l GFP ACes in sheath buffer (15 nM Tris HCl, 0.1 mM EDTA, 20 mM NaCl, 1% hexylene glycol, 100 mM glycine, 20 &mgr;M spermine and 50 &mgr;M spermidine) are added immediately to the well. (Repeat until all samples on the plate requiring ultrasound have been treated). The plate was then sealed once more with parafilm tape and shaken gently (20 rpm) for 1 hour at room temperature. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0194" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0194&rsqb;</number> After the incubation 1 ml (DMEM with 4500 mg/L D-glucose, L-glutamine and pyridoxine hydrochloride, 10% Fetal Bovine Serum, and a 1&times; solution of penicillin and streptomycin from a 10000 units/ml penicillin and 10000 mg/ml Streptomycin, 100&times; stock solution) was added to each well and the cells were incubated 18-24 hours at 37&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0195" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0195&rsqb;</number> The cells in the plates were then washed with antibiotic containing medium and 2 ml of medium was placed in each well. The cells continued to be incubated at 37&deg; C. with 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>until 48 hours after transfection/sonoporation. The cells were then trypsinised and resuspended at a concentration of 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>in DMEM to be analyzed by flow cytometry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0196" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0196&rsqb;</number> Results: Flow analysis was performed on a FACS Vantage (BDIS, San Jose, Calif.) equipped with a turbo-sort option and two Inova 305 lasers (Coherent, Palo Alto, Calif.). The GFP signal excitation is at 488 nm and the emission detected in FL1 using a 500 nm long pass filter. Analysis of the transfected cells generated populations of GFP positive cells ranging from 13-27%. Non-sonoporated control value was 5%. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Ultrasound Mediated Transfection with Saint-2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0197" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0197&rsqb;</number> A. Ultrasound mediated transfection of CHO-KI cells with Saint-2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0198" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0198&rsqb;</number> CHO-KI cells were grown at 37&deg;, 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, in CHO-S-SFM 2 Medium, (Gibco BRL, Paisley, UK). Between 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>and 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>cells were plated onto sterile glass slides in a 12 well plate 24 h before usage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0199" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0199&rsqb;</number> Transfection of the cells was performed as follows. The medium was removed from the cells, and the cells were washed twice with HBSS (Hanks balanced salt solution without Phenol Red (Gibco BRL, UK)) at 37&deg; C. Then 500 &mgr;l HBSS at 37&deg; C. was added per well, followed by 10 &mgr;l of the freshly prepared vesicle solution (prepared in Example 2) to yield a final concentration of 23.3 nmole/ml. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0200" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0200&rsqb;</number> Alternatively, the medium was removed from the cells, and the cells were washed twice with HBSS. 500 &mgr;l HBSS/lipid solution at 37&deg; C. was added to each well. The HBSS/lipid solution was prepared by adding 1 &mgr;l ethanolic lipid solution (prepared as described above) to 500 &mgr;l HBSS under vigorous vortexing. The plates were then sealed with parafilm tape and shaken gently at room temperature for 30 min. After incubation, ultrasound was applied at an output energy of 0.5 Watt/cm<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>for 60 sec through the bottom of the plate to the cells. The ultrasound was mediated by an ultrasound gel (Aquasonic 100, Parker, N.J.) between transducer and plate. The ultrasound was applied with an ImaRx Sonoporator 100. Immediately after applying ultrasound one GFP chromosome per seeded cell (2&times;10<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight>&minus;5&times;10<highlight><superscript>5</superscript></highlight>) (prepared in Example 1) was added. The plate was then sealed again and shaken gently for 1 h at room temperature. After the incubation 1 ml medium (CHO-S-SFM 2 with 10% Fetal Calf Serum, 10000 &mgr;g/ml Penicillin and 10000 &mgr;g/ml Streptomycin Gibco BRL, Paisley, UK) was added to each well and the cells were incubated for 24 h at 37&deg; C. The cells were then washed with medium and 1 ml medium was added and the cells were incubated at 37&deg; for another 24 h. Detection of expressed genes was then assayed by microscopy or detection of the transferred chromosome by FISH analysis. The negative control was performed in the same way, but with no chromosomes added to the cells. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Results </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0201" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0201&rsqb;</number> After transfection, using visual inspection, 30% of the cells remained on the glass slide of which 10% were positive for green fluorescent protein expression after 48 hours (3% of original population). After culturing for two weeks, FISH was performed on the cells and 1.4% of the cells contained an intact artificial chromosome. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0202" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0202&rsqb;</number> B. Ultrasound mediated transfection of Hep-G2 cells with Saint-2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0203" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0203&rsqb;</number> Hep-G2 cells were grown at 37&deg; C., 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, in DMEM with 4500 mg/l Glucose, with Pyridoxine/HCL, 10% Fetal Calf Serum, 10000 &mgr;g/ml Streptomycin and 1000 &mgr;g/ml Penicillin. Between 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>and 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>cells were plated onto sterile glass slides in a 12 wells plate 24 hours before usage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0204" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0204&rsqb;</number> Cells were transfected with GFP chromosomes using the procedure of Example 6A except that the CHO-KI medium was replaced with Hep-G2 medium. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Results </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0205" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0205&rsqb;</number> After transfection, 30% of the cells remained on the glass slide. 80% of these cells were positive for green fluorescent protein expression. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0206" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0206&rsqb;</number> C. Ultrasound mediated transfection of A9 cells with Saint-2 </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0207" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0207&rsqb;</number> A9 cells were grown at 37&deg; C., 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, in DMEM with 4500 mg/l Glucose, with Pyridoxine/HCL, 10% Fetal Calf Serum, 10000 &mgr;g/ml Streptomycin and 10000 &mgr;g/ml Penicillin (GIBCO BRL, Paisley, UK). Between 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>and 5&times;10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>cells were plated onto sterile glass slides in a 12 well plate 24 h before usage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0208" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0208&rsqb;</number> Cells were transfected with GFP chromosomes using the procedure of Example 6A except that CHO-KI medium was replaced with A9 medium. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Results </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0209" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0209&rsqb;</number> After transfection, 30% of the cells remained on the glass of which 50% were positive for green fluorescent protein expression. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 7 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0210" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0210&rsqb;</number> A flow cytometry technique for measuring delivery of artificial chromosomes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0211" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0211&rsqb;</number> Production cells lines (see Example 1) were grown in MEM medium (Gibco BRL) with 10% fetal calf serum (Can Sera, Rexdale ON) with 0.168 &mgr;g/ml hygromycin B (Calbiochem, San Diego, Calif.). Iododeoxyurine or Bromodeoxyurdine were added directly to culture medium of the production cell line (CHO E42019) in the exponential phase of growth. Stock Iododeoxyurdine made in tris base pH 10. Bromodeoxyurdine stocks in PBS. Final concentrations of 0.05-1 &mgr;M for continuous label of 20-24 hours of 5-50 &mgr;M with 15 minute pulse. After 24 hours, exponentially growing cells blocked in mitosis with colchicine (1.0 &mgr;g/ml for 7 hours before harvest. Chromosomes were then isolated and stained with Hoechst 33258 (2.5 &mgr;g/ml) and chromomycin A3 (50 &mgr;g/ml). Purification of artificial chromosomes was performed using a FACS Vantage flow cytometer (Becton Dickinson Immunocytometry systems, San Jose, Calif.). Chromomycin A3 was excited with the primary laser set at 457 nm, with emission detected using 475 nm long pass filter. Hoechst was excited by the secondary UV laser and emission detected using a 420/44 nm band-pass filter. Both lasers had an output of 150 mW. Bivariate distribution showing cell karyotype was accumulated from each sort. ACes were gated from other chromosomes and sorted. Condensing agents (hexylene glycol, spermine, and spermidine) were added to the sheath buffer to maintain condensed intact chromosome after sorting. IdU labeling index of sorted chromosomes was determined microscopically. Aliquot (2-10 &mgr;l) of sorted chromosomes fixed in 0.2% formaldehyde solution for 5 minutes before being dried on clean microscopic slide. Microscope sample fixed with 70% ethanol. Air-dried slide denatured in coplin jar with 2NHCL for 30 minutes at room temperature and washed 2-3 times with PBS. Non specific binding blocked with PBS and 4% BSA or serum for minimum of 10 minutes. A &frac15; dilution of FITC conjugated IdU/BrdU antibody (Becton Dickinson) with a final volume of 60-100 &mgr;l applied to slide. Plastic strips, Durra seal (Diversified Biotech, Boston, Mass.) overlaid on slides, and slides kept in dark at 4%C in humidified covered box for 8-24 hours. DAPI (Sigma) 1 &mgr;g/ml in Vectorshield used as counterstain. Fluorescence detected using Zeiss axioplan 2 microscope equipped for epiflorescence. Minimum of 100 chromosomes scored for determining % labeled. Unlabeled chromosomes used as negative control. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0212" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0212&rsqb;</number> The day before the transfection, trypsinize V79-4 (Chinese Hamster Lung fibroblast) cells and plate at 250,000 into a 6 well petri dish in 4 mls DMEM (Dulbecco&apos;s Modified Eagle Medium, Life Technologies) and 10% FBS (Can Sera Rexdale ON). The protocol modified for use with LM (tk-) cell line by plating 500,000 cells. Lipid or dendrimer reagent was added to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>6 </superscript></highlight>ACes sorted in &tilde;800 &mgr;l sort buffer. Exemplary protocol variations are set forth in Table 1. Chromosome and transfection agents were mixed gently. Complexes added to cells drop-wise and plate swirled to mix. Plates kept at 37&deg; C. in a 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>incubator for specified transfection time. The volume in a well was then made up to 4-5 ml with DMEM and 10% FBS. Recipient cells left for 24 hours at 37&deg; C. in a 5% CO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>incubator. Trypsinize transfected cells. Samples to be analyzed for IdU labeled chromosome delivery are fixed in cold 70% ethanol and stored at &minus;20&deg; C., tp be ready for IdU antibody staining. Samples to be grown for colony selection are counted and then transferred to 10-cm dishes at densities of 10,000 and 100,000 cells in duplicate with remaining cells put in a 15 cm dish. After 24 hours, selection medium containing of DMEM and 10% FBS with 0.7 mg/ml hygromycin B, &num;400051 (Calbiochem San Diego, Calif.) is added. Selection medium is changed every 2-3 days. This concentration of hygromycin B kills the wild type cells after selection for 7 days. At 10-14 days colonies expanded and then screened by FISH for intact chromosome transfer and assayed for beta galactosidase expression.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="343PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Delivery Transfection Protocols</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="7">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="49PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="49PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Medium (ml)</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Pre</entry>
<entry>Complexing</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>added to wells</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>treatment</entry>
<entry>time</entry>
<entry>Added to</entry>
<entry>before</entry>
<entry>Transfection</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Agent</entry>
<entry>Dilution Stock</entry>
<entry>of ACes</entry>
<entry>(minutes)</entry>
<entry>complexes</entry>
<entry>complexes</entry>
<entry>time (hours)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="7" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>CLONFECTIN</entry>
<entry>2-8 &mgr;g in</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry>1.8 ml of</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>NaCl-HEPES</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>serum free</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>CYTOFECTENE</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>10-20</entry>
<entry>200 &mgr;l of 50%</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>24&ensp;</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>FBS plus</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DMEM</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ENHANCER &plus;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Enhancer 5</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>1.2</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EFFECTENE</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>minutes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(1:5 ratio)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-1 to</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ensp;5-10</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>FUGENE 6</entry>
<entry>0.5-6 &mgr;l to</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>15-45</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>final volume</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>of 100 &mgr;l in</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>serum free</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>medium</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>GENEPORTER 2</entry>
<entry>2.5 &mgr;l added</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&ensp;2-10</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>2-4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>to 150 &mgr;l of</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>serum free</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>medium</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>15</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>20</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>2.5</entry>
<entry>5</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2000</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>METAFECTENE</entry>
<entry>diluted into</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>15-45</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>0.8</entry>
<entry>6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>60 &mgr;l serum</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>free medium</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PLUS &plus;</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>PLUS and 200</entry>
<entry>15</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>&mgr;l of DMEM</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(1:1 and 3:2</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>for 15 minutes</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ratio)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SUPERFECT</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry></entry>
<entry>0.6</entry>
<entry>3</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="7" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0213" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0213&rsqb;</number> IDU ANTIBODY LABELING </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0214" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0214&rsqb;</number> A standard BrdU staining flow cytometry protocol (Gratzer et al. Cytometry (1981);6:385-393) used except with some modifications at neutralization step, the presence of detergent during denaturation and the composition of blocking buffer. Between each step samples are centrifuged at 300 g for 7-10 minutes and supernatant removed. Samples of 1-2 million cells are fixed in 70% cold ethanol. Cells are then denatured in 1-2 ml of 2N HCL plus 0.5% triton X for 30 minutes at room temperature. Sample undergoes 3-4 washes with cold DMEM until indictor is neutral. Final wash with cold DMEM plus 5% FBS. Blocking/permeabilization buffer containing PBS, 0.1% triton X and 4% FBS is added for 10-15 minutes before pelleting sample by centrifugation. Add 20 &mgr;l of IdU/BrdU FITC conjugated B44 clone antibody (Becton Dickinson Immunocytometry Systems, San Jose, Calif.) to pellet and leave for 2 hours at room temperature in the dark with agitation every 30 minutes. Wash cells with block/permeabilization buffer and resuspend in PBS for flow analysis. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FLOW CYTOMETRY DETECTION OF FLUORESCENT IDUrdD LABELED ACes </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0215" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0215&rsqb;</number> Percentage of transfected cells containing IdU labeled ACes was determined using a flow cytometry with an argon laser turned to 488 nm at 400 mW. FITC fluorescence was collected through a standard FITC 530/30-nm band pass filter. Cell populations were gated on the basis of side scatter versus forward scatter to exclude debris and doublets. Data was accumulated (15,000 events) to form bivariate channel distribution showing forward scatter versus green fluorescence (IdU-FITC). The fluorescence level at which cells were determined to be positive was established by visual inspection of the histogram of negative control cells, such that approximately 1% appeared in the positive region. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Results: </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0216" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0216&rsqb;</number> The transfection delivery results of IdU labeled ACes are set forth in Table 2.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>DOSE</entry>
<entry>DELIVERY</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Microliters agent</entry>
<entry>% IdU positive</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>COMPOUND</entry>
<entry>added per 1</entry>
<entry>(24 hours)</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="63PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>CLONFECTIN</entry>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>0.61</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>CYTOFECTENE</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>14.67</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>ENHANCER &plus; EFFECTENE</entry>
<entry>1.6, 10</entry>
<entry>17.08</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(1:5)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-1</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>4.57</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-2</entry>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>0.14</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-3</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.69</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-4</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.24</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-5</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.41</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-6</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.46</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-7</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>1.21</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-8</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>1.58</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-9</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-10</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>0.77</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EU-FECTIN-11</entry>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>FUGENE</entry>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>0.49</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>GENEPORTER</entry>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>22.12</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry>25</entry>
<entry>17.81</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>LIPOFECTAMINE 2000</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
<entry>10.96</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PLUS &plus; LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry>&thinsp;12, 12</entry>
<entry>12.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(1:1)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PLUS &plus; LIPOFECTAMINE</entry>
<entry>&thinsp;24, 16</entry>
<entry>26.97</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>(3:2)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>METAFECTENE</entry>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>14.14</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>SUPERFECT</entry>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>27.67</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0217" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0217&rsqb;</number> Since modifications will be apparent to those of skill in this art, it is intended that this invention be limited only by the scope of the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<sequence-cwu id="SEQLST-1">
<number>1</number>
<sequence-list-new-rules>
<s100>
<s160>13 </s160>
</s100>
<s200>
<s210>1 </s210>
<s211>24 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>Primer </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 1 
cgtccaggag cgcaccatct tctt                                            24 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>2 </s210>
<s211>24 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>Primer </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 2 
atcgcgcttc tcgttggggt cttt                                            24 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>3 </s210>
<s211>30 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>Primer </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 3 
aggactgggt ggcttccaac tcccagacac                                      30 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>4 </s210>
<s211>30 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>Primer </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 4 
agcttctcat tgctgcgcgc caggttcagg                                      30 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>5 </s210>
<s211>22118 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 5 
gaattcccct atccctaatc cagattggtg gaataacttg gtatagatgt ttgtgcatta     60 
aaaaccctgt aggatcttca ctctaggtca ctgttcagca ctggaacctg aattgtggcc    120 
ctgagtgata ggtcctggga catatgcagt tctgcacaga cagacagaca gacagacaga    180 
cagacagaca gacagacgtt acaaacaaac acgttgagcc gtgtgccaac acacacacaa    240 
acaccactct ggccataatt attgaggacg ttgatttatt attctgtgtt tgtgagtctg    300 
tctgtctgtc tgtctgtctg tctgtctgtc tatcaaacca aaagaaacca aacaattatg    360 
cctgcctgcc tgcctgcctg cctacacaga gaaatgattt cttcaatcaa tctaaaacga    420 
cctcctaagt ttgccttttt tctctttctt tatctttttc ttttttcttt tcttcttcct    480 
tccttccttc cttccttcct tccttccttt ctttctttct ttctttcttt cttactttct    540 
ttctttcctt cttacattta ttcttttcat acatagtttc ttagtgtaag catccctgac    600 
tgtcttgaag acactttgta ggcctcaatc ctgtaagagc cttcctctgc ttttcaaatg    660 
ctggcatgaa tgttgtacct cactatgacc agcttagtct tcaagtctga gttactggaa    720 
aggagttcca agaagactgg ttatattttt catttattat tgcattttaa ttaaaattta    780 
atttcaccaa aagaatttag actgaccaat tcagagtctg ccgtttaaaa gcataaggaa    840 
aaagtaggag aaaaacgtga ggctgtctgt ggatggtcga ggctgcttta gggagcctcg    900 
tcaccattct gcacttgcaa accgggccac tagaacccgg tgaagggaga aaccaaagcg    960 
acctggaaac aataggtcac atgaaggcca gccacctcca tcttgttgtg cgggagttca   1020 
gttagcagac aagatggctg ccatgcacat gttgtctttc agcttggtga ggtcaaagta   1080 
caaccgagtc acagaacaag gaagtataca cagtgagttc caggtcagcc agagtttaca   1140 
cagagaaacc acatcttgaa aaaaacaaaa aaataaatta aataaatata atttaaaaat   1200 
ttaaaaatag ccgggagtga tggcgcatgt ctttaatccc agctctcttc aggcagagat   1260 
gggaggattt ctgagtttga ggccagcctg gtctgcaaag tgagttccag gacagtcagg   1320 
gctatacaga gaaaccctgt cttgaaaact aaactaaatt aaactaaact aaactaaaaa   1380 
aatataaaat aaaaatttta aagaatttta aaaaactaca gaaatcaaac ataagcccac   1440 
gagatggcaa gtaactgcaa tcatagcaga aatattatac acacacacac acacagactc   1500 
tgtcataaaa tccaatgtgc cttcatgatg atcaaatttc gatagtcagt aatactagaa   1560 
gaatcatatg tctgaaaata aaagccagaa ccttttctgc ttttgttttc ttttgcccca   1620 
agatagggtt tctctcagtg tatccctggc atccctgcct ggaacttcct ttgtaggttt   1680 
ggtagcctca aactcagaga ggtcctctct gcctgcctgc ctgcctgcct gcctgcctgc   1740 
ctgcctgcct gcctgcctca cttcttctgc cacccacaca accgagtcga acctaggatc   1800 
tttatttctt tctctttctc tcttctttct ttctttcttt ctttctttct ttctttcttt   1860 
ctttctttct ttcttattca attagttttc aatgtaagtg tgtgtttgtg ctctatctgc   1920 
tgcctatagg cctgcttgcc aggagagggc aacagaacct aggagaaacc accatgcagc   1980 
tcctgagaat aagtgaaaaa acaacaaaaa aaggaaattc taatcacata gaatgtagat   2040 
atatgccgag gctgtcagag tgctttttaa ggcttagtgt aagtaatgaa aattgttgtg   2100 
tgtcttttat ccaaacacag aagagaggtg gctcggcctg catgtctgtt gtctgcatgt   2160 
agaccaggct ggccttgaac acattaatct gtctgcctct gcttccctaa tgctgcgatt   2220 
aaaggcatgt gccaccactg cccggactga tttcttcttt tttttttttt tggaaaatac   2280 
ctttctttct ttttctctct ctctttcttc cttccttcct ttctttctat tctttttttc   2340 
tttctttttt cttttttttt ttttttttaa aatttgccta aggttaaagg tgtgctccac   2400 
aattgcctca gctctgctct aattctcttt aaaaaaaaac aaacaaaaaa aaaaccaaaa   2460 
cagtatgtat gtatgtatat ttagaagaaa tactaatcca ttaataactc ttttttccta   2520 
aaattcatgt cattcttgtt ccacaaagtg agttccagga cttaccagag aaaccctgtg   2580 
ttcaaatttc tgtgttcaag gtcaccctgg cttacaaagt gagttccaag tccgataggg   2640 
ctacacagaa aaaccatatc tcagaaaaaa aaaaagttcc aaacacacac acacacacac   2700 
acacacacac acacacacac acacacacac acacacacag cgcgccgcgg cgatgagggg   2760 
aagtcgtgcc taaaataaat atttttctgg ccaaagtgaa agcaaatcac tatgaagagg   2820 
tactcctaga aaaaataaat acaaacgggc tttttaatca ttccagcact gttttaattt   2880 
aactctgaat ttagtcttgg aaaagggggc gggtgtgggt gagtgagggc gagcgagcag   2940 
acgggcgggc gggcgggtga gtggccggcg gcggtggcag cgagcaccag aaaacaacaa   3000 
accccaagcg gtagagtgtt ttaaaaatga gacctaaatg tggtggaacg gaggtcgccg   3060 
ccaccctcct cttccactgc ttagatgctc ccttcccctt actgtgctcc cttcccctaa   3120 
ctgtgcctaa ctgtgcctgt tccctcaccc cgctgattcg ccagcgacgt actttgactt   3180 
caagaacgat tttgcctgtt ttcaccgctc cctgtcatac tttcgttttt gggtgcccga   3240 
gtctagcccg ttcgctatgt tcgggcggga cgatggggac cgtttgtgcc actcgggaga   3300 
agtggtgggt gggtacgctg ctccgtcgtg cgtgcgtgag tgccggaacc tgagctcggg   3360 
agaccctccg gagagacaga atgagtgagt gaatgtggcg gcgcgtgacg gatctgtatt   3420 
ggtttgtatg gttgatcgag accattgtcg ggcgacacct agtggtgaca agtttcggga   3480 
acgctccagg cctctcaggt tggtgacaca ggagagggaa gtgcctgtgg tgaggcgacc   3540 
agggtgacag gaggccgggc aagcaggcgg gagcgtctcg gagatggtgt cgtgtttaag   3600 
gacggtctct aacaaggagg tcgtacaggg agatggccaa agcagaccga gttgctgtac   3660 
gcccttttgg gaaaaatgct agggttggtg gcaacgttac taggtcgacc agaaggctta   3720 
agtcctaccc ccccccccct tttttttttt tttcctccag aagccctctc ttgtccccgt   3780 
caccgggggc accgtacatc tgaggccgag aggacgcgat gggcccggct tccaagccgg   3840 
tgtggctcgg ccagctggcg cttcgggtct tttttttttt tttttttttt ttttcctcca   3900 
gaagccttgt ctgtcgctgt caccgggggc gctgtacttc tgaggccgag aggacgcgat   3960 
gggccccggc ttccaagccg gtgtggctcg gccagctgga gcttcgggtc tttttttttt   4020 
tttttttttt tttttttctc cagaagcctt gtctgtcgct gtcaccgggg gcgctgtact   4080 
tctgaggccg agaggacgcg atgggtcggc ttccaagccg atgtggcggg gccagctgga   4140 
gcttcgggtt tttttttttc ctccagaagc cctctcttgt ccccgtcacc gggggcgctg   4200 
tacttctgag gccgagagga cgtgatgggc ccgggttcca ggcggatgtc gcccggtcag   4260 
ctggagcttt ggatcttttt tttttttttt cctccagaag ccctctcttg tccccgtcac   4320 
cgggggcacc ttacatctga gggcgagagg acgtgatggg tccggcttcc aagccgatgt   4380 
ggcggggcca gctggagctt cgggtttttt ttttttcctc cagaagccct ctcttgtccc   4440 
cgtcaccggg ggcgctgtac ttctgaggcc gagaggacgt gatgggcccg ggttccaggc   4500 
ggatgtcgcc cggtcagctg gagctttgga tcattttttt ttttccctcc agaagccctc   4560 
tcttgtcccc gtcaccgggg gcaccgtaca tctgaggccg agaggacacg atgggcctgt   4620 
cttccaagcc gatgtggccc ggccagctgg agcttcgggt cttttttttt ttttttcctc   4680 
cagaagcctt gtctgtcgct gtcacccggg gcgctgtact tctgaggccg agaggacgcg   4740 
atgggcccgg cttccaagcc ggtgtggctc ggccagctgg agcttcgggt cttttttttt   4800 
tttttttttt ttcctccaga aaccttgtct gtcgctgtca cccggggcgc ttgtacttct   4860 
gatgccgaga ggacgcgatg ggcccgtctt ccaggccgat gtggcccggt cagctggagc   4920 
tttggatctt tttttttttt ttttcctcca gaagccctct cttgtccccg tcaccggggg   4980 
caccttacat ctgaggccta gaggacacga tgggcccggg ttccaggccg atgtggcccg   5040 
gtcagctgga gctttggatc tttttttttt ttttcttcca gaagccctct tgtccccgtc   5100 
accggtggca ctgtacatct gaggcggaga ggacattatg ggcccggctt ccaatccgat   5160 
gtggcccggt cagctggagc tttggatctt attttttttt taattttttc ttccagaagc   5220 
cctcttgtcc ctgtcaccgg tggcacggta catctgaggc cgagaggaca ttatgggccc   5280 
ggcttccagg ccgatgtggc ccggtcagct ggagctttgg atcttttttt ttttttttct   5340 
tttttcctcc agaagccctc tctgtccctg tcaccggggg ccctgtacgt ctgaggccga   5400 
gggaaagcta tgggcgcggt tttctttcat tgacctgtcg gtcttatcag ttctccgggt   5460 
tgtcagggtc gaccagttgt tcctttgagg tccggttctt ttcgttatgg ggtcattttt   5520 
gggccacctc cccaggtatg acttccaggc gtcgttgctc gcctgtcact ttcctccctg   5580 
tctcttttat gcttgtgatc ttttctatct gttcctattg gacctggaga taggtactga   5640 
cacgctgtcc tttccctatt aacactaaag gacactataa agagaccctt tcgatttaag   5700 
gctgttttgc ttgtccagcc tattcttttt actggcttgg gtctgtcgcg gtgcctgaag   5760 
ctgtccccga gccacgcttc ctgctttccc gggcttgctg cttgcgtgtg cttgctgtgg   5820 
gcagcttgtg acaactgggc gctgtgactt tgctgcgtgt cagacgtttt tcccgatttc   5880 
cccgaggtgt cgttgtcaca cctgtcccgg ttggaatggt ggagccagct gtggttgagg   5940 
gccaccttat ttcggctcac tttttttttt tttttttctc ttggagtccc gaacctccgc   6000 
tcttttctct tcccggtctt tcttccacat gcctcccgag tgcatttctt tttgtttttt   6060 
ttcttttttt tttttttttt ttggggaggt ggagagtccc gagtacttca ctcctgtctg   6120 
tggtgtccaa gtgttcatgc cacgtgcctc ccgagtgcac ttttttttgt ggcagtcgct   6180 
cgttgtgttc tcttgttctg tgtctgcccg tatcagtaac tgtcttgccc cgcgtgtaag   6240 
acattcctat ctcgcttgtt tctcccgatt gcgcgtcgtt gctcactctt agatcgatgt   6300 
ggtgctccgg agttctcttc gggccagggc caagccgcgc caggcgaggg acggacattc   6360 
atggcgaatg gcggccgctc ttctcgttct gccagcgggc cctcgtctct ccaccccatc   6420 
cgtctgccgg tggtgtgtgg aaggcagggg tgcggctctc cggcccgacg ctgccccgcg   6480 
cgcacttttc tcagtggttc gcgtggtcct tgtggatgtg tgaggcgccc ggttgtgccc   6540 
tcacgtgttt cactttggtc gtgtctcgct tgaccatgtt cccagagtcg gtggatgtgg   6600 
ccggtggcgt tgcataccct tcccgtctgg tgtgtgcacg cgctgtttct tgtaagcgtc   6660 
gaggtgctcc tggagcgttc caggtttgtc tcctaggtgc ctgcttctga gctggtggtg   6720 
gcgctcccca ttccctggtg tgcctccggt gctccgtctg gctgtgtgcc ttcccgtttg   6780 
tgtctgagaa gcccgtgaga ggggggtcga ggagagaagg aggggcaaga ccccccttct   6840 
tcgtcgggtg aggcgcccac cccgcgacta gtacgcctgt gcgtagggct ggtgctgagc   6900 
ggtcgcggct ggggttggaa agtttctcga gagactcatt gctttcccgt ggggagcttt   6960 
gagaggcctg gctttcgggg gggaccggtt gcagggtctc ccctgtccgc ggatgctcag   7020 
aatgcccttg gaagagaacc ttcctgttgc cgcagacccc cccgcgcggt cgcccgcgtg   7080 
ttggtcttct ggtttccctg tgtgctcgtc gcatgcatcc tctctcggtg gccggggctc   7140 
gtcggggttt tgggtccgtc ccgccctcag tgagaaagtt tccttctcta gctatcttcc   7200 
ggaaagggtg cgggcttctt acggtctcga ggggtctctc ccgaatggtc ccctggaggg   7260 
ctcgccccct gaccgcctcc cgcgcgcgca gcgtttgctc tctcgtctac cgcggcccgc   7320 
ggcctccccg ctccgagttc ggggagggat cacgcggggc agagcctgtc tgtcgtcctg   7380 
ccgttgctgc ggagcatgtg gctcggcttg tgtggttggt ggctggggag agggctccgt   7440 
gcacaccccc gcgtgcgcgt actttcctcc cctcctgagg gccgccgtgc ggacggggtg   7500 
tgggtaggcg acggtgggct cccgggtccc cacccgtctt cccgtgcctc acccgtgcct   7560 
tccgtcgcgt gcgtccctct cgctcgcgtc cacgactttg gccgctcccg cgacggcggc   7620 
ctgcgccgcg cgtggtgcgt gctgtgtgct tctcgggctg tgtggttgtg tcgcctcgcc   7680 
ccccccttcc cgcggcagcg ttcccacggc tggcgaaatc gcgggagtcc tccttcccct   7740 
cctcggggtc gagagggtcc gtgtctggcg ttgattgatc tcgctctcgg ggacgggacc   7800 
gttctgtggg agaacggctg ttggccgcgt ccggcgcgac gtcggacgtg gggacccact   7860 
gccgctcggg ggtcttcgtc ggtaggcatc ggtgtgtcgg catcggtctc tctctcgtgt   7920 
cggtgtcgcc tcctcgggct cccggggggc cgtcgtgttt cgggtcggct cggcgctgca   7980 
ggtgtggtgg gactgctcag gggagtggtg cagtgtgatt cccgccggtt ttgcctcgcg   8040 
tgccctgacc ggtccgacgc ccgagcggtc tctcggtccc ttgtgaggac ccccttccgg   8100 
gaggggcccg tttcggccgc ccttgccgtc gtcgccggcc ctcgttctgc tgtgtcgttc   8160 
ccccctcccc gctcgccgca gccggtcttt tttcctctct ccccccctct cctctgactg   8220 
acccgtggcc gtgctgtcgg accccccgca tgggggcggc cgggcacgta cgcgtccggg   8280 
cggtcaccgg ggtcttgggg gggggccgag gggtaagaaa gtcggctcgg cgggcgggag   8340 
gagctgtggt ttggagggcg tcccggcccc gcggccgtgg cggtgtcttg cgcggtcttg   8400 
gagagggctg cgtgcgaggg gaaaaggttg ccccgcgagg gcaaagggaa agaggctagc   8460 
agtggtcatt gtcccgacgg tgtggtggtc tgttggccga ggtgcgtctg gggggctcgt   8520 
ccggccctgt cgtccgtcgg gaaggcgcgt gttggggcct gccggagtgc cgaggtgggt   8580 
accctggcgg tgggattaac cccgcgcgcg tgtcccggtg tggcggtggg ggctccggtc   8640 
gatgtctacc tccctctccc cgaggtctca ggccttctcc gcgcgggctc tcggccctcc   8700 
cctcgttcct ccctctcgcg gggttcaagt cgctcgtcga cctcccctcc tccgtccttc   8760 
catctctcgc gcaatggcgc cgcccgagtt cacggtgggt tcgtcctccg cctccgcttc   8820 
tcgccggggg ctggccgctg tccggtctct cctgcccgac ccccgttggc gtggtcttct   8880 
ctcgccggct tcgcggactc ctggcttcgc ccggagggtc agggggcttc ccggttcccc   8940 
gacgttgcgc ctcgctgctg tgtgcttggg gggggcccgc tgcggcctcc gcccgcccgt   9000 
gagcccctgc cgcacccgcc ggtgtgcggt ttcgcgccgc ggtcagttgg gccctggcgt   9060 
tgtgtcgcgt cgggagcgtg tccgcctcgc ggcggctaga cgcgggtgtc gccgggctcc   9120 
gacgggtggc ctatccaggg ctcgcccccg ccgacccccg cctgcccgtc ccggtggtgg   9180 
tcgttggtgt ggggagtgaa tggtgctacc ggtcattccc tcccgcgtgg tttgactgtc   9240 
tcgccggtgt cgcgcttctc tttccgccaa cccccacgcc aacccaccac cctgctctcc   9300 
cggcccggtg cggtcgacgt tccggctctc ccgatgccga ggggttcggg atttgtgccg   9360 
gggacggagg ggagagcggg taagagaggt gtcggagagc tgtcccgggg cgacgctcgg   9420 
gttggctttg ccgcgtgcgt gtgctcgcgg acgggttttg tcggaccccg acggggtcgg   9480 
tccggccgca tgcactctcc cgttccgcgc gagcgcccgc ccggctcacc cccggtttgt   9540 
cctcccgcga ggctctccgc cgccgccgcc tcctcctcct ctctcgcgct ctctgtcccg   9600 
cctggtcctg tcccaccccc gacgctccgc tcgcgcttcc ttacctggtt gatcctgcca   9660 
ggtagcatat gcttgtctca aagattaagc catgcatgtc taagtacgca cggccggtac   9720 
agtgaaactg cgaatggctc attaaatcag ttatggttcc tttggtcgct cgctcctctc   9780 
ctacttggat aactgtggta attctagagc taatacatgc cgacgggcgc tgacccccct   9840 
tcccgggggg ggatgcgtgc atttatcaga tcaaaaccaa cccggtgagc tccctcccgg   9900 
ctccggccgg gggtcgggcg ccggcggctt ggtgactcta gataacctcg ggccgatcgc   9960 
acgccccccg tggcggcgac gacccattcg aacgtctgcc ctatcaactt tcgatggtag  10020 
tcgccgtgcc taccatggtg accacgggtg acggggaatc agggttcgat tccggagagg  10080 
gagcctgaga aacggctacc acatccaagg aaggcagcag gcgcgcaaat tacccactcc  10140 
cgacccgggg aggtagtgac gaaaaataac aatacaggac tctttcgagg ccctgtaatt  10200 
ggaatgagtc cactttaaat cctttaacga ggatccattg gagggcaagt ctggtgccag  10260 
cagccgcggt aattccagct ccaatagcgt atattaaagt tgctgcagtt aaaaagctcg  10320 
tagttggatc ttgggagcgg gcgggcggtc cgccgcgagg cgagtcaccg cccgtccccg  10380 
ccccttgcct ctcggcgccc cctcgatgct cttagctgag tgtcccgcgg ggcccgaagc  10440 
gtttactttg aaaaaattag agtgttcaaa gcaggcccga gccgcctgga taccgcagct  10500 
aggaataatg gaataggacc gcggttctat tttgttggtt ttcggaactg aggccatgat  10560 
taagagggac ggccgggggc attcgtattg cgccgctaga ggtgaaattc ttggaccggc  10620 
gcaagacgga ccagagcgaa agcatttgcc aagaatgttt tcattaatca agaacgaaag  10680 
tcggaggttc gaagacgatc agataccgtc gtagttccga ccataaacga tgccgactgg  10740 
cgatgcggcg gcgttattcc catgacccgc cgggcagctt ccgggaaacc aaagtctttg  10800 
ggttccgggg ggagtatggt tgcaaagctg aaacttaaag gaattgacgg aagggcacca  10860 
ccaggagtgg gcctgcggct taatttgact caacacggga aacctcaccc ggcccggaca  10920 
cggacaggat tgacagattg atagctcttt ctcgattccg tgggtggtgg tgcatggccg  10980 
ttcttagttg gtggagcgat ttgtctggtt aattccgata acgaacgaga ctctggcatg  11040 
ctaactagtt acgcgacccc cgagcggtcg gcgtccccca acttcttaga gggacaagtg  11100 
gcgttcagcc acccgagatt gagcaataac aggtctgtga tgcccttaga tgtccggggc  11160 
tgcacgcgcg ctacactgac tggctcagcg tgtgcctacc ctgcgccggc aggcgcgggt  11220 
aacccgttga accccattcg tgatggggat cggggattgc aattattccc catgaacgag  11280 
gaattcccag taagtgcggg tcataagctt gcgttgatta agtccctgcc ctttgtacac  11340 
accgcccgtc gctactaccg attggatggt ttagtgaggc cctcggatcg gccccgccgg  11400 
ggtcggccca cggccctggc ggagcgctga gaagacggtc gaacttgact atctagagga  11460 
agtaaaagtc gtaacaaggt ttccgtaggt gaacctgcgg aaggatcatt aaacgggaga  11520 
ctgtggagga gcggcggcgt ggcccgctct ccccgtcttg tgtgtgtcct cgccgggagg  11580 
cgcgtgcgtc ccgggtcccg tcgcccgcgt gtggagcgag gtgtctggag tgaggtgaga  11640 
gaaggggtgg gtggggtcgg tctgggtccg tctgggaccg cctccgattt cccctccccc  11700 
tcccctctcc ctcgtccggc tctgacctcg ccaccctacc gcggcggcgg ctgctcgcgg  11760 
gcgtcttgcc tctttcccgt ccggctcttc cgtgtctacg aggggcggta cgtcgttacg  11820 
ggtttttgac ccgtcccggg ggcgttcggt cgtcggggcg cgcgctttgc tctcccggca  11880 
cccatccccg ccgcggctct ggcttttcta cgttggctgg ggcggttgtc gcgtgtgggg  11940 
ggatgtgagt gtcgcgtgtg ggctcgcccg tcccgatgcc acgcttttct ggcctcgcgt  12000 
gtcctccccg ctcctgtccc gggtacctag ctgtcgcgtt ccggcgcgga ggtttaagga  12060 
ccccgggggg gtcgccctgc cgcccccagg gtcggggggc ggtggggccc gtagggaagt  12120 
cggtcgttcg ggcggctctc cctcagactc catgaccctc ctccccccgc tgccgccgtt  12180 
cccgaggcgg cggtcgtgtg ggggggtgga tgtctggagc cccctcgggc gccgtggggg  12240 
cccgacccgc gccgccggct tgcccgattt ccgcgggtcg gtcctgtcgg tgccggtcgt  12300 
gggttcccgt gtcgttcccg tgtttttccg ctcccgaccc tttttttttc ctccccccca  12360 
cacgtgtctc gtttcgttcc tgctggccgg cctgaggcta cccctcggtc catctgttct  12420 
cctctctctc cggggagagg agggcggtgg tcgttggggg actgtgccgt cgtcagcacc  12480 
cgtgagttcg ctcacacccg aaataccgat acgactctta gcggtggatc actcggctcg  12540 
tgcgtcgatg aagaacgcag ctagctgcga gaattaatgt gaattgcagg acacattgat  12600 
catcgacact tcgaacgcac ttgcggcccc gggttcctcc cggggctacg cctgtctgag  12660 
cgtcggttga cgatcaatcg cgtcacccgc tgcggtgggt gctgcgcggc tgggagtttg  12720 
ctcgcagggc caacccccca acccgggtcg ggccctccgt ctcccgaagt tcagacgtgt  12780 
gggcggttgt cggtgtggcg cgcgcgcccg cgtcgcggag cctggtctcc cccgcgcatc  12840 
cgcgctcgcg gcttcttccc gctccgccgt tcccgccctc gcccgtgcac cccggtcctg  12900 
gcctcgcgtc ggcgcctccc ggaccgctgc ctcaccagtc tttctcggtc ccgtgccccg  12960 
tgggaaccca ccgcgccccc gtggcgcccg ggggtgggcg cgtccgcatc tgctctggtc  13020 
gaggttggcg gttgagggtg tgcgtgcgcc gaggtggtgg tcggtcccct gcggccgcgg  13080 
ggttgtcggg gtggcggtcg acgagggccg gtcggtcgcc tgcggtggtt gtctgtgtgt  13140 
gtttgggtct tgcgctgggg gaggcggggt cgaccgctcg cggggttggc gcggtcgccc  13200 
ggcgccgcgc accctccggc ttgtgtggag ggagagcgag ggcgagaacg gagagaggtg  13260 
gtatccccgg tggcgttgcg agggagggtt tggcgtcccg cgtccgtccg tccctccctc  13320 
cctcggtggg cgccttcgcg ccgcacgcgg ccgctagggg cggtcggggc ccgtggcccc  13380 
cgtggctctt cttcgtctcc gcttctcctt cacccgggcg gtacccgctc cggcgccggc  13440 
ccgcgggacg ccgcggcgtc cgtgcgccga tgcgagtcac ccccgggtgt tgcgagttcg  13500 
gggagggaga gggcctcgct gacccgttgc gtcccggctt ccctgggggg gacccggcgt  13560 
ctgtgggctg tgcgtcccgg gggttgcgtg tgagtaagat cctccacccc cgccgccctc  13620 
ccctcccgcc ggcctctcgg ggaccccctg agacggttcg ccggctcgtc ctcccgtgcc  13680 
gccgggtgcc gtctctttcc cgcccgcctc ctcgctctct tcttcccgcg gctgggcgcg  13740 
tgtcccccct ttctgaccgc gacctcagat cagacgtggc gacccgctga atttaagcat  13800 
attagtcagc ggaggaaaag aaactaacca ggattccctc agtaacggcg agtgaacagg  13860 
gaagagccca gcgccgaatc cccgccgcgc gtcgcggcgt gggaaatgtg gcgtacggaa  13920 
gacccactcc ccggcgccgc tcgtgggggg cccaagtcct tctgatcgag gcccagcccg  13980 
tggacggtgt gaggccggta gcggccccgg cgcgccgggc tcgggtcttc ccggagtcgg  14040 
gttgcttggg aatgcagccc aaagcgggtg gtaaactcca tctaaggcta aataccggca  14100 
cgagaccgat agtcaacaag taccgtaagg gaaagttgaa aagaactttg aagagagagt  14160 
tcaagagggc gtgaaaccgt taagaggtaa acgggtgggg tccgcgcagt ccgcccggag  14220 
gattcaaccc ggcggcgcgc gtccggccgt gcccggtggt cccggcggat ctttcccgct  14280 
ccccgttcct cccgacccct ccacccgcgc gtcgttcccc tcttcctccc cgcgtccggc  14340 
gcctccggcg gcgggcgcgg ggggtggtgt ggtggtggcg cgcgggcggg gccgggggtg  14400 
gggtcggcgg gggaccgccc ccggccggcg accggccgcc gccgggcgca cttccaccgt  14460 
ggcggtgcgc cgcgaccggc tccgggacgg ccgggaaggc ccggtgggga aggtggctcg  14520 
gggggggcgg cgcgtctcag ggcgcgccga accacctcac cccgagtgtt acagccctcc  14580 
ggccgcgctt tcgccgaatc ccggggccga ggaagccaga tacccgtcgc cgcgctctcc  14640 
ctctcccccc gtccgcctcc cgggcgggcg tgggggtggg ggccgggccg cccctcccac  14700 
ggcgcgaccg ctctcccacc cccctccgtc gcctctctcg gggcccggtg gggggcgggg  14760 
cggactgtcc ccagtgcgcc ccgggcgtcg tcgcgccgtc gggtcccggg gggaccgtcg  14820 
gtcacgcgtc tcccgacgaa gccgagcgca cggggtcggc ggcgatgtcg gctacccacc  14880 
cgacccgtct tgaaacacgg accaaggagt ctaacgcgtg cgcgagtcag gggctcgtcc  14940 
gaaagccgcc gtggcgcaat gaaggtgaag ggccccgccc gggggcccga ggtgggatcc  15000 
cgaggcctct ccagtccgcc gagggcgcac caccggcccg tctcgcccgc cgcgccgggg  15060 
aggtggagca cgagcgtacg cgttaggacc cgaaagatgg tgaactatgc ttgggcaggg  15120 
cgaagccaga ggaaactctg gtggaggtcc gtagcggtcc tgacgtgcaa atcggtcgtc  15180 
cgacctgggt ataggggcga aagactaatc gaaccatcta gtagctggtt ccctccgaag  15240 
tttccctcag gatagctggc gctctcgctc ccgacgtacg cagttttatc cggtaaagcg  15300 
aatgattaga ggtcttgggg ccgaaacgat ctcaacctat tctcaaactt taaatgggta  15360 
agaagcccgg ctcgctggcg tggagccggg cgtggaatgc gagtgcctag tgggccactt  15420 
ttggtaagca gaactggcgc tgcgggatga accgaacgcc gggttaaggc gcccgatgcc  15480 
gacgctcatc agaccccaga aaaggtgttg gttgatatag acagcaggac ggtggccatg  15540 
gaagtcggaa tccgctaagg agtgtgtaac aactcacctg ccgaatcaac tagccctgaa  15600 
aatggatggc gctggagcgt cgggcccata cccggccgtc gccgcagtcg gaacggaacg  15660 
ggacgggagc ggccgcgggt gcgcgtctct cggggtcggg ggtgcgtggc gggggcccgt  15720 
cccccgcctc ccctccgcgc gccgggttcg cccccgcggc gtcgggcccc gcggagccta  15780 
cgccgcgacg agtaggaggg ccgctgcggt gagccttgaa gcctagggcg cgggcccggg  15840 
tggagccgcc gcaggtgcag atcttggtgg tagtagcaaa tattcaaacg agaactttga  15900 
aggccgaagt ggagaagggt tccatgtgaa cagcagttga acatgggtca gtcggtcctg  15960 
agagatgggc gagtgccgtt ccgaagggac gggcgatggc ctccgttgcc ctcggccgat  16020 
cgaaagggag tcgggttcag atccccgaat ccggagtggc ggagatgggc gccgcgaggc  16080 
cagtgcggta acgcgaccga tcccggagaa gccggcggga ggcctcgggg agagttctct  16140 
tttctttgtg aagggcaggg cgccctggaa tgggttcgcc ccgagagagg ggcccgtgcc  16200 
ttggaaagcg tcgcggttcc ggcggcgtcc ggtgagctct cgctggccct tgaaaatccg  16260 
ggggagaggg tgtaaatctc gcgccgggcc gtacccatat ccgcagcagg tctccaaggt  16320 
gaacagcctc tggcatgttg gaacaatgta ggtaagggaa gtcggcaagc cggatccgta  16380 
acttcgggat aaggattggc tctaagggct gggtcggtcg ggctggggcg cgaagcgggg  16440 
ctgggcgcgc gccgcggctg gacgaggcgc cgccgccctc tcccacgtcc ggggagaccc  16500 
cccgtccttt ccgcccgggc ccgccctccc ctcttccccg cggggccccg tcgtcccccg  16560 
cgtcgtcgcc acctctcttc ccccctcctt cttcccgtcg gggggcgggt cgggggtcgg  16620 
cgcgcggcgc gggctccggg gcggcgggtc caaccccgcg ggggttccgg agcgggagga  16680 
accagcggtc cccggtgggg cggggggccc ggacactcgg ggggccggcg gcggcggcga  16740 
ctctggacgc gagccgggcc cttcccgtgg atcgcctcag ctgcggcggg cgtcgcggcc  16800 
gctcccgggg agcccggcgg gtgccggcgc gggtcccctc cccgcggggc ctcgctccac  16860 
ccccccatcg cctctcccga ggtgcgtggc gggggcgggc gggcgtgtcc cgcgcgtgtg  16920 
gggggaacct ccgcgtcggt gttcccccgc cgggtccgcc ccccgggccg cggttttccg  16980 
cgcggcgccc ccgcctcggc cggcgcctag cagccgactt agaactggtg cggaccaggg  17040 
gaatccgact gtttaattaa aacaaagcat cgcgaaggcc cgcggcgggt gttgacgcga  17100 
tgtgatttct gcccagtgct ctgaatgtca aagtgaagaa attcaatgaa gcgcgggtaa  17160 
acggcgggag taactatgac tctcttaagg tagccaaatg cctcgtcatc taattagtga  17220 
cgcgcatgaa tggatgaacg agattcccac tgtccctacc tactatccag cgaaaccaca  17280 
gccaagggaa cgggcttggc ggaatcagcg gggaaagaag accctgttga gcttgactct  17340 
agtctggcac ggtgaagaga catgagaggt gtagaataag tgggaggccc ccggcgcccg  17400 
gccccgtcct cgcgtcgggg tcggggcacg ccggcctcgc gggccgccgg tgaaatacca  17460 
ctactctcat cgttttttca ctgacccggt gaggcggggg ggcgagcccc gaggggctct  17520 
cgcttctggc gccaagcgtc cgtcccgcgc gtgcgggcgg gcgcgacccg ctccggggac  17580 
agtgccaggt ggggagtttg actggggcgg tacacctgtc aaacggtaac gcaggtgtcc  17640 
taaggcgagc tcagggagga cagaaacctc ccgtggagca gaagggcaaa agctcgcttg  17700 
atcttgattt tcagtacgaa tacagaccgt gaaagcgggg cctcacgatc cttctgacct  17760 
tttgggtttt aagcaggagg tgtcagaaaa gttaccacag ggataactgg cttgtggcgg  17820 
ccaagcgttc atagcgacgt cgctttttga tccttcgatg tcggctcttc ctatcattgt  17880 
gaagcagaat tcaccaagcg ttggattgtt cacccactaa tagggaacgt gagctgggtt  17940 
tagaccgtcg tgagacaggt tagttttacc ctactgatga tgtgttgttg ccatggtaat  18000 
cctgctcagt acgagaggaa ccgcaggttc agacatttgg tgtatgtgct tggctgagga  18060 
gccaatgggg cgaagctacc atctgtggga ttatgactga acgcctctaa gtcagaatcc  18120 
gcccaagcgg aacgatacgg cagcgccgaa ggagcctcgg ttggccccgg atagccgggt  18180 
ccccgtccgt cccgctcggc ggggtccccg cgtcgccccg cggcggcgcg gggtctcccc  18240 
ccgccgggcg tcgggaccgg ggtccggtgc ggagagccgt tcgtcttggg aaacggggtg  18300 
cggccggaaa gggggccgcc ctctcgcccg tcacgttgaa cgcacgttcg tgtggaacct  18360 
ggcgctaaac cattcgtaga cgacctgctt ctgggtcggg gtttcgtacg tagcagagca  18420 
gctccctcgc tgcgatctat tgaaagtcag ccctcgacac aagggtttgt ctctgcgggc  18480 
tttcccgtcg cacgcccgct cgctcgcacg cgaccgtgtc gccgcccggg cgtcacgggg  18540 
gcggtcgcct cggcccccgc gcggttgccc gaacgaccgt gtggtggttg ggggggggat  18600 
cgtcttctcc tccgtctccc gaggacggtt cgtttctctt tccccttccg tcgctctcct  18660 
tgggtgtggg agcctcgtgc cgtcgcgacc gcggcctgcc gtcgcctgcc gccgcagccc  18720 
cttgccctcc ggccttggcc aagccggagg gcggaggagg gggatcggcg gcggcggcga  18780 
ccgcggcgcg gtgacgcacg gtgggatccc catcctcggc gcgtccgtcg gggacggccg  18840 
gttggagggg cgggaggggt ttttcccgtg aacgccgcgt tcggcgccag gcctctggcg  18900 
gccggggggg cgctctctcc gcccgagcat ccccactccc gcccctcctc ttcgcgcgcc  18960 
gcggcggcga cgtgcgtacg aggggaggat gtcgcggtgt ggaggcggag agggtccggc  19020 
gcggcgcctc ttccattttt tcccccccaa cttcggaggt cgaccagtac tccgggcgac  19080 
actttgtttt ttttttttcc cccgatgctg gaggtcgacc agatgtccga aagtgtcccc  19140 
cccccccccc ccccccggcg cggagcggcg gggccactct ggactctttt tttttttttt  19200 
tttttttttt ttaaattcct ggaaccttta ggtcgaccag ttgtccgtct tttactcctt  19260 
catataggtc gaccagtact ccgggtggta ctttgtcttt ttctgaaaat cccagaggtc  19320 
gaccagatat ccgaaagtcc tctctttccc tttactcttc cccacagcga ttctcttttt  19380 
tttttttttt tttggtgtgc ctctttttga cttatataca tgtaaatagt gtgtacgttt  19440 
atatacttat aggaggaggt cgaccagtac tccgggcgac actttgtttt tttttttttt  19500 
tccaccgatg atggaggtcg accagatgtc cgaaagtgtc ccgtcccccc cctccccccc  19560 
ccgcgacgcg gcgggctcac tctggactct tttttttttt tttttttttt tttaaatttc  19620 
tggaacctta aggtcgacca gttgtccgtc tttcactcat tcatataggt cgaccggtgg  19680 
tactttgtct ttttctgaaa atcgcagagg tcgaccagat gtcagaaagt ctggtggtcg  19740 
ataaattatc tgatctagat ttgtttttct gtttttcagt tttgtgttgt tttgtgttgt  19800 
tttgtgttgt tttgttttgt tttgttttgt tttgttttgt tttgttttgt tttgttttgt  19860 
tttgtgttgt gttgtgttgt gttgtgttgg gttgggttgg gttgggttgg gttgggttgg  19920 
gttgggttgg gttgggttgt gttgtttggt tttgtgttgt ttggtgttgt tggttttgtt  19980 
ttgtttgctg ttgttttgtg ttttgcgggt cgaacagttg tccctaaccg agtttttttg  20040 
tacacaaaca tgcacttttt ttaaaataaa tttttaaaat aaatgcgaaa atcgaccaat  20100 
tatccctttc cttctctctc ttttttaaaa attttctttg tgtgtgtgtg tgtgtgtgtg  20160 
tgtgtgtgtg tgcgtgtgtg tgtgtgtgtg cgtgcagcgt gcgcgcgctc gttttataaa  20220 
tacttataat aataggtcgc cgggtggtgg tagcttcccg gactccagag gcagaggcag  20280 
gcagacttct gagttcgagg ccagcctggt ctacagagga accctgtctc gaaaaatgaa  20340 
aataaataca tacatacata catacataca tacatacata catacataca tacatatgag  20400 
gttgaccagt tgtcaatcct ttagaatttt gtttttaatt aatgtgatag agagatagat  20460 
aatagataga tggatagagt gatacaaata taggtttttt tttcagtaaa tatgaggttg  20520 
attaaccact tttccctttt taggtttttt tttttttccc ctgtccatgt ggttgctggg  20580 
atttgaactc aggaccctgg caggtcaact ggaaaacgtg ttttctatat atataaatag  20640 
tggtctgtct gctgtttgtt tgtttgcttg cttgcttgct tgcttgcttg cttgcttgct  20700 
tgcttttttt tttcttctga gacagtattt ctctgtgtaa cctggtgccc tgaaactcac  20760 
tctgtagacc agcctggcct caatcgaact cagaaatcct cctgcctctt gtctacctcc  20820 
caattttgga gtaaaggtgt gctacaccac tgcctggcat tattatcatt atcattatta  20880 
attttattat tagacagaac gaaatcaact agttggtcct gtttcgttaa ttcatttgaa  20940 
attagttgga ccaattagtt ggctggtttg ggaggtttct tttgtttccg atttgggtgt  21000 
ttgtggggct ggggatcagg tatctcaacg gaatgcatga aggttaaggt gagatggctc  21060 
gatttttgta aagattactt ttcttagtct gaggaaaaaa taaaataata ttgggctacg  21120 
tttcattgct tcatttctat ttctctttct ttctttcttt ctttcagata aggaggtcgg  21180 
ccagttcctc ctgccttctg gaagatgtag gcattgcatt gggaaaagca ttgtttgaga  21240 
gatgtgctag tgaaccagag agtttggatg tcaagccgta taatgtttat tacaatatag  21300 
aaaagttcta acaaagtgat ctttaacttt tttttttttt tttctccttc tacttctact  21360 
tgttctcact ctgccaccaa cgcgctttgt acattgaatg tgagctttgt tttgcttaac  21420 
agacatatat tttttctttt ggttttgctt gacatggttt ccctttctat ccgtgcaggg  21480 
ttcccagacg gccttttgag aataaaatgg gaggccagaa ccaaagtctt ttgaataaag  21540 
caccacaact ctaacctgtt tggctgtttt ccttcccaag gcacagatct ttcccagcat  21600 
ggaaaagcat gtagcagttg taggacacac tagacgagag caccagatct cattgtgggt  21660 
ggttgtgaac cacccaccat gtggttgcct gggatttgaa ctcaggatct tcagaagacg  21720 
agtcagggct ctaaaccgat gagccatctc tccagccctc ctacattcct tcttaaggca  21780 
tgaatgatcc cagcatggga agacagtctg ccctctttgt ggtatatcac catatactca  21840 
ataaaataat gaaatgaatg aagtctccac gtatttattt cttcgagcta tctaaattct  21900 
ctcacagcac ctccccctcc cccacactgc ctttctccct atgtttgggt ggggctgggg  21960 
gaggggtggg gtgggggcag ggatctgcat gtcttcttgc aggtctgtga actatttgcg  22020 
atggcctggt tctctgaact gttgagcctt gtctatccag aggctgactg gctagttttc  22080 
tacctgaagt ccctgagtga tgatttccct gtgaattc                          22118 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>6 </s210>
<s211>175 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus Musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 6 
ctcccgcgcg gcccccgtgt tcgccgttcc cgtggcgcgg acaatgcggt tgtgcgtcca     60 
cgtgtgcgtg tccgtgcagt gccgttgtgg agtgcctcgc tctcctcctc ctccccggca    120 
gcgttcccac ggttggggac caccggtgac ctcgccctct tcgggcctgg atccg         175 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>7 </s210>
<s211>755 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 7 
ggtctggtgg gaattgttga cctcgctctc gggtgcggcc tttggggaac ggcggggtcg     60 
gtcgtgcccg gcgccggacg tgtgtcgggg cccacttccc gctcgagggt ggcggtggcg    120 
gcggcgttgg tagtctcccg tgttgcgtct tcccgggctc ttgggggggg tgccgtcgtt    180 
ttcggggccg gcgttgcttg gcttacgcag gcttggtttg ggactgcctc aggagtcgtg    240 
ggcggtgtga ttcccgccgg ttttgcctcg cgtctgcctg ctttgcctcg ggtttgcttg    300 
gttcgtgtct cgggagcggt ggtttttttt tttttcgggt cccggggaga ggggtttttc    360 
cgggggacgt tcccgtcgcc ccctgccgcc ggtgggtttt cgtttcgggc tgtgttcgtt    420 
tccccttccc cgtttcgccg tcggttctcc ccggtcggtc ggccctctcc ccggtcggtc    480 
gcccggccgt gctgccggac ccccccttct gggggggatg cccgggcacg cacgcgtccg    540 
ggcggccact gtggtccggg agctgctcgg caggcgggtg agccagttgg aggggcgtca    600 
tgcccccgcg ggctcccgtg gccgacgcgg cgtgttcttt gggggggcct gtgcgtgcgg    660 
gaaggctgcg cacgttgtcg gtccttgcga gggaaagagg cttttttttt ttagggggtc    720 
gtccttcgtc gtcccgtcgg cggtggatcc ggcct                               755 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>8 </s210>
<s211>463 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 8 
ggccgaggtg cgtctgcggg ttggggctcg tccggccccg tcgtcctccg ggaaggcgtt     60 
tagcgggtac cgtcgccgcg ccgaggtggg cgcacgtcgg tgagataacc ccgagcgtgt    120 
ttctggttgt tggcggcggg ggctccggtc gatgtcttcc cctccccctc tccccgaggc    180 
caggtcagcc tccgcctgtg ggcttcgtcg gccgtctccc cccccctcac gtccctcgcg    240 
agcgagcccg tccgttcgac cttccttccg ccttcccccc atctttccgc gctccgttgg    300 
ccccggggtt ttcacggcgc cccccacgct cctccgcctc tccgcccgtg gtttggacgc    360 
ctggttccgg tctccccgcc aaaccccggt tgggttggtc tccggccccg gcttgctctt    420 
cgggtctccc aacccccggc cggaagggtt cgggggttcc ggg                      463 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>9 </s210>
<s211>378 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 9 
ggattcttca ggattgaaac ccaaaccggt tcagtttcct ttccggctcc ggccgggggg     60 
ggcggccccg ggcggtttgg tgagttagat aacctcgggc cgatcgcacg ccccccgtgg    120 
cggcgacgac ccattcgaac gtctgcccta tcaactttcg atggtagtcg atgtgcctac    180 
catggtgacc acgggtgacg gggaatcagg gttcgattcc ggagagggag cctgagaaac    240 
ggctaccaca tccaaggaag gcagcaggcg cgcaaattac ccactcccga cccggggagg    300 
tagtgacgaa aaataacaat acaggactct ttcgaggccc tgtaattgga atgagtccac    360 
tttaaatcct ttaagcag                                                  378 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>10 </s210>
<s211>378 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 10 
gatccattgg agggcaagtc tggtgccagc agccgcggta attccagctc caatagcgta     60 
tattaaagtt gctgcagtta aaaagctcgt agttggatct tgggagcggg cgggcggtcc    120 
gccgcgaggc gagtcaccgc ccgtccccgc cccttgcctc tcggcgcccc ctcgatgctc    180 
ttagctgagt tgtcccgcgg ggcccgaagc gtttactttg aaaaaattag agttgtttca    240 
aagcaggccc gagccgcctg gataccgcca gctaggaaat aatggaatag gaccgcggtt    300 
cctattttgt ttggttttcg gaactgagcc catgattaag ggaaacggcc gggggcattc    360 
ccttattgcg ccccccta                                                  378 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>11 </s210>
<s211>719 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 11 
ggatctttcc cgctccccgt tcctcccggc ccctccaccc gcgcgtctcc ccccttcttt     60 
tcccctctcc ggaggggggg gaggtggggg cgcgtgggcg gggtcggggg tggggtcggc    120 
gggggaccgc ccccggccgg caaaaggccg ccgccgggcg cacttcaacc gtagcggtgc    180 
gccgcgaccg gctacgagac ggctgggaag gcccgacggg gaatgtggct cggggggggc    240 
ggcgcgtctc agggcgcgcc gaaccacctc accccgagtg ttacagccct ccggccgcgc    300 
tttcgcggaa tcccggggcc gaggggaagc ccgatacccg tcgccgcgct tttcccctcc    360 
ccccgtccgc ctcccgggcg ggcgtggggg tgggggccgg gccgcccctc ccacgcccgt    420 
ggtttctctc tctcccggtc tcggccggtt tggggggggg agcccggttg ggggcggggc    480 
ggactgtcct cagtgcgccc cgggcgtcgt cgcgccgtcg ggcccggggg gttctctcgg    540 
tcacgccgcc cccgacgaag ccgagcgcac ggggtcggcg gcgatgtcgg ctacccaccc    600 
gacccgtctt gaaacacgga ccaaggagtc taacgcgtgc gcgagtcagg ggctcgcacg    660 
aaagccgccg tggcgcaatg aaggtgaagg gccccgtccg ggggcccgag gtgggatcc     719 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>12 </s210>
<s211>685 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Mus musculus </s213>
</s200>
<s400> 12 
cgaggcctct ccagtccgcc gagggcgcac caccggcccg tctcgcccgc cgcgtcgggg     60 
aggtggagca cgagcgtacg cgttaggacc cgaaagatgg tgaactatgc ctgggcaggg    120 
cgaagccaga ggaaactctg gtggaggtcc gtagcggtcc tgacgtgcaa atcggtcgtc    180 
cgacctgggt ataggggcga aagactaatc gaaccatcta gtagctggtt ccctccgaag    240 
tttccctcag gatagctggc gctctcgcaa ccttcggaag cagttttatc cgggtaaagg    300 
cggaatggat taggaggtct tggggccgga aacgatctca aactatttct caaactttaa    360 
atgggtaagg aagcccggct cgctggcgtg gagccgggcg tggaatgcga gtgcctagtg    420 
ggccactttt ggtaagcaga actggcgctg cgggatgaac cgaacgccgg gttaaggcgc    480 
ccgatgccga cgctcatcag accccagaaa aggtgttggt tgatatagac agcaggacgg    540 
tggccatgga agtcggaatc cgctaaggag tgtgtaacaa ctcacctgcc gaatcaacta    600 
gccctgaaaa tggatggcgc tggagcgtcg ggcccatacc cggccgtcgc cggcagtcgg    660 
aacgggacgg gacgggagcg gccgc                                          685 
</s400>
<s200>
<s210>13 </s210>
<s211>5162 </s211>
<s212>DNA </s212>
<s213>Artificial Sequence </s213>
<s220>
<s223>Chimeric bacterial plasmid </s223>
</s220>
</s200>
<s400> 13 
gacggatcgg gagatctccc gatcccctat ggtcgactct cagtacaatc tgctctgatg     60 
ccgcatagtt aagccagtat ctgctccctg cttgtgtgtt ggaggtcgct gagtagtgcg    120 
cgagcaaaat ttaagctaca acaaggcaag gcttgaccga caattgcatg aagaatctgc    180 
ttagggttag gcgttttgcg ctgcttcgcg atgtacgggc cagatatacg cgttgacatt    240 
gattattgac tagttattaa tagtaatcaa ttacggggtc attagttcat agcccatata    300 
tggagttccg cgttacataa cttacggtaa atggcccgcc tggctgaccg cccaacgacc    360 
cccgcccatt gacgtcaata atgacgtatg ttcccatagt aacgccaata gggactttcc    420 
attgacgtca atgggtggac tatttacggt aaactgccca cttggcagta catcaagtgt    480 
atcatatgcc aagtacgccc cctattgacg tcaatgacgg taaatggccc gcctggcatt    540 
atgcccagta catgacctta tgggactttc ctacttggca gtacatctac gtattagtca    600 
tcgctattac catggtgatg cggttttggc agtacatcaa tgggcgtgga tagcggtttg    660 
actcacgggg atttccaagt ctccacccca ttgacgtcaa tgggagtttg ttttggcacc    720 
aaaatcaacg ggactttcca aaatgtcgta acaactccgc cccattgacg caaatgggcg    780 
gtaggcgtgt acggtgggag gtctatataa gcagagctct ctggctaact agagaaccca    840 
ctgcttactg gcttatcgaa attaatacga ctcactatag ggagacccaa gcttggtacc    900 
gagctcggat cgatatctgc ggccgcgtcg acggaattca gtggatccac tagtaacggc    960 
cgccagtgtg ctggaattaa ttcgctgtct gcgagggcca gctgttgggg tgagtactcc   1020 
ctctcaaaag cgggcatgac ttctgcgcta agattgtcag tttccaaaaa cgaggaggat   1080 
ttgatattca cctggcccgc ggtgatgcct ttgagggtgg ccgcgtccat ctggtcagaa   1140 
aagacaatct ttttgttgtc aagcttgagg tgtggcaggc ttgagatctg gccatacact   1200 
tgagtgacaa tgacatccac tttgcctttc tctccacagg tgtccactcc caggtccaac   1260 
tgcaggtcga gcatgcatct agggcggcca attccgcccc tctccctccc ccccccctaa   1320 
cgttactggc cgaagccgct tggaataagg ccggtgtgcg tttgtctata tgtgattttc   1380 
caccatattg ccgtcttttg gcaatgtgag ggcccggaaa cctggccctg tcttcttgac   1440 
gagcattcct aggggtcttt cccctctcgc caaaggaatg caaggtctgt tgaatgtcgt   1500 
gaaggaagca gttcctctgg aagcttcttg aagacaaaca acgtctgtag cgaccctttg   1560 
caggcagcgg aaccccccac ctggcgacag gtgcctctgc ggccaaaagc cacgtgtata   1620 
agatacacct gcaaaggcgg cacaacccca gtgccacgtt gtgagttgga tagttgtgga   1680 
aagagtcaaa tggctctcct caagcgtatt caacaagggg ctgaaggatg cccagaaggt   1740 
accccattgt atgggatctg atctggggcc tcggtgcaca tgctttacat gtgtttagtc   1800 
gaggttaaaa aaacgtctag gccccccgaa ccacggggac gtggttttcc tttgaaaaac   1860 
acgatgataa gcttgccaca acccgggatc caccggtcgc caccatggtg agcaagggcg   1920 
aggagctgtt caccggggtg gtgcccatcc tggtcgagct ggacggcgac gtaaacggcc   1980 
acaagttcag cgtgtccggc gagggcgagg gcgatgccac ctacggcaag ctgaccctga   2040 
agttcatctg caccaccggc aagctgcccg tgccctggcc caccctcgtg accaccctga   2100 
cctacggcgt gcagtgcttc agccgctacc ccgaccacat gaagcagcac gacttcttca   2160 
agtccgccat gcccgaaggc tacgtccagg agcgcaccat cttcttcaag gacgacggca   2220 
actacaagac ccgcgccgag gtgaagttcg agggcgacac cctggtgaac cgcatcgagc   2280 
tgaagggcat cgacttcaag gaggacggca acatcctggg gcacaagctg gagtacaact   2340 
acaacagcca caacgtctat atcatggccg acaagcagaa gaacggcatc aaggtgaact   2400 
tcaagatccg ccacaacatc gaggacggca gcgtgcagct cgccgaccac taccagcaga   2460 
acacccccat cggcgacggc cccgtgctgc tgcccgacaa ccactacctg agcacccagt   2520 
ccgccctgag caaagacccc aacgagaagc gcgatcacat ggtcctgctg gagttcgtga   2580 
ccgccgccgg gatcactctc ggcatggacg agctgtacaa gtaaagcggc cctagagctc   2640 
gctgatcagc ctcgactgtg cctctagttg ccagccatct gttgtttgcc cctcccccgt   2700 
gccttccttg accctggaag gtgccactcc cactgtcctt tcctaataaa atgaggaaat   2760 
tgcatcgcat tgtctgagta ggtgtcattc tattctgggg ggtggggtgg ggcaggacag   2820 
caagggggag gattgggaag acaatagcag gcatgctggg gatgcggtgg gctctatggc   2880 
ttctgaggcg gaaagaacca gctggggctc gagtgcattc tagttgtggt ttgtccaaac   2940 
tcatcaatgt atcttatcat gtctgtatac cgtcgacctc tagctagagc ttggcgtaat   3000 
catggtcata gctgtttcct gtgtgaaatt gttatccgct cacaattcca cacaacatac   3060 
gagccggaag cataaagtgt aaagcctggg gtgcctaatg agtgagctaa ctcacattaa   3120 
ttgcgttgcg ctcactgccc gctttccagt cgggaaacct gtcgtgccag ctgcattaat   3180 
gaatcggcca acgcgcgggg agaggcggtt tgcgtattgg gcgctcttcc gcttcctcgc   3240 
tcactgactc gctgcgctcg gtcgttcggc tgcggcgagc ggtatcagct cactcaaagg   3300 
cggtaatacg gttatccaca gaatcagggg ataacgcagg aaagaacatg tgagcaaaag   3360 
gccagcaaaa ggccaggaac cgtaaaaagg ccgcgttgct ggcgtttttc cataggctcc   3420 
gcccccctga cgagcatcac aaaaatcgac gctcaagtca gaggtggcga aacccgacag   3480 
gactataaag ataccaggcg tttccccctg gaagctccct cgtgcgctct cctgttccga   3540 
ccctgccgct taccggatac ctgtccgcct ttctcccttc gggaagcgtg gcgctttctc   3600 
aatgctcacg ctgtaggtat ctcagttcgg tgtaggtcgt tcgctccaag ctgggctgtg   3660 
tgcacgaacc ccccgttcag cccgaccgct gcgccttatc cggtaactat cgtcttgagt   3720 
ccaacccggt aagacacgac ttatcgccac tggcagcagc cactggtaac aggattagca   3780 
gagcgaggta tgtaggcggt gctacagagt tcttgaagtg gtggcctaac tacggctaca   3840 
ctagaaggac agtatttggt atctgcgctc tgctgaagcc agttaccttc ggaaaaagag   3900 
ttggtagctc ttgatccggc aaacaaacca ccgctggtag cggtggtttt tttgtttgca   3960 
agcagcagat tacgcgcaga aaaaaaggat ctcaagaaga tcctttgatc ttttctacgg   4020 
ggtctgacgc tcagtggaac gaaaactcac gttaagggat tttggtcatg agattatcaa   4080 
aaaggatctt cacctagatc cttttaaatt aaaaatgaag ttttaaatca atctaaagta   4140 
tatatgagta aacttggtct gacagttacc aatgcttaat cagtgaggca cctatctcag   4200 
cgatctgtct atttcgttca tccatagttg cctgactccc cgtcgtgtag ataactacga   4260 
tacgggaggg cttaccatct ggccccagtg ctgcaatgat accgcgagac ccacgctcac   4320 
cggctccaga tttatcagca ataaaccagc cagccggaag ggccgagcgc agaagtggtc   4380 
ctgcaacttt atccgcctcc atccagtcta ttaattgttg ccgggaagct agagtaagta   4440 
gttcgccagt taatagtttg cgcaacgttg ttgccattgc tacaggcatc gtggtgtcac   4500 
gctcgtcgtt tggtatggct tcattcagct ccggttccca acgatcaagg cgagttacat   4560 
gatcccccat gttgtgcaaa aaagcggtta gctccttcgg tcctccgatc gttgtcagaa   4620 
gtaagttggc cgcagtgtta tcactcatgg ttatggcagc actgcataat tctcttactg   4680 
tcatgccatc cgtaagatgc ttttctgtga ctggtgagta ctcaaccaag tcattctgag   4740 
aatagtgtat gcggcgaccg agttgctctt gcccggcgtc aatacgggat aataccgcgc   4800 
cacatagcag aactttaaaa gtgctcatca ttggaaaacg ttcttcgggg cgaaaactct   4860 
caaggatctt accgctgttg agatccagtt cgatgtaacc cactcgtgca cccaactgat   4920 
cttcagcatc ttttactttc accagcgttt ctgggtgagc aaaaacagga aggcaaaatg   4980 
ccgcaaaaaa gggaataagg gcgacacgga aatgttgaat actcatactc ttcctttttc   5040 
aatattattg aagcatttat cagggttatt gtctcatgag cggatacata tttgaatgta   5100 
tttagaaaaa taaacaaata ggggttccgc gcacatttcc ccgaaaagtg ccacctgacg   5160 
tc                                                                  5162
</s400>
</sequence-list-new-rules>
</sequence-cwu>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for detecting or determining delivery and expression of nucleic acid introduced into a cell comprising; 
<claim-text>introducing labelled nucleic acid molecules that encode a reporter gene into cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting labelled cells as an indication of delivery of the nucleic acid into a cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the product of the reporter gene as an indication of DNA expression in the cell, whereby delivery and expression of nucleic acid molecules in the cell is detected or determined. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the labelled cells are detected by flow cytometry, fluorimetry, cell imaging or fluorescence spectroscopy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the labelled cells are detected by flow cytometry </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecule is DNA. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the label is iododeoxyuridine (IdU or IdUrd) or bromodeoxyuridine (BrdU). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the reporter gene encodes a fluorescent protein, or enzyme or antibody. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the enzyme is a luciferase, &bgr;-galactosidase or alkaline phosphatase. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the fluorescent protein is a red, green or blue fluorescent protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, step (a) comprises contacting the nucleic acid molecule is with a delivery agent that comprises a cationic compound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the compound is selected from the group consisting of N-&lsqb;1-(2,3-dioleyloxy)propyl&rsqb;-N,N, N-trimethyl-ammonium chloride (DOTMA), dioleoylphosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), 2,3-dioleyloxy-N-&lsqb;2(spermine-carboxamido)ethyl&rsqb;-N,N-dimethyl-1-propan-aminiumtrifluoroacetate (DOSPA), dioleoyl phosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), C<highlight><subscript>52</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>106</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>178</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>40</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>84</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>P.CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>103</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>7</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>55</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>116</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.6CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>49</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>102</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>44</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>89</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>41</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>78</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>P), C<highlight><subscript>100</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>206</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.8CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>162</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>330</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>22</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>9</subscript></highlight>.13CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H and (1-methyl-4-(1-octadec-9-enyl-nonadec-10-enylenyl) pyridinium chloride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecules are natural chromosomes, artificial chromosomes, fragments of a chromosome or naked DNA that is greater than at least about 0.6 megabase in size. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecules are artificial chromosomes, plasmids, chromosome fragments, naked DNA, or natural chromosomes. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecules are artificial chromosome expression systems (Aces). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cells are eukaryotic cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cells are primary cells, cell lines, plant cells, animal cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cells, are stem cells, nuclear transfer donor cells, tumor cells or transformed cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method for monitoring the delivery of a nucleic acid molecule into a cell comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) labeling the nucleic acid molecule; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) delivering labeled nucleic acid molecule into a cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) detecting labeled nucleic acid molecule in the cells by flow cytometry, fluorimetry, cell imaging or fluorescence spectroscopy, as an indication of delivery of nucleic acid molecule into the cells. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecule is labeled with a thymidine analog. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the thymidine analog is iododeoxyuridine or bromodeoxyuridine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a delivery agent comprises a cationic compound, and the nucleic acid molecule is treated therewith. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the compound is selected from the group consisting of N-&lsqb;1-(2,3-dioleyloxy)propyl&rsqb;-N,N,N -trimethyl-ammonium chloride (DOTMA), dioleoylphosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), 2,3-dioleyloxy-N-&lsqb;2(spermine-carboxamido)ethyl&rsqb;-N,N-dimethyl-1-propan-aminiumtrifluoroacetate (DOSPA), dioleoyl phosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), C<highlight><subscript>52</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>106</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>178</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>40</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>84</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>P.CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>103</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>7</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>55</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>116</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.6CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>49</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>102</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>44</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>89</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>41</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>78</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>P), C<highlight><subscript>100</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>206</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.8CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>162</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>330</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>22</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>9</subscript></highlight>.13CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H and (1-methyl-4-(1-octadec-9-enyl-nonadec-10-enylenyl) pyridinium chloride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecule is a natural chromosome, an artificial chromosome, a fragment of a chromosome or naked DNA that is greater than at least about 0.6 megabase in size. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method for screening agents for the ability to deliver nucleic acid molecule into a cell comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) delivering a labeled nucleic acid molecule into the cell in the presence of the agent; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) determine the number of cells containing the label, as an indication of the ability of the agent to deliver nucleic acid molecule into the cell. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the number of cells is determined by flow cytometry, fluorimetry, cell imaging or fluorescence spectroscopy. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the label is iododeoxyuridine or bromodeoxyuridine. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the agent comprises a cationic compound. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the compound is selected from the group consisting of N-&lsqb;1-(2,3-dioleyloxy)propyl&rsqb;-N,N,N -trimethyl-ammonium chloride (DOTMA), dioleoylphosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), 2,3-dioleyloxy-N-&lsqb;2(spermine-carboxamido)ethyl&rsqb;-N,N-dimethyl-1-propan-aminiumtrifluoroacetate (DOSPA), dioleoyl phosphatidylethanolamine (DOPE), C<highlight><subscript>52</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>106</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>178</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>40</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>84</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>P.CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>50</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>103</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>7</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>55</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>116</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.6CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>49</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>102</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>6</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.4CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>44</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>89</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>5</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>41</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>78</subscript></highlight>NO<highlight><subscript>8</subscript></highlight>P), C<highlight><subscript>100</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>206</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>12</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>S<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.8CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>162</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>330</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>22</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>9</subscript></highlight>.13CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H, C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H C<highlight><subscript>43</subscript></highlight>H<highlight><subscript>88</subscript></highlight>N<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>.2CF<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>CO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>H and (1-methyl-4-(1-octadec-9-enyl-nonadec-10-enylenyl) pyridinium chloride. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecule is a natural chromosome, an artificial chromosome, a fragment of a chromosome or naked DNA, or a plasmid </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the nucleic acid molecule is a natural chromosome, an artificial chromosome, a fragment of a chromosome or naked DNA that is greater than at least about 0.6 megabase in size. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cell is selected from the group consisting of a primary cell, an immortalized cell, an embryonic cell, a stem cell, a transformed cells and a tumor cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cell is selected from the group consisting of a primary cell, an immortalized cell, an embryonic cell, a stem cell, a transformed cells and a tumor cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the cell is selected from the group consisting of a primary cell, an immortalized cell, an embryonic cell, a stem cell, a transformed cells and a tumor cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
</patent-application-publication>
