<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002993</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10141563</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020507</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F04B049/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>417</class>
<subclass>279000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>417</class>
<subclass>280000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>METHODS OF PRESSURE FLUCTUATION DAMPENING</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10141563</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020507</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09860724</doc-number>
<document-date>20010518</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6406273</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Larry</given-name>
<middle-name>Ping-Kwan</middle-name>
<family-name>Wong</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fremont</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>LAM RESEARCH CORPORATION</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MARTINE &amp; PENILLA, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>710 LAKEWAY DRIVE</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 170</address-2>
<city>SUNNYVALE</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94085</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A pressure booster and method for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility is provided. The pressure booster is configured to be connected between the water facility and one or more semiconductor substrate cleaning systems. The pressure booster includes a pump having a pump input that connects to the water facility and a pump output that is configured to produce a fluctuating amplified water pressure that is greater than the water pressure that is supplied by the water facility. Further included is a pressure dampener having a dampener input for accepting the fluctuating amplified water pressure from the pump output. The pressure dampener is configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure. The pressure dampener also has a dampener output. A pressure regulator having a regulator input for receiving the dampener output is also included as part of the pressure booster. The pressure regulator has a regulator output that is configured to supply an amplified water pressure having a substantially reduced pressure fluctuation, and an adjustment control that is connected to the pressure regulator. The adjustment control is provided to enable precision turning of the pressure fluctuations at the output of the pressure regulator, such that a substantially more stable water supply can be provided to the cleaning system(s) connected to the pressure booster. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to water pressure regulating devices, and more particularly to systems for dampening water pressure fluctuations in pump systems used to supply fluids to wafer cleaning stations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> As is well known, semiconductor devices are fabricated from semiconductor wafers, which are subjected to numerous processing operations. These operations include, for example, impurity implants, gate oxide generation, inter-metal oxide depositions, metallization depositions, photolithography pattering, chemical mechanical polishing (CMP), etc. Although these processes are performed in ultra clean environments, the very nature of many of the process operations is to blame for the generation of surface particles. For instance, when CMP operations are performed, a film of particles and/or metal contaminants are commonly left behind. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Because surface particles can detrimentally impact the performance of an integrated circuit device, wafer cleaning operations have become a standard procedural requirement after certain process steps. Although cleaning operations are rather procedural, the equipment and chemicals implemented to perform the actual cleaning are highly specialized. This specialization is important because each wafer, being at different stages of fabrication, represents a significant investment in terms of raw materials, equipment fabrication time, and associated research and development. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> To perform the cleaning operations in an automated manner, fabrication labs typically employ a cleaning system. A typical cleaning system may be, for example, a Synergy&trade; cleaning system from OnTrak&trade;, of Fremont, Calif., which is a subsidiary of Lam Research Corporation, also of Fremont, Calif. A typical Synergy&trade; cleaning system employs two brush stations, where each brush station has a set of brushes for cleaning the top and bottom surfaces of a wafer. Each of the brushes are commonly configured to deliver chemicals and DI water Through-The-Brush, to enhance the cleaning ability of the system. The system typically also includes a spin-rinse station, where a wafer, after being cleaned in the brush stations is rinsed with DI water and dried before completing the cleaning cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As can be appreciated, it is very important that facility lines, which supply the DI water to the cleaning system supply the water at substantially steady water pressure levels. Unfortunately, the facility lines in different fabrication labs vary substantially. In some cases, the pressure levels are too high and in others too low. In those cases where the pressure level is too low, laboratory technicians sometimes connect a water pump between the facility lines supplying the DI water and the cleaning system. Although water pumps are able to increase pressure levels, a downside to water pumps is that large pressure fluctuations are also introduced and passed to the cleaning system. In view of the fact that cleaning systems are designed to carefully apply selected amounts of DI water to produce very specific chemical solutions, (i.e., mixture) pressure fluctuations can cause erratic changes in the concentration of applied solutions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In view of the foregoing, there is a need for pump systems and methods for implementing booster pump systems that minimize the degree of water pressure fluctuations communicated to wafer cleaning systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Broadly speaking, the present invention fills these needs by providing a booster pump that can supply water pressure sensitive cleaning systems with a controlled water pressure flow that has a substantial reduction in pulsating water pressure fluctuations. It should be appreciated that the present invention can be implemented in numerous ways, including as a process, an apparatus, a system, a device, or a method. Several inventive embodiments of the present invention are described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, a pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility is disclosed. The pressure booster includes a pump having a pump input that connects to the water facility and a pump output that is configured to produce a fluctuating amplified water pressure, which is greater than the water pressure that is supplied by the water facility. A pressure dampener having a dampener input for accepting the fluctuating amplified water pressure from the pump output is also included. The pressure dampener is configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure, the pressure dampener also has a dampener output. The pressure booster further includes a pressure regulator having a regulator input for receiving the dampener output. The pressure regulator has a regulator output that is configured to supply a regulated water pressure having a substantially reduced pressure fluctuation. The regulated water pressure is then supplied to a wafer cleaning station, which is configured to perform precision controlled cleaning operations along with other cleaning chemicals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, a pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility is disclosed. The pressure booster is configured to be connected between the water facility and one or more semiconductor substrate cleaning systems. The pressure booster includes a pump having a pump input that connects to the water facility and a pump output that is configured to produce a fluctuating amplified water pressure that is greater than the water pressure that is supplied by the water facility. Further included is a pressure dampener having a dampener input for accepting the fluctuating amplified water pressure from the pump output. The pressure dampener is configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure. The pressure dampener also has a dampener output. A pressure regulator having a regulator input for receiving the dampener output is also included as part of the pressure booster. The pressure regulator has a regulator output that is configured to supply an amplified water pressure having a substantially reduced pressure fluctuation, and an adjustment control that is connected to the pressure regulator. The adjustment control is provided to enable precision tuning of the pressure fluctuations at the output of the pressure regulator, such that a substantially more stable water supply can be provided to the cleaning system(s) connected to the pressure booster. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In yet a further embodiment, a method for dampening a fluctuation in water pressure that is configured to be supplied to a wafer cleaning system is disclosed. The method includes: (a) providing a pump for amplifying a pressure level of water received from a facility connection; (b) connecting a pulse dampener to an output of the pump to partially reduce fluctuations in pressure produced by the pump; (c) connecting a pressure regulator to an output of the pressure regulator; (d) monitoring a pressure gauge at an output of the pressure regulator; and (e) adjusting the pressure regulator until an acceptable reduced pressure fluctuation is monitored at the pressure gauge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Other aspects and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, illustrating by way of example the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be readily understood by the following detailed description in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, and like reference numerals designate like structural elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a pair of cleaning systems that are connected to a water pressure amplifying system, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> show a side view and a top view, respectively, of a wafer cleaning system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a more detailed block diagram of the booster pump, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a more detailed diagram of a pressure regulator implemented by the booster pump of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flowchart diagram illustrating the method operations performed in reducing pressure fluctuation and pulsation in water lines connected to cleaning systems via a booster pump, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An invention is described for a booster pump that can supply water pressure sensitive cleaning systems with a controlled water pressure flow that has a substantial reduction in pulsating water pressure fluctuations. It will be obvious, however, to one skilled in the art, that the present invention may be practiced without some or all of these specific details. In other instances, well known process operations have not been described in detail in order not to unnecessarily obscure the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a pair of cleaning systems being connected to a water pressure amplifying system, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The system includes a booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, which is connected between a facility water supply <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and cleaning systems <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is also configured to receive a controlling air pressure (P<highlight><subscript>v</subscript></highlight>) that is provided from a facility air pressure <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. Therefore, in situations where the facility water pressure <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is below the pressure acceptable for running the cleaning systems <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, a booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is provided to increase the water pressure in a controlled manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As shown, the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is connected to the facility water supply <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> via a connection line <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. The connection line <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is typically a tubing line that is configured to be connected to an appropriate connector at the facility water supply <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. The booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is then configured to produce an amplified pressure <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that is approximately the same or slightly greater than the pressure desired by the cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In a typical Synergy&trade; cleaning system from OnTrack&trade;, the desired pressure is about 50&plusmn;5 PSI. Of course, the lower the pressure swing the better. In this embodiment, the pressure <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is precision controlled internally to the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to reduce water pressure fluctuations that are common in conventional water pressure amplifying systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Each cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, will preferably have a gauge <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively, for determining the water pressure characteristics provided from lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In order to provide the cleaning system with the appropriate controlled pressure for a particular cleaning process, each cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>will also include a pressure regulating valve <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, respectively. The pressure regulating valves <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>will thus enable the adjustment of the water pressure received from the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in order to obtain the optimum cleaning conditions for the system. However, if the water pressure is exhibiting erratic fluctuating swings in pressure, the regulating valves <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> alone are not capable of reducing the rate of fluctuations in the supplied water pressure. Thus, regulating valves <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> are primarily implemented to reduce or increase the pressure magnitude being passed into the cleaning systems <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Although the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is shown supplying water to two different cleaning systems <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> can also be configured to supply water to a single cleaning system, or more than two cleaning systems, depending upon the booster pump specifications. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference> show a side view and a top view, respectively, of a cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. The cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> typically includes a input station <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> where a plurality of wafers may be inserted for cleaning through the system. Once the wafers are inserted into the input station <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, a wafer may be taken from the input station <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and moved into a first brush station <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, where the wafer is scrubbed with selected chemicals and water (e.g., DI water), before being moved to a second brush station <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of a double contained dual brush box <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> After a wafer has been scrubbed in the double contained dual brush box <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, the wafer is moved into a spin station <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> where de-ionized water is sprayed onto the surface of the wafer and spun to dry. After the wafer has been rinsed in spin station <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, an unload handler <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> takes the wafer and moves it into an output station <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. The cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is configured to be programmed and controlled from system electronics <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight>. The cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> also shows the input water line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, which is received from the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The cleaning system <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> also shows the gauge <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and the adjustment valve <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> at the backside of the cleaning station <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a more detailed block diagram of the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is shown receiving the connection line <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> that leads to an input shutoff <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The input shutoff <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> then leads to a tee connection <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> that flows to a pump <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and through a bypass line <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> that leads to a check valve <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. In an exemplary embodiment, the pump <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is a Yamada &frac34;&Prime; NDP-20 Series Pump, wherein about 0.10 gallon is pumped per pump cycle. This exemplary NDP-20 Series Pump can be obtained from Yamada America, Inc., of Elgin, Ill. Of course, the pump may be obtained from other manufacturers and the pumping power can vary depending upon the needs of the cleaning system arrangement. The pump <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is also shown receiving a controlling air pressure P<highlight><subscript>v </subscript></highlight>from the facility air pressure <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In a preferred embodiment, the controlling air pressure is set to about 85 PSI, and it may range between about 20 and 100 PSI. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The pump <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is then configured to output an amplified water pressure to a tee <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> that connects to the bypass line <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight> and a pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. The controlling air pressure P<highlight><subscript>v </subscript></highlight>is also connected to the pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. An exemplary pulse dampener may be an AD-Series (e.g., an AD-25PT) pulsation dampener, which is also manufactured by Yamada America, Inc. The pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations produced by the pump <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Once the water is passed through the pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the water is passed to a line <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> that is communicated to a pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is configured to be adjusted such that a desired pressure (P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) is achieved at the output of the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> then flows the water through a line <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> to enter a filter <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> that filters the water before it is provided to line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a more detailed diagram of the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> is shown receiving water having a fluctuating water pressure through line <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. The pressure regulator is also provided with an adjustment control <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. The adjustment control <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> enables precision control of the pressure level and tuning control over water pressure fluctuations between the water flowing through line <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> and the water flowing out of the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> in line <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight>. The filter <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is shown connected between filter isolation valves <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. The filter isolation valves <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> are used to shut off the conduction of water through the filter <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> when replacement of the filter is desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Also shown is a pressure gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> which is connected to the output of the filter <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> in order to measure the pressure (P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>). The gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> is then connected to a tee that splits the line into the lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. Output shutoffs <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are also provided to enable the sealing off of one of the lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>or <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>depending upon the number of cleaning systems connected to the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The adjustment control <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> can be a manual control, a pressure control, or an electronic control which enables adjustment of the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>. In one exemplary embodiment, the pressure regulator can be a manually controlled UPR Pressure Regular, which can be obtained from Furon Co. of Los Alamitos, Calif. The adjustment control <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> is therefore tuned while at the same time the pressure gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> is monitored. The simultaneous monitoring therefore enables the user to tune the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to the most optimum setting, which will produce the best reduction in water pressure fluctuation. The pressure output from the pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> provided at line <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight> is pictorially shown to have sporadic fluctuations in pressure <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, which may swing up to 20 PSI or greater. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> By monitoring the pressure gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, an adjustment is made through the adjustment control <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> to the pressure regulator <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> until the pressure gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> shows a waveform <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>that exhibits lower magnitude swings, e.g., below about 5 PSI. The fluctuations will also preferably exhibit a wider period between fluctuating transitions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In Tables A and B, which follow below, experimental data is provided to show how precision control of the pressure regular <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>, which is connected after the pulse dampener <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, will provide significant reductions water pressure fluctuations. For ease of reference, when a system is in process mode (i.e., wafers are being cleaned), the system will be designated as &ldquo;P.&rdquo; When the system is in flush/purge mode, the system will be designated as &ldquo;U.&rdquo; When the system is in an idle state, the system will be designated as &ldquo;I.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In Tables A and B, the facility pressure level P<highlight><subscript>0 </subscript></highlight>will be tested at about 45 PSI (i.e., the facility water supply pressure), and the control pressure P<highlight><subscript>v </subscript></highlight>will be set at 85 PSI. The desired and most optimum pressure that is to be delivered to the systems A and B, in this example, is 50 PSI. However, it is more important that the fluctuation and pulsation in water pressure be at a minimum, and if the pressure P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (at system A) and P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (at system B) are too high, another adjustment in pressure can be performed at the pressure regulating valves <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>(as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). That is, if the pressure is higher than 50 PSI, albeit, with substantially reduced fluctuation and pulsation, the pressure can simply be reduced by the pressure regulating valves <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In Table A, the connection line <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, which connects the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the water facility <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, includes a Y adapter using 1&Prime; ID and &frac34;&Prime; tubing. The Y adapter is used when two facility water lines are provided to the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and the Y adapter converts the two lines into a single line. The length of the two &frac34;&Prime; lines between the Y adapter and the water facility <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is about 10 feet. A one foot &frac34;&Prime; line is then connected between the Y adapter and the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The lines <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> connected between the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the systems A and B are set as 45 foot long &frac34;&Prime; tubing and 9 foot long &frac34;&Prime; tubing, respectively. Implementing these connection conditions, the results of Table A were observed when the systems were placed in the various operational conditions. It should be noticed that the measured pressure fluctuations exhibited less than a 5 PSI swing in each of the process combinations.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE A</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TEST SETUP A</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="7">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>System A/</entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>v</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>System B</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>P/P</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>61-62</entry>
<entry>50-53</entry>
<entry>49-51</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>P/U</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>56-59</entry>
<entry>49-53</entry>
<entry>44-46</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>P/I</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>61-63</entry>
<entry>49-53</entry>
<entry>50-54</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>I/I</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>61-67</entry>
<entry>49-53</entry>
<entry>50-54</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In Table B, the connection line <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, which connects the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> to the water facility <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, includes a 10 foot long 1&Prime; tube and a 1 foot long &frac34;&Prime; piece of tubing that couples between the 1&Prime; tubing and the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. The line <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is connected between the booster pump <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and the system A with a 45 foot long &frac34;&Prime; tubing. No connection was made to the system B. Implementing these connection conditions, the results of Table B were observed when the system A was placed in various operational conditions. As shown, during process mode &ldquo;P&rdquo; and during idle mode &ldquo;I&rdquo;, the pressure swings were less than about 2 PSI. During flushing, which is less important in terms of precise wafer cleaning, the measured swing was about 6 PSI.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE B</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TEST SETUP B</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="7">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>System A/</entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight></entry>
<entry>P<highlight><subscript>v</subscript></highlight></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>System B</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
<entry>(PSI)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>P/N/A</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>58-61</entry>
<entry>50-52</entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>U/N/A</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>55-65</entry>
<entry>43-49</entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>I/N/A</entry>
<entry>&tilde;45</entry>
<entry>58-66</entry>
<entry>50-52</entry>
<entry>N/A</entry>
<entry>85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="6" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flowchart diagram <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> illustrating the method operations performed in reducing pressure fluctuation and pulsation in water lines connected to cleaning systems via a booster pump, in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The method begins at an operation <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> where a pump for amplifying a pressure level of water received from a facility connection is provided. The facility connection may be provided from a wall outlet connection or a floor outlet connection which are part of a room where the cleaning system(s) is to be installed. Upon providing the pump, the method will advance to an operation <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> where a pulse dampener is connected to an output of the pump to partially reduce fluctuations in pressure produced by the pump. Once the pulse dampener has been connected, a pressure regulator is connected to an output of the pulse dampener. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Now, a pressure gauge (e.g., gauge <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> for measuring P<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>) at an output of the pressure regulator is monitored to ascertain the fluctuations in pressure after passing through the pressure regulator. The method then moves to an operation <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> where adjustments to the pressure regulator are made until an acceptable reduced pressure fluctuation is monitored at the pressure gauge. As mentioned above, the adjustment may be made by way of a manual adjustment to the pressure regulator, an air controlled adjustment mechanism, or an electronic controlled adjustment unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Once the appropriate adjustment to the pressure regulator has been performed in order to achieve the reduced pressure fluctuation, the booster pump including the pulse dampener, and the pressure regulator, are connected to an appropriate cleaning system for use in accordance with a particular cleaning process. At that point, the method will end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Although the foregoing invention has been described in some detail for purposes of clarity of understanding, it will be apparent that certain changes and modifications may be practiced within the scope of the appended claims. Accordingly, the present embodiments are to be considered as illustrative and not restrictive, and the invention is not to be limited to the details given herein, but may be modified within the scope and equivalents of the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility, comprising: 
<claim-text>a pump having a pump input that connects to the water facility and a pump output that is configured to produce a fluctuating amplified water pressure that is greater than the water pressure that is supplied by the water facility; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure dampener having a dampener input for accepting the fluctuating amplified water pressure from the pump output, the pressure dampener being configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure, the pressure dampener further having a dampener output; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure regulator having a regulator input for receiving the dampener output, the pressure regulator further having a regulator output that is configured to supply an amplified water pressure having a substantially reduced pressure fluctuation. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an adjustment control connected to the pressure regulator. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustment control is selected from the group consisting of a manual control, a pressure driven control, and an electronic driven control. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a pressure gauge being connected to the regulator output, the pressure gauge being configured to display a pressure reading and a fluctuation reading. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a filter, the filter being coupled between the regulator output and the pressure gauge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustment control that is connected to the pressure regulator is set to a position that causes the amplified water pressure to have the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partially reduced pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure can swing up to about 20 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation swings less than about 10 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation swings less than about 5 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the regulator output is connected to one or more wafer cleaning stations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the water pressure is of a de-ionized water pressure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility, the pressure booster is configured to be connected between the water facility and one or more semiconductor substrate cleaning systems, the pressure booster comprising: 
<claim-text>a pump having a pump input that connects to the water facility and a pump output that is configured to produce a fluctuating amplified water pressure that is greater than the water pressure that is supplied by the water facility; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure dampener having a dampener input for accepting the fluctuating amplified water pressure from the pump output, the pressure dampener being configured to partially reduce pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure, the pressure dampener further having a dampener output; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure regulator having a regulator input for receiving the dampener output, the pressure regulator further having a regulator output that is configured to supply an amplified water pressure having a substantially reduced pressure fluctuation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an adjustment control connected to the pressure regulator. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustment control is selected from the group consisting of a manual control, a pressure driven control, and an electronic driven control. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a pressure gauge being connected to the regulator output, the pressure gauge being configured to display a pressure reading and a fluctuation reading. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a filter, the filter being coupled between the regulator output and the pressure gauge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the adjustment control that is connected to the pressure regulator is set to a position that causes the amplified water pressure to have the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the partially reduced pressure fluctuations in the fluctuating amplified water pressure can swing up to about 20 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation swings less than about 10 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A pressure booster for amplifying a water pressure that is supplied by a water facility as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the substantially reduced pressure fluctuation swings less than about 5 PSI. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method for dampening a fluctuation in water pressure that is configured to be supplied to a wafer cleaning system, the method comprises: 
<claim-text>providing a pump for amplifying a pressure level of water received from a facility connection; </claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting a pulse dampener to an output of the pump to partially reduce fluctuations in pressure produced by the pump; </claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting a pressure regulator to an output of the pressure regulator; </claim-text>
<claim-text>monitoring a pressure gauge at an output of the pressure regulator; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting the pressure regulator until an acceptable reduced pressure fluctuation is monitored at the pressure gauge. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A method for dampening a fluctuation in water pressure that is configured to be supplied to a wafer cleaning system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the acceptable reduced pressure fluctuation is below about 5 PSI swings. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method for dampening a fluctuation in water pressure that is configured to be supplied to a wafer cleaning system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>supplying a constant air pressure to the pump. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A method for dampening a fluctuation in water pressure that is configured to be supplied to a wafer cleaning system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the wafer cleaning system includes a cleaning system pressure regulator that is configured to be adjusted to provide internal cleaning system parts a substantially constant water pressure.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002993A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
