<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002110A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002110A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002110</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896211</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04B010/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H04B010/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>154000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>359</class>
<subclass>110000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>RF level stabilization of optical link over temperature</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marcel</given-name>
<middle-name>F.C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schemmann</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Echt</city>
<country-code>NL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Venkatesh</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Mutalik</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Manlius</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Koninklijke Philips Electronics N.V.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Corporate Patent Counsel</name-1>
<name-2>U.S. Philips Corporation</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>580 White Plains Road</address-1>
<city>Tarrytown</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10591</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A radio frequency stabilization system (e.g., for use with a laser transmitter) in an optical communication system is provided. The present invention relates to maintaining a stable RF level in an optical link despite temperature fluctuations, including a transmitter section, a receiver section, a plurality of feedback loops connected to each of the transmitter section and the receiver section. The present invention further discloses a method of stabilizing an RF level in an optical link which method include providing an optical signal transmitter, an optical signal receiver, and a plurality of feedback loops to the optical transmitter section and the optical receiver section. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Technical Field </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to an optical link and more specifically to stabilization of the radio frequency (RF) level of the optical link. A method is also disclosed for utilizing the disclosed system for stabilization of the radio frequency (RF) level of the optical link. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> It is well known that the efficiency of a laser drops over temperature. It is also known that there exists a tracking error that prevents an exact track of the output levels of the laser over temperature. Due to a combination of these two factors, it is observable that the radio frequency (RF) level of an optical level changes significantly over temperature. The above issue affects the modulation depth that is perceived by the laser, which results in the same RF power affecting the laser and inducing certain extra noise conditions such as Rayleigh noise, etc., under certain conditions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In a typical optical link, such as, inter alia, that found in a cable television (CATV) transmission system having a transmitter section and a receiver section, the RF level in the transmitted signal will vary with four parameters, namely, the laser temperature; the transmission link distance; the RF input changes to the transmitter section; and the overall transmission system gain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The RF level at the receiver section will depend mainly on only two parameters, the optical modulation index (OMI) of the laser; and the optical power at the receiver section. However, to a lesser extent, the RF level also depends on the receiver section sensitivity, which changes from wavelength to wavelength; and the matching gain, which is an RF design issue. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is therefore a feature of the present invention to overcome the above shortcomings related to optical links by providing a novel apparatus and method for maintaining the RF level stability over an optical link regardless of the temperature variation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The present invention seeks to reduce the RF level stabilization over temperature utilizing two concepts. First, on the transmitter section end, the invention seeks to maintain the product of the optical modulation depth and the output power constant. On the receiver section end, appropriate circuitry is utilized to pick up and restore any RF level that was not maintained at the transmitter section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention relies on the realization that the product of the laser OMI and the output power impacts the RF level. Accordingly, on the transmitter section side, a sub-5 Mhz carrier is impressed prior to the laser. This modulation is then simultaneously picked up by the laser rear face photo diode monitor and the receiver photo diode. The invention then maintains the RF level of the optical link constant by a combination of control of both the transmitter section front end and the receiver section front end. The advantage of the above procedure is that it monitors the RF level independent of loading on the transmitter, significantly reduces Rayleigh noise in sparsely loaded return systems, and provides mechanics to control the RF level on both the receiver and transmitter ends which is essential to maintaining the optical link below clipping behavior. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention uses three feedback loops in the transmitter section and two feedback loops in the receiver section to both change, when necessary, and maintain at a particular level, RF levels related to an optically transmitted signal. The present invention further allows the following six functions may be performed simultaneously: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> 1. Preserve or change OMI; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> 2. Maintain output power; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> 3. Compensate for temperature changes; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> 4. Compensate for laser or system tracking errors </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> 5. Provide gain at the right place, that is, in the transmitter section or the receiver section, as needed; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> 6. Provide for RF input changes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Finally, the apparatus and method of the present invention may also be used for any laser system, and in particular for Dynamic Noise-power-ratio (NPR) Boost (DNB) or enhancement as disclosed in related US patent application no.(later), filed July, 2001, and incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In a first general aspect, the present invention provides an apparatus for maintaining a stable RF level in an optical link, said apparatus comprising: a transmitter section; a receiver section; a plurality of feedback loops operationally connected to said transmitter section; and a plurality of feedback loops operationally connected to said receiver section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In a second general aspect, the present invention provides a method of stabilizing an RF level in an optical link, said method comprising: providing an optical signal transmitter section; providing an optical signal receiver section; providing a plurality of feedback loops to said optical signal transmitter section; and providing a plurality of feedback loops to said optical signal receiver section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In a third general aspect, the present invention provides an optical transmission system comprising: an optical signal transmitter section; an optical signal receiver section; an RF stabilization system operationally connected to said optical signal transmitter section; and an RF stabilization system operationally connected to said optical signal receiver section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and other features and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following more particular description of embodiments of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The features and inventive aspects of the present invention will become more apparent upon reading the following detailed description, claims, and drawings, of which the following is a brief description. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a current stabilization system according to an embodiment of the related art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a basic RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of an enhanced RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a full RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a functional RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The following is a detailed explanation, with reference to the attached drawings, of the apparatus for RF level stabilization of an optical link over temperature variations, and a method for using the apparatus for RF level stabilization of an optical link over temperature variations, in embodiments of the present invention. It should be noted that the same reference numbers are assigned to components having approximately the same functions and structural features in the following explanation and the attached drawings to preclude the necessity for repeated explanation thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a block diagram representation of a current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for an optical link according to an embodiment of the related art. Current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, an optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and a receiver section <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Transmitter section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> includes an RF path comprising RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>amplifier circuit <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> and RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, which are coupled to a laser transmitter <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>. Laser transmitter <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> is powered by supply voltage V<highlight><subscript>cc</subscript></highlight>, and includes a laser device (e.g., a laser diode) <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, a bias input circuit <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>, and a back facet (BF) monitor circuit <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight>. A first transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> provides a bias current feedback signal <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> from BF monitor circuit <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> signal to the bias input circuit <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight>. The bias current feedback bias signal <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> derived from the back facet monitor circuit <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> represents the DC current range of the laser device <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The output signal from the laser device <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> is carried over optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and is received by receiver section <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Receiver section <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> includes photo diode circuit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>, which is controlled by optical modulation voltage (OMV) control circuit <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, and powered by supply voltage V<highlight><subscript>cc</subscript></highlight>. The output of photo diode circuit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is coupled to an RF path comprising RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>amplifier circuit <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> may be comprised of, inter alia, erbium doped fiber amplifiers (EDFAS), semiconductor optical amplifiers (SOA&apos;s), and various kinds of optical fiber, such as, inter alia, single mode fiber (SMF) or dispersion compensating fiber (DCF). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> An inherent drawback in the related art current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, is that this current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> cannot compensate for two well known phenomenon, namely that the efficiency of a laser drops as temperature rises, and that tracking errors exist which prevent an exact tracking of the output level of the laser as the temperature varies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> block diagram representation of a basic RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>level stabilization system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> according to an embodiment of the present invention. Basic RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>level stabilization system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter section <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, an optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and a receiver section <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight>. Transmitter section <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is similar to transmitter section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Receiver section <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> is similar to receiver section <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> of the current stabilization system <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, except that receiver section <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> includes an added first receiver feedback loop <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> First receiver feedback loop <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> provides a feedback signal from the optical modulation voltage (OMV) control circuit <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> to the RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. The optical modulation voltage (OMV) control circuit <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> produces an feedback signal which is proportional to changes in the optical level of the photo diode <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. First receiver feedback loop <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> includes a feedback attenuation circuit <highlight><bold>265</bold></highlight> to scale the feedback signal to a level compatible with RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> This embodiment (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) compensates for changes in the optical power, including the tracking error. However, this embodiment cannot accommodate changes in the optical modulation index caused by changes in laser efficiency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of an enhanced RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. Enhanced RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter section <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, an optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and a receiver section <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight>. Transmitter section <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> is similar to transmitter section <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of the basic RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, except that transmitter section <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> includes an added second transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>. Receiver section <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight> is similar to receiver section <highlight><bold>205</bold></highlight> of the basic RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Second transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> provides a feedback attenuation circuit <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> from the back facet monitor <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> to the RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. The feedback attenuation circuit <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> produces an attenuated feedback signal which is proportional to the bias current from the laser. Second transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> includes a feedback attenuation circuit <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> to scale the feedback signal to a level compatible with RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. Feedback attenuation circuit <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> may include a diode, transistor, or other attenuation circuit (e.g., a PIN transistor circuit). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a full RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. Full RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter section <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>, an optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and a receiver section <highlight><bold>405</bold></highlight>. Transmitter section <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> is similar to transmitter section <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the enhanced RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, except that two additions have been made. First, an oscillator circuit <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> has been added to the output of the RF attenuator <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Oscillator circuit <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> introduces a signal tone of e.g., 100 kHz or thereabouts. Second, a third transmitter feedback circuit <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> has been added which provides a feedback loop from the back facet monitor <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> to the RF attenuator <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Third transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>455</bold></highlight> provides a feedback signal from the back facet monitor <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight> to the RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>attenuator <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Third transmitter feedback loop <highlight><bold>455</bold></highlight> includes a filter oscillator circuit, an RF detector circuit, and a feedback attenuator circuit. The RF in the transmitted signal is sensed by the RF detector circuit of feedback circuit <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> and is then fed to the feedback attenuator circuit which reduces or increases attenuation as needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Receiver section <highlight><bold>405</bold></highlight> is similar to receiver section <highlight><bold>305</bold></highlight> of the enhanced RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, except that receiver section <highlight><bold>405</bold></highlight> includes an added second receiver feedback circuit <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> which provides a feedback loop from the photo diode <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to the RF<highlight><subscript>OUT </subscript></highlight>attenuator <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>. A signal from photo diode circuit <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is fed to second receiver feedback circuit <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> which includes a filter oscillator circuit, an RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>sensor circuit, and a feedback attenuator circuit. The RF in the received signal is sensed by the RF detector circuit of second receiver feedback circuit <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight> and is then fed to the feedback attenuator circuit which reduces or increases attenuation as needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a block diagram representation of a functional RF level stabilization system according to an embodiment of the present invention. Functional RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> includes a transmitter section <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>, an optical link <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, and a receiver section <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>. Transmitter section <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> is similar to transmitter section <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of the full RF level stabilization system <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, except that modulation and demodulation circuits have been added to the transmitter section <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> and the receiver section <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The modulation circuit <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> coupled to the oscillator circuit <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> of the transmitter section <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> enables the output signal from oscillator circuit <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> to be selectively varied, which in turn will selectively vary the output at node <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of the RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. This operation effectively tunes the output of the RF<highlight><subscript>IN </subscript></highlight>attenuator circuit <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, and hence the laser device <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Similarly, the demodulation circuit <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight> in receiver section <highlight><bold>505</bold></highlight> provides demodulation of the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention have been disclosed. A person of ordinary skill in the art would realize, however, that certain modifications would come within the teachings of this invention. Therefore, the following claims should be studied to determine the true scope and content of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for maintaining a stable RF level in an optical link, said apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a transmitter section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiver section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of feedback loops operationally connected to said transmitter section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of feedback loops operationally connected to said receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops perform at least one function selected from the group consisting of: 
<claim-text>i. RF level stabilization effects; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. preserve or change optical modulation index (OMI); </claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. adjust output power; </claim-text>
<claim-text>iv. compensate for temperature changes; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v. compensate for laser or system tracking errors; </claim-text>
<claim-text>vi. provide gain at proper places in circuitry; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>vii. provide RF input changes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops operationally connected to said transmitter section include a first, second, and third transmitter section feedback loops. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops operationally connected to said receiver section include a first and second receiver section feedback loops. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first transmitter feedback loop is a constant power feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second transmitter feedback loop is a bias current feedback loop connected between the transmitter section and an attenuation circuit in an RF path. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the attenuation circuit is a PIN transistor circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second transmitter feedback loop is a bias current feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the third transmitter feedback loop provides an RF level from a back facet monitor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, further including an oscillator operationally connected to said third transmitter feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator is characterized by an operational frequency of about 100 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator has an output signal, said output signal coupled to an input of an RF detector, said RF detector having an attenuating output proportional to said input, and said attenuating output coupled to the attenuation circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first receiver feedback loop is an optical modulation voltage (OMV) feedback loop, said optical modulation voltage feedback loop connected to RF circuitry in said receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second receiver feedback loop is an oscillator signal feedback loop, said oscillator feedback loop connected to RF circuitry in said receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator feedback loop includes an oscillator tuned to a frequency of about 100 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator feedback loop includes a device to modulate said oscillator feedback. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of stabilizing an RF level in an optical link, said method comprising: 
<claim-text>providing an optical signal transmitter section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing an optical signal receiver section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a plurality of feedback loops to said optical signal transmitter section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a plurality of feedback loops to said optical signal receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops perform at least one function selected from the group consisting of: 
<claim-text>i. RF level stabilization effects; </claim-text>
<claim-text>ii. preserve or change optical modulation index (OMI); </claim-text>
<claim-text>iii. adjust output power; </claim-text>
<claim-text>iv. compensate for temperature changes; </claim-text>
<claim-text>v. compensate for laser or system tracking errors; </claim-text>
<claim-text>vi. provide gain at proper places in circuitry; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>vii. provide RF input changes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops operationally connected to said transmitter section include a first, second, and third transmitter feedback loops. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the feedback loops operationally connected to said receiver section include a first and second receiver feedback loops. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first transmitter feedback loop is a constant power feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second transmitter feedback loop is a bias current feedback loop connected between the transmitter section and an attenuation circuit in an RF path. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the attenuation circuit is a PIN transistor circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second transmitter feedback loop is a bias current feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the third transmitter feedback loop provides an RF level from a back facet monitor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, further including an oscillator operationally connected to said third transmitter feedback loop. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator is characterized by an operational frequency of about 100 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator has an output signal, said output signal coupled to an input of an RF detector, said RF detector having an attenuating output proportional to said input, and said attenuating output coupled to the attenuation circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first receiver feedback loop is an optical modulation voltage (OMV) feedback loop, said optical modulation voltage feedback loop connected to RF circuitry in said receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second receiver feedback loop is an oscillator signal feedback loop, said oscillator feedback loop connected to RF circuitry in said receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator feedback loop includes an oscillator tuned to a frequency of about 100 kHz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said oscillator feedback loop includes a device to modulate said oscillator feedback. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. An optical transmission system comprising: 
<claim-text>an optical signal transmitter section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical signal receiver section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an RF stabilization system operationally connected to said optical signal transmitter section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an RF stabilization system operationally connected to said optical signal receiver section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The optical transmission system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the optical transmission system is a cable television (CATV) system.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002110A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
