<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004497A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004497A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004497A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004497A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004497A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004497A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004497A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004497A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004497A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004497A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004497</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10154383</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020523</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61B017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>001000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>200</class>
<subclass>086500</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>318</class>
<subclass>551000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60293674</doc-number>
<document-date>20010525</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Chappuis</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Marietta</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>THOMAS, KAYDEN, HORSTEMEYER &amp; RISLEY, LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>100 GALLERIA PARKWAY, NW</address-1>
<address-2>STE 1750</address-2>
<city>ATLANTA</city>
<state>GA</state>
<postalcode>30339-5948</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus comprising a first pedal platform having at least one pedal configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position. At least one outlet, configured to releasably receive a power plug of a surgical power tool, is in communication with the first pedal platform. The pedal apparatus receives power from a power supply and conducts the power to the plug that is in communication with the outlet when the operational pedal is disposed in the depressed position, thereby powering the surgical power tool. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to copending U.S. provisional application entitled, &ldquo;Universal Surgical Power Tool Foot Pedal Apparatus,&rdquo; having Serial No. 60/293,674, filed May 25, 2001, which is entirely incorporated herein by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">TECHNICAL FIELD </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention is generally related to tools and apparatuses implemented in medical procedures, such as surgery, and, more particularly, is related to a universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Many surgical procedures require the use of multiple surgical tools. Some of the tools are somewhat simple, such as non-powered blades, scalpels and scrapers, while other tools, such as burrs and saws, are powered by various power sources, such as, for example, electrically or pneumatically. Use of such power tools requires a surgeon using the tool to turn the power to the tool on and off as necessary to activate and deactivate the tool during a surgical procedure. However, the surgeon&apos;s hands are often not available for such tasks. As a result, the power supply to many of these tools can be controlled with a pedal located on the floor underneath a table on which the patient is positioned. The pedal is designed to be operated by the surgeon&apos;s foot. Typically the surgeon depresses the pedal to supply power to the tool and releases the pedal to discontinue the supply of power to the tool. The pedals are typically not fixed in any particular location on the floor and are free to move around the floor. As such, the pedals move around within and out of reach, or at least easy reach, of the surgeon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> During any given surgical procedure a doctor may use a combination of several non-powered and powered tools. The non-powered tools are typically laid out on a table, tray, or the like and handed to the surgeon as needed by other personnel present in the operating room, such as a surgical assistant, a nurse, or the like. The use of several power tools, however, often results in a plurality of pedals strewn about the operating room floor underneath the operating table. During the course of the surgical procedure, as a result of repeated use and switching from pedal to pedal, the pedals often become tangled together or moved to a location underneath the table where the surgeon has difficulty finding the pedal without looking down at the floor or asking an assistant for help. Additionally, with the pedals being easily moved about the floor, when the surgeon does locate a pedal, it can be difficult for the surgeon to determine which pedal the surgeon&apos;s foot is touching. As such, it can be difficult to ascertain which tool will be powered when a given pedal is depressed, without also looking down. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> It is also common during surgical procedures for the surgeon to alternate between working on various sides of the operating table. However, traditional surgical power tools that are operable by a foot pedal generally have only one pedal. Therefore, it is necessary to move the pedal from one side of the table to the other side of the table as required during the procedure. Where multiple surgical power tools are used in one procedure, moving the pedals back and forth from one side of the table to the other further contributes to the tangling of the pedals as well as the difficulty in locating and identifying the pedals by touch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Thus, a heretofore unaddressed need exists in the industry to address the aforementioned deficiencies and inadequacies. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus. Briefly described, in architecture, one embodiment of the apparatus, among others, can be implemented as follows: a universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus comprising a first pedal platform having at least one pedal configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position. At least one outlet, configured to releasably receive a power plug of a surgical power tool, is in communication with the first pedal platform. The pedal apparatus receives power from a power supply and conducts the power to the plug that is in communication with the outlet when the pedal is disposed in the depressed position, thereby powering the surgical power tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Other systems, methods, features, and advantages of the present invention will be or become apparent to one with skill in the art upon examination of the following drawings and detailed description. It is intended that all such additional systems, methods, features, and advantages be included within this description, be within the scope of the present invention, and be protected by the accompanying claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Many aspects of the invention can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily to scale, emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present invention. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a top plan view of an embodiment of the universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of an embodiment of the universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates a perspective view of an embodiment of the universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a top plan view of an embodiment of the universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates an embodiment of the universal surgical power tool foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of the present invention. The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes at least one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> having at least one pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> disposed thereon. The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can have a plurality of pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> disposed thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is preferred that each of the plurality of pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be arranged and configured to facilitate user identification of the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by touch alone. The pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can differ in size (shown), elevation from a top surface of the platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) or include a pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> disposed thereon, for example, but not limited to, a different textured pedal surface on each pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can also serve as an anti-skid surface. Alternatively, the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can include a means for user identification of the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> by touch disposed on the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> itself. The pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; is disposed on the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> substantially adjacent the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> with which the identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; is associated. The pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; disposed on the platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is a raised, or alternatively depressed, area. Each identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; differs from other identifiers <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; in shape, size, orientation, or any suitable manner such that identification of an adjacent pedal can be readily ascertained. As illustrated, for example, each pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; differs in orientation from the other. Where the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> (as described below) it is preferable that a pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; be substantially similar for pedals on each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> capable of operating a common tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further includes at least one plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is disposed on the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is adapted to receive a power line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of a surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> desired to be operated by a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. It is preferable that the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of plug receivers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> having various configurations being adapted to releasably receive power plugs of various configurations. It should be noted that the plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can also be separate from the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> itself can receive power directly from a power source, such as an electrical power source or a pneumatic power source. Alternatively, power can be transmitted through the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to a surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In this configuration the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> receives power from a power source, such as an electrical power source or a pneumatic power source. Power is transmitted through the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is operated as desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can include more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Where the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> from each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can be used to operate a common surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. As an example, the broader of the two pedals illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> could both be adapted to control the power feed to a burr. This arrangement facilitates the positioning of pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in more than one location underneath an operating table, or any desirable location on the operating room floor. The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can also be adapted to control operating room environment. More specifically, a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be wired to control lights, temperature, music, etc. in an operating room. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be positioned underneath an operating table on which a patient lies for surgery such that the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are disposed on opposing sides of an axis running the length of the operating table. The apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be positioned on the operating room floor or movably fixed to the operating room table. It is preferable that where the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is fixed to the operating table, such as to the underside, or any suitable area on the table, that the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is movable in various direction, such as laterally, upwardly, downwardly, etc. A pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can be disposed substantially adjacent each side of the operating table. Any given surgical tool can be operated from either side of the operating table without moving the pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> from one side of the table to the other. Where a plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprise the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> can be connected together with a platform coupling <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The coupling <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> comprises a plurality of coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and coupling bolts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A pair of coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> extends from each of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Each pair of coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> are preferably arranged in a substantially parallel configuration. The coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> are spaced apart with greater space therebetween than a distance between coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to be disposed opposite. The coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> having greater space therebetween engage the opposing coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> at the outside of each respective coupling arm <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> extending from the opposing pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Each opposing coupling arm <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is fixed to the substantially corresponding coupling arm <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the opposing pair of coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The coupling arms <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> can be fixed by bolts <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, or any suitable means. It should be noted that any suitable means coupling the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> together is within the spirit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Where more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, it is preferable that a power line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime; communicates with a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, a power plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is disposed substantially adjacent each pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and represents a power plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> associated with the substantially adjacent pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Power line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> communicates with the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> smaller in size (also indicated by a pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; arranged horizontal the width of pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) of each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Power line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>&prime; communicates with the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> larger in size (also indicated by a pedal identifier <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; arranged vertical the width of pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) of each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a second embodiment of the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime; of the present invention. The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime; includes a pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime; having at least one pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> disposed thereon. The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; and the foot pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> both slant downward to facilitate ease of use and operation by the foot of the user. The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can, however, comprise any suitable configuration. It is preferable that the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; includes more than one pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> disposed thereon and that each of the plurality of pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is identifiable by touch. The pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> can be distinguishable from each other by varying in size (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), by varying in elevation from a top surface of the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; (shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), by a combination thereof, or any suitable means. This configuration can also include the tactile identifiers <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can also include a selector switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The selector switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is adapted to alternate a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> between operating one surgical tool and operating another surgical tool, thereby allowing one pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> to interchangeably operate more than one surgical tool. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> tool plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> can be located on a top face of the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;. Although a tool plug receiver <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is illustrated in both <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> as being disposed on said pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;, it should be understood that any means by which power can be communicated though a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> disposed on the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; to a surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> such that the pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can be used to control the power supply to the tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is within the spirit of the present invention. It should also be noted that although the configuration in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is illustrated comprising one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;, this second embodiment can also include more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;. The plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can be fixed together and arranged and configured such that the pedals <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of both pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; operate the same set of surgical tools. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> More specifically, more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can comprise the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime; of the present invention. A pair of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; can be fixed together with a coupling <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, or the like. The pair of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; are also preferably wired together such that a given surgical tool can be operated with a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> illustrates another embodiment of the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; of the present invention. The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; includes at least one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; comprising at least one pedal aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A preferred pedal aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is arranged and configured to releasably receive a pedal (not shown) to which a surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is attached. In this configuration the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; acts as a rack or a holder for supporting and separating pedals for operating surgical tools that are marketed and sold with a pedal. It is preferable that the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; includes a plurality of pedal apertures <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in order to organize and separate a plurality of surgical power tool pedals. The pedal apertures <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> can be uniform in size and shape or configured of various sizes and shapes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; can also include a plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime;, where each of the plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; includes at least one pedal aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Each of the plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; can also include a plurality of pedal apertures <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Where more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; is provided, it is preferable that a surgical tool <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can have a pedal (not shown) disposed in a pedal aperture <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of each of the plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime;. The plurality of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; can be fixed together. A splitter (not shown) as known to one skilled in the art, can be used to adapt a surgical tool having one pedal to having a pair of pedals such that one pedal can be disposed in one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime; and the other pedal can be disposed in the other pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A pair of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; can be fixed together with a coupling <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, or any suitable means. It is also preferable that a pair of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; are wired together such that a surgical power tool can be operated by a pedal <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> on each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> An identification means (such as an identification means <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>&prime; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) can be disposed on the pedal platform <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. It is preferable that a plurality of identification means (not shown), each at least slightly differing from the others, is disposed substantially adjacent each of the pedal apertures <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> disposed in the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime;. A preferred identification means (such as, for example but not limited to, a tactile identifier) facilitates a user distinguishing between pedals disposed in each of the pedal apertures <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by touch. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates another embodiment of the foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; of the present invention. The foot pedal apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; comprises at least one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime;, a frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and a power supply <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; comprises any of the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; previously described herein. Furthermore, it should be noted that although two pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; are shown, any desired number of pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; can be included. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is preferably adjustable such that the location of each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; can be adjusted to a desired position and fixed in that desired position. The frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and a pedal platform extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The pedal platform extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extends from each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; and intersects the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> at any suitable angle to the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. It should also be noted that although there are two pedal platform extensions <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> illustrated (one extending from each pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; to the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) there can be any suitable number of pedal platform extensions <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. It is preferable that each pedal platform extension <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is movably attached to the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> with a connector <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> that allows the position of the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; to be adjustable both along the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as well as toward and away from the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The connector <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is preferably adapted to fix the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; in the desired position with respect to the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A power supply <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is positioned substantially adjacent the frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and comprises a plurality of tool plug receivers <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The power supply <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> provides power for electrical as well as pneumatic surgical tools. Frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> can be positioned, and optionally fixed, on the operating room floor or to a portion of the operating table, such as the underside or any suitable location. It is preferable that the where the frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is fixed to the operating table that the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; are additionally movable upwardly and downwardly. The pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&prime;&Prime; can also optionally be adapted to control the environmental conditions in the operating room, for example but not limited to, the lighting, temperature, music, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In a method of use of the apparatus <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime;, the frame <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is positioned beneath an operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is positioned running substantially parallel the length of the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The pedal platform extensions <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> extend substantially perpendicular to the length of the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and away from the primary track <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> such that the pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; is positioned along the side of the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Where more than one pedal platform <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; is present, some of the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; can be positioned toward one side of the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and some of the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> positioned toward the opposing side of the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; are arranged at any location with respect to the operating table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> or at any location with respect to each other. It is further preferable that the pedal platforms <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>&Prime;&Prime; can be positioned as desired with respect to both the length and the width of the table <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and fixed in the that desired position prior to surgery beginning. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> It should be emphasized that the above-described embodiments of the present invention, particularly, any &ldquo;preferred&rdquo; embodiments, are merely possible examples of implementations, merely set forth for a clear understanding of the principles of the invention. Many variations and modifications may be made to the above-described embodiment(s) of the invention without departing substantially from the spirit and principles of the invention. All such modifications and variations are intended to be included herein within the scope of this disclosure and the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Therefore, having thus described the invention, at least the following is claimed: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pedal platform comprising at least one pedal being adapted to move between a depressed position and a released position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one outlet being in communication with said first pedal platform, said outlet being adapted to releasably receive a power plug of a surgical power tool; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said pedal apparatus is arranged and configured to receive power from a power supply and conduct the power to said plug disposed in communication with said outlet when said pedal is disposed in the depressed position, thereby powering the surgical power tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedal is arranged and configured to substantially correspond to a human foot wherein said pedal can be moved between the depressed position and the released position with a human foot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform further comprises an identifier whereby a user can identify the pedal without viewing the pedal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said identifier comprises a tactile identifier whereby a user can identify said pedal by feel without viewing the pedal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform comprises a plurality of pedals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform further comprises a plurality of identifiers, each of said plurality of identifiers being different from each of the other of said plurality of identifiers, whereby a user can identify which of said plurality of pedals the user is engaging without looking at said pedals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plurality of outlets disposed on said first pedal platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said plurality of outlets are arranged and configured to releasably receive plugs of various configurations. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedal comprises a substantially ergonomic shape for a human foot. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said surgical power tool is pneumatically powered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said surgical power tool is electrically powered. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a selector switch having multiple settings and being movable between said multiple settings; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said pedal being arranged and configured to operate a plurality of surgical power tools, said plurality of surgical power tools being a number substantially equivalent to number of multiple settings of said selector switch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said selector switch alternates application of said pedal between operating one of said plurality of surgical power tools and another of said plurality of surgical power tools. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of clam <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second pedal platform comprising at least one pedal being arranged and configured to alternate between a depressed position and a released position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pedal platform being in communication with a power supply, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second pedal platform is arranged and configured to receive power from a power supply and conduct the power to said surgical power tool when said pedal is disposed in the depressed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second pedal platform further comprises an identifier whereby a user can identify said pedal without viewing said pedal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said identifier comprises a tactile identifier whereby a user can identify said pedal by feel without viewing said pedal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second pedal platform comprises a plurality of pedals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second pedal platform further comprises a plurality of identifiers, each identifier being different from the other identifiers whereby a user can identify which of the plurality of pedals the user is engaging for use without viewing said pedals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second selector switch disposed on said second pedal platform, said second selector switch having multiple settings and being movable between said multiple settings; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said pedal of said second pedal platform being arranged and configured to operate a plurality of surgical power tools, said plurality of surgical power tools being a number substantially equivalent to a number of multiple settings of said selector switch; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second selector switch alternates application of said pedal between one of said plurality of surgical power tools and another of said plurality of surgical power tools. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pedal platform means comprising at least one operational means, said operational means being arranged and configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a power outlet means for releasably receiving a plug means of a surgical power tool, said power outlet means being in communication with said operational means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said apparatus is arranged and configured to receive power from a power supply means and conduct the power to said plug means disposed in communication with said operational means when said operational means is disposed in the depressed position, thereby operating the surgical power tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform means further comprises an identification means for identification of said operational means by a user without viewing said operational means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform means comprises a plurality of operational means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first pedal platform means comprises a plurality of identification means, each of said plurality of identification means being different from each of the other of said plurality of identification means whereby a user can identify which of said plurality of operational means the user is engaging for operation without viewing said operational means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a switch means for alternating the application of an operational means; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said operational means being arranged and configured to operate a plurality of surgical power tools; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said switch means alternates the application of said operational means between operating one of said plurality of surgical power tools and another of said plurality of surgical power tools. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plurality of power outlet means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second pedal platform means comprising at least one operational means, said operational means being arranged and configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said operational means of said second pedal platform means receiving power from a power supply and being arranged and configured to operate the surgical power tool. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A universal surgical power tool pedal apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pedal platform having a pedal aperture disposed therein, said pedal aperture being arranged and configured to releasably receive and support a pedal therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said pedal being arranged and configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position, wherein said pedal operates a power surgical tool when said pedal is disposed in the depressed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a pedal identifier disposed on said first pedal platform such that said pedal identifier is substantially aligned with said pedal aperture; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said pedal identifier is arranged and configured to indicate to a user the location of said pedal aperture without the user viewing the apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedal identifier comprises a tactile identifier. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of pedal apertures disposed in said first pedal platform, each of said plurality of pedal apertures being arranged and configured to releasably receive and support a separate pedal therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said pedals being arranged and configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position individually, wherein each of said pedals operates a separate power surgical tool when said pedal is disposed in the depressed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of pedal identifiers disposed on said first pedal platform such that each of said plurality of pedal identifiers is substantially aligned with a different one of said plurality of pedal apertures; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said plurality of pedal identifiers is arranged and configured to indicate to a user the location of each pedal aperture without looking at the apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second pedal platform having a pedal aperture disposed therein, said pedal aperture being arranged and configured to releasably receive and support a pedal therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said pedal being arranged and configured to be movable between a depressed position and a released position, wherein said pedal operates a power surgical tool when said pedal is disposed in the depressed position. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a pedal identifier disposed on said second pedal platform such that said pedal identifier is substantially aligned with said pedal aperture; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said pedal identifier is arranged and configured to indicate to a user the location of said pedal aperture without looking at the apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of pedal apertures disposed in said second pedal platform, each of said plurality of pedal apertures being arranged and configured to releasably receive and support a separate pedal therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said pedals is arranged and configured to operate a different surgical power tool and the same power tool as a pedal disposed in a corresponding pedal aperture disposed in said first pedal platform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a plurality of pedal identifiers such that each of said plurality of pedal identifiers is substantially aligned with a different one of said plurality of pedal apertures; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said plurality of pedal identifiers is arranged and configured to indicate to a user the location of one of said pedal apertures without looking at the apparatus. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. A control apparatus for an operating room, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pedal platform comprising at least one pedal being adapted to move between a depressed position and released position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said pedal is adapted to be operated by a human foot and said pedal is adapted to operate a powered element in the operating room. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The control apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedal is adapted to operate a surgical power tool. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The control apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pedal is adapted to operate lights in the operating room. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. A frame for an operating room controller, comprising: 
<claim-text>a pedal platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a platform extension extending from said pedal platform; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a primary track being fixed to said pedal extension opposing said pedal platform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The frame of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said platform extension is movably fixed to said primary track. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The frame of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said frame is fixed to a portion of floor in the operating room. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The frame of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said frame is fixed to a portion of a table in an operating room, wherein said table is adapted to support a patient thereon. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The frame of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second pedal platform; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pedal platform extension being fixed to said primary track opposing said pedal platform. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The frame of claim <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, wherein said primary track is disposed between said pedal platform and said second pedal platform.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004497A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004497A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004497A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004497A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004497A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
