<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030005188A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005188A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005188A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005188A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005188A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005188A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005188A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005188A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030005188A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030005188A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030005188</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10000626</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011030</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06F003/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>710</class>
<subclass>015000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly for a data storage device</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302530</doc-number>
<document-date>20010702</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Bijan</given-name>
<family-name>Tehrani</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Shrewsbury</city>
<state>MA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Arthur</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Clark</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Oklahoma City</city>
<state>OK</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hardy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Oklahoma City</city>
<state>OK</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>SEAGATE TECHNOLOGY LLC</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Randall K. McCarthy</name-1>
<name-2>CROWE &amp; DUNLEVY, P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1800 Mid-America Tower</address-1>
<address-2>20 North Broadway</address-2>
<city>Oklahoma City</city>
<state>OK</state>
<postalcode>73102</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly including a printed circuit board for supporting additional components of the dual serial port assembly, a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector secured to the printed circuit board for passing data between the printed circuit board and a personal computer. A first serial port connector mounted on the printed circuit transferring communication data and synchronization data between the personal computer and the data storage device through a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip, and a second serial port connector mounted on the printed circuit board passing a performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device through a serial-to-parallel converter to the personal computer. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to United States Provisional Application No. 60/302,530 filed Jul. 2, 2001, entitled DUAL SERIAL PORT REAL-TIME PCI DATA ACQUISITION INTERFACE.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the field of magnetic data storage devices, and more particularly, but not by way of limitation, to a dual serial port data acquisition interface for a data storage device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Data storage devices are used for data storage in modem electronic products ranging from digital cameras to computer systems and networks. A typical data storage device includes a head-disc assembly (HDA), housing the mechanical portion of the data storage device, and a printed circuit board assembly (PCBA) attached to the head-disc assembly, for controlling operations of the head-disc assembly and providing a communication link between the data storage device and its host. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Typically, a head-disc assembly comprises a recording surface on a disc affixed to a spindle motor assembly for rotation at a constant speed and an actuator assembly positionably controlled by a closed loop servo system. The actuator assembly supports a read/write head that traverses a plurality of radially spaced, generally concentric information tracks on the recording surface. Data storage devices using magneto resistive read/write heads typically use an inductive element, or writer, to write data to the information tracks and a magneto resistive element, or reader, to read data from the information tracks during data storage device operations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> One type of data recorded to and read from the information tracks is servo data. Servo data, including a physical track identification portion (also referred to as a servo track number or physical track number), is written to the recording surface to define each specific physical track written on the recording surface. Typically a servo track writer is used in writing a predetermined number of physical tracks, also referred to as servo tracks, to each recording surface during the manufacturing process for use by the closed loop servo system in controlling the position of the read/write head relative to the recording surface during operation of the data storage device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> High performance data storage devices of the present generation typically achieve areal bit densities measured in several gigabits per square centimeter, Gbits/cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. Higher recording densities can be achieved by increasing the number of bits stored along each information track, or bits per inch (BPI), and by increasing the number of information tracks provided per unit width, or tracks per inch (TPI), across each recording surface. Increased BPI generally requires improvements in the read/write channel electronics to enable the data to be written (and subsequently read) at a correspondingly higher frequency. Higher TPI generally requires improvements in servo control systems to enable the read/write heads to be more precisely positioned relative to the information tracks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> To facilitate improvements in servo control systems, and to prepare for high volume data storage device manufacturing, the servo system of the data storage device needs to be characterized, and its operating points defined. However, the servo system is complex and requires real time interface capability to fully identify, evaluate and test weaknesses, and strengths. The need for a real time interface poses a challenging problem. Typical interfaces provided for the user (SCSI, ATA, and Fiber Channel) do not yield the required bandwidth (data rate) to accomplish the task. These interfaces provide limited visibility and interaction with the servo microprocessor and application specific integrated circuits (ASIC). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Therefore, challenges remain and a need persists for methods and test systems for measuring the attributes, boundaries and operational characteristics of present generation servo systems on a real time basis. A measured response of the servo control circuit to the combination of factors, along with a characterization of specific limitations of the servo control circuit system, are key pieces of information needed to develop manufacturing test regimens for both present and future generation data storage devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An ability to measure, map and diagnose the attributes of the servo system in a data storage device, in real time, holds the capability of developing more efficient and focused manufacturing test systems for improved control over the data storage device manufacturing process. It is to this and other features and advantages set forth herein that embodiments of the present invention are directed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Embodiments of the present invention address some of the difficulties and problems discussed above, by providing a dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly for characterizing a servo control circuit of a data storage device. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly includes a printed circuit board for supporting various components of the dual serial port assembly. Included among those components are a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector for passing data between the printed circuit board and a personal computer, a first serial port connector mounted on the printed circuit board transferring communication and synchronization data between the personal computer and the data storage device through a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip, and a second serial port connector mounted on the printed circuit board passing performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device through a serial-to-parallel converter to the personal computer for analysis by the personal computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> These and various other features and advantages which characterize the present invention will be apparent from a reading of the following detailed description and a review of the associated drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a partial cutaway top plan view of a data storage device with a servo control circuit characterized by a dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a functional block diagram of control circuitry of the data storage device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a functional block diagram of a dual serial port interface assembly used in characterizing the servo control circuit of the data storage device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a servo control circuit performance measurement station for measuring an operating point of the servo control circuit of the data storage device of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Referring to the drawings in general, and more particularly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, depicted therein is a top view of a data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> having a cover partially removed to display the components thereof. The data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is also sometimes referred to as disc drive <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and is constructed in accordance with the present invention. Numerous details of and variations for the construction of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are not included in the following description, which, are well-known to those skilled in the art, and believed unnecessary for the purpose of describing the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a basedeck <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> supporting various data storage device components, including a spindle motor assembly <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> supporting an axially aligned rotatable recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and forming a disc stack <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Adjacent the disc stack <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is an actuator assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> also referred to as a head stack assembly (HSA), which pivots about a bearing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> in a rotary fashion. The head stack assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> includes an actuator arm <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> that supports a load arm <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, which in turn supports a read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> corresponding to the rotatable recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The rotatable recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is divided into a plurality of concentric information tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (also known as data tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> only one of which is depicted) over which the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is positionably located. The information tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> are caused to contain head position control information written to embedded servo sectors (not separately depicted). Between the embedded servo sectors are data sectors used for storing bit patterns or data (not separately depicted). The read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> includes a read element or reader offset radially and laterally from a write element or writer (neither separately depicted). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> During write operations of the data storage devices <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the writer writes data to the concentric information tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, while the reader controls the positioning of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the concentric information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. During read operations of the data storage devices <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, the reader controls the positioning of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the concentric information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> being read and reads the information thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The term &ldquo;servoing,&rdquo; also referred to as position-controlling as used herein, means maintaining control of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the rotating recording surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> during operation of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Servoing to or on a selected information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the head stack assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is controllably positioned by a primary actuator motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> (also referred to as a voice coil motor assembly, VCM). The voice coil motor assembly <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> includes an actuator coil <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> immersed in a magnetic field generated by a magnet assembly <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. A pair of steel plates <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> (pole pieces) mounted above and below the actuator coil <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> provides a magnetically permeable flux path for a magnetic circuit of the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> During operation of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, current is passed through the actuator coil <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> forming an electromagnetic field which interacts with the magnetic circuit of the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, causing the actuator coil <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> to move relative to the magnet assembly <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>. As the actuator coil <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> moves, the head stack assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> pivots about the bearing assembly <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, causing the head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to move over the rotatable recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, thereby enabling the head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> to interact with the information tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the recording surfaces <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> To provide the requisite electrical conduction paths between the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> and read/write circuitry of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, read/write head wires (not depicted) of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> are affixed to a read/write flex circuit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The read/write flex circuit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is routed from the load arms <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> along the actuator arms <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> and into a flex circuit containment channel <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The read/write flex circuit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is secured to a flex connector body <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. The flex connector body <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> supports the read/write flex circuit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> during passage of the read/write flex circuit <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> through the basedeck <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and into electrical communication with a printed circuit board assembly (PCBA not depicted). The printed circuit board assembly is mounted to the underside of the basedeck <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The flex circuit containment channel <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> also supports read/write signal circuitry including a preamplifier/driver (preamp) <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> used to condition read/write signals passed between the read/write circuitry (not depicted) and the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>. The printed circuit board assembly provides the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> with read/write circuitry, which controls the operation of the head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, as well as other interface and control circuitry for use by the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in controlling data storage device operations and communicating with its host. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> has two primary assemblies, the PCBA (not depicted) and a head disc assembly (HDA) <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> attached to the PCBA. Typically, included within the head disc assembly <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are the head stack assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> and the disc stack <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, position-controlling of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> is provided by the positioning mechanism (not separately depicted) operating under the control of servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> programmed with servo control code, which forms the servo control loop. The servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> typically may include a control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, a demodulator (demod) <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>, an application specific integrated circuit (ASIC) hardware-based servo controller (&ldquo;servo engine&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, a digital signal processor (DSP) <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, a volatile memory (VM) <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, a digital to analog converter (DAC) <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> and a motor driver circuit <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Optionally, the functions of servo engine <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, DSP <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and volatile memory <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> may all be contained within the control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>. The components of the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> utilize track following algorithms to effect control of the head stack assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and more specifically for controlling the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in position-controlling the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the selected information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The demodulator <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> conditions head position control information transduced from the information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the rotatable recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> to provide position information of the read/write head <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The servo engine <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> generates servo control loop values used by control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> in generating command signals used by the voice coil motor <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in executing seek commands, and in executing track following commands during data transfer operations. The command signals generated by the control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> are converted by the digital to analog converter <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight> to analog control signals for use by the motor driver circuit <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> in position-controlling the read/write heads <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight> relative to the selected information track <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> during track following, and relative to the recording surface <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> during track to track seek functions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> and the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> each communicate with an asynchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> for sending and receiving asynchronous, full-duplex serial port signals operating in excess of mega-bits per second (3 Mb/sec). The full-duplex serial port signals are used to provide communication and disc synchronization among the control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, and an external dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly (not depicted). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The external dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly is used for characterizing the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of a data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Additionally, the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> provides high-speed, one way, synchronous signals to a synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> supports data collected from the drive at intervals of 1&times; or 2&times; for each of the servo sectors (not separately depicted) of the information tracks <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for characterization and operating point definition of the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> by a personal computer (not depicted). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts a dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> having a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip (UART) <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> mounted on a printed circuit board <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>. The programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> controls a computer&apos;s interface (not separately depicted) when attached to the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Specifically, it provides the computer with an RS-232C data terminal equipment (DTE) interface so that it can &ldquo;talk&rdquo; to and exchange data with data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> As part of this interface, the programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> converts the bytes it receives from the computer along parallel circuits into a single serial bit stream for outbound transmission, converts the serial bit stream into the bytes that the computer handles on inbound transmissions, adds a parity bit (if the feature is selected or &ldquo;turned on&rdquo;) on outbound transmissions and checks the parity of incoming bytes (if selected). Additionally, the programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> discards the parity bit from inbound transmissions, adds start and stop delineators on outbound transmissions and strips them from inbound transmissions, and may handle other kinds of interrupts and device management that require coordinating the computer&apos;s speed of operation with device speeds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> also depicts an asynchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and a synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, each attached to the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>. An asynchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> attaches to the asynchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> at a first end. At its distal end, the asynchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> attaches to the asynchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The asynchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> supports the communication between the programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and the application specific integrated circuit (ASIC) hardware-based servo controller (&ldquo;servo engine&rdquo;) <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, as well as the control processor <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> is also depicted by <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> to be mounted to the printed circuit board <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> and attached to a first end of a synchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>, which is likewise attached on its distal end to the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> at synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The synchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> supports communication between a serial-to-parallel converter <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> and the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> through a high-speed, one way, and synchronous serial port utilized to collect data from the drive at intervals of 1&times; or 2&times; per servo sector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> There are two basic types of serial communications, synchronous and asynchronous. With synchronous communications, two devices initially synchronize themselves to each other, and then continually send characters to stay in synchronization. Even when data is not being sent, a constant flow of bits allows each device to know where the other is at any given time. That is, each character that is sent is either actual data or an idle character. Synchronous communications allows faster data transfer rates than asynchronous methods, because additional bits to mark the beginning and end of each data byte are not required. The serial ports on IBM compatible personal computers (PCs) are asynchronous devices and therefore only support asynchronous serial communications. As such the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> is provided to form an interface between a personal computer (not depicted) and the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> for the purpose of characterizing the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight> of the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Asynchronous means &ldquo;no synchronization&rdquo;, and thus does not require sending and receiving idle characters. However, the beginning and end of each byte of data must be identified by start and stop bits. The start bit indicates when the data byte is about to begin and the stop bit signals when it ends. The requirement to send these additional two bits cause asynchronous communications to be slightly slower than synchronous communications; however, it has the advantage that the processor does not have to deal with the additional idle characters. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An asynchronous line that is idle is identified with a value of 1, (also called a mark state). By using this value to indicate that no data is currently being sent, the devices are able to distinguish between an idle state and a disconnected line. When a character is about to be transmitted, a start bit is sent. A start bit has a value of 0, (also called a space state). Thus, when the line switches from a value of 1 to a value of 0, the receiver is alerted that a data character is about to come down the line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Besides the synchronization provided by the use of start and stop bits, an additional bit called a parity bit may be optionally transmitted along with the data. A parity bit affords a small amount of error checking, to help detect data corruption that might occur during transmission. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Both the serial-to-parallel converter <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight> and the programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> communicate with a personal computer (not depicted) via a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> (PC-PCI). Although many computer users think of the peripheral component interconnect standard as a way of laying out electrical wires, it is actually a complete set of specifications defining how different parts of a computer should interact, and specifically, how the command structures for various devices communicate with the computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> depicts a servo control circuit performance measurement station <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> with a personal computer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> supporting a chassis <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight>. The chassis <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> supports several assemblies of the servo control circuit performance measurement stations <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> including a motherboard <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> for processing measurement information collected from the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The motherboard <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight> includes a peripheral component interconnect (PCI) expansion slot <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, used to interface the personal computer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> with the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> is used in characterizing and defining the operating points of the servo control circuit <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> communicates with the personal computer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> through the peripheral component interconnect expansion slot <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The synchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> is attached on a first end to the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> via the synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) and communicates on a distal end with the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The asynchronous serial port cable <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> attached on a first end to the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> via the synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) and communicates on a distal end with the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> via synchronous serial port connector <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> also depicts a monitor <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> communicating with the motherboard <highlight><bold>186</bold></highlight>, and a keyboard <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> communicating with the motherboard. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> It will be noted that for clarity of the disclosure, the present embodiment depicts that the data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, while undergoing a characterization of its servo control circuit <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, is external to the personal computer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, and only one data storage device <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is depicted connected to the personal computer <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. The structure selected for disclosure of the present invention was selected for ease of presentation and is but one of multiple configurations in which numerous changes would readily suggest themselves to those skilled in the art, without changing the functionality of the servo control circuit performance measurement stations <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>. Nor does the structure selected for presentation impart limitations on the scope and spirit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention is directed to a dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly, such as <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, for characterizing a servo control circuit, such as <highlight><bold>148</bold></highlight>, of a data storage device, such as <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly comprises a printed circuit board, such as <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight>, for supporting components of the dual serial port assembly; a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector, such as <highlight><bold>188</bold></highlight>, communicating with the printed circuit board for passing data between a personal computer, such as <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>, and the data storage device; a first serial port connector, such as <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight>, mounted on the printed circuit board for passing communication and synchronization data between the data storage device and personal computer; a second serial port connector, such as <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, mounted on the printed circuit board for passing a performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device to the personal computer; a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip, such as <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight>, attached to the printed circuit board and communicating with the first serial port connector for controlling an interface between the personal computer and the data storage device; and a serial-to-parallel converter, such as <highlight><bold>178</bold></highlight>, attached to the print circuit board and communicating with the second serial port connector for converting the performance data of the servo control circuit from a serial communication data string to a parallel communication data string for analysis by the personal computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> It will be clear that the present invention is well adapted to attain the ends and advantages mentioned as well as those inherent therein. While presently preferred embodiments have been described for purposes of this disclosure, numerous changes may be made which will readily suggest themselves to those skilled in the art and which are encompassed in the spirit of the invention disclosed and as defined in the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly for characterizing a servo control circuit of a data storage device comprising: 
<claim-text>a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing data between a personal computer and the data storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing communication and synchronization data between the data storage device and the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing a performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device to the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip supported by the printed circuit board and communicating with the first serial port connector for controlling an interface between the personal computer and the data storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a serial-to-parallel converter supported by the print circuit board and communicating with the second serial port connector for converting the performance data of the servo control circuit from a serial communication data string to a parallel communication data string for analysis by the personal computer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the first serial port connector is a synchronous serial port connector and supports a synchronous serial port cable for connection to the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the second serial port connector is an asynchronous serial port connector and supports an asynchronous serial port cable for connection to the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the programed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip supports an asynchronous full-duplex serial communication protocol. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> in which the serial-to-parallel converter supports a high-speed, one-way, synchronous serial communication protocol used for collecting data from the servo control circuit of the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> in which the asynchronous full-duplex serial port operates at a rate in excess of a three mega-bits per second. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> in which the synchronous serial port performs an acquisition of a real-time data from a servo sector of the data storage device at an interval of once per servo sector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> in which the synchronous serial port performs an acquisition of a real-time data from a servo sector of the data storage device at an interval of twice per servo sector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A servo control circuit performance measurement station for measuring an operating point of a servo control circuit of a data storage device comprising: 
<claim-text>a personal computer with a chassis for supporting assemblies of the servo control circuit performance measurement station; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motherboard with a personal computer peripheral component interconnect expansion slot attached to the chassis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly for characterizing the servo control circuit of the data storage device, the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly communicating with the personal computer through the peripheral component interconnect expansion slot; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a synchronous serial port cable attached on a first end to the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly and communicating on a distal end with the data storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an asynchronous serial port cable attached on a first end to the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly and communicating on a distal end with the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The servo control circuit performance measurement station of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> in which the data storage device is external to the personal computer chassis. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The servo control circuit performance measurement station of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> further including a monitor communicating with the motherboard and still further including a keyboard communicating with the motherboard. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The servo control circuit performance measurement station of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> in which the dual serial port data acquisition interface assembly comprises: 
<claim-text>a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing data between a personal computer and the data storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing communication and synchronization data between the data storage device and the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing a performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device to the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip supported by the printed circuit board and communicating with the first serial port connector for controlling an interface between the personal computer and the data storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a serial-to-parallel converter supported by the print circuit board and communicating with the second serial port connector for converting the performance data of the servo control circuit from a serial communication data string to a parallel communication data string for analysis by the personal computer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A data storage device comprising: 
<claim-text>a basedeck; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a spindle motor assembly supported by the basedeck; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a disc attached to the spindle motor assembly, the disc having an information track for data storage; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator assembly supported by the basedeck and having a read/write head rotationally positionable adjacent the recording surface, the read/write head comprising a read element for reading data from the information track and a write element offset from the read element for writing data to the information track; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a printed circuit board assembly attached to the basedeck; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a servo control circuit supported by the printed circuit board assembly position-controlling the actuator assembly, the servo control circuit characterized by means for characterizing the servo control circuit of the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> in which the means for characterizing the servo control circuit of the data storage device comprises: 
<claim-text>a printed circuit board; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a personal computer peripheral component interconnect connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing data between a personal computer and the data storage device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing communication and synchronization data between the data storage device and the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second serial port connector supported by the printed circuit board for passing a performance data of the servo control circuit from the data storage device to the personal computer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip supported by the printed circuit board and communicating with the first serial port connector for controlling an interface between the personal computer and the data storage device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a serial-to-parallel converter supported by the printed circuit board and communicating with the second serial port connector for converting the performance data of the servo control circuit from a serial communication data string to a parallel communication data string for analysis by the personal computer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> in which the first serial port connector is a synchronous serial port connector and supports a synchronous serial port cable for connection to the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> in which the second serial port connector is an asynchronous serial port connector and supports an asynchronous serial port cable for connection to the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> in which the programmed universal asynchronous receiver/transmitter microchip supports an asynchronous full-duplex serial communication protocol. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> in which the serial-to-parallel converter supports a high-speed, one-way, synchronous serial communication protocol used for collecting data from the servo control circuit of the data storage device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference> in which the asynchronous full-duplex serial port operates at a rate in excess of a three mega-bits per second. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> in which the synchronous serial port performs an acquisition of a real-time data from a servo sector of the data storage device at an interval of once per servo sector. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The data storage device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference> in which the synchronous serial port performs an acquisition of a real-time data from a servo sector of the data storage device at an interval of twice per servo sector.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030005188A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030005188A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030005188A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030005188A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030005188A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
