<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000106A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000106A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000106A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000106A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000106A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000106A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000106A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000106A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000106A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000106A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000106</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10212340</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020805</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>F26B011/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>034</class>
<subclass>598000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Combination closed-circuit washer and dryer</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10212340</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020805</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09610035</doc-number>
<document-date>20000705</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6434857</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<middle-name>David</middle-name>
<family-name>Anderson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Wichita Falls</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Matthew</given-name>
<middle-name>David</middle-name>
<family-name>Anderson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Wichita Falls</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Charles D. Gunter, Jr.</name-1>
<name-2>Bracewell &amp; Patteson, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 1600</address-1>
<address-2>201 Main Street</address-2>
<city>Fort Worth</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75102-3105</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A combination closed-circuit washer and dryer apparatus having a washing cycle and a drying cycle. The apparatus comprises a unitary housing having a tub and a tumbler within the tub, the tub also having an air inlet and air outlet which allows air to flow through the tub, wherein air flowing from the air inlet is in communication with the tumbler. The apparatus also includes a desiccant recharging system located within the unitary housing having a entrance and an exit, the entrance coupled to the air outlet and the exit coupled to the air entrance, thus allowing a continuous flow of air through the system. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/610,035, filed Jul. 5, 2000, entitled &ldquo;Combination Closed-Circuit Washer and Drier.&rdquo;</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a combination clothing washer and dryer apparatus. More specifically, the present invention relates to a clothing dryer that incorporates the use of solid phase desiccants such as molecular sieves or silica gel to remove water from the drying air, the drying air being recirculated through the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Clothing washers and dryers are well known in the art. Given the desire to save space, there is increasing interest in combination washer and dryer systems, wherein a single rotating drum is utilized for both the washing of clothing and drying of the clothing in one unit. However, since most prior art clothing dryers pull surrounding air into the dryer that is then heated, passed over the wet clothing where water is transferred to the hot air, and the air then vented to the outside, an external air vent is thus required. This method not only requires a vent pipe to the outside, it requires air to be flowing into the building or dwelling containing the dryer. This requires continuous cooling or heating of the replacement air by the air conditioner or heater in the building. This extra air cooling or heating is expensive. Further, the drying time and efficiency is limited by the amount of external air that can be pulled into the dryer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Convenience for household use is gained by replacing the entire washer and dryer system into a ventless system that uses the same volume of air in the entire drying process. This is typically accomplished in one combination washer/dryer unit, such as that marketed by EQUATOR Corporation (Houston, Tex.). The lint taken up from the drying clothing is absorbed by a spray of water through the heated air coming from the clothing, thus trapping the lint in the cooling water and then discharging the water from the unit. However, the problem with this ventless system is that the drying time is impractically long&mdash;from two to three hours. This is because the mister only removes some of the moisture in the hot air by condensation, but still leaves some of the moisture in the air only to be heated and passed back over the clothing to be dried. And, while increasing the air flow may improve the drying time, this also necessitates an increase in the misting to the point of being impractical to achieve the desired drying time because of the large amount of misting water required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is desirable in a ventless washer-dryer system to have an alternative method of drying the heated, moisture laden air from the clothing that does not rely entirely on the mister sprayer. Desiccants, and in particular, solid desiccants such as molecular sieves, are one alternative. Solid desiccants such as 3A, 4A, and 5A molecular sieves and silica gel can selectively adhere water molecules to the surfaces and interiors of the lattice structure. These desiccants have been used to dry air in applications such as in Larsson (U.S. Pat. No. 4,581,047), who discloses a method of using a solid desiccant in a compressed air line to dry the air, the desiccant being in the form of a cartridge that is replaced once the desiccant has reached its adsorptive capacity. However, it is desirable to regenerate the desiccant and thus re-use the same desiccant many times, especially in residential washer and dryer units. Reversible removal of the adsorbed water is necessary to make the use of solid desiccants practical in a washer-dryer system that is to be used repeatedly in an economical manner. This is typically accomplished by passing relatively dry air over the desiccant while heating the desiccant, as, for instance, is disclosed by Shultz (U.S. Pat. No. 4,023,940). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> There are several other methods of regenerating or &ldquo;charging&rdquo; solid desiccants. A simple, rechargeable silica gel solid desiccant is disclosed by Peace in U.S. Pat. No. 4,756,726. Another is disclosed by Inglis et al. (U.S. Pat. No. 4,805,317), which uses microwave irradiation of the sieves to drive the water off. Meckler (U.S. Pat. No. 4,887,438) discloses a desiccant assisted air conditioner that uses hot air from the cooling condenser to heat and charge the desiccant. Finally, McFadden (U.S. Pat. No. 5,373,704) uses desiccants in a dehumidifier for home use, the desiccant being regenerated by regenerative air heated by such means as an electric heating coil or natural gas. All of these prior art methods employ the use of air or heated air passed over the moist desiccant that is supplied by external air. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> A combination washer-dryer that uses the same volume of air to dry clothing (hence, ventless) through the use of solid desiccants has not been disclosed. There is a need for a practical to use washer and dryer combination that has no vent, thus allowing more convenient use in apartment or condominium dwellings. Further, there is a need for a combination washer-dryer that operates efficiently and has a reasonably short drying time for the clothing. The present invention is directed towards such use. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> It is therefore one object of the present invention to provide a combination washer and dryer apparatus for washing clothing and other water-washable articles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> It is another object of the present invention to provide a combination washer-dryer apparatus that is made ventless by utilizing the same or substantially the same volume of air during the drying cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> It is yet another object of the present invention to provide a solid desiccant clothes drying system that can be re-used by being dehumidified during the wash cycle of the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> These and other objects of the present invention are achieved by providing a combination closed-circuit washer and dryer apparatus having a washing cycle and a drying cycle. The apparatus comprises a unitary housing having a tub and a tumbler within the tub, the tub also having an air inlet and air outlet which allows air to flow through the tub, wherein air flowing from the air inlet is in communication with the tumbler. The apparatus also includes a desiccant charging system located within the unitary housing having a entrance and an exit, the entrance coupled to the air outlet and the exit coupled to the air entrance, thus allowing a continuous flow of air through the system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The desiccant charging system has a solid desiccant packed within a desiccant housing, typically molecular sieves of a pore diameter of between about 3 and 5 Angstroms. The desiccant housing typically has a thickness that is at least twice as long as the length to increase the adsorption efficiency. Further, the desiccant charging system includes a dehumidification means, wherein the dehumidification means can be a heating coil, a vacuum apparatus, a microwave generator, or any combination of these. In yet a third embodiment, the desiccant charging system has a water mist spray apparatus to facilitate the removal of water from the air flow during the washing and drying cycles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Additional objects, features and advantages will be apparent in the written description which follows. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The novel features believed characteristic of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. The invention itself however, as well as a preferred mode of use, further objects and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description of an illustrative embodiment when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the washing cycle of the combination washer-dryer of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the drying cycle of the combination washer-dryer of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a variation of the combination washer-dryer of Figure; and. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a schematic view of another embodiment of the combination washer-dryer of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The present invention is a combination closed-circuit washer and dryer apparatus having a washing cycle and a drying cycle. The apparatus is preferably used to wash and dry clothing and other water-washable articles in a unitary washer-dryer that uses the same or substantially the same volume of air to dry the clothing throughout the washing and drying process. Thus, little or no air is drawn from the surroundings of the apparatus once it is closed. The apparatus is designed to use traditional washing detergents in the washing cycle, and have various washing cycles that are operated by mechanical and/or electronic timing devices known in the art. For example, there may be a regular wash cycle and a delicate wash cycle, each cycle having washing and rinsing cycles therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The combination washer-dryer apparatus includes a tub and tumbler made from such materials as stainless steel to house the clothing to be washed and water within the tub. The tub and tumbler therein is part of a washing cycle air pathway and a drying cycle air pathway, each pathway allowing the same volume of air to flow there through. Thus, once clothing is placed within the tub, a doorway seals the tub and all air pathways to create a volume of air within the apparatus tub and air pathways that is then circulated to dry the clothing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The washing cycle air pathway includes a desiccant charging system and the drying cycle air pathway comprises the tub having a tumbler therein also in air-flow communication with the desiccant charging system. In one embodiment of the invention, a diverting valve diverts the flow of air from the drying cycle air pathway to the washing cycle air pathway during the washing cycle in order to dehydrate the air passing there through. The air is then re-diverted to facilitate the drying cycle. During both cycles, the air passes through a desiccant which is part of the desiccant recharging system. In another embodiment of the invention, the diverter valve is not used. The air flow through the desiccant serves two purposes, depending upon the cycle the apparatus is operating in: first to dehumidify the desiccant during the washing cycle (or &ldquo;recharging&rdquo; the desiccant), and second to dry the moisture laden air from the drying clothing during the drying cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Thus, the desiccant recharging system removes moisture from the air used in drying the clothing during the drying cycle, the solid desiccant thus adsorbing the moisture from the air. The desiccant recharging system then removes the adsorbed water from the desiccant. In this manner, the desiccant recharging system is regenerated during the washing cycle. This is a reversible process that can preferably be carried out for between 10 to 20 years, depending upon the type of desiccant used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the desiccant recharging system utilizes a solid desiccant. The preferred desiccant is silica gel&mdash;H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>SiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. The silica gel used in the present invention are particles in the size range of between about 2-10 mm crushed rock. Silica gel is commercially available from various vendors, and its use as a regenerable dehumidifier is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,756,726. Other materials such as CaSO<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>and clay materials can serve as the solid desiccant. Other desiccants can also be used such as a molecular sieve zeolite material that is commercially available from such sources as ZEOCHEM (Louisville, Ky.). The preferred type of molecular sieve is a Type A sieve which is structured as a series of tetrahedra grouped to form truncated octahedrons having a pore size of about 4.2 Angstroms that opens up to a cavity of about 11.5 Angstroms in diameter. Typically, sieves that are used in the present invention are termed 3A, 4A or 5A, (3-5 Angstroms pore diameters) depending upon the structure and hence, pore sizes. The sieves are typically beads of between about 1 and 4 mm diameter, and are highly efficient in absorbing water. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> While solid desiccants will absorb moisture when used as an open bed, it is more practical and efficient to place the sieves in a housing having an air entrance and an air exit. The placement of the entrance and exits, and the geometry of the housing, can be adjusted to alter the efficiency of the water absorption process and the pressure drop created in the housing between the entrance and exit when molecular sieves are present. For example, when the bed diameter (or thickness) is at least &frac14; of the bed length and the housing is filled with sieves or crushed silica gel, a relatively high water capacity of 10% by weight is achieved. However, this is at the expense of having a high pressure drop. Making the ratio of bed thickness to bed length closer to unity lowers the pressure drop, but also lowers the water capacity. In the present invention, it is preferable that the desiccant housing have a thickness that is at least twice as long as the length, thus improving the airflow required for efficient drying of the clothing. It is ideal to utilize the air circulating fan in conjunction with the desiccant to create a large amount of air turbulence within the desiccant housing, as this increases the efficiency of desiccant regeneration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The desiccant recharging system also has heating coils to heat the air therein for use in drying the clothing during the drying cycle, and in heating the air within the apparatus air pathways during the washing cycle in order to facilitate the dehumidification of the desiccant. For a relatively small, compact unit, the heating coils can be either 110 volt unit or a 220 volt unit. The 110 volt unit, for example, may be an 11 Amp unit of 1200 watt power. For faster drying and desiccant regeneration times, a 220 volt unit of 11 Amps can be used having a power of 2400 watts. At least one fan is used to circulate air through the air pathways. Preferably, the fan should be able to circulate at a rate of at least 150 cfm, and preferably 250 cfm (typically 1.5 Amp) for a smaller washer-dryer unit. For a larger washer-dryer apparatus, a fan that can circulate at a rate of 400-500 cfm (typically 3-5 Amp, or 4500 watts power) is preferable. The more air that can be circulated through the air pathways, the faster the drying and regeneration times become. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> To increase the efficiency of the closed-system washer-dryer, several other design features are present. The tub is placed in the housing at an angle of between about 0&deg; to 30&deg; relative to the flat surface (horizon) upon which the apparatus is placed, the tumbler being at an angle equal to that of the tub. This horizontal or near horizontal placement of the axis of rotation of the tumbler improves the drying efficiency of the apparatus. The tub may also be insulated in one embodiment of the invention to help hold heat within the compartment and thus improve the drying efficiency. Further, the tumbler is programmed in the present invention to turn continuously in one direction during the drying cycle, contrary to its action in the washing cycle. Finally, in another embodiment of the invention, the desiccant recharging system may incorporate a water mist spray apparatus to facilitate the removal of water from the air flow during the washing and drying cycles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The invention is further described with respect to the figures, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram of the washing cycle, and hence first cycle, of the combination washer-dryer apparatus <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises two closed air flow pathways, one air flow pathway primarily operational during the washing cycle and the other pathway primarily operational during the drying cycle. Substantially or all of the same volume of air is used throughout the washing and drying process of one load of laundry. By use of the phrase &ldquo;substantially all of the same volume of air&rdquo;, it is understood that the air flow system and tub door may not be completely free of air leakage. Thus, a small amount of air from the surroundings could leak into the system, or be released from the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The washing cycle air pathway primarily takes place in the desiccant recharging system <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The recharging system includes a desiccant <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> housed in a desiccant housing <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The housing has an entrance <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and an exit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to which conduits can be connected, and through which air can flow. The air flow is described in more detail below. The recharging system <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> also includes a dehumidifying means <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the dehumidifying means is a set of heating coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The coils may be powered by a 110 volt power source, but preferably a 220 volt power source. The dehumidifying means may also be a microwave generating apparatus such as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,805,317, herein incorporated by reference. In either embodiment, a set of heating coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is necessary to heat the air for the drying cycle. The microwave generating apparatus may be used to help dehumidify the desiccant <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. In yet another embodiment, the dehumidifying means is a vacuum pump that will lower the air pressure above the desiccant bed within the housing while it is being heated, thus drawing the desorbed water from the bed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The desiccant housing <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a geometry to maximize the air flow through the desiccant bed, and minimize the pressure drop. A preferred geometry is for the length L to be less than or equal to &frac12; the thickness T. Further, the entrance and exit of the housing is preferably offset from one another. In one specific embodiment, the housing <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is rectangular in shape, having an L value of 4 inches and a T value of 24 inches (and a width of 18 inches). It is to be understood that the housing, and the placement of the entrance and exit, can be of many shapes and designs in order to maximize the air flow through the desiccant within the housing, and to maximize the rate and amount (efficiency) of water absorption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Within the air flow pathway in both the washing and drying cycle is a fan and associated motor <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The fan must be of such a strength that it will create a desirable air flow through the desiccant bed <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Preferably, a high rate of air flow should be achieved so that a suitable amount of turbulence is created within the desiccant housing. In a smaller washer-dryer unit, a fan that generates between about 200-300 cfm can be used, while for a larger, standard residential sized washer-dryer unit a fan that generates between about 400-500 cfm should be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The desiccant recharging system <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> also includes a primary retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a wash cycle retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and a drying cycle retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>. In the embodiment of the invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, air flow is diverted by diverting valve <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Thus, in its wash position, the valve <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> allows air to flow through retort tubes <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, while in the drying position valve <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> allows air flow through retort tubes <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. Coupled to this tubing system is air duct <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>, which is in turn coupled to the tub <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> through air inlet <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. To complete the air circuit, air outlet <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> within the tub <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is coupled to the retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The clothing or other articles to be washed and dried are placed within the tub <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> having tumbler <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. A doorway <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is coupled to the tub <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> to allow closure of the system, air space <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> thus created within the tub. The tumbler <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> may be insulated to increase the efficiency of the heating process. The tub and tumbler therein may be tilted relative to the horizon <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Thus, a tilt axis <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be created relative to the horizon (or level floor) <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to an angle &agr; of between about 0&deg; and 30&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The tumbler <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is operatively coupled to drive shaft <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and drive wheel <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The tumbler motor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is coupled to the wheel <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> by belt <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The tumbler motor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> can be programmed by standard means, either mechanically or electronically, to agitate the clothing within the tumbler with a back and forth motion, or to turn continuously in the same direction when drying. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Water is pumped into the tub through inlet <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and water makeup valve <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. It is to be understood that for standard residential and commercial usage, both a hot water inlet and a cold water inlet will be required, and means to synchronize the two provided. When the tub is filled with water, the door <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> should make sealing contact with the tub to keep water within the tub from leaking out. The water makeup valve can also be programmed by standard means to purge water into the tub at the appropriate wash times during a wash cycle. The water flows through tub inlet <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The water can then exit through tub drain <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>, the drainage of water controlled by the water pump <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. Water is drained using pump <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> through water outlet <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The general mode of operation, and hence the air flow pathways, is now described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. The apparatus is first installed into a dwelling such as a home, apartment, or other area having a flat, horizontal surface to rest the apparatus upon and having a 110 or 220 volt power supply. Further, a cold and hot water supply and water drain is also necessary. The cold and hot water supplies are then coupled to the apparatus as in standard washer systems. Further, the combination washer-dryer is connected to a power supply to supply power to the entire unit. Finally, the water outlet is coupled to a water drain within the dwelling. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In the washing mode of the invention, the apparatus <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> creates a washing cycle air pathway described by arrows A, B, and C. While in the washing mode, the desiccant <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> must be regenerated or dehumidified prior to use in drying the clothing in the tumbler. Thus, in the washing mode as described in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the fan <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> creates an air flow A-B-C through the dehumidifying means <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, then through retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, then through retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, then through the desiccant <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, first entering the entrance <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and exiting at the exit <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The air is then passed again through the dehumidifying means <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in a cyclic fashion throughout the washing cycle. The diverting valve <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is programmed along with the tumbler motor <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> to work in synchrony between the washing cycle and drying cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> During the washing cycle, air is passed through the dehumidifying means, preferably heating coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, to heat the air. The A-B-C air pathway is heated such that the air leaving the heating coils is steam. This steam-air expanding from the regenerating desiccant as water desorbs. This expanding water-laden air expands through pathway D-E where it condenses. The fan maintains an air flow through the A-B-C pathway during this expansion. The cooled, relatively dry air then passes to path A-B to the desiccant to then facilitate the desorption of water that is adsorbed onto the desiccant. The coils may also be used to heat the housing <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and hence the desiccant <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in order to drive off the adsorbed water therein. Preferably, the washing cycle should allow for 20-40 minutes of desiccant recharging time in order to adequately recharge the desiccant material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> During the washing cycle, the washing of the clothing and other articles is carried out within the tumbler <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> and tub <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The tumbler is programmed by any suitable means to agitate the clothing within while the tub is filled with water to, for example, a level <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. After a washing cycle, the water is preferably drained from the tub and refilled with fresh water to rinse the clothing while the tumbler agitates the clothes. Finally, the rinse water is then drained and the tumbler may then spin rapidly in one direction to flush the clothing and articles of excess water. The clothing is then ready for the drying cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In the drying cycle described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the diverting valve <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> alters the flow of air to a dryer cycle air pathway U-V-W-X-Y-Z. This is a continuous flow of air that utilizes the same or substantially the same volume of air that was used in cycle A-B-C (D-E). A removable lint filter <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is placed in retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>in the present embodiment to capture any lint from the drying clothing. Initially, the heating coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> heat air passed over the coils by fan <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The air passes through duct <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> to the air inlet <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> into the tub to extract the moisture from the articles within the tumbler. The tumbler may be perforated to allow air to flow through and around the clothing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The air flow Z, which is moisture laden air, flows out of the tub through air outlet <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> into retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, where it passes into retort tube <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and then into the desiccant bed <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The &ldquo;regenerated&rdquo; or dehumidified desiccant then adsorbs moisture from the air flow U-V-W. The air then is heated in part by heating coils <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and in part by the exothermic heat of absorption from the desiccant bed to for a dry air flow X. The cycle is repeated for 15 to 40 minutes to completely dry the clothing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In the above described embodiment of the washer-dryer system, the regeneration and drying times can be affected by altering the power of the fan and heater. For example, in a relatively small unit that washes and dries 6 bath towels using silica gel desiccant, a 110 volt fan (1.5 Amp, about 150 cfm) and 110 volt heater can dry the towels in about 45 minutes, while regeneration takes about 35 minutes when the heater heats the desiccant to between about 250-300&deg; F. When a 110 volt fan of 3.5 amps is used that circulates the air at about 250 cfm with the same heater, the dry time is reduced to 25 min and the regeneration time to 35 min. When the heater is then increased in power to 240 watts (220 volts, 11 Amps), the drying time for the 6 towels is 10-15 min and regeneration time is 35 min. In the later case, a power cut-off for the heater is set at 300&deg; F. so as to prevent overheating. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the invention is described with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, wherein the drying and washing of the clothing is facilitated with a misting sprayer apparatus <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> coupled to the combination washer-dryer apparatus <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. The apparatus <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> includes a desiccant recharging system <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight>, a tub <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> having a tumbler <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight> and airspace <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, and doorway <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>. Within the tub is air inlet <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> and air outlet <highlight><bold>117</bold></highlight>. Further, the desiccant recharging system <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> includes heating coils <highlight><bold>121</bold></highlight>, desiccant housing <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>, desiccant <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight>, and a fan with an associated motor <highlight><bold>123</bold></highlight>. Air flow is maintained by the fan through retort tubes <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>143</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, the diverting valve <highlight><bold>119</bold></highlight> used to divert the flow of air between the washing and drying cycles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The spray mist apparatus <highlight><bold>125</bold></highlight> includes a spray nozzle <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight> coupled to a misting valve inlet to allow water to flow through the nozzle in synchrony with the cycle of the apparatus <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. Fan and associated motor <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> is used to facilitate the movement of the air through the air flow pathways, and is optional. The water catch <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight> catches the condensed water that comes from the heated, moisture laden air within the tub of drying clothing. Water pump <highlight><bold>137</bold></highlight> drains away the water, and drain valve <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> drains excess water from the catch <highlight><bold>129</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Use of the spray mist apparatus is shown in the drying cycle in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, wherein drying cycle air flow U-V-W-X-Y-Z is made to flow through the apparatus <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>, the heated dry air flow X flowing into the tub of wet clothing, and the moisture laden air flow Z passing from the tub to flow U. Flow U turns to flow V, which passes the heated, moisture laden air through the mister <highlight><bold>127</bold></highlight>, which sprays a fine, cool mist of water into the air pathway. This causes excess moisture to condense from the pathway as it flows into the desiccant in flow W, the desiccant then adsorbing the excess moisture from the air flow. The cycle is then repeated for 15-40 minutes while clothing is continuously turned within the tumbler, or until the clothing is dry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> During the washing cycle, the desiccant is being dehumidified or regenerated. The recharging cycle removes water adsorbed into the solid phase desiccant, preparing it for adsorbing water in the drying mode of operation. The bed of desiccant is regenerated by the use of a thermal swing. The thermal swing involves heating the bed to a temperature at which the adsorptive capacity for water is reduced to a low level so the adsorbate, water, leaves the surface and is easily removed by a small stream of purge air. The heating is normally done with this purge air at operating pressure generated within the air flow pathways by the fan <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> (and fan <highlight><bold>141</bold></highlight> in another embodiment). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> When a thermal swing regeneration is used as in the present invention, the temperature required to desorb the adsorbed water is determined primarily by the type of adsorbate to be removed, the type of adsorbent, and the nature of any co-adsorbed contaminants. Naturally, the regeneration conditions control the effluent dewpoint during the next adsorption cycle. Normally, the effluent dew point can be improved by an increase in temperature, a decrease in pressure, a decrease in water content in the regeneration gas, and a longer heating time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> For example, typical molecular sieves require a regeneration temperature range of between 375&deg; F. and 600&deg; F., while silica gel requires a range from about 200&deg; F. to 400&deg; F. This temperature is necessary to overcome the energy required to desorb an adsorbate. For example, at least 1800 btu are required to remove one pound of water from a typical molecular sieve. This includes the heat for the phase change to vapor and the adsorption bond breakage or heat of wetting. This energy corresponds to the heat released when water binds to molecular sieves. R. E. Trent, <highlight><italic>Fundamentals of Adsorption, </italic></highlight>10 (Feb. 26, 1995). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As water is released from the desiccant into the hot air, it is in the form of steam. This release of steam from the desiccant increases the volume of air and steam that is in the air flow pathway C through the desiccant. This increase in volume expands through the air duct <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and into the tub. Because the temperature of the tub is maintained at a temperature much lower than steam by the wash and rinse water, the steam is condensed into the liquid state and collects in the wash and rinse water. This reduced air volume in the tub area <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> caused by condensation pulls more steam through pathway D-E. In this manner, the air within the apparatus air flow pathways is dehumidified, and more importantly, can then be used to further dehumidify the desiccant <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Another embodiment of the invention is illustrated schematically in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> of the drawings. This version of the washer-dryer of the invention eliminates the previously described diverter valve and merely recirculates the air flow through the system at a greater rate in order to dry the clothes. Turning to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the apparatus <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight> has an inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> is rotatably carried within an outer tub <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight>, which is stationarily mounted in a housing <highlight><bold>159</bold></highlight>. A motor <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> is connected to inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> by belt <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> for rotating inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>. A water valve assembly <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> provides water for use during the wash cycle, and water exits tubs <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight> through water drain <highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight>. A blower <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> draws air from a secondary air flow passage <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and discharges the air into passage <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>, which acts as an air inlet and leads to inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>. Passage <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> houses a heating coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> for heating air passing through passage <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> when coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> is operating. Air exits inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> through perforations in tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, the air passing into outer tub <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight>. Air exits outer tub <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight> through passage <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> which acts as an air outlet for the tub. A lint screen <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> is mounted at the end of passage <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> for filtering lint out of the airflow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Air exiting passage <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> passes through lint screen <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> and into a primary air flow passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. A second, supplemental blower <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> is installed at an upstream portion of passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. A second heating coil <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> is located in a downstream portion of passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. Air passes over coil <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>, into passage <highlight><bold>193</bold></highlight>, and then through desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight>. As will be seen in the example which follows, the desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> has a shallow depth compared to its length and width. Because of the larger airflow volume used in this version of the invention, the velocity through the relatively flat bed is high enough to achieve the desired absorbing efficiency. This results in a low pressure drop across the bed and a higher relative airflow in the drying tub. Air exiting the desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> is routed to passage <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight>. Air travels out of passage <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight> and into passage <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> for recirculation through apparatus <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> In operation, apparatus <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight> operates using substantially the same methods of drying as described for the previous embodiments. During the washing cycle, power is supplied to blower <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> to force air through passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> and across heating coil <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>, which is also operating to heat the air before the air passes through desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight>. The heated air heats desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> to a temperature sufficient to drive out adsorbed moisture, which is carried by the air away from bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> through passage <highlight><bold>197</bold></highlight>. The air passes through passage <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and through blower <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight>, which is not powered during the washing cycle. The moisture-laden air travels through passage <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight>, past heating coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight>, and into inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>. Heating coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> is also not operating during the washing cycle. The air cools within tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, and the moisture condenses, reducing the moisture content of the air. The air passes out of inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, into outer tub <highlight><bold>157</bold></highlight>, and then through passage <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> and lint screen <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> to be recirculated by blower <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight>. This cycle continues until all water is removed from desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight>, then power to blower <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> and heating coil <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> is turned off. Desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> remains at an increased temperature level until the final spin portion of the washing cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> When the final spin portion begins, blowers <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>189</bold></highlight> are turned on, moving air through the airflow pathway at a greater flow rate. This airflow carries heat from desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> into inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>, cooling bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> to a temperature that allows bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight> to adsorb moisture from the airflow during the drying cycle. Power is supplied to heating coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> for heating air passing through passage <highlight><bold>175</bold></highlight> into inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight>. The heated air carries moisture from inner tub <highlight><bold>155</bold></highlight> into passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight>. The air in passage <highlight><bold>183</bold></highlight> continues to desiccant bed <highlight><bold>195</bold></highlight>, which adsorbs moisture from the airflow. The air then flows back through blower <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> and heating coil <highlight><bold>177</bold></highlight> to be recirculated during the drying process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The actual sizing parameters for the version of the invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are given in the example which follows:  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="70PT" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Tub size</entry>
<entry>21&Prime; diameter and 17&Prime; deep</entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Desiccant Bed Size</entry>
<entry>24&Prime; wide &times; 27&Prime; long and 3&Prime; deep</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Air flow rates</entry>
<entry>Washing cycle (desiccant rejuvenation)</entry>
<entry>150 CFM</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Drying cycle</entry>
<entry>500 CFM</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Heating elements</entry>
<entry>Item &num;191- washing cycle</entry>
<entry>5,000 Watts</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Item &num;177- drying cycle</entry>
<entry>5,000 Watts</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Drying Times</entry>
<entry>(Time until clothes are dry beginning</entry>
<entry>12 lb. Load- 10 min.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>after the washing cycles)</entry>
<entry>16 lb. Load- 25 min.</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Yet another advantage to the present invention is that space is economized within the dwelling in which the apparatus is used. Typically, separate washer and dryer units can take up as much as 70-75 cubic feet of space, while the present invention may take up only half the space. This is especially advantageous in small dwellings such as apartments or condominiums. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown in only one of its forms, it is not thus limited but is susceptible to various changes and modifications without departing from the spirit thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A combination closed-circuit washer and dryer apparatus having a washing cycle and a drying cycle, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a unitary washer housing having an insulated tub and a tumbler within the tub, the tub also having an air inlet and air outlet which allows air to flow through the tub, wherein air flowing from the air inlet is in communication with the tumbler; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a desiccant housing containing a solid desiccant, the desiccant housing being located within the unitary washer housing and having a entrance and an exit, the entrance coupled to the air outlet and the exit coupled to the air inlet, thus allowing a continuous flow of air through the tub and desiccant housing in an air flow circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>desiccant recharging means for providing a reversible removal of water adsorbed onto the desiccant using air in the air flow circuit, wherein the desiccant recharging means provides a continuous flow of air over the desiccant bed in both the washing cycle and the drying cycle, the air flow being fed at an increased rate during the drying cycle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a supplemental blower means for providing an increased air flow through the air flow circuit during the drying cycle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tub is placed in the housing at an angle of between about 0&deg; to 30&deg; relative to the horizon, the tumbler being at an angle equal to that of the tub. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the desiccant is silica gel particles. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the desiccant is molecular sieves of a pore diameter of between about 3 and 5 Angstroms. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the desiccant housing has a thickness that is at least twice as long as the length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the desiccant recharging system includes a dehumidification means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dehumidification means is a heating coil. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the dehumidification means is a microwave generator. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tumbler is programmed to turn continuously in one direction during the drying cycle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A combination closed-circuit washer and dryer apparatus having a washing cycle and a drying cycle, the apparatus comprising: 
<claim-text>a unitary washer housing having an insulated tub and a tumbler within the tub, the tub also having an air inlet and air outlet which allows air to flow through the tub, wherein air flowing from the air inlet is in communication with the tumbler; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a primary air flow passageleading from the air outlet, the primary air flow passage being connected to an entrance of a desiccant housing containing a solid desiccant, the desiccant housing being located within the unitary washer housing and also having an exit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a secondary air flow passage connected to the exit from the desiccant housing and communicating with the air inlet to the tub, the primary and secondary air flow passages thus allowing a continuous flow of air through the tub and desiccant housing in an air flow circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>desiccant recharging means for providing a reversible removal of water adsorbed onto the desiccant using air in the air flow circuit, wherein the desiccant recharging means provides a continuous flow of air over the desiccant bed in both the washing cycle and the drying cycle, the air flow being fed at an increased rate during the drying cycle. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the desiccant recharging means includes a heating coil located in the primary air flow passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a heating coil is also located within the air intake to the tub. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a primary blower is located within the secondary air flow passage and communicates air to the air inlet of the tub and wherein a supplemental blower is located in the primary air flow passage to provide an increased air flow to the desiccant bed during the drying cycle.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000106A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000106A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000106A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000106A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000106A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
