<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002800A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002800A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002800</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09892843</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/26</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>052000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>ALIGNMENT TECHNIQUE FOR OPTICAL FIBER ARRAY</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Eli</given-name>
<family-name>Rephaeli</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Neve Daniel</city>
<country-code>IL</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>NIXON &amp; VANDERHYE P.C.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>8th Floor</address-1>
<address-2>1100 North Glebe Road</address-2>
<city>Arlington</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22201-4714</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Improved apparatus and method allow rapid and precise alignment of a fiber optic array on a substrate, in which the offset between the end faces of the array and the edge of the substrate must be precisely known. The arrangement is adaptable for the construction of microlens assemblies and other optical elements that must be precisely placed proximate the end faces of the optical fibers. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to alignment of optical devices. More particularly this invention relates to a technique for the axial alignment of the end face of an array of optical fibers with an edge of a support block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the past, the assembly and manufacture of optical assemblies having a linear array of optical elements has been time consuming and prone to quality control problems. The latest developments in optical cross-connect assemblies have only magnified these problems. Precisely engineered optical receiver arrays are required in these devices. A general demand for more precisely constructed assemblies having greater reliability has translated into a demand for better manufacturing apparatuses and processes. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Optical devices of the type addressed by the present invention currently in use involve an array of optical fibers having light transmitted therethrough. In typical devices the light exiting the end faces of the fibers is transmitted through a plurality of waveguides, which produce a diffraction pattern. The diffracted light is collimated by focusing optics, and then falls on a detector array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In current devices, it is required to precisely position an assembly of micro-lenses close to the end faces of an optical fiber array. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is therefore a primary object of some aspects of the present invention to provide an improved technique for attaching the end of an optical fiber array to a glass block, such that the end faces of the block and the array are in precise alignment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is another object of some aspects of the present invention to attach an array of microlenses in precise alignment with corresponding members of an optical fiber array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The invention provides a method for aligning two blocks, including the steps of placing an end face of a first block in a first face-to-face contacting position against a planar wall, laterally stabilizing the first block in the first face-to-face contacting position, and disposing the bottom surface of a second block in a second face-to-face contacting position with the top surface of the first block, wherein an end face of the second block is in a third face-to-face contacting position with the wall. The method further includes applying pressure against the top surface of the second block while maintaining the second face-to-face contacting position, wherein the pressure is distributed substantially over the top surface of the second block. The method further includes, while applying the pressure, adhering the bottom surface of the second block to the top surface of the first block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the method, the pressure is applied by disposing a third block on the top surface of the second block, and applying the pressure to the third block. The third block can be a Delarin block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the method includes applying an adhesive to the bottom surface of the second block prior to disposing the bottom surface of the second block on the top surface of the first block, and curing the adhesive. The adhesive can be UV glue or an epoxy glue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to an additional aspect of the method, the wall has a lower segment and an upper segment that is offset from the lower segment, wherein in the first face-to-face contacting position the end face of the first block contacts the lower segment, and in the second face-to-face contacting position the end face of the second block contacts the upper segment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the method, the second block includes an array of optical fibers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the method includes disposing an array of microlenses on the second block proximate an outlet of the array of optical fibers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> According to a further aspect of the method, the wall includes a first pin and a second pin that is spaced apart from the first pin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The invention provides a method for aligning an array of optical elements on a block, including the steps of placing an end face of a first block in a first face-to-face contacting position against a planar wall, laterally stabilizing the first block in the first face-to-face contacting position, disposing the bottom surface of a fiberoptic array in a second face-to-face contacting position with a top surface of the first block, wherein an end face of the fiberoptic array is in a third face-to-face contacting position with the wall. The method includes applying pressure against the top surface of the fiberoptic array, while maintaining the second face-to-face contacting position, wherein the pressure is distributed substantially over the top surface of the fiberoptic array, and while applying the pressure, adhering the bottom surface of the fiberoptic array to the top surface of the first block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the method, the pressure is applied by disposing a third block on the top surface of the fiberoptic array, and applying the pressure to the third block. The third block may be a Delarin block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the method includes applying an adhesive to the bottom surface of the fiberoptic array prior to disposing the bottom surface of the fiberoptic array, and curing the adhesive. The adhesive may be UV glue or epoxy glue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> According to still another aspect of the method, the wall includes a lower segment and an upper segment that is offset from the lower segment, wherein in the first face-to-face contacting position the end face of the first block contacts the lower segment, and in the second face-to-face contacting position the end face of the fiberoptic array contacts the upper segment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> An additional aspect of the method includes disposing an array of microlenses on the fiberoptic array proximate the end face of the fiberoptic array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the method, the wall includes a first pin and a second pin that is spaced apart from the first pin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The invention provides an apparatus for aligning an optical array, including a receiving section that accepts a first block and an array of optical elements, wherein the array of optical elements includes a second block. The apparatus further includes a retaining section adjacent the receiving section for stabilizing the first block in an operating position, wherein the retaining section includes a platform that carries the first block thereon. The apparatus further includes an upright frame, which has an extension that overhangs the platform, and has a wall that abuts the first block and the second block during alignment thereof. The apparatus further includes a plurality of horizontally directed stabilizers mounted on the retaining section that urge the first block into a first face-to-face contacting position with a lower segment of the wall, and a vertically directed stabilizer mounted on the extension that holds a bottom surface of the second block in face-to-face contact with a top surface of the first block and holds an end face of the second block in a second face-to-face contacting position with an upper segment of the wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the apparatus, the horizontally directed stabilizers each comprise an upright stub having a hole bored therethrough, and a pin inserted through the hole. The pin may be a bolt threaded through the hole. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> According to yet another aspect of the apparatus, the vertically directed stabilizer includes a pin inserted through a bore that is formed in the extension. The pin can be a bolt threaded through the bore. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> According to still another aspect of the apparatus, the wall includes two upright posts and a gap therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> According to an additional aspect of the apparatus, the lower segment of the wall includes a niche, the end face of which is offset from the upper segment of the wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the apparatus the lower segment of the wall includes an outstanding step that is offset from the upper segment of the wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> According to a further aspect of the apparatus, a width dimension of the extension is less than a width dimension of the platform. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The invention provides an apparatus for aligning an optical array, including a receiving section that accepts a first block, and an array of optical elements, wherein the array of optical elements includes a second block. The apparatus further includes a retaining section adjacent the receiving section for stabilizing the first block in an operating position, wherein the retaining section includes a platform for carrying the first block thereon. The apparatus further includes an upright frame having an extension that overhangs the platform, wherein the width dimension of the extension is less than the width dimension of the platform. The apparatus further includes a wall that abuts the first block and the second block during alignment thereof, a plurality of horizontally directed stabilizers mounted on the retaining section that urge the first block into a first face-to-face contacting position with a lower segment of the wall. The horizontally directed stabilizers each comprise an upright stub that has a hole bored therethrough and a first bolt threaded through the hole, and a vertically directed stabilizer mounted on the extension that holds a bottom surface of the second block in face-to-face contact with a top surface of the first block, and holds an end face of the second block in a second face-to-face contacting position with an upper segment of the wall, wherein the vertically directed stabilizer includes a second bolt threaded through a bore that is formed in the extension. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> According to an aspect of the apparatus, the wall includes two upright posts and a gap therebetween. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> According to an additional aspect of the apparatus, the lower segment of the wall includes a niche that is offset from the upper segment of the wall. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the apparatus the lower segment of the wall includes an outstanding step that is offset from the upper segment of the wall. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> For a better understanding of these and other objects of the present invention, reference is made to the detailed description of the invention, by way of example, which is to be read in conjunction with the following drawings, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a partial top view of an array of optical fibers, which can be aligned in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alignment apparatus in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the alignment apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with the bolts removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view of an alignment apparatus according to an alternate embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a sectional view of an alignment apparatus according to an alternate embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of an alignment apparatus according an alternate embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an enlarged view of a portion of the alignment apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with a glass block in a working position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with a fiberoptic assembly ready for placement therein for alignment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> with a fiberoptic assembly in place; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> illustrates a fiberoptic assembly, which has been completed according to a preferred embodiment of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In the following description, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the present invention. It will be apparent however, to one skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these specific details. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In describing the embodiments herein, the following conventions are used. The Z-axis is nominally horizontal, and has the same direction as the optical axes of an array of optical fibers that is being held and manipulated. The X-axis refers to the horizontal axis that is orthogonal to the Z-axis. The Y-axis is the vertical axis, and is orthogonal to both the X-axis and the Z-axis. Rotation about the X-axis, Y-axis, and Z-axis is referred to as theta-X, theta-Y and theta-Z motion respectively. Of course, it is possible to operate the apparatus disclosed herein in many positions and orientations, in which case the X-axis, Y-axis, and Z-axis are appropriately translated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Alignment Issue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, reference is made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, which illustrates a top view of an array of optical fibers, which can be aligned in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention. The array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of optical fibers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the terminal segments of which are embedded in a substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> can be a glass block. The array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is constructed such that the edge <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the end faces of the optical fibers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are aligned within a tolerance in the Z-axis that is given by the dimension &ldquo;A&rdquo;. In some manufacturing applications, an assembly of microlenses (not shown) may be positioned near the outlet of the array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. In order for the assembly of microlenses to function properly with the array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the dimension &ldquo;A&rdquo; is required to be less than 1 micron. If the tolerance were not met, then the focal points of the microlenses would vary unacceptably in the Z-axis. A supporting block <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is needed for additional physical support, because the optical fibers <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of the array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are too delicate to support an assembly of microlenses. It is necessary to position the array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> atop the block <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and to align the edge <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of the array <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in parallel with the edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of underlying block <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and at a known distance &ldquo;D&rdquo; from the edge <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In some embodiments the distance &ldquo;D&rdquo; can be zero. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> First Embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, which illustrates an alignment apparatus for a fiberoptic array that is constructed and operative in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention. An alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has a receiving section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> that receives a fiberoptic array to be aligned, and a retaining section <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which stabilizes the fiberoptic array during its alignment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The retaining section <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has a platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, which supports the fiberoptic array during alignment. A frame <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is disposed adjacent the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, The frame <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has an extension <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> that overhangs the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and is provided with a retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> threaded therethrough. The purpose of the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is to urge the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned against the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and thereby vertically stabilize it. The extension <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is narrower than the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. It is thus possible to view the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> from above through two open corners <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> that are formed by the base of the extension <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and the frame <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. In applications requiring more exacting visual control, it is possible to fabricate the extension <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> from a transparent material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The retaining section <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is provided with two laterally disposed stubs <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> that project upward, each supporting a stabilizing bolt <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> threaded therethrough. The stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are substantially horizontally disposed, and are angled inward toward the central axis of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are used to further stabilize the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned, as will be disclosed in further detail hereinbelow. A staging area <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> disposed intermediate the stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> admits the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned into an operational position in the receiving section <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. A hole <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is threaded through the retaining section <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. It can optionally receive a mounting bolt or screw (not shown), if it is desired to secure the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to an optical stage (not shown) or other working platform. Anodized aluminum is a suitable material for the construction of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which illustrates a sectional view of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is bounded by a flat wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, which abuts the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned. It is desirable that the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> be precisely planar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Second Embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, which illustrates a sectional view of an alignment apparatus that is constructed and operative in accordance with an alternate embodiment of the invention. An alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is similar to the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference>), except that a platform <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is continuous with the floor of a niche <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> that is formed in the lower portion of a wall <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The niche terminates in a short vertical segment <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. With this embodiment, a lower block can be attached beneath a fiber optic array, and aligned so as to project forward a known distance beyond the end face of the array. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Third Embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, which illustrates a sectional view of an alignment apparatus that is constructed and operative in accordance with an another alternate embodiment of the invention. An alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> is similar to the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference>), except that the lower segment of a wall <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> has an outward step or extension <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. A platform <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> terminates at a short vertical segment <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> that forms the free end of the extension <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. With this embodiment, an underlying block can be attached beneath a fiber optic array or another block, and aligned such that the end face of the overlying fiber optic array or other block projects forward a known distance beyond the end face of the underlying block. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Fourth Embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, which is a perspective view of an alignment apparatus that is constructed and operative in accordance with another alternate embodiment of the invention. An alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is similar to the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2, 3</cross-reference>), except that that two upright pins <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are disposed at the end of a platform <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, which is an enlarged schematic view of a portion of an alignment apparatus similar to that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. A fiber-optic array is shown in alignment position. The fiber-optic array has a top block <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> mounted on a bottom block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight>. During alignment, the block <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and the block <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are both in held in firm contact with the pins <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> by pressure exerted by the stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). The difference between the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and the embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is that the function of the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) is carried out by the pins <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> can be successfully operated even if the blocks <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> have an imperfect planar end face. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Operation of the alignment apparatus will now be disclosed with reference to the first embodiment. Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, which is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). It is convenient to orient the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> diagonally on the optical table (not shown), such that the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> faces a corner of the optical table. Preferably, a stereo microscope (not shown) is positioned above the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in order to view the alignment operation from above. The procedure can be viewed from the side using direct vision. A video camera (not shown) may optionally be positioned to view the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from the side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> A glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is in a working position on the platform <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. A mounting screw <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> secures the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> to an optical table (not shown). Prior to mounting the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, the surfaces of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> that come into contact with the surfaces of the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned are cleaned with a suitable cleaning substance. It is desirable to meticulously clean the surfaces of the fibers of the fiberoptic array that is to be aligned, and the surfaces of the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> A Delarin block <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> which is preferably less than 5 millimeters in thickness is set atop the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, and the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is gently tightened against the Delarin block <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>. A glass block can be used instead of the Delarin block <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight>, provided that its face is accurately planar. Interposition of the Delarin block <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> between the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> uniformly distributes the pressure produced by the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> over the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. The stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are then tightened to urge the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> against the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is constantly viewed from the side, and from above through the stereo microscope (not shown) as the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> are tightened, in order to assure that the end face of the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is accurately positioned in face-to-face contact with the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, which is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). The description of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is to be read in conjunction with the disclosure of the next stage in the alignment operation and with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is released, and the Delarin block <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is removed. The glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> continues to be stabilized by the stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, which is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), and illustrates a fiberoptic array that is to be aligned. The description of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is to be read in conjunction with the disclosure of the next stage in the alignment operation and with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. A fiberoptic array <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> comprises a glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> that encloses the terminal segments <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> of a plurality of optical fibers <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A thin layer of UV-glue is spread over the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, taking care that the glue does not extend closer than 2 mm. to the end faces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the optical fibers <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. Restricting the placement of the glue in this manner is desirable in order to prevent the glue from obscuring the end faces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. A glue such as UV-81, available from Norland Co., is suitable. It is important that the UV-glue be applied to the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, and not to the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. Other glues, such as epoxy, can be substituted for the UV-glue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, which is a perspective view of the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>), and illustrates a fiberoptic array during a further stage of its alignment. The description of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is to be read in conjunction with the disclosure of the next stage in the alignment operation and with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. The fiberoptic array <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is passed into the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> over the staging area <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, until the end faces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of the optical fibers <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> are near the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The top surface of the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> and the bottom surface of the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> are then in face-to-face contact. While viewing the procedure from above through the corners <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, using the stereo microscope (not shown), the end faces <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> are urged against the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> until they are in firm contact with the wall <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The fiberoptic array <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight> is manually held in position, while a Delarin block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is placed atop the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>. The Delarin block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> is preferably less than 5 mm. In thickness, and slightly smaller than the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> in order to continue to view the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> from above. Then the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is gently tightened against the Delarin block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>. Interposition of the Delarin block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> between the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> uniformly distributes the pressure produced by the retaining bolt <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> over the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> A UV gun <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is then directed horizontally toward the side of the glass plate <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight>, and the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>, which are then exposed to ultraviolet light for about a minute. After loosening the stabilizing bolts <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, the fiberoptic array is then removed from the alignment apparatus <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and the entire glue-containing area exposed to the UV gun for an additional four minutes, in order for the glue to harden. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Reference is now made to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, which illustrates a completed assembly <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, comprising the fiberoptic array <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, now mounted on and properly aligned with the glass block <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> While this invention has been explained with reference to the structure disclosed herein, it is not confined to the details set forth, and this application is intended to cover any modifications and changes as may come within the scope of the following claims: </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for aligning an optical assembly, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>placing an end face of a first block in a first face-to-face contacting position against a planar wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>laterally stabilizing said first block in said first face-to-face contacting position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a bottom surface of an array of optical elements in a second face-to-face contacting position with a top surface of said first block, wherein an end face of said array of optical elements is in a third face-to-face contacting position with said wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>while maintaining said second face-to-face contacting position applying a pressure against a top surface of said array of optical elements, wherein said pressure is distributed substantially over said top surface of said array of optical elements; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>while performing said step of applying said pressure, adhering said bottom surface of said array of optical elements to said top surface of said first block. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of applying said pressure is performed by the steps of: 
<claim-text>disposing a third block on said top surface of said array of optical elements; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying said pressure to said third block. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said third block is a Delarin block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of applying an adhesive to said bottom surface of said array of optical elements prior to performing said step of disposing said bottom surface of said array of optical elements; 
<claim-text>wherein said step of adhering comprises curing said adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adhesive is a UV glue. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adhesive is an epoxy glue. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises a lower segment and an upper segment that is offset from said lower segment, wherein in said first face-to-face contacting position said end face of said first block contacts said lower segment, and in said second face-to-face contacting position said end face of said array of optical elements contacts said upper segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said array of optical elements comprises an array of optical fibers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of disposing an array of microlenses on said first block proximate an outlet of said array of optical fibers. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises a first pin and a second pin that is spaced apart from said first pin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method for aligning an array of optical elements on a block, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>placing an end face of a first block in a first face-to-face contacting position against a planar wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>laterally stabilizing said first block in said first face-to-face contacting position; </claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing a bottom surface of a fiberoptic array in a second face-to-face contacting position with a top surface of said first block, wherein an end face of said fiberoptic array is in a third face-to-face contacting position with said wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>while maintaining said second face-to-face contacting position applying a pressure against a top surface of said fiberoptic array, wherein said pressure is distributed substantially over said top surface of said fiberoptic array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>while performing said step of applying said pressure, adhering said bottom surface of said fiberoptic array to said top surface of said first block. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of applying said pressure is performed by the steps of: 
<claim-text>disposing a third block on said top surface of said fiberoptic array; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>applying said pressure to said third block. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said third block is a Delarin block. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of applying an adhesive to said bottom surface of said fiberoptic array prior to performing said step of disposing said bottom surface of said fiberoptic array; 
<claim-text>wherein said step of adhering comprises curing said adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adhesive is a UV glue. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said adhesive is an epoxy glue. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises a lower segment and an upper segment that is offset from said lower segment, wherein in said first face-to-face contacting position said end face of said first block contacts said lower segment, and in said second face-to-face contacting position said end face of said fiberoptic array contacts said upper segment. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of disposing an array of microlenses on said fiberoptic array proximate said end face of said fiberoptic array. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises a first pin and a second pin that is spaced apart from said first pin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for aligning an optical array, comprising: 
<claim-text>a receiving section that accepts a first block, and an array of optical elements, wherein said array of optical elements comprises a second block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a retaining section adjacent said receiving section for stabilizing said first block in an operating position, wherein said retaining section comprises: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a platform for carrying said first block thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a upright frame having an extension that overhangs said platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wall that abuts said first block and said second block during alignment thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of horizontally directed stabilizers mounted on said retaining section that urge said first block into a first face-to-face contacting position with a lower segment of said wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertically directed stabilizer mounted on said extension that holds a bottom surface of said second block in face-to-face contact with a top surface of said first block and holds an end face of said second block in a second face-to-face contacting position with an upper segment of said wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said horizontally directed stabilizers each comprise an upright stub having a hole bored therethrough and a pin inserted through said hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pin is a bolt threaded through said hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said vertically directed stabilizer comprises a pin inserted through a bore that is formed in said extension. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said pin comprises a bolt threaded through said bore. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises two upright posts and a gap therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower segment of said wall comprises a niche that is offset from said upper segment of said wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower segment of said wall comprises an outstanding step that is offset from said upper segment of said wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a width dimension of said extension is less than a width dimension of said platform. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for aligning an optical array, comprising: 
<claim-text>a receiving section that accepts a first block, and an array of optical elements, wherein said array of optical elements comprises a second block; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a retaining section adjacent said receiving section for stabilizing said first block in an operating position, wherein said retaining section comprises: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a platform for carrying said first block thereon; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a upright frame having an extension that overhangs said platform, a width dimension of said extension being less than a width dimension of said platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a wall that abuts said first block and said second block during alignment thereof, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of horizontally directed stabilizers mounted on said retaining section that urge said first block into a first face-to-face contacting position with a lower segment of said wall; wherein said horizontally directed stabilizers each comprise an upright stub having a hole bored therethrough and a first bolt threaded through said hole; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertically directed stabilizer mounted on said extension that holds a bottom surface of said second block in face-to-face contact with a top surface of said first block and holds an end face of said second block in a second face-to-face contacting position with an upper segment of said wall, wherein said vertically directed stabilizer comprises a second bolt threaded through a bore that is formed in said extension. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said wall comprises two upright posts and a gap therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower segment of said wall comprises a niche that is offset from said upper segment of said wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said lower segment of said wall comprises an outstanding step that is offset from said upper segment of said wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002800A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
