<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000901A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000901A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000901</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10233861</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020903</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A47G029/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G09F011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G09F007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>211</class>
<subclass>085160</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>040</class>
<subclass>001000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>040</class>
<subclass>584000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Display for a casket selection and/or viewing room</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10233861</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020903</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09638576</doc-number>
<document-date>20000815</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<continuations>
<continuation-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09638576</doc-number>
<document-date>20000815</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>08911823</doc-number>
<document-date>19970815</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Randall</given-name>
<middle-name>S.</middle-name>
<family-name>Salatin</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Greensburg</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Laios</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Szabo</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Columbus</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marcus</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Szabo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Columbus</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Terry</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Carpenter</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Edwards</city>
<state>CO</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Judith</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Steele</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Columbus</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Batesville Services, Inc.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Batesville</city>
<state>IN</state>
</address>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>WOOD, HERRON &amp; EVANS, L.L.P.</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2700 Carew Tower</address-1>
<address-2>441 Vine St.</address-2>
<city>Cincinnati</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postalcode>45202</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A selection room display facilitates a casket selection by a customer of a funeral home. The display includes a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with the back wall to form an alcove. A plurality of casket portions are displayed in the alcove. A vertical signage column may be positioned in the alcove. Information modules are also displayed in the alcove. The modules correspond to the casket portions. The casket portions are supported on shelves which are removably secured to the back wall. The information modules are similarly removably secured to the back wall. The display may incorporate &ldquo;themes&rdquo; to feature the various casket choices. The theme technique may also be utilized in the funeral home viewing room. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to the funeral service industry, and more particularly to a display system facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket in a funeral home selection room. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Funeral home casket selection rooms have evolved as those in the industry have attempted to better meet the funeral customers&apos; needs. The &ldquo;traditional&rdquo; presentation of product in a funeral home selection room was to simply place each casket on a bier and open the head end cap or lid of the casket to permit viewing inside the casket. As many caskets as possible were displayed in a selection room in order to maximize the number of product choices for the customer. Unfortunately, such a &ldquo;traditional&rdquo; presentation results in what has been referred to as a &ldquo;sea of caskets&rdquo; effect, which can be both distressing or alarming and confusing to the customer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Advances in the design of funeral home selection rooms have taken the form of providing a plurality of alcove structures, either of a &ldquo;modular&rdquo; construction or of a &ldquo;stick built&rdquo; construction, in the funeral home selection room. Each alcove structure includes a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with the back wall to form an alcove. A soffit may span the upper front edges of the wing walls, and lighting, for example track lighting, may be incorporated into the soffit. A two-tier casket rack is located within the alcove, the lower tier of the casket rack being a roll out rack permitting the lower casket to be rolled out from under the upper casket and the casket lid opened for display of the lower casket. Tasteful signage and the like is mounted on the back wall above the caskets. Such a construction, which is the subject of the assignee&apos;s prior U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,405,017 and 5,524,394, both increases the number of caskets which can be displayed in a funeral home selection room, as well as greatly improves the &ldquo;look and feel&rdquo; of the casket presentations, reducing the clutter and confusion of the so-called &ldquo;sea of caskets&rdquo; effect and providing a feeling of comfort to the families. U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,405,017 and 5,524,394 are hereby incorporated by reference herein at this point as if fully set forth in their entirety. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> New construction and renovation costs being what they are, there is an ever-increasing need to increase the product density displayable in the funeral home selection room, without sacrificing comfort, convenience and look and feel of the casket display systems of U.S. Pat. Nos. 5,405,017 and 5,524,394. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention provides a number of selection room displays for facilitating the selection of a casket by a customer of the funeral home, which displays increase the density of product displayable in the selection room yet without compromising the pleasing look and feel of prior displays. One such selection room display comprises a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with the back wall to form an alcove. A plurality of casket portions are displayed in the alcove. The plurality of casket portions represent a plurality of casket choices from which the customer may select. A vertical signage column or graphics tower is positioned in the alcove and displays information. The column would display information to create a &ldquo;theme&rdquo; for the alcove, such as informational and inspirational graphics; text and copy and lifestyle imagery. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In another aspect, a selection room display is provided which comprises as before, a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with the back wall to form an alcove. A plurality of casket portions are displayed in the alcove, with each of the plurality of casket portions being removably positioned atop a shelf which itself is removably secured to the back wall. A plurality of casket information modules are displayed in the alcove, with each information module being removably secured to the back wall and corresponding to one of a plurality of casket portions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In yet another aspect, an information insert for use in a selection room display is provided. The information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises a first pocket having upper and lower edges and having a generally C-shaped cross section, a second pocket attached to the upper edge of the first pocket, the second pocket having a generally U-shaped cross section, and a third pocket attached to the lower edge of the first pocket, the third pocket having a generally U-shaped cross section. The second and third pockets have lower and upper edges, respectively; the lower edge of the second pocket is spaced above the upper edge of the third pocket. In an alternative embodiment, the third or lower pocket is eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In still another aspect, an information module for use in a selection room display is provided. The information module comprises an enclosure including a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position, and the above-mentioned information insert, which is movable into and out of the enclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect of the present invention, a selection room display is provided which comprises a vertical back wall including-at least one horizontal groove therein. A plurality of shelves are removably secured to the back wall. Each shelf of the plurality includes an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof. The lip is received in the horizontal groove thereby cantilevering the shelf from the back wall. Each of a plurality of casket portions is displayed on one of the shelves. A plurality of casket information modules are displayed on the back wall. Each of the information modules includes an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof. The lip is received in the horizontal groove thereby cantilevering the information module from the back wall as well. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a further aspect of the present invention, a selection room display is provided which comprises a vertical back wall and two pairs of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with the back wall to form a centrally positioned center alcove and two laterally positioned side alcoves. An entire casket is displayed in the center alcove, and a plurality of casket portions are displayed in each of the side alcoves. In an alternative embodiment, one of the side alcoves is eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The display system of the present invention includes a number of additional features. For example, the vertical signage column has a square cross section. The signage column extends from the floor substantially to an upper edge of the back wall of the alcove. The signage column is positioned in the alcove such that one wall of the column abuts the back wall and another adjacent wall of the column abuts one of the wing walls. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The first pocket of the information insert includes therein a portion of the cap panel of the casket. The second pocket includes therein a photo of the casket and the third pocket includes therein a fabric swatch of the casket. The information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof. The hook is positionable over an upper edge of the door of the enclosure of the information module when the door is in the open position and the information insert is removed from the enclosure to thereby display the information insert. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the three alcove selection room display, the full size casket is supported atop a floor engaging support. Each of the plurality of casket portions is removably positioned atop a shelf which is removably secured to the back wall, as described above. Either or both of the side alcoves may include a vertical signage column therein. The side alcoves further include a plurality of the above-described casket information modules displayed therein and removably secured to the back wall thereof. This three alcove display may further include cremation urns, vaults, head stones and sympathy cards displayed in the side alcoves. Graphics may be displayed on a central portion of the back wall forming the center alcove to create a &ldquo;theme&rdquo;. Similarly, graphics may be displayed on the signage columns to likewise create a &ldquo;theme.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The present invention may also be utilized in a funeral home viewing room for displaying a body of a deceased. The viewing room comprises a vertical back room wall and a pair of vertical side room walls. A pair of vertical, horizontally spaced apart wing walls cooperate with the back room wall to form an alcove. A casket containing the body is positioned within the alcove. Signage forms the background for the casket. The signage includes text and/or graphics to create a theme. The theme is preferably patterned along the lifestyle of the deceased, for example, gender, religion, sports, politics, patriotism, outdoors and/or athletics. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The present invention therefore provides a number of display systems for use in a funeral home selection room which not only increase the number of product choices displayable in the selection room and therefore available to be chosen by the customer, but do so in a way which is tasteful and visually appealing. The invention also provides a funeral home viewing room. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> These and other advantages of the present invention will become more readily apparent during the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the drawings herein, in which:</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a wall of a funeral home selection room including three alcoves, the center alcove including an entire casket, and the two side alcoves including a plurality of casket portions displayed therein and information modules associated with the casket portions displayed therein; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a front elevational view of the display of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view illustrating the grooved rear wall of the display and the method of attaching the casket portion shelves and information modules to the grooved wall; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a partial vertical cross sectional view through the back wall of the display illustrating the back wall of the display attached to plywood which itself is attached to dry wall studs and illustrating the attachment of the shelves and information modules to the display back wall; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view illustrating the information module comprising an enclosure with an openable and closable door and a removable information insert which is hangable on the door when the door is open and the insert is withdrawn from the enclosure; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates the principles of the present invention adapted for use in the funeral home viewing room for display and viewing of a body of a deceased.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Referring first to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, there is illustrated a display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> according to the principles of the present invention. The display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> would be installed in the selection room of a funeral home for facilitating the selection by a customer or a family member of a casket. As illustrated, the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes essentially three alcoves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, though it is to be understood that the present invention admits of many different possibilities and combinations and therefore is not to be limited to any specific number or arrangement of alcoves. Referring first to alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, a vertical back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> cooperates with a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to form the alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A soffit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> spans the upper front edges of the wing walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and may include recessed track lighting (not shown). A ceiling <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is positioned near the upper edges of the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, wing walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and soffit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The wing walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are removably secured to the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> via fasteners as shown in the assignee&apos;s prior U.S. Pat. No. 5,405,017. Additionally, the soffit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, recessed track lighting and ceiling <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are also as shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,405,017. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the construction of the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is shown in more detail. Back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is a commercially available product known as &ldquo;Slat Wall&rdquo;, available from Marlite of Dover, Ohio. The Slat Wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of horizontal grooves <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> therein, each of which is lined with an aluminum extrusion <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> having generally a dovetailed cross-sectioned configuration. The Slat Wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is mounted to a sheet of &frac34;&Prime; CDX plywood <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with screws <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Approximately 100 to 150 screws are required to secure a 4 ft.&times;8 ft. sheet of the Slat Wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to the plywood <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The plywood <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is in turn glued with construction adhesive <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, for example &ldquo;Liquid Nails&rdquo;, available from the Glidden Company of Cleveland, Ohio, to the dry wall <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and additionally screwed to the wall studs <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> with 2&frac12;&Prime; No. 6 screws <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Screws <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are preferably spaced approximately 6&Prime; apart down each stud <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. (If the plywood <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is to be mounted to masonry, then the plywood may be attached to the masonry with the appropriate masonry screws, for example a masonry fastener known as &ldquo;Tapcon&rdquo;, available from Elco Industries, Inc. of Rockford, Ill.) The adhesive <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is preferably placed as &frac38;&Prime; wide beads, spaced four inches apart up and down the stud lines. In the event that signage, for example a category sign, is mounted to the Slat Wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the Slat Wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is similarly secured to the plywood <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with construction adhesive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Referring now back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of casket portions <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> displayed therein. Each of the casket portions represents a different casket choice from which the customer or family member may select. In other words, each of the casket portions are of a different color, material, finish and/or include different hardware styles. The casket portions are each removably positioned atop a shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, a typical shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> used as a display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is illustrated. The shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, fabricated of, for example, transparent acrylic, includes a casket portion supporting surface <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>, a pair of lateral stiffening gussets <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>, and upwardly projecting back and front lips <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> respectively. As is seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, back lip <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> of shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may be inserted within the groove <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to thereby cantilever the shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> from the wall <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Front lip <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> prevents the respective casket portion from being inadvertently dragged off the front edge of the shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring still to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the casket portions may take one of many forms. For example, portions <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> are short quarter sections of a casket showing half of an end wall and an end portion of a side wall of a casket. Portions <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> are portions which show a short length of the casket side wall. Portion <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> shows a short length of the entire end of a casket. It will thus be appreciated that many different configurations of casket portions may be displayed in the alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> depending on the positioning of the shelves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> and the selection of the portion of the casket to be displayed. As can be appreciated, in the alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as many as eight different caskets may be represented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> A plurality of casket information modules <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> are displayed in the alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Like the shelves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, each information module <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is removably secured to the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and corresponds to one of the casket portions <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> displayed in the alcove. Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, it will be seen that each information module <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> includes an enclosure <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> including top and bottom walls <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, side walls <highlight><bold>98</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and a rear wall <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. A door <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> is pivoted to one of the side walls <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and is movable to and between a closed position and an open position. The enclosure <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is preferably fabricated of pressed wood and is assembled with wood screws. A bracket <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> including an upwardly extending lip <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is secured to the rear wall <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> in an upper location via screws <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. Lip <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> is receivable in one of the grooves <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in the wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in a manner similar to the manner that back lip <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> of shelf <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> may be inserted in groove <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The information module <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is thereby cantilevered from wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in the same manner as the shelves <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. While it is preferable to orient the information modules <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> vertically, it is within the scope of the present invention to orient information modules <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> horizontally as illustrated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Each information module <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> further includes an insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> fabricated of a transparent material such as acrylic. The information insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> includes a first pocket <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, a second pocket <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> attached to an upper edge <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> of first pocket <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and a third pocket <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> attached to a lower edge <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> of first pocket <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The first pocket <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is generally C-shaped in cross section, whereas the second and third pockets <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, respectively, are generally U-shaped in cross section. Preferably the first, second and third pockets <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are integrally fabricated as by molding. Of course it will be appreciated that either or both of the small pockets <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> may be eliminated, depending on how much information is desired to be displayed in the information insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. The information insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> further includes a hook <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> attached to the back side <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> of the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> in an upper location. Hook <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> is positionable over the top edge <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the door <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. In this way, a funeral director illustrating the features of the various caskets which are represented by the casket portions in the alcove may remove the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> from the module <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> associated with one of the casket portions and hang the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> on the edge <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> of the door <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> thereby permitting easy viewing of information in the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In particular, it is contemplated that the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> would include a portion of a cap panel <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> positioned in the first pocket <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. The second pocket <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> would include a photo <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> of the casket, and the third pocket <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> would include a fabric swatch <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> of the fabric of the casket. The lower edge <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> of the second pocket <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is preferably spaced above the upper edge <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the third pocket <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the cap panel <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> is easily viewed between the lower and upper edges <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight>, respectively, of the upper and lower pockets <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, respectively. Furthermore, a customer may access the cap panel <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> to feel the fabric thereon. Similarly, it is contemplated that the fabric swatch <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>, which might be mounted on a card (not shown) to provide rigidity, is of a height such that its upper edge <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> extends above the upper edge <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the third pocket <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, similarly allowing the customer to touch and feel the fabric <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight>. Additionally, information cards such as those shown at <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>184</bold></highlight> may also be positioned in the second and third pockets <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, respectively. In the event that one or the other of the small pockets <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> are eliminated then of course less information would be displayable in the insert <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> as compared to that illustrated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Referring now back to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the alcoves may include a vertical signage column such as that shown at <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> in any or all of the alcoves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The signage column <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> has a square cross section and extends from the floor to a lower edge <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> of the soffit <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or substantially to an upper edge of the back wall. The column <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> is positioned in the alcove, for example alcove <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, such that one wall (not shown) abuts the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and another adjacent wall <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> abuts one of the wing walls <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Thus, two remaining walls <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight>, the front wall and the laterally inboard side wall, respectively, may be utilized to display information thereon. The signage columns or graphics towers <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> are intended to be utilized as &ldquo;positioning devices&rdquo; identifying a specific theme for the alcove, be it the physical material of the casket (wood, metal, etc.) or a lifestyle particularly identified with the deceased (male or female gender, personal lifestyles or orientations like religious, patriotic, outdoorsman, athletic, etc.). It is contemplated that the graphics towers/signage columns would provide informational text and imagery to describe particular product offerings, as well as more inspirational text/poetry and imagery to describe the person, the lifestyle, etc. in a way that will resonate with the consumer in this particular context. The latter may be referred to as &ldquo;lifestyle orientation&rdquo;, i.e. providing a thematic lifestyle context for selection. The signage columns <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> are preferably fabricated of pressed wood and are assembled with wood screws. Graphics panels can be mounted in several ways on the column <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. First, transparent acrylic covers or the like (with or without frames) mounted on the columns <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be utilized to display signage, product information, photo imagery, text and the like thereunder. Second, graphic prints can be mounted to a foam or plastic substrate (including foam core, gator board, sintra or the like) and laminated with a UV protective laminating film. In this second case, no acrylic cover would be required. Third, the graphic print could be on a transparent film and then backlit with a light inside the column, making the column a &ldquo;light box&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring still to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, it will be seen that the center alcove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> includes an entire casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> displayed therein. Casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is preferably supported atop a floor engaging support <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> such as a bier or the like. Alternatively, a two-tiered casket rack of the type disclosed in the assignee&apos;s U.S. Pat. No. 5,405,017 may be utilized to display two entire caskets stacked vertically in the alcove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. With the center alcove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> being utilized to display an entire casket <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> the left or right or both side alcoves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and/or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are utilized to display a plurality of casket portions in conjunction with corresponding information modules and vertical signage columns. In addition, the side alcoves <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> may include additional products either removably positioned on shelves removably secured to the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or simply placed on the floor within the alcoves. These products may include, for example, cremation urns <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, vaults <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight>, head stones <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> and sympathy cards <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight>. Flower sprays may also be displayed in the alcoves. Additional signage may be mounted to the rear walls <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as indicated at <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>246</bold></highlight>. Further, graphics <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be applied to the portion of the back wall <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> forming the back wall of the center alcove <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The graphics <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be chosen to create a &ldquo;theme&rdquo; for the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, such as a patriotic theme for a deceased veteran, outdoor theme, sports theme or the like. Such graphics <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> in combination with the visual impact of the entire casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> in combination with the many casket portions and corresponding information displayed in the lateral side alcoves presents a dramatic presentation for a funeral customer which is tasteful and presents all of the information required to make selections from the display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the principles of the present invention are illustrated adapted for use in a viewing room <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> of a funeral home. The funeral home viewing room <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> includes a back room wall <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> and a pair of side room walls <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight>. The walls <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> form one end of the viewing room <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. A pair of wing wall panels <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> are positioned along the back wall <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight>. A casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is displayed atop a pedestal or bier <highlight><bold>280</bold></highlight> with a body <highlight><bold>282</bold></highlight> of a deceased being displayed in the casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Signage <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> of the type described above forms a background for the casket <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and creates a theme for the alcove <highlight><bold>274</bold></highlight>. Sprays of flowers <highlight><bold>284</bold></highlight> may be supported on easels <highlight><bold>286</bold></highlight> and positioned between each room wall <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> and its corresponding adjacent wing wall <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight>, respectively. Thus, the prior described room environment may be carried over from the casket selection room of a funeral home directly into the body viewing room of a funeral home with similar effects and advantages as described above. Further, the portions of the back wall <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> between the side walls <highlight><bold>264</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>266</bold></highlight> and their adjacent, respective wing walls <highlight><bold>268</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>270</bold></highlight> may include additional signage, text, graphics or memorabilia mounted thereto, by way of for example the use of the above-described Slatwall to build upon the theme chosen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Those skilled in the art will readily recognize numerous adaptations and modifications which can be made to the present invention which will result in an improved selection room display, yet all of which will fall within the spirit and scope of the present invention as defined in the following claims. Accordingly, the invention is to be limited only by the scope of the following claims and their equivalents.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form an alcove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions displayed in said alcove, said plurality of casket portions representing a plurality of casket choices from which the customer may select; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical signage column positioned in said alcove displaying information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said signage column has a square cross-section, extends from the floor substantially to an upper edge of said back wall and is positioned in said alcove such that one wall of said column abuts said back wall and another adjacent wall of said column abuts one of said wing walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of said plurality of casket portions is removably positioned atop a shelf removably secured to said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said alcove includes a plurality of casket information modules displayed therein, each of said information modules corresponding to one of said plurality of casket portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information modules are removably secured to said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said information module includes an enclosure and an information insert movable into and out of said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enclosure includes a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket is generally C-shaped in cross-section and said second and third pockets are generally U-shaped in cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket includes therein a portion of a cap panel of the casket, said second pocket includes therein a photo of the casket and said third pocket includes therein a fabric swatch of the casket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form an alcove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions displayed in said alcove, said plurality of casket portions representing a plurality of casket choices from which the customer may select, each of said plurality of casket portions being removably positioned atop a shelf which is removably secured to said back wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket information modules displayed in said alcove, each of said information modules being removably secured to said back wall and corresponding to one of said plurality of casket portions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said information module includes an enclosure and an information insert movable into and out of said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enclosure includes a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket is generally C-shaped in cross-section and said second and third pockets are generally U-shaped in cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket includes therein a portion of a cap panel of the casket, said second pocket includes therein a photo of the casket and said third pocket includes therein a fabric swatch of the casket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. An information insert for use in a selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said information insert being fabricated of a transparent material, said information insert comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges and having a generally C-shaped cross-section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket, said second pocket having a generally U-shaped cross-section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket, said third pocket having a generally U-shaped cross-section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. An information module for use in a selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said information module comprising: 
<claim-text>an enclosure including a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an information insert fabricated of a transparent material, said information insert being movable into and out of said enclosure, said information insert comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges and having a generally C-shaped cross-section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket, said second pocket having a generally U-shaped cross-section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket, said third pocket having a generally U-shaped cross-section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The information module of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall including at least one horizontal groove therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of shelves removably secured to said back wall, each shelf of said plurality including an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof, said lip being received in said at least one horizontal groove thereby cantilevering said shelf from said back wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions each of which is displayed on one of said shelves; said plurality of casket portions representing a plurality of casket choices from-which the customer may select; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket information modules displayed on said back wall, each of said information modules corresponding to one of said plurality of casket portions and including an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof, said lip being received in said at least one horizontal groove thereby cantilevering said information module from said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> further including a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form an alcove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said information module includes an enclosure and an information insert movable into and out of said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enclosure includes a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall and two pairs of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form a centrally positioned center alcove and two laterally positioned side alcoves, one of said two side alcoves being positioned on each side of said center alcove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an entire casket displayed in said center alcove; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions displayed in each said side alcove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said entire casket is supported atop a floor-engaging support, and wherein each of said plurality of casket portions is removably positioned atop a shelf which is removably secured to said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further including a vertical signage column positioned in at least one of said side alcoves displaying information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further including a plurality of casket information modules displayed in said side alcoves, each of said information modules corresponding to one of said plurality of casket portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information modules are removably secured to said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said information module includes an enclosure and an information insert movable into and out of said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 33</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enclosure includes a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 34</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket is generally C-shaped in cross-section and said second and third pockets are generally U-shaped in cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket includes therein a portion of a cap panel of the casket, said second pocket includes therein a photo of the casket and said third pocket includes therein a fabric swatch of the casket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 35</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> wherein: 
<claim-text>lateral side portions of said back wall forming said side alcoves each include a plurality of horizontal grooves therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of shelves are removably secured to said lateral side portions of said back wall, each shelf of said plurality including an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof, said lip being received in one of said horizontal grooves thereby cantilevering said shelf from said back wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions representing a plurality of casket choices from which the customer may select are displayed on said shelves; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket information modules are displayed on said lateral side portions of said back wall, each of said information modules corresponding to one of said plurality of casket portions and including an upstanding lip on a back edge thereof, said lip being received in one of said horizontal grooves thereby cantilevering said information module from said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 39</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each said information module includes an enclosure and an information insert movable into and out of said enclosure. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 40</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said enclosure includes a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert is fabricated of a transparent material and comprises: 
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to said upper edge of said first pocket; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pocket attached to said lower edge of said first pocket; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second pocket having a lower edge, said third pocket having an upper edge, said lower edge of said second pocket spaced above said upper edge of said third pocket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 42</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket is generally C-shaped in cross-section and said second and third pockets are generally U-shaped in cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 43</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first pocket includes therein a portion of a cap panel of the casket, said second pocket includes therein a photo of the casket and said third pocket includes therein a fabric swatch of the casket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said information insert further includes a hook on an upper back side thereof, said hook being positionable over an upper edge of said door when said door is in the open position to display said information insert. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further including cremation urns, vaults, headstones and sympathy cards displayed in said side alcoves. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further including graphics displayed on a central portion of said back wall forming said center alcove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference> further including a vertical signage column positioned in each said side alcove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall and three vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form two side-by-side alcoves; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an entire casket displayed in one of said alcoves; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of casket portions displayed in the other said alcove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference> further including a plurality of information modules displayed in said other alcove along with said casket portions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference> wherein each of said plurality of casket portions is removably positioned atop a shelf removably secured to said back wall, and said information modules are removably secured to said back wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. An information module for use in a selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said information module comprising: 
<claim-text>an enclosure including a door pivotable to and between a closed position and an open position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an information insert fabricated of a transparent material, said information insert being movable into and out of said enclosure, said information insert comprising: </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pocket having upper and lower edges and having a generally C-shaped cross-section; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second pocket attached to one of said upper and lower edges of said first pocket, said second pocket having a generally U-shaped cross-section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The information module of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 52</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said second pocket is attached to said upper edge of said first pocket. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. A selection room display for facilitating the selection by a customer of a casket, said display comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back wall and a pair of vertical, spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back wall to form an alcove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least a portion of a casket displayed in said alcove; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a vertical signage column positioned in said alcove, said column displaying text and graphics thereby creating a theme for said alcove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The selection room display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said theme is the material from which the casket is fabricated. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The selection room display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said theme is the lifestyle of the deceased. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The selection room display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 56</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lifestyle is one from the group consisting of gender, religion, patriotism, outdoors and athletics. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The selection room display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a plurality of casket portions representing a plurality of casket choices from which the customer may select are displayed in said alcove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The selection room display of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 54</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said back wall includes signage thereon, said signage corresponding to said text and graphics on said column. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A viewing room for displaying a body of a deceased, said viewing room comprising: 
<claim-text>a vertical back room wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of vertical side room walls cooperating with said back room wall to form one end of said viewing room; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of vertical, horizontally spaced apart wing walls cooperating with said back room wall to form an alcove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a casket positioned within said alcove; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a body positioned in said casket. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. The viewing room of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference> further including signage in said alcove behind said casket and forming a background for said casket, said signage including at least one of text and graphics to create a theme for said alcove. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. The viewing room of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 61</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said theme is the lifestyle of the deceased. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The viewing room of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the lifestyle is one from the group consisting of gender, religion, patriotism, outdoors and athletics. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The viewing room of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference> further including at least one flower spray positioned between each said vertical side room wall and adjacent said wing wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. A method of displaying a body of a deceased comprising the steps of providing a viewing room as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference> and displaying said body in said casket in said viewing room. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. A funeral home including a viewing room as claimed in claim <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000901A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
