<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00024.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00025.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00026.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00027.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00028.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00029.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00030.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00031.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00032.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00032.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00033.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00033.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00034.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00034.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00035.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00035.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00036.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00036.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00037.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00037.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00038.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00038.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00039.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00039.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00040.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00040.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00041.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00041.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00042.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00042.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004513A1-20030102-D00043.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004513A1-20030102-D00043.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004513</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10154558</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020524</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A61B017/56</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>606</class>
<subclass>062000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus for use in the performance of endoscopic minimally invasive orthopaedic plating procedures</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60301309</doc-number>
<document-date>20010627</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Pamela</given-name>
<middle-name>C.</middle-name>
<family-name>Guzman</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fort Wayne</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Wack</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Warsaw</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dale</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Schulze</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lebanon</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Knight</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>West Chester</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Christopher</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hess</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Lebanon</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Rudolph</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Nobis</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Mason</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Michael</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>Clem</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Maineville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ronald</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kolata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Cincinnati</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BARNES &amp; THORNBURG</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>11 SOUTH MERIDIAN</address-1>
<city>INDIANAPOLIS</city>
<state>IN</state>
<postalcode>46204</postalcode>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A bone plating apparatus includes a handle having extending therefrom a tissue expander for insertion through a skin incision and through the subcutaneous tissue surrounding a fractured bone. A bone plate may be secured to the handle during advancement of the tissue expander so as to deliver the bone plate to a desired location proximate to the fractured bone. Both the tissue expander and the bone plate may be advanced to the desired location proximate to the fractured bone under the visualization of an endoscope. A screw alignment jig is secured to the handle and has a guide hole which aligns with an access hole of the tissue expander. The alignment of the guide hole and the access hole allow for percutaneous screw insertion into the delivered bone plate. A method for plating a fractured bone is also disclosed. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/301,309 entitled &ldquo;Methods and Apparatuses for Use in the Performance of Endoscopic Minimally Invasive Orthopaedic Procedures&rdquo; filed on Jun. 27, 2001 by Michael A. Wack, Pamela C. Guzman, Thomas Ferro, Dale R. Schulze, Gary W. Knight, Christopher J. Hess, Rudolph H. Nobis, Michael F. Clem, and Ronald J. Kolata, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present disclosure relates generally to orthopaedic methods and apparatus, and more particularly to methods and apparatus for use in the performance of endoscopic minimally invasive orthopaedic procedures. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Minimally invasive surgical techniques have been developed for many different types of surgical procedures. Such techniques attempt to balance the need to achieve the goal of the surgical procedure while minimizing the surgical injury to the patient. As such, surgeries performed by use of minimally invasive techniques generally result in lower postoperative morbidity, shorter postoperative stay, less postoperative pain, decreased cost, and quicker recovery as compared to &ldquo;open&rdquo; or conventional surgical techniques. Because of the aforementioned advantages, these minimally invasive techniques are being applied to an increasing variety of surgical procedures. For example, minimally invasive techniques in the form of laparoscopic procedures, such as a laparoscopic colectomy for carcinoma of the colon, have been developed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> However, despite growing use in other surgical fields, minimally invasive techniques have not been significantly developed for use in orthopaedic procedures. In particular, although orthopaedic surgeons have recognized the general principle that maintenance of soft tissue contributes significantly to the postoperative healing process, conventional techniques in which the soft tissue is completely opened in order to gain complete access to the bone structure therein are still in widespread use. One reason for this is the unique nature of many orthopaedic procedures. In particular, orthopaedic procedures often involve the &ldquo;delivery&rdquo; and implantation of devices which are relatively large in design compared to the &ldquo;deliverables&rdquo; associated with other forms of surgery. In particular, in the case of, for example, an appendectomy, minimally invasive techniques are adaptable since the surgeon may aptly remove the subject tissue (i.e., the patient&apos;s appendix) and thereafter deliver and install the necessary sutures through the relatively small confines of a cannula of a trocar. However, in the case of, for example, trauma repair of a heavily fractured long bone (e.g., a femur or tibia), one or more relatively large plates are screwed or otherwise fastened to the fractured bone. The size of such plates has long since been viewed as prohibitive in regard to the use of minimally invasive techniques for the implantation thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Another reason commonly cited in regard to the use of traditional techniques (i.e., &ldquo;open&rdquo; incisions) is the surgeon&apos;s need to visualize the surgical site. In particular, orthopaedic procedures commonly include complicated fractures which require precision in regard to the installation of fixation devices (e.g., screws and the like) and the reduction of such fractures. As such, surgeons have heretofore preferred to open the soft tissue surrounding the bone to be treated in order to completely expose the surgical site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As a result of such continued use of &ldquo;open&rdquo; procedures, soft tissue surrounding the bone continues to be compromised thereby impairing normal blood circulation to the treated bone, potentially delaying fracture healing, and potentially increasing the risk of infection. Indeed, although the majority of patients treated with such procedures heal without complication, there are certain occasions in which complications such as infection or non-union occur thereby prolonging healing rates and, in certain cases, increasing the rates of secondary revisions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As a result of the aforedescribed shortcomings associated with traditional orthopaedic surgeries, along with the promise associated with minimally invasive techniques, a number of attempts have been made to provide certain of the advantages associated with minimally invasive techniques to a limited number of orthopaedic procedures. For example, plate fixation assemblies have heretofore been developed for use in fracture repair of femurs. However, such assemblies suffer from a number of drawbacks. For example, such assemblies rely heavily on the use of fluoroscopy as the manner by which the surgeon &ldquo;visualizes&rdquo; the surgical site. In addition to the fundamental limitations relating to the resolution associated with fluoroscopy, many surgeons may also be reluctant to embrace the use of large amounts of fluoroscopy in order to minimize radiation exposure to themselves, the other members of the surgical staff, and the patient. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure provide apparatus and methods for use in the performance of minimally invasive orthopaedic procedures. The concepts of the present disclosure also provide apparatus and methods for use in the performance of such procedures under the visualization of an endoscope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of a minimally invasive intramedullary nailing procedure. In accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an endoscopic minimally invasive intramedullary nailing procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of a minimally invasive bone graft harvesting procedure. In accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an endoscopic minimally invasive bone graft harvesting procedure. There are also provided, in accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, methods and apparatus for use in the performance of a minimally invasive, or even an endoscopic minimally invasive, bone graft material delivery procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of a minimally invasive pelvic osteotomy procedure. In accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an endoscopic minimally invasive pelvic osteotomy procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an orthopaedic implant revision procedure. In accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an endoscopic orthopaedic implant revision procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of a minimally invasive percutaneous bone plating procedure. In accordance with a more specific implementation of this illustrative embodiment, there are provided apparatus and methods for use in the performance of an endoscopic minimally invasive percutaneous bone plating procedure.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a surgical site utilizing a prior art intramedullary nailing technique; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic view which shows a trocar being advanced to a nail entry point on the proximal femur; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a proximal view of a prepared femur; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows a guide pin being advanced into a prepared proximal femur; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the installation of a tubular-shaped skin protector; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of an intramedullary nail; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an exploded fragmentary perspective view which shows the nail of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> being secured to a jig; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the nail being implanted into the proximal femur; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the installation of a number of cortical screws into the implanted nail; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the installation of an end cap into the implanted nail; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows a trocar being advanced to a bone graft harvesting location on the ilium; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the harvest area of the ilium being outlined with an osteotome; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the bone graft material being harvested from the ilium; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic perspective view which shows the entry points for a pair of trocars utilized to perform a pelvic osteotomy; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a pair of diagrammatic cross sectional views which show the performance of an endoscopic implant revision procedure; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of an exemplary embodiment of a bone plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of another exemplary embodiment of a bone plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of another exemplary embodiment of a bone plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic side elevational view of a bone plating instrument positioned in the body of a patient; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a screw locating device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a fragmentary diagrammatic side elevational view of a plating instrument which shows a remotely controllable hole cover; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a plan view of a rotatable screw alignment device; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view which shows a spoon having a leading edge which is configured to conform to the contour of a fractured bone; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a plan view of a spoon which has a slot defined therein; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic side elevational view which shows a number of LED&apos;s positioned with the spoon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic plan view which shows a template for use during screw insertion, note that the template and the bone plate are shown in cross section for clarity of description; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> is a side elevational view which shows a feature which may be utilized to secure the bone plate to the plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic side elevational view which shows a guide wire for use in determining hole location of the spoon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference> is a fragmentary elevational view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>, but showing another feature which may be utilized to secure the bone plate to the plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> is a fragmentary cross sectional view of the spoon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view of the spoon which shows a seal covering the hole in the spoon; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic elevational view of a bone clamping assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 33</cross-reference> is a plan view of a screw alignment device having a latch mechanism; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference> is a diagrammatic side elevational view which shows the different positions in which the bone plate may be positioned during delivery thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 35</cross-reference> is a fragmentary elevational view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>, but showing another feature which may be utilized to secure the bone plate to the plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 36</cross-reference> is an exploded diagrammatic view which shows a locating assembly being utilized to position a bone plate in a desired implant location; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 37</cross-reference> is a view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference>, but showing a different embodiment of a bone clamping assembly; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 38</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a bone plating instrument having an integrated cannulated sleeve; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 39</cross-reference> is a fragmentary elevational view which shows a bone plating instrument being utilized to secure a bone plate to a bone, note that the bone plate is shown in cross section for clarity of description; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 40</cross-reference> is a fragmentary perspective view of a tap which may be used with the instrument of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 38</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are fragmentary perspective views of plate attachment and delivery mechanisms for securing the bone plate to the plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference> is a side elevational view of a plating instrument having a plate attachment and delivery mechanism which utilizes two hooks to secure the bone plate to the plating instrument; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 45</cross-reference> is a side elevational view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference>, but showing the hooks in spaced apart relation relative to one another, note that a portion of the instrument is shown in cross section for clarity of description; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 46</cross-reference> is a fragmentary side elevational view of the plating instrument of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 44 and 50</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 47</cross-reference> is a fragmentary bottom elevational view of the plating instrument of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 44 and 50</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 48</cross-reference> is view similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 46</cross-reference>, but showing the hooks engaged with a bone plate, note that the bone plate is shown in cross section for clarity of description; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 49</cross-reference> is a perspective view showing the plating instrument being supported by a support block; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are views similar to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference>, but showing a movable plate attachment and delivery mechanism; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 53</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a plating instrument having a telescoping tissue expander and screw alignment device. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ILLUSTRATIVE EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> While the concepts of the present disclosure are susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof have been shown by way of example in the drawings and will herein be described in detail. It should be understood, however, that there is no intent to limit the concepts of the present disclosure to the particular forms disclosed, but on the contrary, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the spirit and scope of the disclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, there is shown a number of apparatus and methods which may be utilized to perform a minimally invasive orthopaedic surgical procedure. Common to many of the concepts disclosed herein is the notion of utilizing endoscopic instruments to provide the surgeon with enhanced viewing capabilities in the form of direct visualization of the surgical site. The concepts of the present disclosure may be utilized in a wide variety of orthopaedic procedures. Indeed, although the concepts of the present disclosure will be described in regard to specific orthopaedic procedures, it should be appreciated that such concepts are not limited to the specific exemplary embodiments described herein, but rather may be utilized in a wide variety of orthopaedic procedures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Endoscopes </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> As utilized herein, the term &ldquo;endoscope&rdquo; is intended to mean any device which is capable of collecting images for display on a display device. As such, the endoscopes of the present disclosure may take the form of a conventional endoscopic &ldquo;wand&rdquo; which utilizes conventional endoscopic imaging techniques. Conventional endoscopes are constructed such that an objective lens and an eyepiece are disposed at opposite end portions of optical fibers for transmitting an image. The image of an article to be observed is made to focus at one end face of the optical fibers. A transmitted image of the article is transmitted through the optical fibers and appears on the other end face so as to be observed through the eyepiece. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> More recently, endoscopes have been constructed in which an image sensor converts an optical image focused on the sensor into electrical signals. The image sensor typically includes an array of light detecting elements in which each element produces a signal corresponding to the intensity of light impinging on the element when an image is focused on the array. These signals may then be used, for example, to display a corresponding image on a monitor or otherwise used to provide information about the optical image. One common type of image sensor is a charged coupled device (CCD). CCDs have been improved greatly during the last several years, and, as a result, provide images with very good resolution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Another type of image sensor is formed as an integrated circuit using a complementary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) process. In such a CMOS type image sensor, a photodiode or phototransistor (or other suitable device) is used as the light-detecting element in which the conductivity of the element corresponds to the intensity of light impinging on the element. The variable signal thus generated by the light-detecting element is an analog signal whose magnitude is approximately proportional (within a certain range) to the amount of light impinging on the element. Examples of medical devices using a CMOS chip are provided in U.S. Pat. No. 5,817,015 issued to Adair on Oct. 6, 1998 and U.S. Pat. No. 6,139,489 issued to Wampler et al. on Oct. 31, 2000, both of which are hereby incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> It is known to form these light-detecting elements in a two-dimensional core array that is addressable by row and column. Once a row of elements has been addressed, the analog signals from each of the light detecting elements in the row are coupled to the respective columns in the array. In some CMOS based systems, an analog-to-digital (A/D) converter may then be used to convert the analog signals on the columns to digital signals so as to provide only digital signals at the output of the image sensor chip. These signals may then be transmitted to a video display for viewing of the image. Examples of this type of video format include the PAL format commonly used for European televisions, and the high resolution S-video format used in, for example, surgical operating rooms. Indeed, most CCD based endoscopic systems also use the S-video format. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> Other CMOS based systems send an analog signal to the video display. An example of this type of format is the NTSC format such as the format used for standard television signals in the United States. The latter is a very popular format, therefore, for CMOS based systems, due to the huge number of NTSC formatted televisions available. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> CMOS image sensors are generally highly sensitive to light. As a result, the light intensity required to illuminate the image when using a CMOS system (typically less than or equal to one lux) is relatively low. In fact, a very low power light source, such as a tungsten filament, incandescent, penlight bulb, placed near the area being imaged, or used within a short distance of a light transmitting element such as an acrylic rod, is sufficient for the CMOS system to obtain a good image. The low power light source and transmitting element are small enough to be placed inside of a handheld, endoscopic medical instrument. Moreover, CMOS image sensors require very little electrical power and it is practical to use small (in the range of 6-9 VDC) batteries to operate them, although a CMOS image sensor can also be used with a conventional DC power supply connected to a wall outlet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing discussion, it is evident that a CMOS based visualization system may provide a disposable, low cost, high resolution, wireless system. Indeed, one or both the light source and the power source can be integrated into a handheld instrument to operate the CMOS image sensor constructed into the viewing end of the instrument. The output signal of the CMOS image sensor could then be connected to any one of a number of video displays, including conventional televisions or monitors, depending on the video format chosen. Alternatively, the output signal of the CMOS image sensor may be coupled to a &ldquo;heads up&rdquo; display such as a commercially available heads up display unit being offered by, amongst others, Sony Corporation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> In any of the above described cases, the image collecting unit (e.g., the camera) may be fixed in position or steerable. Moreover, illumination for operating any of the aforedescribed endoscopes may be provided by the use of commercially available LED&apos;s, tungsten bulbs, or a light pipe with an illumination source mounted in the handle or externally to the device. Illumination may also be provided in conventional manners. In the case of when a CMOS pinhole camera is used, the illumination source may be infrared LED&apos;s. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Moreover, in the case of utilizing an endoscope to visualize the advancement of an obturator of a trocar, a number of different configurations are available for use in regard to the concepts of the present disclosure. For example, a separate, independent endoscope may be utilized which peers through or even around the tip of the obturator. Alternatively, the endoscope may be integrated into the clear tip of the obturator itself. Examples of an integrated endoscope and obturator are shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,797,944 which was issued to Nobles et al. on Aug. 25, 1998, and which is hereby incorporated herein by reference. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Intramedullary Nailing </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In one exemplary embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided to allow a surgeon to perform an intramedullary nailing procedure. This concept will be described herein in regard to the nailing of a patient&apos;s femur, although it should be appreciated that the concepts of the present disclosure may be utilized in regard to the nailing of other bone structures. For example, the concepts described herein may also be utilized to install intramedullary nails in a tibia or a humerus or supracondylar nails in a distal femur. As will now be discussed in regard to the installation of an intramedullary nail into the intramedullary canal of a femur, the concepts of the present disclosure allow for such installation of intramedullary nails without the use of a large, open incision and without the use of fluoroscopy. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Heretofore utilized intramedullary femoral nailing techniques required the &ldquo;filleting&rdquo; of the patient&apos;s hip <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to expose the greater trochanter <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Such filleting of the patient&apos;s hip <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> provides the surgeon with direct visualization of the proximal end of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, such heretofore utilized techniques require that an awl <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> or other type of instrument be placed on the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> at the approximate entry point for a guide pin (not shown) which is used in the installation of the intramedullary nail. To confirm that the awl <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is at the proper entry point of the guide pin (i.e., a point on the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> adjacent to the greater trochanter <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the lateral edge of the piriformis fossa), a number of intraoperative anterior-posterior and lateral radiographs are taken for use by the surgeon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> However, procedures utilizing certain of the concepts of the present disclosure avoid such filleting of the hip <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and the use of radiographs. In particular, according to one illustrative embodiment of this concept, an endoscopic instrument may be utilized by the surgeon to directly visualize the entry point for the guide pin. In a more specific illustrative embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> cannulated instrument such as a trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is inserted through a small stab incision <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> in the skin of the patient. The trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has an endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> associated therewith. In one exemplary embodiment, the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is positioned in the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be of conventional design and is positioned to visualize through a clear tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of an obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> associated with the trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. However, it should be appreciated that other configurations of the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are also contemplated. For example, the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> may be secured to an outer portion of the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or may be integrated into the tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> Under visualization, the tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is advanced through the underlying tissue to a location on the proximal end of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> adjacent to the greater trochanter <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. As such, the surgeon may utilize the images generated and returned from the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to position the tip <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> on the desired entry point for a guide pin. The surgeon may then remove the obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> Once the obturator <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has been removed, the surgeon may then advance instruments through the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, such as an awl or step drill (not shown), to prepare the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> for the introduction of a guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The prepared femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Thereafter, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is advanced through the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> until the distal tip <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> thereof approaches the prepared hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The tip <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is then advanced under visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the images of the prepared entry point (i.e., the hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> collected by the endoscope <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are utilized by the surgeon to aid the advancement of the distal tip <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into the hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> prepared in the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Once the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has been inserted into the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, the nailing procedure may be completed. Specifically, the cannula <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be removed so that a tubular shaped skin protector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be slipped over the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and thereafter inserted through the incision <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> in the skin. The skin protector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is then advanced through the underlying tissue to a position proximate to the entry point of the guide pin <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> into the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. During such advancement of skin protector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, the skin, along with the underlying tissue, is spread slightly in order to protect the same during subsequent implantation of a cannulated intramedullary nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Once the skin protector <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is secured in place, the distal tip <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>) may be advanced into the prepared hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the proximal end of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> To do so, the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is first secured to a jig <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. Specifically, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7, a</cross-reference> locking bolt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is utilized to threadingly engage a proximal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Once secured in such a manner, the distal tip <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is advanced into the prepared hole <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the proximal end of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, a sliding hammer <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> may be utilized to drive the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> into the intramedullary canal of the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> to a desired depth, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the jig <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may then be utilized to guide the placement of a number of cortical screws <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> into a number of holes <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> defined in the proximal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the implanted nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The screws <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> are advanced through a number of stab incisions <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> created in the skin of the patient. It should be appreciated that a number of such cortical screws may also be installed in similar holes located on the distal end of the implanted nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the jig <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> may then be removed by removal of the locking bolt <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. An end cap <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> may then be advanced through the incision <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and thereafter screwed or otherwise secured to the proximal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the implanted nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Installation of the end cap <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> prevents bony ingrowth into the threads of the proximal end <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the implanted nail thereby facilitating subsequent removal of the nail <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> after the femur <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has healed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Bone Harvesting and Delivery </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In another exemplary embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided to allow a surgeon to harvest bone graft material along with the subsequent delivery of the same. This concept will be described herein in regard to the harvesting of bone graft material from the anterior surface of the patient&apos;s ilium, although it should be appreciated that the concepts of the present disclosure may be utilized in regard to the harvesting of bone graft material from other bone structures. For example, the concepts described herein may also be utilized to harvest bone graft material from the posteriorsuperior iliac spine of the ilium, a bicortical graft from the anterior aspect of the ilium, the styloid of the radius, the olecranon, the anterior aspect of the greater trochanter, the distal femoral condyle, the proximal tibia, and the distal tibia. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In regard to the specific exemplary embodiment of harvesting of bone graft material from the anterior surface of the patient&apos;s ilium, the concepts of the present disclosure allow for such bone harvesting without the use of a large, painful, open incision. In particular, heretofore utilized iliac harvesting techniques have required the filleting of the patient. Specifically, the surgeon cuts a large curvilinear incision along a path that is parallel to the iliac crest. Thereafter, the surgeon must subperiosteally dissect the abdominal musculature and, subsequently, the iliacus from the inner wall of the ilium. The bone graft material is then harvested from the ilium. Once the harvest is complete, the surgical site is closed and sutured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> An improvement to such a technique has been a long felt need. In particular, it has been noted that many patients observe significantly greater amounts of postoperative discomfort (i.e., pain), and are subjected to a significantly longer recovery period, as a result of the harvesting procedure than is generally attributable to the underlying ailment for which the patient is treated (i.e., the ailment at the site of the bone graft delivery). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> In one illustrative embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an endoscopic instrument may be utilized by the surgeon to directly visualize the harvest location of the anterior surface <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In a more specific illustrative embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11, a</cross-reference> cannulated instrument such as a trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is inserted through a small stab incision <highlight><bold>158</bold></highlight> in the skin of the patient. The trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> has an endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> associated therewith. In one exemplary embodiment, the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is positioned in the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be of conventional design and is positioned to visualize through a clear tip <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of an obturator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> associated with the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. However, it should be appreciated that other configurations of the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are also contemplated. For example, the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> may be secured to an outer portion of the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, or, alternatively, may be integrated into the tip <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of the obturator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> Under visualization, the tip <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> is advanced through the underlying tissue to a location proximate to the anterior surface <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. As such, the surgeon may utilize the images generated and returned from the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> to position the tip <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> of the obturator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> proximate to the desired harvesting location of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. The surgeon may then remove the obturator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> from the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> Once the obturator <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> has been removed, the surgeon may then advance a number of instruments through the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> in order to perform the harvesting operation. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12, a</cross-reference> number of straight and/or curved osteotomes <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are advanced through the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and thereafter manipulated or otherwise operated by the surgeon to form an outline of the area to be harvested in the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> of the patient. Such outlining of the anterior ilium prevents splitting of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> into the sciatic notch. It should be appreciated that the surgeon performs such outlining of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> under the visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Specifically, along with the osteotome <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is present in the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> to provide direct visualization of the harvest site during use of the osteotome <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Once outlined in such a manner, corticocancellous strips or other portions of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> may then be removed. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13, a</cross-reference> material removal instrument such as a curette or a gouge <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and thereafter manipulated by the surgeon in order to harvest bone graft material from the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. Such harvesting of the anterior ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> is also performed under the visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>. Specifically, along with the material removal instrument (e.g., the gouge <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>), the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> is also positioned in the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> during the harvesting operation. As such, the images collected by the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> are utilized by the surgeon to visualize the surgical site (i.e. the anterior ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>) during use of the gouge <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that other types of instruments may also be utilized to remove the bone graft material from the patient&apos;s ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. For example, an auger (not shown) may be advanced through the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> and thereafter into the cortex of the ilium <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, rotation of the auger causes removed bone material to be advanced through the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> via the helical band of the auger. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> It should also be appreciated that the concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized during delivery of the bone graft material to a delivery site such as a spinal location. For instance, a trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> having an endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> associated therewith may be utilized to access the delivery site. Use of a minimally invasive device such as the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> prevents the need for elongated incisions and dissection at the delivery site. Moreover, by utilizing the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, the delivery operation may be performed under direct visualization thereby allowing the surgeon to implant the graft material without inadvertently contacting other anatomical structures proximate to the delivery site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> It should also be appreciated that other surgical configurations may also be utilized during bone harvesting/delivery. For example, if the number or configuration of the surgical instruments required to harvest or deliver the bone graft material utilizes substantially all of the area within the cannula <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> of the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, a second trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be utilized. For example, a first trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be utilized to permit visualization of the surgical site with the endoscope <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, whereas a second trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> may be utilized to permit access to the surgical site by providing for advancement of the necessary harvesting instruments (e.g., an osteotome, gouge, or auger). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Pelvic Osteotomies </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> In another exemplary embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided to allow a surgeon to perform a pelvic osteotomy. As will now be discussed in greater detail, the concepts of the present disclosure allow for the performance of a pelvic osteotomy without requiring a large, open incision. In particular, heretofore utilized techniques for performing a pelvic osteotomy generally require the use of a number of relatively long incisions, along with extensive muscle stripping and tendon division. As a result, patients often suffered from heavy blood loss, lengthy hospitalization stays, and relatively long recovery periods. Moreover, even despite the relatively extensive exposure of the hip during such a procedure, certain portions of the periacetabular osteotomy may still be difficult for the surgeon to visualize. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> However, procedures utilizing concepts of the present disclosure avoid such drawbacks of heretofore utilized techniques. In particular, according to one illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure, a pelvic osteotomy may be performed by the surgeon while directly visualizing the bone during sawing thereof. In a more particular illustrative embodiment, a number of trocars, similar in nature to the trocars hereinbefore described (i.e., the trocar <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the trocar <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>) are inserted through small stab incisions in the skin of the patient to visualize the surgical site. Specifically, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14, a</cross-reference> first trocar (not shown) may be inserted at a groin insertion location <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, whereas a second trocar (not shown) may be inserted at an iliac insertion location <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> One or both of the inserted trocars have an endoscope associated therewith. In one exemplary embodiment, the endoscope is positioned in the cannula of the trocar. In such an arrangement, the endoscope may be of conventional design and is positioned to visualize through a clear tip of an obturator associated with the trocar much in the same way the endoscopes were utilized to visualize the approach to the surgical site in the aforedescribed procedures. It should be appreciated that other configurations of the endoscope are also contemplated for use during performance of a pelvic osteotomy. For example, the endoscope may be secured to an outer portion of the cannula of the trocar, or, alternatively, may be integrated into the tip of the obturator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Under visualization, the tip of the trocar may be advanced through the underlying tissue to a desired location near the hip bone structures to be treated. As such, the surgeon may utilize the images generated and returned from the endoscope to position the tip of the obturator proximate to the hip bone structures which are to be treated. The surgeon may then remove the obturator from the cannula of the trocar. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Once the obturator has been removed, the surgeon may then advance a number of surgical instruments through the cannulae of the trocars in order to perform the pelvic osteotomy. For example, a number of micro sawing instruments may be advanced through the cannulae and thereafter utilized to saw one or more of the structures of the hip bone in a desired location. It should be appreciated that such sawing of the hip bone is performed under the direct visualization of the endoscopes positioned in one or both of the trocars. As such, the surgeon maintains a direct view of the bone being sawed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In addition to providing visualization of the bone which is being sawed, use of the endoscopes positioned in the trocars provides a number of other distinct advantages. For example, by directly visualizing the surgical site, inadvertent severing of certain anatomic structures may be avoided. For example, such visualization of the surgical site will prevent the inadvertent severing of the obturator neurovascular bundle or the sciatic nerve. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> Implant Revision Procedures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> In another exemplary embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided to allow a surgeon to visualize the surgical site during performance of an orthopaedic implant revision procedure. In particular, as will now be discussed in greater detail, the concepts of the present disclosure allow the surgeon to visualize the intramedullary canal of a bone during an orthopaedic implant revision procedure. Such capability is a significant improvement over heretofore utilized techniques in which the surgeon did not possess the ability to &ldquo;see&rdquo; into the intramedullary canal beyond his or her ability to &ldquo;peer&rdquo; into the canal. The ability to visualize the intramedullary canal has been improved somewhat by the use of illumination instruments which are lowered into the canal, but the surgeon remains constrained by the limitation that he or she can only observe the canal from &ldquo;outside&rdquo; the bone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> However, procedures utilizing concepts of the present disclosure avoid such drawbacks of heretofore utilized techniques. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, according to one illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure, an endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> is lowered into the intramedullary canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> of the bone <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> to directly visualize the bone during the implant revision procedure. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15, a</cross-reference> number of cutting instruments <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be utilized to scrape or otherwise remove any residual bone cement <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> (i.e., the cement <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> that was utilized to retain the previously removed prosthesis). During such a procedure, the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be lowered into the intramedullary canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> such that the images generated by the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be utilized to inspect the intramedullary canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> during the implant revision procedure. Such an inspection may be utilized to confirm, amongst other things, adequate bone cement removal and the lack of any spiral fractures in the bone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> In such an arrangement, the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be of conventional design and may be positioned to visualize the canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> continuously during the procedure. Alternatively, the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be lowered into the canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> only periodically during the procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> In a more specific exemplary embodiment, the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> may be provided as part of a &ldquo;combination&rdquo; instrument. For example, instruments for use in implant revision procedures have heretofore been designed which provide for irrigation of the canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, suction of removed material or debris, illumination (i.e., lighting) of the canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, and cutting of the residual cement <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight>. As such, these irrigation-suction-illumination-cutting instruments have become a useful tool for surgeons since they perform multiple functions within the confines of a single instrument. In order to render such instruments even further useful to a surgeon, the concepts of the present disclosure provide for the bundling of the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> with such a combination instrument. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> The resultant instrument would provide for all of the functions described above (i.e., irrigation, suction, illumination, and cutting) while also providing for visualization of the intramedullary canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the integration of the endoscope <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> into the device would provide for a device which allows the surgeon to visualize the inner surfaces of the intramedullary canal <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, including the residual bone cement <highlight><bold>218</bold></highlight> present therein, while also performing one or more of the other associated functions of the instrument (i.e., irrigation, suction, illumination, and cutting). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Percutaneous Plating </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> In another exemplary embodiment of the concepts of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided to allow a surgeon to perform a bone plating procedure in a percutaneous manner. As will now be discussed in greater detail, the concepts of the present disclosure allow for the performance of a minimally invasive, percutaneous bone plating procedure without requiring a large, open incision. In particular, heretofore utilized techniques for performing such a plating procedure generally require the use of a number of relatively long incisions, along with the associated extensive muscle stripping and tendon division. As a result, patients often suffered from heavy blood loss, lengthy hospitalization stays, and relatively long recovery periods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> However, procedures utilizing concepts of the present disclosure overcome such drawbacks of heretofore utilized techniques. In particular, according to one illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure, an apparatus and method are provided for inserting a bone plate into a relatively small incision and thereafter securing the plate to a desired position on a bone. In doing so, the plate is inserted under visualization provided by an endoscope associated with the apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Referring now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, there is shown a number of exemplary embodiments of a bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> (which, in the exemplary embodiment described herein, includes a handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>), an elongated cannulated shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, and a tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, in one exemplary embodiment, the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may be embodied as a spoon-shaped member <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (referred to hereinafter simply as spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>), whereas in other embodiments, the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is embodied as a tunnel-shaped member <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> (referred to hereinafter simply as tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>). It should be appreciated that the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is utilized to expand the tissue around the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to be treated to provide access to the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> for both a bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and the instruments necessary for installation of the same. As such, the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> provides a subcutaneous working space for the positioning and securing (with bone screws) of a bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> onto a fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> As shown in, for example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16, 17</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> of the present disclosure include a body <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight> having a top wall <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> and a pair of downwardly extending side walls <highlight><bold>313</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that although the body <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight> of the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> are herein described as being generally semi-tubular or otherwise arcuate shaped in cross section, other configurations of the body <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight> are also contemplated for use. For example, the cross sectional shape of the body <highlight><bold>309</bold></highlight> of the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (i.e., either the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>) may be non-arcuate in shape such as in the case of two longitudinal rails spaced apart and coupled by a number of cross elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> The aforedescribed embodiments of the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> provide for a relatively large degree of flexibility in regard to the design of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Additional flexibility may be achieved by the use of removable tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. In particular, the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may be configured to be removably secured to the elongated cannulated shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, whereas the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be configured to be removably secured to the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, different sizes, shapes, or types of spoons and tunnels may be utilized on a common shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>/handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> assembly thereby allowing the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to be adapted to fit the needs of a given patient&apos;s anatomy or surgical procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> The plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> has an endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> associated therewith (see, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>). The endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is provided to allow the surgeon to visualize the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> along with the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> being secured thereto. Specifically, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, during installation of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, the images generated by the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> are utilized by the surgeon to visualize the surgical site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> The plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> also includes a screw alignment device or jig <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. The screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is provided to align bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> with a number of holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (see, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 39</cross-reference>). Specifically, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>, when secured to the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, may be utilized to guide the screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> during percutaneous advancement thereof into the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. To do so, the surgeon visualizes the location of the individual holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> by use of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. Under such visualization, the surgeon may then align one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> with an access hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> defined in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> has a single hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> defined therein. As such, the surgeon, under visualization, aligns the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> with one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Once the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> are aligned with one another, a screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may be inserted through a stab incision in the skin of a patient by use of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. Specifically, when the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is secured to the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, a guide hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> defined therein is aligned with both the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and the hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. As such, a cannulated guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> in the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>, the stab incision and underlying tissue, and through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (see, e.g., <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 39</cross-reference>). A bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may then be advanced through the cannulated guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight>, the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>, and one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and thereafter threadingly engage the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that the stab incision through which the screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is advanced may be created in a number of different manners. For example, an obturator (not shown) may first be advanced through the cannulated guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> and into the skin and underlying tissue of the patient. The obturator may be advanced to the point at which the obturator enters the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. The obturator may then be removed from the cannulated guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> such that the screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may thereafter be advanced through the guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that an elongated screw driver (not shown) may be advanced through the cannulated guide <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> (and hence the incision) to drive the screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> into the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may take on many different forms. Specifically, the design of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be modified to, for example, cooperate with a given design of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may take the form of an elongated member with only a single hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. In such an embodiment, the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the alignment device <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> is aligned with the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. In use, the surgeon utilizes the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to pull the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> along the length of the implanted plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in order to successively align the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (and hence the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>) with the individual holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the implanted plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> However, in the case of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> being configured with the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be configured with a plurality of the holes <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, each of which aligns with one of the plurality of holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> defined in the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, the position of the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (and hence the holes <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>) may be predetermined in order to align with the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> defined in the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. In this manner, the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> need not be moved in order to drive successive screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> has an attachment member such as a number of pins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> defined in the inner end thereof. The pins <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> may be positioned in any adjacent pair of holes <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> defined in the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> (specifically, the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) in order to secure the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> to the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may be configured with a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>. In doing so, the height at which the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is secured to the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> may be adjusted thereby allowing for variations in the thickness of the tissue surrounding the fracture bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> Numerous other manners for adjusting the height of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> are also contemplated for use. For example, the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be configured to include a gear assembly which, upon rotation of a knob or the like, causes the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> to be moved upwardly and downwardly. For instance, a rack and pinion gear assembly, similar to the type utilized in the construction of conventional microscopes for moving the specimen tray relative to the lens, may be utilized to adjust the position of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> The screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may also be secured to the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> in other manners. For example, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be pivotally secured to the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to allow the surgeon to pivot the device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> out of the way when, for example, operating on tissue. Moreover, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be arcuate or curved in shape to conform to the arcuate or curved shape of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> being implanted (which in turn conforms to the bone to which it is being secured). In such an arrangement, the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be rotatably secured to the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> (or removable for rotation) thereby allowing the device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> to conform to a plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> with either a right-hand or left-hand curvature (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>). Moreover, the locations of the holes <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be configured to allow for the use of a single design of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> with a number of different bone plate designs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> A further alternative feature for use in the design of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 33</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> has a single hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. The alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> of this embodiment includes a pivotal latch <highlight><bold>358</bold></highlight> which may be utilized to allow the surgeon to leave an instrument or the like in the stab incision. For example, an instrument, such as the trocar/obturator assembly utilized to create the stab incision for screw insertion, is only removable from the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> when the distal tip thereof is external to the body of the patient. However, use of the latch <highlight><bold>358</bold></highlight> allows an implanted instrument (i.e., an instrument having a distal end present in the tissue of the patient) to be removed from the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> thereby allowing the instrument to remain in the body of the patient for subsequent use during the procedure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 38</cross-reference>, in an alternate configuration of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, an integrated handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>/screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> includes a cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> that is pivotally and slidably secured to the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. In such an arrangement, a number of instruments <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> in order to perform a desired function. For example, one of the removable instruments <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight> may be an obturator which is advanced through the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> to create the stab incision. The removable instrument <highlight><bold>370</bold></highlight> could also be a drill or tap which is advanced through the sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> and thereafter utilized to create a hole in the fracture bone into which a screw will be driven. As shown in phantom lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 38</cross-reference>, when not in use, the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> may be slid and pivoted to a substantially horizontal storage position on the upper surface of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Use of a cannulated sleeve which is integral to the instrument (i.e., the integrated cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight>) allows for the elimination of certain instruments which are commonly utilized in plating procedures. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 40, a</cross-reference> tap instrument <highlight><bold>372</bold></highlight> having a shoulder portion <highlight><bold>374</bold></highlight> and a tap portion <highlight><bold>376</bold></highlight> may be utilized in conjunction with the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight>. A similarly configured (i.e., shouldered) drill (not shown) could also be utilized in conjunction with the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight>. By doing so (i.e., utilizing the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> for operation of both instruments), the need for separate tap and drill guides is eliminated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> The cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> may be transparent in design and thus allow for the instruments advancing therethrough (e.g., the obturator) to be endoscopically viewed. Alternatively, the cannulated sleeve <highlight><bold>368</bold></highlight> may have a number of longitudinal slots defined therein for such endoscopic viewing of the passage of an instrument therethrough. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Other embodiments of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> are also contemplated for use. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> may be movable relative to the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Specifically, a ratchet mechanism <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> may be utilized to ratchet or otherwise move the screw alignment device in the general direction of arrows <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>. In such an arrangement, the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> need only be embodied with a single hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> since the movement of the device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> provided by the ratcheting mechanism <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> is utilized to position the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> in the appropriate location relative to the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that the ratchet mechanism <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> may be configured such that each incremental movement of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> generated by the ratchet mechanism <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> coincides with the placement of the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> into alignment with one of the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> also includes a coupler <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> which coordinates the movement of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> with that of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the coupler <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> may be utilized to mechanically couple the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>. As such, as the surgeon operates the ratchet mechanism <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> to position hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> over one of the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is likewise moved in the direction of arrows <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> to a position which allows the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> to collect the desired images of the screw driving operation. Hence, when the surgeon positions the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> in a desired location, the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is likewise positioned in a desired location to observe the associated procedure (e.g., screw insertion). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 53</cross-reference>, there is shown another exemplary embodiment of the bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In lieu of a gear mechanism for re-positioning the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>, the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 53</cross-reference> includes a telescoping shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> and an alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> with a telescoping body. A spring loaded detent <highlight><bold>319</bold></highlight> is positionable in any one of a number of locator holes <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> to position the shaft (and hence the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>) and the alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> in a desired position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>, there is shown another exemplary embodiment of a bone plating instrument. In this case, an alignment instrument <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> provides the screw alignment function and is intended to be utilized in conjunction with the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The alignment instrument <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> includes a handle <highlight><bold>378</bold></highlight> having a pair of parallel arms <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> extending therefrom. The upper arm <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight> has a hole <highlight><bold>388</bold></highlight> defined in that functions essentially the same as the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> (i.e., aligns with the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>). The lower arm <highlight><bold>382</bold></highlight> includes a location feature <highlight><bold>384</bold></highlight> in the form of a tab <highlight><bold>386</bold></highlight> which aligns with one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> defined in the implanted bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. The dimensions of the alignment instrument <highlight><bold>390</bold></highlight> are selected such that when the tab <highlight><bold>386</bold></highlight> is positioned in one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>, one of the other holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> (e.g., the adjacent hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>) is aligned with both the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and the hole <highlight><bold>388</bold></highlight> of the upper arm <highlight><bold>380</bold></highlight>. As such, the precise location for the stab incisions associated with screw insertion can be enhanced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that similar concepts may be incorporated into the design of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. For example, the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be configured to include a locating tab similar to the tab <highlight><bold>386</bold></highlight> such that when the tab is positioned in one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>, one of the other holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> (e.g., the adjacent hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>) is aligned with the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the spoon or tunnel (and hence the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that there are numerous other manners for aligning the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (or holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>) of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (and hence the hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>) with the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28, a</cross-reference> flexible, remotely operable, guide wire <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> may be extendable and retractable through the cannulated shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Once the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>) is located precisely over the plate hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of interest (as determined by use a locating feature on the spoon or tunnel, or the use of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>), the surgeon may advance the wire <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> distally. During such distal movement of the wire <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight>, the tip <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of the wire is guided by a ramp <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> which guides the wire tip <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> vertically out of the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>). Continued vertical advancement of the wire tip <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> causes it to penetrate through the underlying tissue and eventually puncture the skin (as shown in phantom in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference>). The point at which the tip <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of the wire exits the skin may be utilized as an indicator for the location of a stab incision for subsequent screw insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> itself may provide the necessary alignment features for screw insertion. For example, the outer surfaces of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may have alignment features defined therein which allow the surgeon to tactilely locate the position of the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (or holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>) in the spoon or tunnel through the tissue of the patient. Alternatively, a pointer laser may be mounted on the cannulated shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>, with an associated mirror positioned on the inside surface of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>, so that a laser beam may be reflected or otherwise directed outwardly and upwardly through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> (or holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>) of the spoon or tunnel. In this manner, the directed beam would illuminate the location of the stab incision to be utilized to drive a screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and hence the hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> positioned thereunder. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> Another device <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight> which utilizes certain features of the present disclosure is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference>. This screw alignment device <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight> is embodied as a flexible guide which may be secured or &ldquo;keyed&rdquo; off of one of the bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> which has been installed in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. In doing so, a number of holes <highlight><bold>394</bold></highlight> defined in the alignment device <highlight><bold>392</bold></highlight> are aligned with the remaining holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> One manner of providing a bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> for such a &ldquo;keying&rdquo; function is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 36</cross-reference> in which the bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is provided as an assembly having a threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> and a compression component <highlight><bold>398</bold></highlight>. The threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> is first threadingly implanted into the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> via a stab incision as described above. The threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> is implanted at a location which corresponds to a desired location of the distal tip <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. In particular, the distal tip of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is slid or otherwise advanced through a small incision <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> and advanced along the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to a point in which the threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> of the bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is captured or otherwise received into a slot <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. Once the threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> is positioned in the slot <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight>, the compression component <highlight><bold>398</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and into a bore <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> defined in the head of the implanted threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight>. Advancement of the compression component <highlight><bold>398</bold></highlight> into the bore <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> of the threaded component <highlight><bold>396</bold></highlight> forces the distal tip <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> downwardly into contact with the surface of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> thereby vertically aligning the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that the alignment bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may be left in the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> or removed after the remaining bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> have been secured within the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in one of the numerous manners described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference>, there is shown one of the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> in greater detail. Although the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> in the context of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, it should be appreciated that the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be constructed in a similar manner. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference>, the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> defined in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> has a chamfered portion <highlight><bold>346</bold></highlight>. Such a feature functions as a &ldquo;lead-in&rdquo; which facilitates the advancement of instruments (e.g., drills, taps, or even the screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>) through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> extends through a boss <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> which, for example, may be integrally molded with the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (i.e., either the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>). Use of the boss <highlight><bold>348</bold></highlight> provides a structure of sufficient length and rigidity to allow proper alignment of instruments (e.g., drills, taps, or even the screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>) during advancement of the same through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21, a</cross-reference> remotely controllable (i.e., from a control mechanism (not shown) associated with the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) cover <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> may translate within the elongated cannulated shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> (which, in this case has a plurality of holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> defined therein). The cover <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> prevents fat or other types of tissue from entering the workspace inside the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. In the specific exemplary embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, the remotely controlled cover <highlight><bold>350</bold></highlight> is secured to the movable endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Such protection from the entry of unwanted tissue may also be provided by other structures. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31, a</cross-reference> flexible seal <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> constructed of, for example, silicon may cover the entrance to the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. The seal <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight> prevents the entry of fat or other tissue into the hole, but yet may be relatively easily pierced by instruments during advancement thereof into the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, the upper surface <highlight><bold>356</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may be configured to include a number of illumination devices such as light emitting diodes (LED&apos;s) <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight>. The LED&apos;s <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight> may be utilized to illuminate portions of the workspace (e.g., the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> during screw insertion) during a procedure. Such use of the LED&apos;s <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight> is particularly useful for use with an endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> constructed with a CMOS chipset (such as in the case of the CMOS-based design of the endoscope shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>). It should be appreciated that the upper surface <highlight><bold>356</bold></highlight> (or the other inner surfaces of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>) may be configured as optical lenses or other similar structures to intensify the light generated by the LED&apos;s <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight> in a number of different directions. For example, in addition to directing light onto the workspace, the configuration of the inner surfaces of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may direct intensified light outwardly through the underlying tissue and skin of the patient to provide an external indication of the location of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Such &ldquo;trans-illumination&rdquo; may be useful to supplement or perhaps even replace the use of the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> during screw insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure also provide for the lateral and vertical alignment of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> prior to securing the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23, a</cross-reference> leading edge <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may be configured to conform to the contour of the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Such a feature assists in the centering of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> onto the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> when the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is secured thereto. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>, extended side wings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> may also be utilized in the construction of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> in order to provide similar functionality. It should be appreciated that although the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 21 and 23</cross-reference>, similar features (i.e., a contoured leading edge <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> or the use of extended side wings <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight>) may be utilized in the design of the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> Other configurations of plate alignment features are also contemplated for use in the design of the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. For example, the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be adapted to &ldquo;grab&rdquo; around the outer periphery of the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to assist in aligning the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, and hence the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> positioned thereunder, over the center axis of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that such engagement or &ldquo;grabbing&rdquo; of the bone would also allow the surgeon to selectively release the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> thereby permitting a certain degree of &ldquo;hands free&rdquo; operation of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>, additional &ldquo;hands free&rdquo; operation may be achieved by use of features associated with the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight>, specifically the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>. For example, a number of lateral extensions <highlight><bold>444</bold></highlight> may be provided to support the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> against, for example, the patient&apos;s leg, an operating table, or the like. Such extensions <highlight><bold>444</bold></highlight> may take on the form of wings, legs, or any other type of similar structure. During a procedure, the surgeon may utilize the lateral extensions <highlight><bold>444</bold></highlight> to engage a support structure thereby allowing the surgeon to release the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> to perform other tasks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> Other support mechanisms may also be utilized to support the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during a procedure (e.g., to provide for &ldquo;hands free&rdquo; operation). For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 49, a</cross-reference> support block <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> may be secured to the an outer surface of the patient&apos;s body (e.g., the patient&apos;s leg). The plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be supported by the support block <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> thereby eliminating the need for the surgeon (or other personnel) to support the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 49</cross-reference>, the support block <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> is constructed from a deformable material (e.g., foam) with a channel <highlight><bold>447</bold></highlight> formed therein. The housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is positionable in the channel <highlight><bold>447</bold></highlight>. A lower surface <highlight><bold>449</bold></highlight> of the support block <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> is secured to the patient (or other surface, if desired) by the use of, for example, an adhesive. In such a way, use of the support block <highlight><bold>445</bold></highlight> allows the surgeon to release the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to perform other tasks. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>, the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may also have a slot <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> defined therein. The slot <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> extends from the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> to the outer edge of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. Use of the slot <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight> allows the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> to be removed from the body of the patient while a K-wire, alignment screw, or the like that is being utilized to align the plate to the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> is left secured to the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the K-wire or alignment screw may be advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> in the manner described above and thereafter left in place during subsequent movement of the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> by sliding the implanted K-wire or alignment screw through the slot <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32, a</cross-reference> separate bone clamp assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may be provided for use with the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (i.e., the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>). The clamp assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> includes a pair of arms <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> pivotally coupled to a frame <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight>. The distal end of each arm <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> has a barb <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> defined therein which is capable of penetrating the skin, underlying tissue, and thereafter engaging the outer surfaces of the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. A biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> threadingly engages the frame <highlight><bold>424</bold></highlight> and, as a result, is movable upwardly and downwardly (as viewed in the orientation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference>) by rotation of a handle <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> in one direction or the other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> In order to center the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> over the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, the surgeon positions the clamp assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> externally over the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> and thereafter advances the arms <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> inwardly toward one another. The surgeon continues advancement of the arms <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> such that the barbs <highlight><bold>426</bold></highlight> pierce the skin, penetrate the underlying tissue, and engage the outer surfaces of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. The surgeon may then turn the handle <highlight><bold>430</bold></highlight> so as to advance the biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> downwardly (as viewed in the orientation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference>) through the skin and underlying tissue via a previously created stab incision. The distal tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> of the biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> is advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and into the workspace created thereby. The distal tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> is then advanced into contact with the top of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in order to bias the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> firmly against the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. In a specific exemplary embodiment, an extension portion <highlight><bold>434</bold></highlight> of the tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> of the biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> may be advanced into one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> with a shoulder portion <highlight><bold>436</bold></highlight> of the tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> engaging the upper surface of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 37</cross-reference>, the design of the clamp assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may be modified to include a pair of flexible, spring biased arms <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> secured to a frame (not shown) within a tube <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight>. The flexible arms <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> may be brought together by use of the tube <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight>. Specifically, when the tube <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight> is moved upwardly (as viewed in the orientation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 37</cross-reference>), the arms <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> are spread outwardly in a direction away from one another. However, when the tube assembly <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight> is advanced downwardly (as viewed in the orientation of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 37</cross-reference>), the arms <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> are urged toward one another and, as a result, may be inserted through a stab incision <highlight><bold>440</bold></highlight>. The arms <highlight><bold>438</bold></highlight> may then be spread away from one another (i.e., by movement of the tube <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight>), advanced around the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and then moved toward one another (i.e., by movement of the tube <highlight><bold>442</bold></highlight> in the opposite direction) so as to engage the outer surfaces of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 37</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> A biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight>, similarly to as previously described in regard to the assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 32</cross-reference>, may then be utilized to bias the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> downwardly into contact with the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the distal tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> of the biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> and into the workspace created thereby. The distal tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> is then advanced into contact with the top of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in order to bias the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> firmly against the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. In particular, the extension portion <highlight><bold>434</bold></highlight> of the tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> of the biasing member <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> may be advanced into one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> with the shoulder portion <highlight><bold>436</bold></highlight> of the tip <highlight><bold>432</bold></highlight> engaging the upper surface of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that other mechanisms may also be utilized to exert a downward bias on the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. For example, a number of inflatable bladders may be mounted on the anterior surface of the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>. Such bladders are remotely inflatable with air, saline, or other fluids. As such, when the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is positioned over the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, the inflated bladders exert a bias against the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> which urges the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> into firm contact with the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized to &ldquo;deliver&rdquo; the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to a desired location along the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 27, 29</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, the tissue expanders <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> (either the spoon <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> or the tunnel <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight>) may have a feature defined therein which is utilized to engage the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> near the distal tip <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> thereof. Such a feature may take the form of a rearwardly facing flange or lip <highlight><bold>446</bold></highlight> which is received into a corresponding slot <highlight><bold>448</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>). Such a feature may also take the form of a forwardly facing flange or lip <highlight><bold>450</bold></highlight> which is received into a corresponding slot <highlight><bold>452</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 35</cross-reference>). Alternatively, such a feature may take the form of a protrusion, detent, or tab <highlight><bold>454</bold></highlight> which is received into a corresponding recess <highlight><bold>456</bold></highlight> defined in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> As described, such features support the distal end of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. To support the other end of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (i.e., the proximal end), a removable fastener <highlight><bold>458</bold></highlight> is provided (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>). The fastener <highlight><bold>458</bold></highlight> is received through a bore defined in the housing <highlight><bold>302</bold></highlight> and thereafter threadingly engages the proximal end of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> thereby allowing the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to be removably secured to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> Once positioned in a desired position, one or more bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may be inserted through the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and into the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to initially secure the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in the desired location. The surgeon may then remove the fastener <highlight><bold>458</bold></highlight> and thereafter manipulate the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> so as to release the distal tip <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (i.e., remove the lip from the associated slot or the tab from the associated recess). Once done, the surgeon may then insert the remaining bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> in the manner described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> Other exemplary embodiments of plate attachment and delivery mechanisms are shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 41</cross-reference>, the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be embodied to include a plate attachment and delivery mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight>. The mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> includes a saddle <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight> that is movably secured to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary embodiment shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, the saddle <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight> is slidable along the shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Such mobility (e.g., slidability) allows the position of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to move relative to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during implantation thereof. In such a manner, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be positioned in a temporary delivery position during advancement of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> into the body. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>, the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be retained in a delivery position (indicated generally at <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>) during insertion into the incision and advancement through the underlying tissue to the desired position along the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Positioning the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in such a position prevents the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> from obstructing the view of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> thereby allowing full use of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> during navigation of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to the delivery site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> The saddle <highlight><bold>472</bold></highlight> has a thumbwheel <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> rotatably secured thereto. A first end of a shaft <highlight><bold>476</bold></highlight> is secured to the thumbwheel <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> and extends downwardly therefrom. The other end of the shaft <highlight><bold>476</bold></highlight> has a flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> secured thereto. As such, rotation of the thumbwheel <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> causes rotation of the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> The mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> is operable to secure the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In particular, the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> may be positioned in a release position which allows the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> to be advanced through one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (the release position of the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> being approximately 90&deg; from the position of the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 41</cross-reference>). Once the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> is advanced through the hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> (i.e., the shaft <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> extends through the hole <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>), the thumbwheel <highlight><bold>474</bold></highlight> may be rotated such that the flange <highlight><bold>478</bold></highlight> is positioned in a locked position (such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 41</cross-reference>) thereby causing the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to be secured to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In such a manner, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be delivered to a desired location proximate to the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>, and thereafter released prior to, or during, bone screw insertion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 42 and 43</cross-reference>, the mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> may also be configured to include a number of alignment features for aligning the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in a desired lateral and/or longitudinal orientation relative to the bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 42</cross-reference>, the attachment mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> may be embodied to include a pair of downwardly extending locator tabs <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight>. The plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is positioned between the locator tabs <highlight><bold>480</bold></highlight> when the plate is secured to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> thereby maintaining the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in a desired lateral orientation. The attachment mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> may also be configured to include a downwardly extending flange in the form of a hook <highlight><bold>482</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 43</cross-reference>). The hook <highlight><bold>482</bold></highlight> is received through one of the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> when the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is secured to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In such a way, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be maintained in a desired longitudinal orientation. It should be appreciated that the design of the attachment mechanism <highlight><bold>470</bold></highlight> may be varied to include any one or more of the afore-described alignment features, or may alternatively, be configured without any of the alignment features (such as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 41</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that other types of retention mechanisms may also be utilized to secure the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> during delivery of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. For example, a remotely controllable clasping or gripping assembly may be utilized to engage the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> during delivery thereof to a desired location. For example, as shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be configured to include an attachment and delivery mechanism <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> The mechanism <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> includes a number of downwardly extending flanges <highlight><bold>492</bold></highlight> which, in the case of the exemplary embodiments described herein, are embodied as a pair of hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight>. The hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> are movable relative to one another. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 44 and 45</cross-reference>, the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> may be slid or otherwise moved relative to one another. More specifically, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference>, the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> may be positioned at a relative close distance to one another, or may be spaced apart from one another as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 45</cross-reference>. A spring <highlight><bold>498</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 45</cross-reference>) biases the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> toward one another (i.e., biases the hooks into the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference>). When a user (e.g., a surgeon) urges a lever <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> in the general direction of arrow <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference> (i.e., in the general direction of the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>), the bias of the spring <highlight><bold>498</bold></highlight> is overcome, thereby urging the hook <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> away from the hook <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight> in the general direction of arrow <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Such movement of the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> relative to one another allows for attachment of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In particular, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 48</cross-reference>, the surgeon may first urge the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight> away from one another (i.e., to the position shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 45</cross-reference>) and thereafter advance the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> into respective holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. Thereafter, when the surgeon releases the lever <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, the bias of the spring <highlight><bold>498</bold></highlight> urges the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> toward one another thereby causing the hooks to engage the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 48</cross-reference>) thereby securing the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be released from the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> by again urging the lever <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> toward the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> and advancing the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> out of their respective holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 46 and 47</cross-reference>, the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> may be configured to &ldquo;nest&rdquo; with one another when positioned in the closed position of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 44</cross-reference>. In such a manner, the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> are prevented from inadvertently engaging tissue (e.g., snagging) during manipulation of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in the body of the patient. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the attachment and delivery mechanism <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> may be configured such that the entire mechanism (including both hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight>) is movable (e.g., slidable) along the shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight>. To do so, the hook <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight> is defined in one end of an elongated, tubular shaped body <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> with a first lever <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight> being defined in the opposite end of the body <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. The body <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> is cannulated and slides along the shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> of the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The hook <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight>, on the other hand, is defined in one end of an elongated, tubular body <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> with a second lever <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> being defined in the opposite end of the body <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight>. In a similar manner as the body <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>, the body <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> is also cannulated. In such a manner, the body <highlight><bold>508</bold></highlight> slides along the body <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> When the two levers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> are urged toward one another (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 51</cross-reference>), the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> are urged away from one another. However, when the levers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> are released, the bias of the spring <highlight><bold>498</bold></highlight> urges the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> toward one another (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 50</cross-reference>). As such the levers <highlight><bold>506</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>510</bold></highlight> may be manipulated to allow the hooks <highlight><bold>494</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>496</bold></highlight> to engage the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in a similar manner to as described above in regard to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 48</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the mobility of the attachment and delivery mechanism <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> of FIGS. <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> allows for the selective positioning of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> during implantation thereof in the manner previously described in regard to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>. By sliding the mechanism <highlight><bold>490</bold></highlight> along the shaft <highlight><bold>306</bold></highlight> (as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 52</cross-reference>), the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be positioned in a temporary delivery position during advancement of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> into the body. For example, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>, the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be retained in a delivery position (indicated generally at <highlight><bold>460</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>) during insertion into the incision and advancement through the underlying tissue to the desired position along the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. Positioning the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> in such a position prevents the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> from obstructing the view of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> thereby allowing full use of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> during navigation of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to the delivery site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> Use of the aforedescribed components (e.g., the attachment and delivery mechanisms described in regard to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 27, 29</cross-reference>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) allows the surgeon to deliver the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> during insertion of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Specifically, prior to insertion of the bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> into the body of the patient, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is secured to the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in one of the manners described above. Thereafter, under visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, with the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> secured thereto, is inserted through a relatively small incision and thereafter advanced beneath the underlying tissue along the length of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> Once the instrument arrives at the location of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to which the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is to be secured, the surgeon may remotely (e.g., by use of a control (not shown) positioned on the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight>) advance the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> distally to its final position against the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> (indicated generally at <highlight><bold>462</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 34</cross-reference>). It should be appreciated that the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may then be secured (e.g., screwed) to the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> within full view of the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> when positioned in its final position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> In operation, the bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be utilized to secure the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> to a fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. To do so, a small incision is made in the skin overlying the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to be repaired. A relatively small degree of dissection is performed which extends from the incision in the skin through the underlying incision down to the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> The instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is then inserted into the incision and advanced under the visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. It should be appreciated that, if so desired, the surgeon could insert the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> through a secondary incision proximate to the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to be treated. In either case, the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is then advanced along the surface of the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> to allow for imaging of fracture lines, fragments, surrounding tissue, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> The bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> is inserted through the incision and positioned along the fractured bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. As described above, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be delivered to the desired location on the fracture bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> by the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> may be independently advanced to the desired location on the fractured bone once the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is properly positioned. It should be appreciated that when so positioned, the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> bridges the fracture or fractures in the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> Once the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> has been positioned, instruments and implant devices may be advanced through the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> in the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> and thereafter into contact with the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> under the visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. For example, under the visualization provided by the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, K-wires, soft tissue cannulated sleeves, drill guides and bits, tap guides and taps, screws and screw drivers may be advanced through the soft tissue and into the holes <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> of the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> (and hence the portions of the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> thereunder). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> A number of external devices, such as the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight>, may be utilized to guide the advancement of such instruments and implants. In addition, an integral or independent clamp assembly <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> may be utilized to further align the plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> prior to securing the same to the bone <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> In such a fashion, a plurality of bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may be installed on the bone plate <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. Once the last of such screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> has been installed, the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be removed. The incision may then be closed in a conventional manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> Other Orthopaedic Procedures </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized in the performance of other orthopaedic procedures. For example, the concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized in the performance of procedures to relieve carpal tunnel syndrome. Specifically, a small, portable, preferably disposable version of the endoscopic instruments hereinbefore described may be utilized during the performance of such a procedure. Typically, a surgeon performing a carpal tunnel procedure will utilize relatively large incisions along the wrist and hand of the patient and thereafter dissect a portion of the underlying tissue. This is done, primarily, so that the surgeon may directly visualize the underlying anatomy (such as median nerve in the case of carpal tunnel) thereby preventing inadvertent damage thereto. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> However, by use of an endoscopic instrument constructed in accordance with the present disclosure, the affected soft tissues may be dissected subcutaneously while under direct visualization from the endoscope. Specifically, an endoscope may be integrated into the subcutaneous scalpel assembly thereby allowing the surgeon to directly visualize the surgical site. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> Similar concepts may also be utilized in regard to the performance of a procedure to relieve compartment syndrome or plantar fasciitis. For example, the concepts of the present disclosure may be utilized to eliminate the need to cut an elongated incision in an extremity of the patient. To do so, an endoscope of the type described herein my be integrated into the hook portion of a hook knife instrument thereby allowing the surgeon to manipulate the relatively long instrument up through a small incision made in the extremity under the visualization provided by the endoscope. Once present at the surgical site, the endoscope provides the visualization necessary to aid the surgeon in the cutting of the desired tissue without damaging surrounding anatomical structures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized in regard to orthobiologics. Specifically, the concepts of the present disclosure may be utilized to deliver and place orthobiologic components such as resorbable patches and the like. For example, devices such as those devices sold under the trade names Restore&trade;, Orthosorb&trade; pins, &agr;-BSM&trade;, and Symphony&trade; may be placed utilizing the concepts of the present disclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized to provide direct visualization during skinny wire placement in regard to circular external fixation. Such visualization allows the surgeon to avoid neurological bundles and blood vessels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> The concepts of the present disclosure may also be utilized in the evaluation and removal of a tumor biopsy or an aneurysmal bone cyst. In particular, under the visualization of an endoscope, the surgeon may gain access to the surgical site via a trocar. Thereafter, the surgeon may evaluate the tumor or cyst by use of the endoscope, and, if need be, remove the tumor or cyst via the cannula of the trocar. Moreover, if the procedure so requires, graft material may be implanted into the surgical site via the cannula of the trocar and under the visualization of the endoscope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> Moreover, while a number of the concepts of the present disclosure have herein been described in detail in regard to delivery and installation of a bone plate, it should be appreciated that the instruments and methods described herein may also be utilized to remove a bone plate or other hardware such as screws in an IM nail or the nail itself. For example, the plating instruments described herein may be utilized to locate and remove an implanted bone plate (including the locating and removal of each of the bone screws). More specifically, the tissue expander, under the visualization of the endoscope, may be positioned over each of the bone screws. Then, under the alignment provided by the screw alignment device, the bone screws may then be removed via a series of stab incisions. Once the screws have been removed, the bone plate may then be removed from the body of the patient via the incision through which the plating instrument was inserted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> While the concepts of the present disclosure have been illustrated and described in detail in the drawings and foregoing description, such an illustration and description is to be considered as exemplary and not restrictive in character, it being understood that only illustrative embodiments have been shown and described and that all changes and modifications that come within the spirit of the disclosure are desired to be protected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> There are a plurality of advantages of the present disclosure arising from the various features of the apparatus and methods described herein. It will be noted that alternative embodiments of each of the apparatus and methods of the present disclosure may not include all of the features described yet still benefit from at least some of the advantages of such features. Those of ordinary skill in the art may readily devise their own implementations of apparatus and methods that incorporate one or more of the features of the present disclosure and fall within the spirit and scope of the present disclosure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> For example, in lieu of utilizing the plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> described herein, a trocar alone may be utilized to perform a plating operation. For example, a trocar with embedded CMOS or conventional endoscopic camera may be advanced (with a sheath) through a jig connected to the plate. The holes in the jig are in direct alignment with the holes in the plate. As the trocar/camera is passed through a stab incision, the plate and surrounding areas can be visualized. Once the surgeon is satisfied with the plate placement and proposed screw location, the trocar/camera is removed from the sheath, whereupon drills, taps, depth gauges, and screwdrivers can be used in succession to place screws. The process is repeated for each screw. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> Moreover, although the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> of the bone plating instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is herein described as being advanced through the handle <highlight><bold>304</bold></highlight> of the instrument <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, it should be appreciated that other configurations are also contemplated. For instance, the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be advanced into the workspace created by the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> via a stab incision which is distinct from the incision through which the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> enters the body. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> In a specific implementation of this exemplary embodiment, the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be advanced into the body in a similar nature as the bone screws <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be advanced through one of the holes <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> in the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and thereafter through one of the holes <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> in the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. For example, both the screw alignment device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and the tissue expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> may be configured to include a pair of holes <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, respectively. The endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be advanced through the first hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and the first hole <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> of the expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight> so as to visualize the insertion of a screw driver and bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> through the second hole <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> of the device <highlight><bold>318</bold></highlight> and the second hole of the expander <highlight><bold>308</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> It should be appreciated that the incisions through which the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is advanced may be later utilized for screw insertion to avoid the creation of additional stab incisions. Specifically, the stab incision through which the endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> is advanced to visualize insertion of a first bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> may be later utilized for the insertion of a second bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The endoscope <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may then visualize the insertion of the second bone screw <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> from a third stab incision which is later utilized for insertion of a third bone screw, and so forth. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A bone plating apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a shaft having a first end portion thereof secured to the housing such that a second portion thereof extends outwardly away from the housing, the second end portion of the shaft having an access hole, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a screw alignment jig having a first end portion thereof secured to the housing such that a second end portion thereof extends outwardly away from the housing, the second end portion of the screw alignment jig having a guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the access hole is aligned with the guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a tissue expander secured to the second end portion of the shaft, wherein the access hole is defined in the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tissue expander comprises a semi-tubular shaped member. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the housing comprises a handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the shaft is cannulated, further comprising an endoscope positioned in the cannulated shaft. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a tissue expander secured to the second end portion of the shaft, </claim-text>
<claim-text>an endoscope having a visualization tip, wherein (i) the shaft is cannulated, and (ii) the endoscope is positionable in the cannulated shaft such that the visualization tip thereof extends into the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the access hole is defined in the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a screw guide configured to extend through both the guide hole and the access hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first end portion of the screw alignment jig is removably secured to the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a plate attachment mechanism, the plate attachment mechanism being configured to secure a bone plate to the housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A bone plating apparatus, comprising: 
<claim-text>a handle, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a tissue expander secured to the handle, the tissue expander having an access hole, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a screw alignment jig having a first end portion thereof secured to the handle such that a second end portion thereof extends outwardly away from the handle, the second end portion of the screw alignment jig having a guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the access hole is aligned with the guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a shaft having a first end portion thereof secured to the handle and a second end portion thereof secured to the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the tissue expander comprises a semi-tubular shaped tunnel member having a first end portion thereof secured to the handle such that a second end portion thereof extends outwardly from the handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an endoscope, the endoscope having a visualization tip positioned in the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a screw guide configured to extend through both the guide hole and the access hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The bone plating apparatus of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first end portion of the screw alignment jig is removably secured to the handle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method of repairing a fractured bone, the method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>manipulating a handle such that a tissue expander secured to the handle is advanced through a skin incision and into subcutaneous tissue surrounding the fractured bone, the tissue expander having an access hole, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>securing a first end portion of a screw alignment jig to the handle such that a second end portion thereof extends outwardly from the handle, the screw alignment jig have a guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the securing step comprises aligning the access hole with the guide hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the manipulating step comprises advancing the tissue expander through the subcutaneous tissue surrounding the fractured bone under the visualization of an endoscope. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a visualization tip of the endoscope is positioned in the tissue expander during advancement thereof through the subcutaneous tissue surrounding the fractured bone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of advancing a bone plate to a position proximate to the fractured bone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of advancing the bone plate comprises advancing the bone plate through the skin incision. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of advancing the bone plate is performed contemporaneously with the step of advancing the tissue expander. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 25</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the bone plate is removably secured to the handle during advancement of the tissue expander and the bone plate through the subcutaneous tissue surrounding the fractured bone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of releasing the bone plate from the handle when the bone plate is positioned in a desired position proximate to the fractured bone. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 23</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of advancing a screw guide through both the guide hole and the access hole. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the step of advancing the screw guide comprises advancing the screw guide through a puncture incision. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 28</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of advancing a bone screw through the screw guide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The method of claim <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, wherein the step of advancing the bone screw comprises threadingly engaging the bone screw into the fractured bone so as to secure the bone plate to the fractured bone.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00024">
<image id="EMI-D00024" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00025">
<image id="EMI-D00025" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00026">
<image id="EMI-D00026" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00027">
<image id="EMI-D00027" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00028">
<image id="EMI-D00028" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00029">
<image id="EMI-D00029" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00030">
<image id="EMI-D00030" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00031">
<image id="EMI-D00031" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00031.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00032">
<image id="EMI-D00032" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00032.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00033">
<image id="EMI-D00033" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00033.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00034">
<image id="EMI-D00034" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00034.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00035">
<image id="EMI-D00035" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00035.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00036">
<image id="EMI-D00036" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00036.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00037">
<image id="EMI-D00037" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00037.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00038">
<image id="EMI-D00038" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00038.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00039">
<image id="EMI-D00039" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00039.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00040">
<image id="EMI-D00040" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00040.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00041">
<image id="EMI-D00041" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00041.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00042">
<image id="EMI-D00042" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00042.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00043">
<image id="EMI-D00043" file="US20030004513A1-20030102-D00043.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
