<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003626A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003626A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003626</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10231347</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020830</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/44</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>121000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>117000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>106000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Open-cavity semiconductor die package</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10231347</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020830</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09950702</doc-number>
<document-date>20010913</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6475832</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
<division-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09950702</doc-number>
<document-date>20010913</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09218180</doc-number>
<document-date>19981222</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>GRANTED</parent-status>
<parent-patent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>6307258</doc-number>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent-patent>
</parent-child>
</division-of>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Stanford</given-name>
<middle-name>W.</middle-name>
<family-name>Crane</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boca Raton</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lakshminarasimha</given-name>
<family-name>Krishnapura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Delray Beach</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yun</given-name>
<family-name>Li</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Boca Raton</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Silicon Bandwidth, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MORGAN LEWIS &amp; BOCKIUS LLP</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1111 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE NW</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20004</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A semiconductor die carrier includes a housing that defines a cavity for holding one or more semiconductor dies, electrically conductive leads, and a cover plate having an aperture formed therethrough. The housing includes insulative side walls and a end plate joined to the side walls. The side walls and the end plate may be molded together as a one-piece unit. One or more of the side walls includes openings for receiving the leads so that an internal lead section extends within the cavity and an external lead section extends from the side walls external of the housing. The side walls may include a recess for receiving the cover plate. The aperture in the cover plate allows a semiconductor die held in the housing to be exposed to the environment. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is related in subject matter to U.S. application Ser. No. 08/208,586, entitled &ldquo;Prefabricated Semiconductor Chip Carrier&rdquo;, filed Mar. 11, 1994, and expressly incorporated by reference herein; U.S. application Ser. No. 08/465,146, entitled &ldquo;Method of Manufacturing A Semiconductor Chip Carrier&rdquo;, filed Jun. 5, 1995, and expressly incorporated by reference herein; U.S. application Ser. No. 08/487,103, entitled &ldquo;Semiconductor Die Carrier Having Double-Sided Die Attach Plate&rdquo;, filed Jun. 7, 1995, and expressly incorporated by reference herein; U.S. application Ser. No. 08/902,032, entitled &ldquo;Semiconductor Die Carrier Having A Dielectric Epoxy Between Adjacent Leads&rdquo;, filed Jul. 29, 1997, which is a continuation of U.S. application Ser. No. 08/487,100, filed Jun. 7, 1995, and expressly incorporated by reference herein; U.S. application Ser. No. 08/482,00, entitled &ldquo;Low Profile Semiconductor Die Carrier&rdquo;, filed Jun. 7, 1995, and expressly incorporated by reference herein; U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/970,379, entitled &ldquo;Multi-Chip Module Having Interconnect Dies&rdquo;, filed Nov. 15, 1997 and expressly incorporated by reference herein; and U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/033,480, entitled &ldquo;Semiconductor Die Package For Mounting In Horizontal And Upright Configurations&rdquo;, filed Mar. 3, 1998 and expressly incorporated by reference herein.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a semiconductor die package having an open cavity that exposes a semiconductor die held in the package to the environment and, more particularly, to an open-cavity semiconductor die package adapted to enable a person to place a finger tip on the semiconductor die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor die or chip is an electrical component on which a microcircuit is built. The microcircuits can be interconnected together on the printed circuit board to form larger electrical circuits for use in radios, televisions, compact disk players, and computers, to name just a few. Because the semiconductor die is fragile, it is encased in a semiconductor die package to protect it from the environment. If one were to look inside an electronic device, such as a computer or a compact disk player, one would see one or more printed circuit boards on which semiconductor die packages are mounted and electrically interconnected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor die package includes a housing that holds the semiconductor die and conductive leads or pins that extend from the bottom or sides of the housing. The conductive leads are electrically connected to the semiconductor die within the housing. The outside ends of the leads are soldered to conductive paths on the printed circuit board. This secures the semiconductor die package to the printed circuit board and permits electrical signals to pass between the semiconductor die and other components on the printed circuit board. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In a conventional semiconductor die package, the housing encases the semiconductor die to prevent damage to the semiconductor die from exposure to the environment. The housing may be hermetically sealed, encased in plastic, or otherwise sealed against the environment. Some sealed packages can be opened, without damaging the semiconductor die or the wire bonding between the semiconductor die and the package leads, to allow reworking of the semiconductor die and the leads. These packages are re-sealed after reworking is completed. The process for resealing the package is complex and difficult to accomplish. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In some applications, it may be desirable to expose the semiconductor die to the environment. Some semiconductor dies are designed for use as sensors for sensing, for example, an environmental condition. As a result, at least a portion of the semiconductor dies must be exposed to the environment in order to perform sensing functions. For example, the semiconductor die may serve as a sensor for sensing a person&apos;s fingerprint for identification purposes. In this case, the person&apos;s finger must contact the semiconductor die to enable sensing. Conventional semiconductor die packages cannot be used for such applications because, as noted above, the packages are designed to encase and seal the semiconductor die to prevent exposure to the environment. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention has been made in view of the above circumstances and has as an object to provide an economical semiconductor die package having an open cavity that exposes a semiconductor die held in the package to the environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide a sturdy and reliable semiconductor die package having an open cavity that exposes a semiconductor die held in the package to the environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provided an economical method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package having an open cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Additional objects and advantages of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The objects and advantages of the invention will be realized and attained by means of the elements and combinations particularly pointed out in the appended claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> To achieve the objects and in accordance with the purpose of the invention, as embodied and broadly described herein, the invention comprises a semiconductor die package having a housing defining a cavity for holding at least one semiconductor die, a plurality of electrically conductive leads, and a cover plate. The housing includes a plurality of insulative side walls and an end plate joined to the side walls. The plurality of electrically conductive leads extend through at least one of the side walls, wherein each of the leads includes an internal lead section extending within the cavity and an external lead section extending externally of the at least one side wall. The cover plate is joined to the side walls opposite the end plate and includes an aperture formed therethrough for exposing to the environment the at least one semiconductor die held in the cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The invention further comprises a method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package comprising the steps of (1) forming a package assembly including a housing defining a cavity for holding at least one semiconductor die and a plurality of electrically conductive leads, the housing including a plurality of insulative side walls and an end plate joined to the side walls and the plurality of electrically conductive leads extending through at least one of the side walls, wherein each of the leads including an internal lead section extending within the cavity and an external lead section extending externally of the at least one side wall; and (2) forming a cover plate for joining to the side walls opposite the end plate, wherein the cover plate includes an aperture formed therethrough for exposing to the environment the at least one semiconductor die held in the cavity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary and explanatory only and are not restrictive of the invention, as claimed.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiment(s) of the invention and together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> provides an exploded view of an embodiment of a semiconductor die package according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows the semiconductor die package of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> when assembled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a top view of an embodiment of a housing for the semiconductor die package shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows the side of the housing depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a close-up view of the side of the housing shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a cross section of the housing depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a close-up view of the cross section of the housing shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8, 9</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrate various views of an embodiment of a lead for use in the semiconductor die carrier shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> illustrates the side of an embodiment of a cover plate for use with semiconductor die package shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows the top of the cover plate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> depicts a bonding arrangement for use in the semiconductor die package of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> illustrates a cross section of the semiconductor die package having a bonding arrangement as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows a close-up view of the cross section of the semiconductor die package shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16, 17</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> show views of a cap for a semiconductor die package according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Reference will now be made in detail to the present exemplary embodiment(s) of the invention illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> illustrate one embodiment of a semiconductor die package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for holding a semiconductor die according to the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> provides an exploded view of the semiconductor die package and semiconductor die shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, semiconductor die package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for holding one or more semiconductor dies <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> retained in the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and a cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> disposed at the top of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes a plurality of side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and an end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> extend from the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a single row of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> extending from opposite side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may extend from any one or more of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and may extend from the side wall(s) <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> in one or more rows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> A cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is defined within the interior of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. One or more semiconductor dies <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be housed within the cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>, for example, by mounting to end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> using an adhesive, such as an epoxy. Of course, semiconductor dies <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be mounted within cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> by means other than adhesive and may be mounted to structure other than the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Electrically conductive material (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>), such as bonding wire, tape automated bonding, jumpers, and/or other electrically conductive material, may be used to electrically connect the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to the semiconductor die(s). Not all of the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> need to be electrically connected to the semiconductor die. Some of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may not be connected to any electrically conductive element within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Alternatively or in addition, some of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be electrically connected to electromagnetic interference (EMI) or electrostatic discharge (ESD) shielding either internal or external to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, a ground or power plane included within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, or another electrical component within the housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> An encapsulant (not shown) may cover all or part of the electrically conductive material and a portion of the semiconductor die(s). Cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> includes an aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight>. When cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is mounted to housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> exposes a portion of at least one of the semiconductor die(s). Accordingly, the semiconductor die package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has an open-cavity design in that a surface of the semiconductor die is exposed through aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> in cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. In this regard, it is possible but not necessary for cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to be exposed through the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. For example, the open-cavity arrangement according to the present invention may be achieved when the cover plate is flush with the surface of the semiconductor die(s), when the gap between the die(s) and the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is closed with encapsulant or another sealant or fitting, or when the gap between the dies(s) and the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is open. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> will be described in greater detail in connection with FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. As indicated above, housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> includes side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, which is joined to the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> for receiving one or more semiconductor dies. While in one preferred embodiment the cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> receives one semiconductor die, multiple semiconductor dies may be accommodated by appropriately sizing and/or shaping the cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. Cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be defined within the interior of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, for example, by the interior surfaces of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, including recesses in the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, in one or more of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, or in both the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and one or more of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Of course, cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> may be defined in whole or in part by other structure located within side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> One or more of side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> preferably include openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> formed therethrough for receiving leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be shaped to accommodate insertion of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be rectangular to receive and retain leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be shaped like tombstones, i.e., generally rectangular with two square corners opposite two rounded corners, to facilitate retention and accurate positioning of the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the bottom of openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be flush with the top of end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. As a result, the semiconductor die(s) <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is positioned close to the open surface of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to make it easier for a person to place a finger on the surface of the semiconductor die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the thickness of end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> is substantially greater than the distance that side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> extend from the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. While this arrangement is not a necessary part of the present invention, it provides several advantages when the package is used to house a fingerprint sensor die. The thick end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> provides a stable and sturdy base for supporting the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and will not bend, bow, or flex when pressure is applied to the die, for example, when a person presses on the semiconductor die within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. When the package is mounted to a printed circuit board or other substrate, an adhesive, such as an epoxy, may be applied to secure the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to the substrate. Consequently, external forces applied to the package will be transferred to the substrate through the thick end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> to reduce shear forces on the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. The short side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> provide ready access to the semiconductor die within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for a finger and enable large surface area of the finger to contact the semiconductor die. Of course, for this or other applications, the package may have side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> with a greater height to limit access to the semiconductor die or provide directional access. Further, the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may have different heights to facilitate directional access at an angle to the semiconductor die. The dimensions of the cavity and its aperture ratio may be designed to meet the objectives of the application to which the package is used. When used as a fingerprint sensor, the cavity <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight> is sized to accommodate a sensor die and to permit a finger to touch the sensor die. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> An interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> maybe provided adjacent to and spaced from side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> may extend the entire length of the cavity. A conductive material (not shown), such as a conductive epoxy, may be introduced between the interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> and the side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> may serve as a dam for retaining the conductive material and preventing it from reaching the semiconductor dies. The conductive material may electrically connect together the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> that extend from side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> are preferably molded from an insulative, polymeric material, such as a liquid crystal polymer. One suitable liquid crystal polymer is VECTRA&trade; E <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>i, </italic></highlight>which is available from Hoechst-Celanese. Of course, housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be made of any suitable organic or inorganic material or combination of materials. The openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> may be molded into the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> or may be formed after molding by removing material from the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. Further, the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may be formed together as a single unit or, alternatively, molded separately and then joined together using an adhesive or other suitable means. The end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be molded together with the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to form a single one-piece unit, or the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be formed separately and then attached. FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> show an embodiment of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> having a single material, one-piece molded construction of side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. Of course, the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> may be made from different materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor die or dies may be mounted directly to the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> using an adhesive. A platform (not shown) for mounting the semiconductor die may be formed as part of the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> or formed separately and attached as part of the end plate. The platform may be used to adjust the level of the top surface of the semiconductor die(s) relative to the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, and/or the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may include an exterior lip <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> along an upper edge thereof. In addition, the top of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> may include a recess <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> for receiving the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. An adhesive may be applied to the recess and/or the edges of the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to secure the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Other mechanisms for mounting the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be used as well, for example, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be adhered to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> without the use of a recess, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may clip or snap to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, be press fit, or heat sealed, or be permanently or removably attached by other means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> provides a detailed view of the openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> in the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. As shown, the exterior end of the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is flared to guide leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> into the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> during insertion. In a preferred embodiment, the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are inserted into preformed openings <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> in the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. As an alternative, housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may be molded around leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, for example, by injection molding techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8, 9</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> illustrate one embodiment of the conductive leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, the conductive leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are generally L-shaped. The conductive leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> each include an internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>, a stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, and an external lead section <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>. The internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> resides inside the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to facilitate direct or indirect connection to the semiconductor die(s) or other electrical components within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may be relatively narrow compared to the stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> to facilitate insertion of the lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> into the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. A sloping transitional section <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> couples the internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> to the stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. Sloping transitional section <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> prevents the lead from digging into the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> upon insertion. The internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may include a flat bonding surface <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> for contacting electrically conductive material used to connect the leads to the semiconductor die(s). The bonding surface <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> may be plated with gold or another highly conductive material to ensure a reliable electrical connection. If a particular lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is not intended to be used for establishing an electrical connection, the bonding surface <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> need not be formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In one preferred embodiment, stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> frictionally engages the inner walls of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> within opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>. The strength of the frictional engagement may be sufficient to retain lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> in housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be bonded to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> using a suitable adhesive. Further, the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, or just the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, may be molded around the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> has a rectangular cross section with its height greater than its width. When the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> is tombstone-shaped, the rounded corners of the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> force the sides of stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> against the flat sides of the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, which are opposite the rounded corners, to accurately position the lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> against the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>. In addition, the corners of the stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of the lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> press into the rounded corners of the opening <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> to help secure the lead <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The external lead section <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> extends from the side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and may have the same axial dimensions as the stabilizing section <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> to produce a robust, rigid lead that is difficult to bend. The leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be arranged in multiple, vertically spaced rows or tiers through the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and may extend from one or more of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>. The generally L-shaped leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are designed for surface mounting to a printed circuit board or other substrate. The external lead section includes a foot portion <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> at an end distal to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. The foot portion <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight> facilitates surface mounting to bonding pads on the surface of a substrate, for example a printed circuit board. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Further, leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are shown to have a toe <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>on foot portion <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight>. The toe <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>increases the soldering space and provides a toe geometry for a standard TQFP open top socket. Of course, the toe <highlight><bold>331</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>may be omitted or replaced by other end configurations. Rather than a foot portion, the distal end of the external lead section <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may have a butt end, a curled end, or a gull wing configuration. Alternatively, the external lead section <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> may be adapted to connect to a printed circuit board or other substrate by other means, such as, for example, plated through hole (PTH) technology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are preferably stamped from a metal blank into an L-shape and then finished by machining. In this way, the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are extremely rigid because they are not bent or designed to be bent during manufacture. Accordingly, leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> resist bending when mounted to a substrate, such as a printed circuit board, and provide a sturdy, stable connection. This is particularly important in a fingerprint sensor application, where the stress of repeated pressure must be absorbed without bending or breaking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 11 and 12</cross-reference> illustrate the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. As shown from the side in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be flat to facilitate reception into the recess <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. In the alternative, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may include lips, apertures, or protrusions, for example, to aid in mounting to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Also, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is thin to limit the distance between the environment and the semiconductor die and so that a large area of the finger may touch the semiconductor die. For example, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may have a thickness of 0.008 inches (3.1 mm) or less. While <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> shows aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to be slightly off center, this is not necessary for the present invention. The size, shape, location, and number of the apertures through cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be selected based on the area, location, and number of dies to be exposed. In some applications, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may be made of a conductive material, for example copper or another conductive metal. For example, in a package designed for use as a fingerprint sensor, a conductive material may be used to form the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to discharge static from a person&apos;s finger prior to touching the semiconductor die(s). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> illustrates one embodiment for electrically connecting a semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Other arrangements may be used as well and the arrangement shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> should not be considered to limit the present invention. Further, while <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows a single semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> mounted directly to end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, it should be understood that multiple semiconductor dies <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be mounted within housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Rather than direct mounting to the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight>, the semiconductor die(s) may be mounted to an intervening substrate, which may be electrically active, such as a ceramic substrate or circuit board. Housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> may also include one or more interconnect dies as disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 08/970,379, entitled &ldquo;Multi-Chip Module Having Interconnect Dies&rdquo;, filed Nov. 15, 1997 and expressly incorporated by reference herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is used to interconnect the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to bonding pads formed at the periphery of the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> may be, for example, wire bonding, tape automated bonding (TAB), conductive traces on insulated substrates, interconnect dies, and jumper wires, among others and/or a combination thereof. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows the electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> as a direct wire bonding between leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> and the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> preferably contacts the bonding surfaces <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to establish a good electrical connection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> shows that the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is not centered on the end plate <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. This arrangement is adapted for the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>, which includes a concentration of bonding pads <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> at the right hand side of the lower peripheral area. The semiconductor die is mounted so as to center the bonding pads <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> at the right hand side of the lower peripheral area to corresponding leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for electrical connection. Therefore, the length of the wire bonding connection <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for electrically connecting to a bonding pad <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at a first end of the bonding pads <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> is substantially the same length as a wire bonding connection <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>for electrically connecting to a bonding pad <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>at a second end of the bonding pads <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>. As a result, the wire bonding connections <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>-<highlight><italic>n </italic></highlight>are balanced. This arrangement is not a necessary part of the present invention. Alternatively, the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be centered when mounted within housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, and the electrical connections may be established according to known techniques. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> extending from side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> are not electrically connected to the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Some or all of these leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be electrically isolated and used solely to provide a stable mount to the printed circuit board or other substrate to which the package is mounted. One or more of the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be connected to a ground plane, a power plane, or EMI or ESD shielding. Further, others of the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> may be connected to the semiconductor die, either directly or indirectly. In one preferred embodiment, leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> extending from side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are electrically connected together using a conductive epoxy or paste and are connected to EMI shielding housed within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> or ESD shielding on the outside of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. Note that the conductive epoxy or paste may be used to couple the leads to the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, thereby providing an ESD discharge path from the cover plate, through the epoxy or paste, through the leads, and to a ground on the PCB. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> illustrates a cross section of the semiconductor die package having the bonding arrangement shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates a close-up view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 14 and 15</cross-reference>, cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> seats within recess <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> at the top of side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and on the top of interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. As shown, the interior wall <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> isolates the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> that extend through side wall <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The bonding surface <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> of the internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> may be positioned below the active surface of the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> so that the active surface of the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be located closer to the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. Electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> connects the internal lead section <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> to bonding pads on the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The external lead section of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> extend from side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for surface mounting to a substrate, such as a printed circuit board. As shown, the bottom surface of the foot portion may extend slightly below the bottom surface of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. This provides clearance for an adhesive, for example, an epoxy, to be applied to the bottom surface of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to secure the housing to the printed circuit board or other substrate to which the package is mounted. The aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> is located to expose a portion of semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to the environment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> After electrically connecting the semiconductor die(s) to the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, an encapsulant may be used to seal all or a portion of the internal lead sections <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, the electrically conductive material <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, and a portion of the semiconductor die(s) to which the electrically conductive material is connected. In such as case, the encapsulant may bond to the portion of leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> that is exposed within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference> illustrate various views of an optional cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> for the semiconductor die package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> fits over the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>, and thereby closes aperture <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> to protect the semiconductor die package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> after packaging and during reflow processes. In one embodiment, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be snapped on to the top of package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be removably secured to the package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> by other means. For example, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may slide on an off the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> or cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be attached to the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> or cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> using a hinge (not shown). In this case, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may swing open to expose the semiconductor die(s) when needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16 and 17</cross-reference>, cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> includes a top surface <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> and two spring sides <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>for holding the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> to removably retain the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> to the package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The top surface <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight> may be generally flat but with a slight curvature such that a pick-and-place assembly machine can pick the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> and package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and place it on the solder pads of a substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> The cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be made of a resilient material, for example, stainless steel, to provide a spring force to sides <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, the sides <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>form angles &agr;<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and&agr;<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>to the top surface <highlight><bold>610</bold></highlight>. Angles &agr;<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and&agr;<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>may be the same or different. Angles &agr;<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>and&agr;<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>may be, for example, 80&deg;. After the leads of the package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are soldered, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> can be removed using the handle <highlight><bold>630</bold></highlight>. The cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be reusable or disposable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> After the semiconductor die(s) <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are mounted within the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and electrically connected (e.g., wire bonded) to leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> is secured to the top of the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>. In certain applications, the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> may be exposed after packaging to function as a sensor. When the leads <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> are soldered to a printed circuit board or other substrate, the package <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> will be exposed to a high temperature reflow process, which may damage the exposed semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. Cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be fit over the housing <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> to close the aperture in the cover plate <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> and protect the semiconductor die <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> during this reflow process and other related processes, such as aqueous cascade washing and/or hot air drying. The cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> shields the semiconductor die from the impact of cleaning solutions, blown air, and other processing or environmental conditions that might damage the die(s). Of course, the cap <highlight><bold>600</bold></highlight> may be used to protect the semiconductor die at other times as well, but may be removed for sensing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made without departing from the scope or spirit of the invention. Other embodiments of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from consideration of the specification and practice of the invention disclosed herein. It is intended that the specification and examples be considered as exemplary only, with a true scope and spirit of the invention being indicated by the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing defining a cavity for holding at least one semiconductor die, said housing including a plurality of insulative side walls and an end plate joined to said side walls; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of electrically conductive leads extending through at least one of said side walls, each of said leads including an internal lead section extending within the cavity and an external lead section extending externally of said at least one side wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover plate joined to said side walls opposite said end plate, wherein said cover plate includes an aperture formed therethrough for exposing to the environment the at least one semiconductor die held in the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said side walls and said end plate are a one-piece unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the external lead section is substantially L-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said side walls include a recess for receiving said cover plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aperture in said cover plate is sized to expose a majority of the upper surface of the at least semiconductor die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cover plate extends over and covers at least a portion of the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said electrically conductive leads extend from at least two of said side walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said housing includes an interior wall that separates leads extending from a first one of said at least two side walls from leads extending from a second one of said at least two side walls. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said end plate is adapted to support the at least one semiconductor die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming a package assembly including a plurality of electrically conductive leads and a housing defining a cavity for holding at least one semiconductor die, said housing including a plurality of insulative side walls and an end plate joined to the side walls, wherein each of said plurality of electrically conductive leads extend through at least one of said side walls such that an internal lead section extends within the cavity and an external lead section extends externally of said at least one side wall; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a cover plate for joining to said side walls opposite said end plate, wherein said cover plate includes an aperture formed therethrough for exposing to the environment the at least one semiconductor die held in the cavity. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of forming a package assembly comprises: 
<claim-text>molding said housing with openings formed in the at least one side wall; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting said conductive leads into the openings in the at least one side wall. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of forming a package assembly comprises: 
<claim-text>holding the conductive leads in position; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>molding said housing around the conductive leads. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of forming the package assembly includes the step of molding said side walls and said end plate as a one-piece unit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the external lead section is substantially L-shaped. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said step of forming the package assembly includes forming in said side walls a recess for receiving said cover plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the aperture in said cover plate is sized to expose a majority of the upper surface of the at least semiconductor die. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of joining said cover plate to said housing. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor die package according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cove plate covers at least a portion of the cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003626A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
