<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.NB SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004007A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004007A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004007</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09826544</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010404</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>A63B057/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>473</class>
<subclass>221000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Measurement of the coefficient of restitution of a golf club</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Matthew</given-name>
<middle-name>J.</middle-name>
<family-name>Erickson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Frank</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Fan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Steven</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Ehlers</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>John</given-name>
<middle-name>B.</middle-name>
<family-name>Kosmatka</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CALLAWAY GOLF COMPANY</name-1>
<name-2>Attention: MICHAEL A. CATANIA</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2285 Rutherford Road</address-1>
<city>Carlsbad</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>92008-8815</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method (<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>) and system (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) or golf club head (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>) is disclosed herein. The system (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) and method (<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>) are able to predict the COR in a non-destructive manner for a particular golf ball and impact speed. The system (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) and method (<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>) utilize a vibration sensor (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) attached to the face (<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>) of a golf club (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>). The vibration sensor (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) is excited with an excitation device (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>), and data is transmitted to an analyzer (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>). A mathematical model of the golf club (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>) is created allowing for the coefficient of restitution to be predicted without destroying the golf club (<highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Not Applicable </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a system and method for measuring the coefficient of restitution of a golf club. More specifically, the present invention relates to an on-site system and method for measuring the coefficient of restitution of a golf club without alteration of the golf club. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In 1998, the United States Golf Association (&ldquo;USGA&rdquo;) decided to regulate technological improvements through a liberal interpretation of Rule 4.1 of the Rules of Golf, as set forth by the USGA and the Royals and Ancient Club of Saint Andrews. The USGA determined that a golf club head having a coefficient of restitution (&ldquo;COR&rdquo;) greater than 0.83, on a scale of 0.00 to 1.00, would be non-conforming under the Rules of Golf as a club head having a spring-like effect. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In order to determine the COR of a golf club head, the USGA devised a laboratory test that necessitates the removal of the shaft of a golf club. The test is conducted at the USGA testing laboratory requiring that a golf club be submitted to the USGA for conformance. The unshafted golf club head is placed on a pedestal without securing the club head to the pedestal. A PINNACLE&reg; Gold two-piece golf ball is fired at the face of the club head at 160 feet per second. The club head is knocked-off the pedestal, and the COR is measured by the rebound of the golf ball. A grid is established on the club face using the scorelines and etched vertical lines, further destroying the club and creating further uncertainties. The procedure is repeated at random sites on the grid on the face of the golf club until the point with the highest COR is determined from the test. The outbound velocity of the golf ball after impact with the face is determined using a light gate systems such as described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,682,230. A more detailed explanation of the test is provided at www.usga.com. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is obvious to anyone skilled in the art that such a test is inapplicable to on-course testing, and requires a specific laboratory with skilled technicians to perform the test. Further, the &ldquo;cannon test&rdquo; results in destruction of the club. Yet further, the test is conducted on an unshafted club head, completely ignoring the shaft and grip. What is needed is a test that can be performed on course, with consistent repeatability, and minimal operator error. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a solution to the problems associated with testing for COR using the method of the prior art. The present invention is able to accomplish this by providing a method and system that measures the COR of a golf club in a non-destructive manner, and without removal of the shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> One aspect of the present invention is a method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club. The method includes attaching a vibration sensor to a face of the golf club. Next, the attached vibration sensor is excited or impacted with an excitation or impact device to generate vibrations in the face. Next, the force of impact or the excitation from the device and the vibrations measured by the vibration sensor are transmitted to an analyzer to generate frequency domain data for the golf club. Next, the frequency domain data for the golf club is transformed into a transfer function for the golf club. Then, a golf ball model for a specific golf ball is inputted into the transfer function along with an impact speed in order to generate a predicted COR for the golf club at a specified impact speed with the specific golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is a system for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club during impact at a specified speed with a specific golf ball. The system includes an accelerometer, an excitation or impact means, and a calculation means. The accelerometer is attached to a point on the face of the golf club. The accelerometer has means for measuring the vibration of the face. The means for exciting or impacting the face of the golf club in order to vibrate the face has means for measuring the force of excitation or impact with the face. The calculation means calculates the coefficient of restitution of the golf club from the vibration of the face, the force of impact or excitation with the face from the impacting or exciting means, an effective mass of the golf club and a mass of a golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Another aspect of the present invention is a system and method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club head during impact with a golf ball. The system and method is as described above, however, instead of an entire golf club, only the golf club head is utilized for predicting the COR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Yet another aspect of the present invention is a method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club using time domain data. The method includes attaching a vibration sensor to a face of the golf club. Then, the attached vibration sensor is excited or impacted with an excitation or impact device to generate vibrations in the face. Next, the force of impact or excitation from the device and the vibrations measured by the vibration sensor are transmitted to an analyzer to generate time domain data for the golf club. Next, the time domain data for the golf club is transformed into a state-space representation of the golf club. Then, a golf ball model for a specific golf ball is inputted into the state-space representation and an impact speed in order to generate a predicted COR for the golf club at a specified impact speed with the specific golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> It is a primary object of the present invention to provide a method and apparatus for predicting the COR of a golf club or golf club head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is an additional object of the present invention to provide a method and apparatus for predicting the COR of a golf club in a non-destructive manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> It is an additional object of the present invention to provide a method and apparatus for predicting the COR of a golf club that is portable, and may be performed on-course. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is an additional object of the present invention to provide a method and apparatus for predicting the COR of a golf club that requires less time than the USGA cannon test. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Having briefly described the present invention, the above and further objects, features and advantages thereof will be recognized by those skilled in the pertinent art from the following detailed description of the invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the system of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a golf club head. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a toe end side view of the golf club head of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a bottom view of the golf club head of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a heel end side view of the golf club head of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a side view of a golf club prior to impact with a golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a side view of a golf club during impact with a golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a side view of a golf club after impact with a golf ball. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the general method of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the data acquisition process of the method of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the transformation of the frequency domain data into a transfer finction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is schematic diagram of the general model used to identify dynamic linear systems in the frequency domain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a graph of frequency versus magnitude of the fitted curve from the frequency domain data. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a flow chart of the ball model input into the transfer function. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a chart comparing the predicted values of several golf clubs using the present invention versus the USGA cannon test values. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a chart demonstrating the differences in values between the present invention and the USGA cannon test for the golf clubs in the chart of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The present invention is directed at a method and system for measuring the coefficient of restitution (also referred to herein as &ldquo;COR&rdquo;) of a golf club in a non-destructive manner. The COR is generally set forth by the following equation:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mi>e</mi>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mfrac>
    <mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>v</mi>
        <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
      <mo>-</mo>
      <msub>
        <mi>v</mi>
        <mn>1</mn>
      </msub>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
      <msub>
        <mi>U</mi>
        <mn>1</mn>
      </msub>
      <mo>-</mo>
      <msub>
        <mi>U</mi>
        <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
    </mrow>
  </mfrac>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="17.03835" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> wherein U<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, is the club head velocity prior to impact; U<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is the golf ball velocity prior to impact which is zero; v<highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>is the club head velocity just after separation of the golf ball from the face of the club head; v<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is the golf ball velocity just after separation of the golf ball from the face of the club head; and e is the coefficient of restitution between the golf ball and the club face. The values of e are limited between zero and 1.0 for systems with no energy addition. The coefficient of restitution, e, for a material such as a soft clay or putty would be near zero, while for a perfectly elastic material, where no energy is lost as a result of deformation, the value of e would be 1.0. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the system of the present invention is generally designated <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The system includes an analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and an impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and the impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are preferably connected to the analyzer through wires <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. However, those skilled in the art will recognize that other data transmission means, such as wireless transmission, could be used without departing from the scope and spirit of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The vibration sensor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is attached to a golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> through use of an adhesive <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> such as epoxy, beeswax, or the like. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, the golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> includes a shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, a golf club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> with a body <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The body <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> of the club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> generally includes the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, a crown <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and a sole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is partitioned into a heel section <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> nearest the shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a toe section <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> opposite the heel section <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, and a rear section <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> opposite the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has a plurality of scorelines <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> thereon. The club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has a hosel <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> for receiving the shaft <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and the hosel <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> may be internal or external. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is typically composed of a stainless steel material or a titanium material. However, those skilled in the art will recognize that the club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be composed of other materials such as vitreous metals, ceramics, composites, carbon, carbon fibers and other fibrous materials. The club head <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is typically cast or forged, and the thickness of the crown <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, the sole <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may be constant or varying. Typically, the construction of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> will effect the COR of the golf club. For example, a high COR golf club is disclosed in co-pending U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/431,982, filed on Nov. 1, 1999, entitled Golf Club Head With Face Composed of a Forged Material, which pertinent parts are hereby incorporated by reference. An example of a low COR golf club would be a golf club head composed of a persimmon wood. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, the flexibility of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> allows for a greater coefficient of restitution. At <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is immediately prior to striking a golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. At <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is engaging the golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, and deformation of the golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is illustrated. At <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> has just been launched from the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In a preferred embodiment, the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is an accelerometer that is capable of measuring the vibrations of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> generated by impact with an impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. An alternative vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is a laser Doppler vibrometer. The accelerometer may have a titanium cap for protection during impact. The impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is preferably a hammer with a connection to measure the force in volts, and transmit the force information to the analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the wire <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. An alternative impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is a fixed striking device that would remove any operator error. In an alternative embodiment, the impact device is an excitation device that imparts vibrations in the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. However, those skilled in the pertinent art will recognize that other impact or excitation devices <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be used without departing from the scope and spirit of the present invention. The analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is preferably a spectrum analyzer such as an OROS-OR763 spectrum analyzer available from OROS S.A. of France. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The general method is set forth in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, which is a flow chart of the overall method <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. At block <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, the information is acquired from the golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> by the system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, as described in greater detail below. At block <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>, the acquired data is transformed into a transfer function using a software such as MATLAB frequency domain system identification toolbox, as described in greater detail below. At block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>, the transfer function is utilized with additional information to create a mathematical model of the club. At block <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>, either of the following equations is utilized to generate the COR of the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for a given golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at a predetermined impact speed: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>COR&equals;</italic></highlight>(<highlight><italic>V&prime;</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/V</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>club</subscript></highlight>)(1&equals;<highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight>/<highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>effective club</subscript></highlight>)&minus;1</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>COR&equals;(<highlight><italic>V&prime;</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/V</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball)(</subscript></highlight>1&plus;<highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball </subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>m </italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>effective club)&plus;</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight>/<highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>effective club</subscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> V<highlight><subscript>ball </subscript></highlight>is the velocity of the golf ball after impact with the club. V&prime;<highlight><subscript>ball </subscript></highlight>is the velocity of the golf ball if it is fired at the golf club instead of having the golf club swing at a stationary golf ball. V<highlight><subscript>club </subscript></highlight>is the swing speed of the club. m<highlight><subscript>ball </subscript></highlight>is the mass of the golf ball. m<highlight><subscript>effective club </subscript></highlight>is the effective mass of the golf club determined at zero frequency. The data acquisition process, block <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, is further explained in the flow chart of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. At block <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>, the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is weighed to obtain the mass of the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. At block <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>, the projection of the center of gravity (&ldquo;CG&rdquo;) through the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is determined by using known methods of finding the CG, including laying the club face down on a flat surface. At block <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>, the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is placed on the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> at the point where the CG projects through the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. As mentioned above, the sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> may be mounted using beeswax, epoxy, or the like. It is preferred that an adhesive material with minimal insulating properties be used for mounting the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in order to allow the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to capture as true vibration as possible for the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. At block <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is impacted/struck with the impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the impact force, as measured in voltage, is transmitted by the impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to the analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the cable <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. At block <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>, a vibration is generated in the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and this vibration is transmitted by the sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to the analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the cable <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. At block <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>, the analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> transforms the time domain data into a frequency domain equivalent. The output/input ratio (acceleration as indicated by vibration of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>/the impact force of the hammer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) is generated by the analyzer <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in a frequency domain. The frequency domain represents how the system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> reacts at the location of the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> to a unit impulse input into the system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at the location of the input force by the impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. This impulse response indicates how the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> responds to a predetermined force such as impact with a golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. Those skilled in the art will recognize that time domain data could be substituted for the frequency domain data. At block <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>, a new point may be chosen on the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> for placement of the vibration sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> thereto. Then, at block <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>, the sensor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is impacted with the impact device <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the cycle is repeated. The cycle may be repeated a multitude of times in order to obtain a grid of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> showing the impulse response for different points on the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. Eventually, this grid information could be utilized to obtain the point on the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> with the highest COR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The transformation of the frequency domain data into a transfer function, block <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, is further explained in the flow chart of the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. This transformation is preferably performed using the system identification software. System identification is a means for determining a model of a physical system. A model that is used for identifying models for dynamic physical systems is an ordinary differential equation or difference equation with constant coefficients. Linear dynamic systems can be described in two regimes: frequency and time. The frequency domain is preferred due to the proliferation of the digital computer and the fast Fourier transform. The general model used to identify dynamic linear systems in the frequency domain is set in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The transfer function H&prime;(&OHgr;) represents the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> where &prime;&OHgr;&equals;s&equals;j&ohgr;&equals;j2&pgr;f. &ldquo;f&rdquo;is the frequency and &ldquo;j&rdquo; is an imaginary number square root of negative one. &ldquo;<highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>&rdquo; is the angular frequency. Xm and Ym represent the measured input and output complex amplitudes respectively. These values are the combination of noise (Nx and Ny) superimposed upon the theoretical &ldquo;true&rdquo; input and output amplitudes X and Y. The transfer function, in its rational fraction form, is as follows:  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mrow>
    <mi>H</mi>
    <mo>&af;</mo>
    <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mi>&Omega;</mi>
      <mo>)</mo>
    </mrow>
  </mrow>
  <mo>=</mo>
  <mrow>
    <msup>
      <mi>&ee;</mi>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <mo>-</mo>
          <mi>j&omega;</mi>
        </mrow>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <mstyle>
          <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
        </mstyle>
        <mo>&it;</mo>
        <msub>
          <mi>T</mi>
          <mi>d</mi>
        </msub>
      </mrow>
    </msup>
    <mo>&it;</mo>
    <mfrac>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>b</mi>
            <mn>0</mn>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mn>0</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>+</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>b</mi>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>+</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&hellip;</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>b</mi>
            <mi>nn</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mi>nn</mi>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>a</mi>
            <mn>0</mn>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mn>0</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>+</mo>
        <mrow>
          <msub>
            <mi>a</mi>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mn>1</mn>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
        <mo>+</mo>
        <mrow>
          <mi>&hellip;</mi>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <mstyle>
            <mtext>&emsp;</mtext>
          </mstyle>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msub>
            <mi>a</mi>
            <mi>nd</mi>
          </msub>
          <mo>&it;</mo>
          <msup>
            <mi>&Omega;</mi>
            <mi>nd</mi>
          </msup>
        </mrow>
      </mrow>
    </mfrac>
  </mrow>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00002" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00002" wi="216.027" he="19.93005" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-M00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Advanced curve-fitting and cost function optimization is utilized to derive rational fraction polynomial numerator and denominator coefficients (b<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>, and a<highlight><subscript>n </subscript></highlight>) in the equation above. These coefficients are then used to form a theoretical transfer function that best represents the true model Y/X. This is then used to find the best fit to a measured transfer function that represents the physical system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring again to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, at block <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight>, a graph of frequency versus magnitude of transfer accelerance (1/kg) is generated from the frequency domain data, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. At block <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight>, the phase is analyzed to determine when the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is traveling inward and outward. At block <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, a frequency band that is the best mathematical representation of the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and minimizes noise is selected from the graph. At block <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, the system identification calculation is performed by the software. At block <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>, the transfer function is generated from the fitted information from the graph. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, the effective mass of the club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be obtained at zero frequency since according to Newton&apos;s Second Law, Force&equals;mass&times;acceleration, (F&equals;ma) and 1/m&equals;a/F. The effective mass is compared to the measured mass of the club. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> It should be noted that the COR of a golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is dependent on the golf ball and speed of impact, and thus, the COR of a golf club will vary if the golf ball is changed or if the speed is changed. For example, if the COR is measured for a golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> using a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; RULE 35&reg; SOFTFEEL&trade; golf ball at a speed of 110 miles per hour (&ldquo;mph&rdquo;), the COR will be different than that measured using a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; CB1&trade; golf ball at a speed of 110 mph. Additionally, if the COR is measured for a golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> using a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; RULE 35&reg; SOFTFEEL&trade; golf ball at a speed of 110 mph, the COR will be different than that measured using a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; RULE 35&reg; SOFTFEEL&trade; golf ball at a speed of 85 mph. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In order for the method and system <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> of the present invention to operate in a non-destructive manner, at block <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9, a</cross-reference> golf ball model must be used with the transfer function in order to have a means for generating the COR for a golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Just like the transfer function is unique to a specific golf club <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, the golf ball model is unique to a specific golf ball. Thus, the golf ball model for the a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; RULE 35&reg; SOFTFEEL&trade; golf ball (a three-piece solid golf ball with a very thin thermoset polyurethane cover) is different than a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; CB1&trade; golf ball (a two-piece golf ball with an ionomer blend cover). The golf ball model is obtained by recording: the inbound speed and outbound speed for a specific golf ball fired at a zero degree loft striking plate; the contact duration; the contact force; and the COR of the golf ball. This data is obtained for different speeds and a non-linear ball model is created such as disclosed in Chapter 61 of Alastair Cochran&apos;s <highlight><italic>Science and Golf III, Proceedings of the </italic></highlight>1998 <highlight><italic>World Scientific Congress of Golf</italic></highlight>, Human Kinetics 1999. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> As shown in the flow chart of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, at block <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, the force output of the golf ball model is inputted to the transfer function. At block <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, the club speed with the output from block <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> generates a contact point velocity. At block <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, the contact point velocity is integrated to give the contact point displacement, which is a representation of the bending of the face <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> about the golf ball <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> This information is used in block <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> to input into the previously mentioned equations to obtain the COR: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>COR&equals;</italic></highlight>(<highlight><italic>V</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>/V</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>club</subscript></highlight>)&minus;1 </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>COR&equals;(&minus;</italic></highlight><highlight><italic>V&prime;</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball</subscript></highlight>)(1&equals;<highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball/m</subscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball/</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>m</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>ball/m</subscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>effective club</subscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> For example, a CALLAWAY GOLF&reg; HAWK EYE&reg;) nine degree driver (club head only) was tested using the present invention. The driver had a measured mass of 195.9 grams and an effective mass of 193.9 grams. Using a contact point velocity of 21.9 feet per second, and a V<highlight><subscript>out</subscript></highlight>/V<highlight><subscript>m </subscript></highlight>ratio of 0.4485, the COR was predicted to be 0.7905. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> illustrates a chart of the COR values generated from the method and system of the present invention as compared to the COR values generated from the USGA cannon test as previously described and as set forth on the USGA web site, www.usga.com. The nine club heads are composed of titanium, titanium alloy, stainless steel, or in the case of the CALLAWAY&reg; CLASSIC&reg; golf club, persimmon wood. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> illustrates the difference in values between the method and system of the present invention and the USGA cannon test for the nine clubs. The actual numbers are provided in Table One below. As mentioned above, the present invention may be utilized for clubs or for club heads. In order to provide a more accurate comparison to the USGA test, the information in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 15 and 16</cross-reference>, and in Table One is for club heads. As is apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the predicted COR from the present invention is within &plusmn;0.008 of the USGA values.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center">TABLE ONE</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Ball</entry>
<entry>Head</entry>
<entry>Predicted</entry>
<entry>USGA</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Club Head</entry>
<entry>mass</entry>
<entry>mass</entry>
<entry>COR</entry>
<entry>COR</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Callaway Classic</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.19813</entry>
<entry>0.775</entry>
<entry>0.778</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Callaway Steelhead Plus 9&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.20106</entry>
<entry>0.795</entry>
<entry>0.793</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Taylor Made Firesole 9.5&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.20377</entry>
<entry>0.805</entry>
<entry>0.803</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>PING Ti ISI 8.5&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.19974</entry>
<entry>0.809</entry>
<entry>0.811</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Taylor Made Firesole 320 10.5&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.18855</entry>
<entry>0.820</entry>
<entry>0.817</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Mizuno Pro 300S 10&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.19998</entry>
<entry>0.820</entry>
<entry>0.821</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Katana Sword 300Ti 10&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.1924&ensp;</entry>
<entry>0.832</entry>
<entry>0.833</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Bridgestone Break the Mode 10&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.19672</entry>
<entry>0.840</entry>
<entry>0.843</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Daiwa G-3 Hyper Titan 10.5&deg;</entry>
<entry>0.0456</entry>
<entry>0.18781</entry>
<entry>0.852</entry>
<entry>0.855</entry>
</row>
<row><entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> From the foregoing it is believed that those skilled in the pertinent art will recognize the meritorious advancement of this invention and will readily understand that while the present invention has been described in association with a preferred embodiment thereof, and other embodiments illustrated in the accompanying drawings, numerous changes, modifications and substitutions of equivalents may be made therein without departing from the spirit and scope of this invention which is intended to be unlimited by the foregoing except as may appear in the following appended claims. Therefore, the embodiments of the invention in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined in the following appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim as our invention: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>attaching a vibration sensor to a face of the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>impacting the attached vibration sensor with an excitation device to generate vibrations in the face; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the force of excitation from the excitation device and the vibrations measured by the vibration sensor to an analyzer to generate frequency domain data for the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transforming the frequency domain data for the golf club into a transfer function for the golf club; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>inputting a golf ball model for a specific golf ball into the transfer function and an impact speed in order to generate a predicted COR for the golf club at the impact speed with the specific golf ball. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the impact speed is the club speed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the impact speed is the ball speed. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vibration sensor is an accelerometer with the capability of transmitting data to the analyzer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the excitation device is an impact device with the capability of measuring the force of impact and transmitting the impact force to the analyzer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein transforming the frequency domain data comprises: 
<claim-text>generating a graph of the frequency; </claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the phase of the motion of the face of the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a frequency band to minimize noise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating the transfer function. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the frequency band is from 0 Hertz to 10,000 Hertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising inputting an effective mass of the golf club, the effective mass calculated from the graph of the frequency at 0 Hertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein a system identification is used to generate the transfer function. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A system for measuring the coefficient of restitution of a golf club during impact with a golf ball, the system comprising: 
<claim-text>a vibration sensor attached to a point on the face of the golf club, the vibration sensor having means for measuring the vibration of the face; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for exciting the face of the golf club in order to vibrate the face, the excitation means having means for measuring the force of excitation with the face; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for calculating the coefficient of restitution of the golf club from the vibration of the face, the force of excitation with the face from the excitation means, an effective mass of the golf club and a mass of a golf ball. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the vibration sensor is an accelerometer with the capability of transmitting data to the analyzer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the excitation means is a hammer with the capability of measuring the force of impact and transmitting the impact force to the analyzer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the calculating means comprises: 
<claim-text>means for generating frequency domain data from the vibrations of the face of the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for generating a graph of the frequency from the frequency domain data; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for analyzing the phase of the motion of the face of the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for selecting a frequency band to minimize noise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for calculating a transfer function. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising means for calculating the effective mass of the golf club at zero Hertz on the graph of the frequency. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club head, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>attaching a vibration sensor to a face of the golf club head; </claim-text>
<claim-text>impacting the attached vibration sensor with an impact device to generate vibrations in the face; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the force of impact from the impact device and the vibrations measured by the vibration sensor to an analyzer to generate frequency domain data for the golf club head; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transforming the frequency domain data for the golf club head into a transfer function for the golf club head; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>inputting a golf ball model for a specific golf ball into the transfer function and an impact speed in order to generate a predicted COR for the golf club head at the impact speed with the specific golf ball. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein transforming the frequency domain data comprises: 
<claim-text>generating a graph of the frequency; </claim-text>
<claim-text>analyzing the phase of the motion of the face of the golf club head; </claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a frequency band to minimize noise; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating the transfer function. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the frequency band is from 0 Hertz to 10,000 Hertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 16</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising inputting an effective mass of the golf club head, the effective mass calculated from the graph of the frequency at 0 Hertz. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A method for predicting the coefficient of restitution of a golf club, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>attaching a vibration sensor to a face of the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exciting the attached vibration sensor with an excitation device to generate vibrations in the face; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the force of excitation from the excitation device and the vibrations measured by the vibration sensor to an analyzer to generate time domain data for the golf club; </claim-text>
<claim-text>transforming the time domain data for the golf club into a state-space representation of the golf club; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>inputting a golf ball model for a specific golf ball into the transfer function and an impact speed in order to generate a predicted COR for the golf club at the specified impact speed with the specific golf ball. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the golf club is unshafted.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004007A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
