<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.NB SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.NB" NDATA NB>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002772A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002772A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002772</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10114322</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020403</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-179088</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010613</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G02B006/26</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>015000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>385</class>
<subclass>027000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Variable dispersion compensator and optical transmission system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Makoto</given-name>
<family-name>Katayama</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yokohama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Tomohiko</given-name>
<family-name>Kanie</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yokohama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masayuki</given-name>
<family-name>Nishimura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Yokohama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shunichi</given-name>
<family-name>Tsuchiya</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Sagamihara-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>McDERMOTT, WILL &amp; EMERY</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 13th Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3096</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An optical signal, which is to become the subject of dispersion compensation, is split by optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2, </bold></highlight>and each frequency component of the optical signal that is split is reflected by each reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40 </bold></highlight>of reflective means <highlight><bold>4 </bold></highlight>to apply a predetermined phase shift to the respective frequency components. Each reflected frequency component is then combined using optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2, </bold></highlight>to give dispersion compensated optical signal. Furthermore, in regards to reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, which is used to apply phase shift to each frequency component of an optical signal, reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40 </bold></highlight>is made a variable movable mirror by reflection position at each reflective surface, which is reflects the frequency components, deforming the entire reflective surface. This allows dispersion that is created in an optical signal to be compensated with favorable controllability and high accuracy. As a result, it becomes possible to provide a variable dispersion compensator that presents high precision and controllability of dispersion compensation, and has a miniaturized optical circuit, and an optical transmission system comprising such variable dispersion compensator. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a variable dispersion compensator, which compensates for dispersion that develops in an optical signal due to its propagation through an optical transmission line such as an optical fiber transmission line, and an optical transmission system in which it is provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In an optical transmission system in which optical signals are propagated by optical fiber transmission lines and the like., dispersion accumulates in optical components of each frequency (each wavelength) that is included in an optical signal through the dispersion that exists in an optical fiber. In this regard, it is desired that the amount of dispersion in an optical transmission system be reduced in the frequency band that includes optical signal frequencies in order to suppress waveform deterioration of an optical signal due to propagation along an optical transmission line. In addition, it wavelength division multiplexing (WDM) transmission systems, which propagate multi-wavelength optical signals, in the same manner, it is necessary to reduce the amount of dispersion in the frequency band that includes optical signal frequencies (optical signal wavelengths) of the respective multi-wavelength optical signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To compensate dispersion that accumulates in each frequency component of an optical signal, a dispersion compensator is provided upon an optical transmission line With a dispersion compensator, the dispersion that develops in an optical signal is compensated by applying an appropriate phase shift to an optical signal. Such an optical compensator is disclosed in, for example, Document 1 &lsqb;The Journal of the Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers (Shingaku Gihou) Vol. 100, No. 379, OCS2000-61&rsqb;, Document2 &lsqb;O plus E Sol. 22, No. 9, v. 1151&rsqb;, and Document 3 &lsqb;OFC2000, Shirasaki, et al, Variable Dispersion Compensator Using The Virtually Imaged Phased Array (VIPA) for 40-Gbit/s WDM Transmission Systems&rsqb;. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In recent years, due to the expansion of optical transmission systems, dispersion compensation with even higher accuracy is possible in dispersion compensators configured upon optical transmission lines, and there are also demands for dispersion compensators with superior controllability of dispersion compensation. In this regard, sufficient controllability and accuracy of dispersion compensation cannot be obtained with conventional dispersion compensators. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> For example, the dispersion compensator disclosed in the above-mentioned Document 1 is configured comprising arrayed-waveguide grating (AWG). Phase adjustment is performed by the spatial phase filter for each frequency component of an optical signal that is input from the first slab waveguide side of the AWG, and output from the second slab waveguide on the opposite side to compensate the dispersion of an optical signal. However, with such configuration, since a spatial phase filter is used for phase adjustment of each frequency component of the optical signal, the applied phase shift is fixed so that dispersion compensation cannot be adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the dispersion compensator disclosed in Document 2 is configured so as to use a planar waveguide type optical circuit with a variable optical path difference with a Mach Zender interferometer (MZI) to perform dispersion compensation. However, with such configuration, the structure of the optical circuit becomes complex, and its size also becomes large (e.g., approximately 5 cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>). In addition, the response of phase adjustment is low (e.g., approximately 10 ms). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, with the dispersion compensator disclosed in Document 3, a device that propagates an optical signal through space is used to change optical path length; however, with such configuration, the system is large, and highly accurate phase adjustment is difficult. In addition, the insertion loss into the optical fiber transmission line is large, for instance, 10 dB or greater </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention has come about in order to solve the problems mentioned above, and aims to provide a variable dispersion compensator, and an optical transmission system equipped therewith, which have superior controllability and accuracy of dispersion compensation while also allowing size reduction of that optical circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve such an objective, the variable dispersion compensator according to the present invention is a variable dispersion compensator, which applies a phase shift to an optical signal to compensate dispersion in the optical signal, and is characterized by comprising (1) optical splitting means, which inputs an optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation, and splits the optical signal for every frequency component within a predetermined frequency band (2) reflecting means, which reflects each of the respective frequency components that are split by the optical splitting means to apply a predetermined phase shift to each frequency component, and is configured with the reflection position for each of the respective frequency components being movable in the direction of optical signal propagation; and (3) optical combining means, which combines the frequency components reflected by the reflecting means to give a dispersion compensated optical signal, wherein the reflective means is constituted by a single reflective mirror; the single reflective mirror is a movable mirror capable of moving each of its reflective surfaces corresponding to the frequency component in the optical signal propagation direction by deforming the entire reflective surface thereof; and wherein the movable mirror, which is the single reflective mirror, is designed such that the entire reflective surface thereof is deformed by applying a moment to application portions provided respectively to the vicinity of the end portion on both sides by means of a moment application means, while fixing a fixed portion provided to the vicinity of the center thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In the variable dispersion compensator mentioned above, the difference in optical path length from an optical splitting means, through a reflecting means, until an optical combining means is used to apply a predetermined phase shift to each frequency component of an optical signal. Then through the use of the reflecting means having a movable reflection position for each frequency component, the phase shift applied to each frequency component is made variable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> With such configuration, it is possible to compensate dispersion that develops in an optical signal with high accuracy. Furthermore, by adjusting the reflection position at the reflecting means relative to each frequency component, it is possible to control the dispersion compensation due to application of a phase shift. Furthermore, since dispersion compensation is controlled with only the reflecting means, it is possible to simplify the structure of the optical circuit, and accordingly, allow for the size reduction of the optical circuit </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Moreover, according to the structure deforming the portion in the vicinity of the end portion of the movable mirror with a moment application meals as described above, the force necessary in application for deforming the movable mirror becomes small, and the entire reflective surface thereof can be deformed easier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In addition, an optical transmission system according to the present invention is characterized by comprising (a) an optical transmission line, which propagates an optical signal having a frequency component within a predetermined frequency band; and (b) the variable dispersion compensator mentioned above, which is disposed at a predetermined position upon the optical transmission line and compensates dispersion that develops in the optical signal propagated through the optical transmission line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Through this, dispersion that develops in an optical signal that propagates through an optical transmission line such as an optical fiber transmission line maybe compensated with favorable controllability and high accuracy to achieve an optical transmission system that prevents waveform deterioration of an optical signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be more fully understood from the detailed description given hereinbelow and the accompanying drawings, which are given by way of illustration only and are not to be considered as limiting the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Further scope of applicability of the present invention will become apparent from the detailed description given hereinafter. However, it should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples, while indicating preferred embodiments of the invention, are given by way of illustration only, since various changes and modifications within the spirit and scope of the invention will be apparent to those skilled in the art from this detailed description.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows the one of the embodiments of a variable dispersion compensator; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows the one of the embodiments of an optical transmission system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a planar view showing a more specific structural example of a variable dispersion compensator according to the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an example of the movable reflective mirror; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference> are structural diagrams showing an example of the comb drive employed in the movable reflective mirror; <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A and 6B</cross-reference> are graphs of an example of (A) the input optical signal, and (B) the pre-dispersion compensation output optical signal in a 10 Gbps optical transmission system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A and 7B</cross-reference> are graphs of an example of (A) the phase shift of an optical signal, and (B) the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal in a 10 Gbps optical transmission system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A and 8B</cross-reference> are graphs of another example of (A) the phase shift of an optical signal, and (B) the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal in a 10 Gbps optical transmission system </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A and 9B</cross-reference> are graphs of an Example of (A) the input optical signal, and (B) the pre-dispersion compensation output optical signal in a 40 Gbps optical transmission system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A and 10B</cross-reference> are graphs of an example of (A) the phase shift of an optical signal, and (B) the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal in a 40 Gbps optical transmission system; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11B</cross-reference> are diagrams explaining the driving method of the movable reflective mirror; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows another embodiment of a variable dispersion compensator; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows another embodiment of a variable dispersion compensator.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In the following, the preferred embodiments of a variable dispersion compensator and optical transmission system according to the present invention, together with drawings, are described in detail. It is noted here that in the description of drawings the same elements are given the same reference markers, and repetitive descriptions are omitted. In addition, the measurement scale of the drawings does not always match that of the description. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> To begin with, the schematic of a variable dispersion compensator is described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is. a block diagram that illustratively shows the one of the embodiments of a variable dispersion compensator according to he present invention. Variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of this embodiment applies a predetermined amount of phase shift to an input optical signal to compensate the dispersion of the optical signal, and is configured comprising optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. In addition, regarding the dispersion compensation functionally, the amount of phase shift that is applied to each frequency component of the optical signal for dispersion compensation is variable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> An optical signal, which is to become the subject of dispersion compensation and which has a frequency component (wavelength component) within a predetermined frequency band (wavelength band), is input from input terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and after a predetermined phase shift is applied, is output as a dispersion compensated optical signal from output terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Between input terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and output terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>there is provided optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through which an optical signal is propagated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> is provided at a predetermined position upon optical transmission Line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In addition, optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, which is used for dispersion compensation, is connected to optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Through this, the pre-dispersion compensation optical signal from the input terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>side of optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> passes through optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to be output towards optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In addition, the post-dispersion compensation optical signal from optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> passes through optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> to be output towards the output terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>side of optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The aforementioned optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, in such order, are disposed at the end of the side opposite optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of dispersion compensation optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In accordance with this optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and this reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, phase shift is applied to an optical signal to compensate the dispersion thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is a single optical combining/splitting means, which functions as an optical splitting means that inputs the pre-dispersion compensation optical signal and splits every frequency component of the optical signal within a predetermined frequency band, and functions as an optical combining means that combines each frequency component of the optical signal to give the post-dispersion compensation optical signal. The optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation, in this optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, is split or combined by frequency &ngr; or wavelength &lgr; ) along a predetermined splitting direction (direction of the &ngr;-axis in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In addition, reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is a reflecting means that reflects the respective frequency components of the optical signal that is split by optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to apply a predetermined phase shift to each frequency component. Phase shift is applied to each frequency component of the optical signal using the optical path length and optical path length differences from optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (optical splitting means) through reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> reflecting means until again reaching optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (optical combining means). In addition, this reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is configured to be variable in terms of the reflecting point for the respective frequency components along the direction of optical signal propagation (direction of the d-axis shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, which is a reflecting means in this embodiment, is structured from a single reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. This single reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is disposed in the direction of the &ngr;-axis, which is the direction of the splitting of optical signal and approximately perpendicular to the direction of optical signal propagation, as the direction of spread of reflective surface; and in accordance with this, reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, which reflects the respective frequency components of the optical signal within the entire frequency band that is to be subjected to dispersion compensation, is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Further, reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> structuring reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is a movable mirror capable of moving each of its reflective surfaces corresponding to the frequency component in the d-axis direction, which is the optical signal propagation direction, by deforming the entire reflective surface thereof. Specifically, with reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, fixed portion <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> provided to the vicinity of the center thereof is fixed, and moment application means (not shown) is provided to application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> provided respectively to the vicinity of the end portion on both sides. And, the entire reflective surface of the reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is deformed by applying a moment to the application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> with the moment application means. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the above configuration, the optical signal, which is the subject of dispersion compensation and input to variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> from input terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a, </italic></highlight>is input to optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> through optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>; and each frequency component is split off according to such frequency &ngr;. Each frequency component of the optical signal that has been split is propagated towards reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and is reflected at a predetermined reflection position by corresponding reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Each frequency component that has been reflected is then combined again by optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to become a post-dispersion compensation optical signal, and is output to an external portion from output terminal <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>through optical transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Here, the reflection position of a frequency component of the optical signal in each reflective surface with reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is determined based on the amount of phase shift that should be applied to that frequency component. The deformation of the reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is a movable mirror, is controlled by the moment application means so as to move the respective reflective surfaces in the direction of optical signal propagation and into the set reflection position; as a result, dispersion compensation of the optical signal is achieved within the entire frequency band. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Next, the optical transmission system comprising the variable dispersion compensator mentioned above is described. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows the one of the embodiments of an optical transmission system according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The optical transmission system of this embodiment is configured comprising transmitter (transmitting station) T, which transmits an optical signal; optical fiber transmission line L, which is an optical transmission line that propagates the optical signal that is transmitted from transmitter T; and receiver (receiving station) R, which receives the optical signal that if propagated through optical fiber transmission line L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which has the configuration shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is disposed at a predetermined position upon optical fiber transmission line L. This variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is preferably provided at a position upon optical fiber transmission line L that is near receiver R, for instance, it a position that is immediately before receiver R. Through this, dispersion compensation can be performed for the dispersion that has accumulated in the optical signal propagating from transmitter T towards receiver R through optical fiber transmission line L using variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> before the optical signal is received by receiver R. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In the variable dispersion compensator and optical transmission system according to this embodiment, where the optical signal that is split by the optical splitting means, optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, travels until it is combined again by the optical combining means, optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, is used to apply phase shift to each frequency component of the optical signal. Then as for reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is the reflecting means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and which is used for setting the optical path length and phase shift for each frequency component, the reflection position of the respective reflective surfaces corresponding to the frequency component is made variable by deforming the entire reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Through this, since the phase shift that is applied to each frequency component is variable, it becomes possible to perform discretionary phase adjustment, and makes it possible to compensate the dispersion that develops in an optical signal with high accuracy. Furthermore, since it is possible to control the reflection position of the respective frequency components by deforming reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> structuring reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the amount of phase shift that is applied to the optical signal can be controlled with favorable controllability, thereby making it possible to set or change the details of the conditions of dispersion compensation in a favorable manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> Moreover, according to the structure deforming portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the end portion of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is the movable mirror, with a moment application means as described above, the force necessary in application for deforming the movable mirror becomes small, and the entire reflective surface thereof can be deformed easier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Moreover, since the control of dispersion compensation is performed only with the reflecting means, it is possible to simplify the structure of the optical circuit and allow for the size reduction of the optical circuit. It is noted here that such a reflecting means may be manufactured using, for instance, Micro Electro Mechanical System (MEMS) technology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> With an optical transmission system that applies a variable dispersion compensator having such structure, dispersion that develops in optical signal that propagates through an optical transmission line, such as optical fiber transmission line L may be compensated having favorable controllability and high accuracy to achieve an optical transmission system that reliably prevents waveform deterioration of an optical signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> It is noted here that with variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, single optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is used as optical splitting means for splitting a pre-dispersion compensation optical signal into frequency components, and as optical combining means for combining frequency components to give a post-dispersion compensation optical signal. Accordingly, the structure of variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is simplified to allow the further size reduction of such optical circuit. However, such optical splitting means and optical combining means may even be configured separately. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a planar view showing a more specific structural example of the variable dispersion compensator according to this embodiment that is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. It is noted here that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, optical transmission line <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and optical circulator <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, etc. are not shown, but only the optical circuit comprising optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, which actually perform dispersion compensation of an optical signal, is shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of this example, arrayed waveguide grating (AWG) <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with a planar waveguide type optical circuit that is formed in a predetermined waveguide pattern upon substrate <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is used as optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which splits and alternately combines an optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> AWG <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is configured including input/output channel waveguide <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, the end thereof being made into an input/output port; first slab waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which is connected to input/output channel waveguide <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>; array waveguide portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, which comprises a plurality of channel waveguides that are connected to first slab waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> with each differing in optical path length from the others; and second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which is connected to array waveguide portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. Moreover, movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which is reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is provided to the side opposite array waveguide portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> Here, with variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, shown is a structural example where n number of movable reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>to <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>n </subscript></highlight>is provided as reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Each of these movable reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>to <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>n </subscript></highlight>corresponds to reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, respectively. In other words, in this structural example, the frequency band of the optical signal, which is the subject of dispersion compensation, is divided into n number of bands, and, dispersion compensation is performed within the respective frequency bands by providing a single movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for each n number of frequency bands divided as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Each of reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>to <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>n </subscript></highlight>structuring reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is a movable mirror capable of moving each of the reflective surfaces corresponding to each frequency component in the optical signal propagation direction by deforming its entire reflective surface. The deformation method of the reflective surface is as per the description of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In the above configuration, when an optical signal is input to input/output channel waveguide <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> from the input/output port of AWG <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>the optical signal is split into every frequency (every wavelength) while being guided through first slab waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, array waveguide portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, in that order. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Each frequency component of the optical signal that has been split is reflected with corresponding movable reflective mirrors <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>1 </subscript></highlight>to <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>n </subscript></highlight>of reflective means 4 per frequency band divided into n numbers. Each frequency component is then combined while being guided through second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, array waveguide portion <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, and first slab waveguide <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, in that order, outputting the dispersion compensated optical signal from the input/output port through input/output channel waveguide <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> Further, the reflective means structured from n number of reflective mirrors illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, for example, may be used in cases when n channels of optical signals each having a different wavelength are the subject of dispersion compensation. Here, dispersion compensation is performed by reflecting the optical signal with a movable reflective mirror corresponding to each of the n channels of optical signals. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Generally, it is preferable to set the number of movable reflective mirrors in accordance with the number of channels of optical signals subject to dispersion compensation or the broadness of the frequency band of the optical signal. For example, when the optical signal is <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> channel, or when the frequency band is relatively narrow in a plurality of channels, the structure may be such that n&equals;1 as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and to provide one movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> for the entire exit of second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> In variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the structure and driving method of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> used as reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are now described in further detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> are diagrams showing a movable reflective mirror when using a single reflective mirror as the reflective means in the variable dispersion compensator, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a diagram showing schematically the shape and driving method thereof, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a specific structural example thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, as described with respect to reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, is structured of a single movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. This movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, is capable of moving each of the reflective surfaces corresponding to the respective frequency components of the optical signal in the optical signal propagation direction by deforming the entire reflective surface thereof in a curved surface shape (deformation in a parabolic shape, for example) Dispersion compensation may thereby be conducted variably high favorable precision. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> is a structural diagram showing an example of the movable reflective mirror illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</cross-reference> makes portion <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the center thereof the fixed portion, and portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the end portion of both ends portions capable of being displaced, respectively. In this example, these portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> are made the application portions, and moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, which are moment application means for displacing application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> by applying moment thereto, are connected to application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> are respectively connected to these moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at the end opposite the end to which application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are connected. Comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> respectively drive moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in the direction of the arrow shown in FIG <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>B. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing structure, when the ends of moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are driven pursuant to the movement of comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, the entire application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> move or deform. Here, moment is applied to application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> connected to these moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, such portions are displaced thereby, and the entire reflective surface of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> deforms in synchronization therewith. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> Further, as comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> in reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, for example, the comb drive structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is respectively used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Comb drive <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) in the present example comprises a structure of combining a comb-shaped electrode in <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> sections Seven sections of comb-shaped electrodes <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>567</bold></highlight> are provided, with respect to frame shape electrode <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> having a width w<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> in the drive direction, to drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> for driving momentum application mechanism <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>). This drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is established with the drive direction as a direction shown with the arrow in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>A, and connected to moment application mechanism <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) via connection portion <highlight><bold>568</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> Seven sections of comb-shaped electrodes <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight> are provided so as to mutually engage with corresponding comb-shaped electrode portions <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>567</bold></highlight>, respectively, with respect to the comb-shaped electrode portions <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>567</bold></highlight> of these drive electrodes <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. These comb-shaped electrodes <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight> are fixed to a substrate or the like to which is provided movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and, for example, are electrically connected to each other so as to have the same potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In comb drive <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) having the foregoing electrode structure and in reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> Comprising comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, by applying power voltage between drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> including comb-shaped electrode portions <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>567</bold></highlight> and comb-shaped electrodes <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight>, drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> moves in the predetermined drive direction, pursuant to static electricity with respect to the fixed comb-shaped electrodes <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>577</bold></highlight>. Here, the ends of moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> are driven by the movement of comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, and the entire reflective surface of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> becomes deformed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> An example of a concrete structure of comb drive <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is explained with reference to the partially enlarged view of comb-shaped electrode portion <highlight><bold>561</bold></highlight> of drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and corresponding comb-shaped electrode <highlight><bold>571</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</cross-reference>. Foremost, as the overall drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>, width in the longitudinal of frame-shaped electrode portion <highlight><bold>560</bold></highlight> was set to w<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&equals;610 &mgr;m, and structured as a 7-section electrode as depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Further, regarding the structure and the like of the respective comb-shaped electrodes, the width of the comb-shaped electrode was set to w<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&equals;10 &mgr;m, the gap in the drive direction between the comb-shared electrodes in a state where drive electrode <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is in its initial position was set to g<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&equals;60&mgr;m, the gap between the combs in the direction perpendicular to the drive direction was set to g<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&equals;10 &mgr;m, the length of the overlapping portion of the comb-shaped electrodes was set to t&equals;10 &mgr;m, the height of the respective electrodes was set to 50 &mgr;m, and the number of comb-shaped electrodes was set to <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As a result of examining the displacement of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> upon employing the comb drive having the structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> as comb drives <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> for driving moment application mechanisms <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> in reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, the displacement of application portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> was respectively 4 &mgr;m when applying 15V of power voltage (corresponds to applying force of 30 &mgr;N). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> The dispersion that develops in an optical signal in an optical transmission system, and dispersion compensation using a variable dispersion compensator are further described while referencing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. It is noted that in the following, optical intensity of an optical signal that is the subject of dispersion compensation is assumed as given by the value of amplitude &verbar;E&verbar; of that electric field, or the value of the square thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> An optical signal that is propagated through optical fiber transmission line L in an optical transmission system, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, is generated in transmitter T so that optical intensity &verbar;E&verbar; has a predetermined signal waveform A, and transmitted as an input optical signal to the optical transmission system. This input optical signal has optical signal components that are spread out across a predetermined optical signal frequency band (wavelength band) with optical signal frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>(optical signal wavelength &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;c/&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) as the median frequency. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> When such an optical signal is propagated through optical fiber transmission line L, the dispersion of optical fiber transmission line L accumulates in the optical signal. The propagated optical signal then, as shown by signal waveform B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, develops waveform deterioration, where the signal waveform of optical intensity &verbar;E&verbar; is distorted from signal waveform A of the input optical signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, phase shift, which is used to compensate the dispersion of each frequency component of optical signal, is applied to each frequency component of an optical signal that is the subject of dispersion compensation and in which such waveform deterioration has developed, so as to negate the phase shift from dispersion that has accumulated in optical fiber transmission line L in order to compensate the dispersion. Through this, an optical signal is Obtained having signal waveform C of optical intensity &verbar;E&verbar;, which has removed to the greatest extent possible the effects of dispersion due to being propagated through optical fiber transmission line L. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> In more detail, in cases where there exists second order dispersion (dispersion) D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>and third order dispersion (dispersion slope) D<highlight><superscript>(3) </superscript></highlight>in optical fiber transmission line L, the value of total dispersion D for the optical signal components of wavelength &lgr; (&equals;c/&ngr;) is given by the following expression, wherein group delay time&excl; is assumed as &tgr; and &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>is the median wavelength of the above-mentioned optical signal.  
<math-cwu id="MATH-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<math>
<mrow>
  <mtable>
    <mtr>
      <mtd>
        <mrow>
          <mrow>
            <mi>D</mi>
            <mo>&af;</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>(</mo>
              <mi>&lambda;</mi>
              <mo>)</mo>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&dd;</mo>
              <mi>&tau;</mi>
            </mrow>
            <mo>/</mo>
            <mrow>
              <mo>&dd;</mo>
              <mi>&lambda;</mi>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mtd>
    </mtr>
    <mtr>
      <mtd>
        <mrow>
          <mo>=</mo>
          <mrow>
            <msup>
              <mi>D</mi>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mn>2</mn>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </msup>
            <mo>+</mo>
            <mrow>
              <msup>
                <mi>D</mi>
                <mrow>
                  <mo>(</mo>
                  <mn>3</mn>
                  <mo>)</mo>
                </mrow>
              </msup>
              <mo>&af;</mo>
              <mrow>
                <mo>(</mo>
                <mrow>
                  <mi>&lambda;</mi>
                  <mo>-</mo>
                  <msub>
                    <mi>&lambda;</mi>
                    <mn>0</mn>
                  </msub>
                </mrow>
                <mo>)</mo>
              </mrow>
            </mrow>
          </mrow>
        </mrow>
      </mtd>
    </mtr>
  </mtable>
  <mo>&AutoLeftMatch;</mo>
</mrow>
</math>
<mathematica-file id="MATHEMATICA-00001" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.NB"/>
<image id="EMI-M00001" wi="216.027" he="24.01245" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-M00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="MF"/>
</math-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> When second order dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>is made dominant in the total dispersion D, the group delay time &tgr; for the optical signal component of wavelength &lgr; becomes</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&tgr; (&lgr;)&equals;<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>(&lgr;&minus;&lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>).</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> At this point, phase shift &phgr; due to dispersion that develops in each optical signal component of the optical signal that has propagated through optical fiber transmission line L, when the phase shift at median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>(median wavelength &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>) is given as 0, becomes the following.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&phgr;&equals;&minus;&pgr;<highlight><italic>cD</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>((&ngr;&minus;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>)/&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> or when the rate of change of phase shift &phgr; is</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>d&phgr;/d&ngr;&equals;&minus;</italic></highlight>(2&pgr;<highlight><italic>cD</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>/&ngr;,<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)&times;(&ngr;&minus;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>).</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> In other words, phase shift that has parabolic change with a center of median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>develops in an optical signal that propagates through optical fiber transmission line L due to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Dispersion compensation is performed using variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, for an optical signal in which such phase shift develops. Here, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the total width of the frequency band in the entire reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> that is to become the frequency band in which dispersion compensation is performed is given as 2 &dgr;&ngr;, and the dispersion compensation resolution, on the premise that dispersion compensation, which is conducted by respectively reflecting each of the frequency components of optical signals with the corresponding reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, is performed pursuant to a finite frequency resolution, is given as &Dgr;&ngr;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in regards to each of the reflective surfaces of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; included in reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, the median frequency of the frequency component of the optical signal that is reflected by such reflective surfaces is given as &ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>, and the phase shift that is applied for dispersion compensation in each frequency component of the optical signal is given as &psgr;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> The reflection position of each frequency component in accordance with each reflective surface included in reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the over all reflective surface shape of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> pursuant thereto is set so that phase shift &phgr; in optical fiber transmission line L at median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>of each reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is negated by making the phase shift applied to a frequency component of the optical signal due to the reflection at each reflective surface become &psgr;&equals;&minus;&phgr;(&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Once the reflection position for each of the reflective surfaces of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; included in reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is set, each reflective surface is shifted to have the reflection position that is set by deforming the entire reflective surface of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. Through this, a configuration that is capable of compensating dispersion in an optical transmission system is realized Position d (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) of each reflective surface of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, which applies phase shift &psgr;&equals;&minus;&phgr;(&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>) can be found with the following expression, wherein the refractive index of the medium between optical combining/splitting unit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and reflective means <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is given as n,</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>d&equals;c</italic></highlight>&phgr;(&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>)/4&pgr;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>.</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> When making the frequency resolution of the dispersion compensation &Dgr;&ngr; as described above, it is preferable that the phase shift &phgr;(&ngr;), which develops in optical signal, does not change drastically within the frequency range &Dgr;&ngr; in order to perform dispersion compensation effectively to the optical signals. More specifically, it is preferable that the frequency resolution &Dgr;&ngr; meet the conditions of the following expression relative to the rate of change d &phgr;/<highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>&ngr; of phase shift &phgr;.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&verbar;&Dgr;&ngr;&times;(<highlight><italic>d&phgr;/d</italic></highlight>&ngr;)&verbar;&lE;&pgr;</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> When second order dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>is dominant in the total dispersion D, the absolute value of the rate of change &verbar;(d&phgr;/d&ngr;) of phase shift &phgr; is maximized at the frequency components at the extremities of the frequency band, which are separated by frequency &ngr;&equals;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&plusmn;&bgr;&ngr;, namely by frequency &bgr;&ngr; which is half of the total width 2&bgr;&ngr; from median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>, with that maximized value being</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&verbar;<highlight><italic>d&phgr;/d</italic></highlight>&ngr;&verbar;<highlight><subscript>max</subscript></highlight>&equals;2<highlight><italic>&pgr;cD</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&bgr;&ngr;/&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&verbar;.</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the maximized value of dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>that meets the above preferred conditions of</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&verbar;&Dgr;&ngr;&times;(<highlight><italic>d&phgr;/d&ngr;)&verbar;&lE;&pgr;</italic></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> becomes</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&verbar;<highlight><italic>D</italic></highlight><highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&verbar;<highlight><subscript>max</subscript></highlight>&equals;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>/2<highlight><italic>c&Dgr;&ngr;&bgr;&ngr;.</italic></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> For example, in regards to the optical signal that becomes the subject of dispersion compensation, if that median frequency is given as &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz (median wavelength given as &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;1585 nm), the half-width of the frequency band as &dgr;&ngr;&equals;50 GHz,and the frequency resolution of the dispersion compensation as &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;5 GHz, then it follows that the maximum dispersion capable of being compensated is &verbar;D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&verbar;<highlight><subscript>max</subscript></highlight>&equals;240 ps/nm. In addition, with similar conditions, if the half-width of the frequency band is given as <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> &ngr;&equals;15 GHz, and the frequency resolution as &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;3 GHz, then it follows that the maximum dispersion capable of being compensated is &verbar;D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&verbar;<highlight><subscript>max</subscript></highlight>&equals;1300 ps/nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> Here, a more specific structural example of variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> that is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> including AWG <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is illustrated. If the interval between neighboring channels capable of being separated at the exit of second slab waveguide <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> (position resolution) is given as &Dgr;x, and the wavelength interval between the frequency components of the optical signal propagated through neighboring separable channels as &Dgr;&lgr;, then the following expression is obtained.</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>&Dgr;x/&Dgr;&lgr;&equals;N</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>c</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>f&Dgr;L/n</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight><highlight><italic>&Dgr;x&lgr;</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>,</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> wherein N<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>is the group refractive index of the waveguide, f is the length of the slab waveguides along their length, &Dgr;L is the optical path length difference of the channel waveguides in the array waveguide portion, and n<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>is the effective refractive index of the slab waveguides. Of these the group refractive index N<highlight><subscript>c </subscript></highlight>and effective refractive index n<highlight><subscript>s </subscript></highlight>are in the range of 1.5, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In this regard, if the median wavelength of the optical signal is given as &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;1550 nm and the frequency band in which dispersion compensation is performed is 2&dgr;&ngr;&equals;100 GHz (which correlates to wavelength band 0.8 nm), then the frequency resolution of this frequency band being divided into 10 parts becomes &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;10 GHz Accordingly, the wavelength resolution is &Dgr;&lgr;&equals;0.08 nm. Furthermore, the interval between channels becomes &Dgr;x&equals;20 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> If these numeric values are substituted, then as a structural condition that should be met for AWG <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, it is found that</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>f&Dgr;L&equals;</italic></highlight>7.75&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6 </superscript></highlight>m.</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> It is possible to meet this condition if with a structure, for example, where the slab waveguide is set with f&equals;30 mm, and the array waveguide portion is set with &Dgr;L&equals;258 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> It is noted that it is preferable that dispersion compensation frequency band 2&dgr;&ngr; be set so that it sufficiently includes a frequency range throughout which the optical signal component of the optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation is distributed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, if the optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation is a multi-wavelength optical signal comprising a plurality of optical signals having optical signal wavelengths differing from each other, then in cases where dispersion compensation is performed for a single optical signal included in the multi-wavelength optical signal, it is possible for the frequency interval between neighboring optical signals to be total frequency width 2&dgr;&ngr;. Furthermore, when the total frequency width 2&dgr;&ngr; is made larger than the frequency interval between neighboring optical signals (e g. in integral multiples), the structure becomes capable of dispersion compensating the plurality of optical signals included a multi-wavelength optical signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in regards to the bit rate (modulation rate) of the optical signal, it is preferable that the bit rate be 10 Gbps or faster, and even more preferably, 40 Gbps or faster. The development of dispersion in the optical transmission line becomes particularly problematic with such high-speedbit rates; however, even in such cases, by adopting the configuration described above in a variable dispersion compensator, favorable dispersion compensation of the optical signal can be performed with sufficient accuracy. However, needless to say, variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> may be effectively adopted for optical signals with bit rates that are lower than those mentioned above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, it is preferable that the shape of the reflecting surface of the reflective mirror that comprises the reflective means be somewhat parabolic in relation to the frequency component to be reflected. Through this, in cases where second order dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>becomes dominant in the dispersion that develops in the optical transmission line, it is possible to achieve favorable dispersion compensation for an optical signal throughout the entire frequency band that becomes the subject of dispersion compensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Simulations were performed by applying the specific conditions in the optical transmission system and variable dispersion compensator having the configuration mentioned above, and the results were confirmed with regard to dispersion compensation of the optical signal and waveform deterioration of the optical signal due to dispersion in the optical transmission line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> As for the optical signal that was to become the subject of dispersion compensation, the median frequency was set at &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz (median wavelength of &lgr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;1585 nm), in addition, the modulation scheme was set to NRZ, and modulation rate (bitrate) M set to either 10 Gbps or 40 Gbps. In addition, the waveform of the optical pulse of the optical signal was set to be a super-Gaussian, non-chip form. Here, if the duration of the one-bit signal is given as 2t<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>(&equals;1/M), then the signal waveform of the optical signal is applied as</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula><highlight><italic>E</italic></highlight>(<highlight><italic>t</italic></highlight>)&equals;exp &lcub;&minus;log2/2&times;(<highlight><italic>t/t</italic></highlight><highlight><subscript>0</subscript></highlight>)<highlight><superscript>2m</superscript></highlight>&rcub;,</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> where in misgiven as the parameter that determines the optical pulse form and here it is set to m&equals;2. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, random codes of 2<highlight><superscript>9</superscript></highlight>&equals;512 bits were transmitted as the optical signal to actually be subjected to dispersion compensation, and the obtained signal waveform was estimated through the eye pattern displayed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> To begin with, an example of dispersion compensation in the case where the bit rate was made to be M&equals;10 Gbps is illustrated. With this 10 Gbps bit rate, the clock for the signal period is 100 ps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A and 6B</cross-reference> are graphs illustrating an example of the optical signal that the 10 Gbps optical transmission system transmits, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> illustrates the signal waveform of the input optical signal immediately after the transmitter (refer to signal waveform A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>); and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference> illustrates the signal waveform of the output optical signal before dispersion compensation (without dispersion compensation) (refer to signal waveform B in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> The input optical signal having the signal waveform shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> has frequency components in a frequency range of approximately &plusmn;15 GHz, with optical signal frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz as the median. In this regard, when the dispersion that develops in the optical signal due to propagation in the optical transmission line is set as D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&equals;&plus;1200 ps/nm, D<highlight><superscript>(3)</superscript></highlight>&equals;0 ps/nm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, the signal waveform in the post-propagation output optical signal becomes a waveform with developed waveform deterioration due to dispersion, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A and 7B</cross-reference> are graphs showing an example of dispersion compensation for an optical signal that is transmitted by a 10 Gbps optical transmission system, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> illustrates the phase shift of the optical signal, and in addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> illustrates the waveform of the output optical signal after dispersion compensation (with dispersion compensation) (refer to signal waveform C in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> Here, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, the horizontal axis shows the relative frequency &ngr;&minus;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>(GHZ) vis-&agrave;-vis median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz. In addition, the vertical axis shows the rate of change of phase shift d&phgr;/d&ngr; (rad/GHz) corresponding to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&equals;&plus;1200 ps/nm and phase shifts &phgr; and &minus;&psgr; (rad) . </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> For each frequency component of the input optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, due to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>in the above-mentioned optical transmission line, the parabolic phase shift &phgr; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> develops in the post-propagation output optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference>. In this regard, in this example, dispersion compensation is performed with the half-width of frequency band being set to &dgr;&ngr;&equals;15 GHz, and frequency resolution set to &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;3 Ghz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> At this point, in variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, phase shift I, which is shown as the graph of &minus;&psgr; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, is applied to each frequency component of the optical signal In this graph of phase shift &phgr; with a stepped-shape at frequency width &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;3 GHz, the frequency resolution is &Dgr;&ngr;, and corresponds to the shape of the reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the premise that the phase shift within the range of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; is fixed. In other words, the direction of the horizontal axis of phase shift &phgr; corresponds to the position of each reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> along the &ngr;-axis. In addition, the direction of the vertical axis corresponds to the position of each reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> along the d-axis (refer to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> Reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>A, is configured so that the two phase shifts match with &minus;&psgr;&equals;&phgr;(&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>) at the respective median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>for the frequency component of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; reflected by each reflective surface. With such configuration, phase shift &phgr;, which develops in the optical signal along the optical transmission line, is negated to the greatest extent possible by phase shift &psgr;, which is applied by variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</cross-reference> by the signal waveform of the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal, dispersion in the optical signal is sufficiently compensated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A and 8B</cross-reference> are graphs of another example of dispersion compensation of an optical signal propagated by a 10 Gbps optical transmission system wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> shows the phase shift of the optical signal, and in addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> shows the signal waveform of the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal. It is noted that in the graph of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>A, the rate of change of phase shift d&phgr;/d&ngr; and phase shift &phgr; are the same as that shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</cross-reference> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> For each frequency component of the input optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>A, due to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(12) </superscript></highlight>in the above-mentioned optical transmission line, the parabolic phase shift &phgr; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</cross-reference> develops in the post-propiigation output optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6B</cross-reference>. In this regard, in this example, dispersion compensation is performed with the half-width of frequency band being set to &dgr;&ngr;&equals;15 GHz, and frequency resolution set to &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;1 GHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> At this point, in variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, phase shift &psgr;, which is shown as the graph of &minus;&psgr; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>A, is applied to each frequency component of the optical signal In this graph of phase shift &psgr; with a stepped-shape at frequency width &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;1 GHz, the frequency resolution is &Dgr;&ngr;, and corresponds to the shape of the reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the premise that the phase shift within the range of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; is fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> Reflective mirror <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>O, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>A, is configured so that the two phase shifts match with &minus;&psgr;&equals;&phgr;(&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>) at the respective median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>for the frequency component of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; reflected by each reflective surface. With such configuration, phase shift &phgr;, which develops in the optical signal along the optical transmission line, is negated to the greatest extent possible by phase shift &psgr;, which is applied by variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</cross-reference> by the signal waveform of the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal, dispersion in the optical signal is sufficiently compensated. In particular, in this example, by making the frequency resolution &Dgr;&ngr; 1 GHz, which is smaller than the 3 GHz of the example shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A and 7B</cross-reference>, the accuracy of dispersion compensation is improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> Next, an example of dispersion compensation in the case where the bit rate is made to be M&equals;40 Gbps is shown. With this 40 Gbps bit rate, the clock that is to become the period of the signal is 25 ps. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A and 9B</cross-reference> are graphs illustrating an example of the optical signal that the 40 Gbps optical transmission system transmits, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> illustrates the signal waveform of the input optical signal immediately after the transmitter; and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference> illustrates the signal waveform of the output optical signal before dispersion compensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> The input optical signal having the signal waveform shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> has frequency components in a frequency range of approximately &plusmn;50 GHz, with optical signal frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz as the median. In this regard, when the dispersion that develops in the optical signal due to propagation in the optical transmission line is set as D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&equals;&plus;200 ps/nm, D<highlight><superscript>(3)</superscript></highlight>&equals;0 ps/nm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, the signal waveform in the post-propagation output optical signal becomes a waveform with developed waveform deterioration due to dispersion, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A and 10B</cross-reference> are graphs showing an example of dispersion compensation for an optical signal that is transmitted by a 40 Gbps optical transmission system, wherein <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> illustrates the phase shift of the optical signal, and in addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> illustrates the signal waveform of the output optical signal after dispersion compensation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> Here, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, the horizontal axis shows the relative frequency &ngr;&minus;&ngr;<highlight><subscript>o </subscript></highlight>(GHz) vis-&agrave;-vis median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>o</subscript></highlight>&equals;189.1 THz. In addition, the vertical axis shows the rate of change of phase shift d&phgr;/d&ngr; (rad/GHz) corresponding to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2)</superscript></highlight>&equals;&plus;200 ps/nm and phase shifts &phgr; and &minus;&psgr; (rad). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> For each frequency component of the input optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>A, due to dispersion D<highlight><superscript>(2) </superscript></highlight>in the above-mentioned optical transmission line, the parabolic phase shift &phgr; shown in FIG <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A develops in the post-propagation output optical signal shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9B</cross-reference>. In this reboard, in this example, dispersion compensation is performed with the half-width of frequency band being set to &dgr;&ngr;&equals;50 GHz, and frequency resolution set to &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;2 GHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> At this point, in variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, phase shift V, which is shown as the graph of &minus;&psgr; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, is applied to each frequency component of the optical signal. In this graph of phase shift &psgr; with a stepped-shape at frequency width &Dgr;&ngr;&equals;2 GHz, the frequency resolution is &Dgr;&ngr;, and corresponds to the shape of the reflective surface of reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> on the premise that the phase shift within the range of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; is fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> Reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>A, is configured so that the two phase shifts &minus;&psgr;&equals;&phgr; (&ngr;<highlight><subscript>i</subscript></highlight>) match at the respective median frequency &ngr;<highlight><subscript>i </subscript></highlight>for the frequency component of frequency width &Dgr;&ngr; reflected by each reflective surface. With such configuration, phase shift &phgr;, which develops in the optical signal along the optical transmission line, is negated to the greatest extent possible by phase shift &psgr;, which is applied by variable dispersion compensator <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> by the signal waveform of the post-dispersion compensation output optical signal, dispersion in the optical signal is sufficiently compensated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Here, when employing the structure of fixing the portion in the vicinity of the end portions on both sides of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and deforming the reflective surface, in comparison to the structure of fixing the portion in the vicinity of the center of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and deforming the reflective surface, force to be applied to reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is smaller in the structure of fixing the portion in the vicinity of the center and driving the portion in the vicinity of the end portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> In other words, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>A and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>B, when comparing the case of fixing portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of end portions on both sides thereof with the case of fixing portion <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the (enter with respect to movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> having the same shape, with the structure of fixing portions <highlight><bold>401</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the end portions (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11A</cross-reference>), force of f<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>&equals;8.7&times;10 <highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>&mgr;N was required in order to displace the portion in the vicinity of the center 5 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Contrarily, with the structure( of fixing portion <highlight><bold>403</bold></highlight> in the vicinity of the center (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 113</cross-reference>), when applying force of f<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&equals;f<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&equals;f<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>/2&equals;4.35&times;10<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>&mgr;N, respectively, to the portion in the vicinity of the end portion so as to make the total force equal the aforementioned example, the displacement of the portion in the vicinity of the end portion approximately quadrupled to 19.6 &mgr;m. Moreover, when making the displacement of movable reflective mirror <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> similar to the above at 5 &mgr;m, the total force to be applied to the portion in the vicinity of the end portion became approximately &frac14; the force at approximately 2&times;10<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>&mgr;N. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> As described above, by employing the structure of driving the portion in the vicinity of the end portion of the movable mirror, the force necessary to be applied for driving the movable mirror becomes small, and the entire reflective surface thereof can easily be deformed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> The variable dispersion compensator according to the present invention and the optical transmission system comprising the same are not limited to the embodiments described above, and may be modified in various forms. For example, the optical combining/splitting unit, which performs splitting and combining of the optical signal is not limited to an AWG, but various elements may also be used, or alternatively, the optical splitting unit and optical combining unit may also be provided separately. Furthermore, in regards to the splitting of the optical signal, splitting maybe performed so as to divide into a plurality of frequency components, for example, according to the configuration of the reflecting means, or alternatively, splitting may also be performed into a continuous spectral shape by frequency <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows another embodiment of the variable dispersion compensator. In this embodiment, the optical signal from optical fiber transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, which is used for dispersion compensation, is input to diffractive grating <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>which is an optical combining/splitting means, and is reflected for every frequency component at reflecting means <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Each of the reflected frequency components is combined to become the post-dispersion compensation optical signal again by diffractive grating <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>and is input towards optical fiber transmission line <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a block diagram that illustratively shows another embodiment of the variable dispersion compensator. In this embodiment, silicon oxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>which comprises two diffractive gratings <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e </italic></highlight>on the underside thereof, is used as optical combining/splitting means. The optical signal from optical fiber transmission line <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which is used for input, is input to diffractive grating <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d, </italic></highlight>which is optical splitting means, after being incident on the top surface of plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>and is reflected for every frequency component at reflecting means <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> Each of the reflected frequency components is then combined at refractive grating <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>e, </italic></highlight>which is optical combining means, to become the post-dispersion compensation optical signal, and is input toward optical fiber transmission line <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, which is used for output, through the top of plate <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Besides these structural examples, optical splitting means, reflecting means, and optical combining means, or combinations thereof, are possible for adaptation of the various respective figurations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> The variable dispersion compensator and optical transmission system according to the present invention, as detailed in the above, are superior in the precision and controllability of dispersion compensation, and may be used as the variable dispersion compensator and optical transmission system in which the optical circuit thereof will be miniaturized. Namely, in accordance with a variable dispersion compensator in which the optical path length difference from an optical splitting means, through a reflecting means, until an optical combining means is used to apply phase shift to each frequency component of an optical signal, and also, the phase shift is changed using a reflecting means having a variable reflection position for each frequency component, make it possible to compensate dispersion that develops in an optical signal accurately and with favorable controllability. Furthermore, since dispersion compensation is controlled only with reflecting means, it is possible to simplify the structure of an optical circuit, and accordingly, allow the size reduction of the optical circuit. Moreover, according to the structure deforming the portion in the vicinity of the end portion of the movable mirror with a moment application means, the force necessary in application for reforming the movable mirror becomes small, and the entire reflective surface thereof can be deformed easier. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> From the invention thus described, it will be obvious that the embodiments of the invention may be varied in many ways. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the spirit and scope of the invention, and all such modifications as would be obvious to one skilled in the art are intended for inclusion within the scope of the following claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A variable dispersion compensator, which applies a phase shift to an optical signal to compensate dispersion in the optical signal, comprising: 
<claim-text>optical splitting means, which inputs an optical signal that is to become the subject of dispersion compensation, and splits said optical signal for every frequency component within a predetermined frequency band; </claim-text>
<claim-text>reflecting means, which reflects each of said respective frequency components that are split by said optical splitting means to apply a predetermined phase shift to each frequency component, and is configured with the reflection position for each of said respective frequency components being movable in the direction of optical signal propagation; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>optical combining means, which combines said frequency components reflected by said reflecting means to give a dispersion compensated optical signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said reflective means is constituted by a single reflective mirror, said single reflective mirror is a movable mirror capable of moving each of its reflective surfaces corresponding to said frequency component in said optical signal propagation direction by deforming the entire reflective surface thereof; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said movable mirror, which is said single reflective mirror, is designed such that the entire reflective surface thereof is deformed by applying a moment to application portions provided respectively to the vicinity of the end portion on both sides by means of a moment application means, while fixing a fixed portion provided to the vicinity of the center thereof. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A variable dispersion compensator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized by said optical splitting means and said optical combining means comprising a single optical combining/splitting means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A variable dispersion compensator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized by the shape of the reflective surface of said reflective mirrors, which configures said reflecting means, being approximately parabolic in relation to said frequency component to be reflected. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An optical transmission system characterized by comprising 
<claim-text>an optical transmission line, which propagates an optical signal having a frequency component within a predetermined frequency band; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the variable dispersion compensator according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, which is disposed at a predetermined position upon said optical transmission line and compensates dispersion that develops in said optical signal propagated through said optical transmission line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. An optical transmission system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized by the bit rate of said optical signal being 10 Gbps or faster.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030002772A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
