<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001205A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001205A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001205</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10141171</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020509</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-0037463</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/4763</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/3205</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/76</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L029/94</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>336000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>592000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>305000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>344000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Transistor of semiconductor device and method of manufacturing the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kil</given-name>
<middle-name>Ho</middle-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoungki-do</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jong</given-name>
<middle-name>II</middle-name>
<family-name>Kim</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Daejeon Metropolitan City</city>
<country-code>KR</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Hynix Semiconductor Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow,</name-1>
<name-2>Garrett &amp; Dunner, L.L.P.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>1300 I Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3315</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">The present invention relates to a transistor of a semiconductor and a method of fabricating the same. In the method, the dual gate electrode may have different widths and is formed using a damascene process. The dual gate electrode is formed using a stacked upper having a first gate electrode and a second gate electrode. The second gate electrode may have a broader width than the lower first gate electrode. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention generally relates to a semiconductor device and a method of manufacturing the same. In particular, the present invention relates to a dual gate electrode having a stacked structure comprising a first gate electrode and a second gate electrode larger than the first gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional semiconductor devices have problems, such as RC delay, short channel effects, and increased contact resistance as junction depth is decreased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> As a result, a salicide structure, an elevated source/drain (&ldquo;ESD&rdquo;), or both are employed to form a source/drain region on a semiconductor substrate, such as by a selective epitaxial process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate a conventional method of fabricating a transistor. A gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and a gate electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are formed on a p-type semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>). A lightly doped drain region (hereinafter referred to as the &lsquo;LDD&rsquo; region) <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is then formed by ion-implanting low concentration, low energy n-type impurities and using a mask on the surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at both sides of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>). Next, an oxide film is formed on the entire surface including the gate electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The oxide film is etched to form an oxide spacer <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on side walls of the gate electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>). A source/drain region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is formed on the exposed region of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> by ion-implanting high concentration, high energy n-type impurities using the oxide spacer <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and the gate electrode <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> as masks (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> However, the conventional method of fabricating a transistor has several problems. The width of a gate electrode is limited by the thickness of the polysilicon layer, which is used to form the gate electrode, and the etching selectivity of the photoresist layer used as a mask for etching the polysilicon layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> It is difficult to decrease the width of the photoresist layer. The thickness of the photoresist layer must often be maintained at a certain level. In addition, a limit in the channel length can also prevent high integration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In addition, when the width of the gate electrode is reduced, the surface resistance of the gate electrode increases and, thus, deteriorates the performance characteristics of the device. Furthermore, when a contact hole is formed at the upper side of the gate electrode, the process margin of the contact hole decreases and, thereby, potentially allowing a short circuit between the gate electrode and the active region, and resulting in decreased yield and reliability of the device. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, a transistor of a semiconductor device comprises: a gate insulating film formed on a semiconductor substrate; a first gate electrode formed on the gate insulating film; a lightly doped drain (LDD) region formed on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the first gate electrode; an oxide pattern of a predetermined width formed at a side wall of the first gate electrode; a second gate electrode formed at an upper portion of the first gate electrode and the oxide pattern; and a source/drain region formed on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the second gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the present invention, a method of fabricating a transistor of a semiconductor device comprises: sequentially forming a gate insulating film on a semiconductor substrate and a first gate electrode on the gate insulating film; forming a lightly doped drain (LDD) region on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the first gate electrode; forming an insulating film; forming a groove exposing an upper portion of the first gate electrode by removing a portion of the insulating film at an upper portion of the first gate electrode, wherein a width of the removed portion of the insulating film is larger than that of the first gate electrode; forming a second gate electrode contacting the first gate electrode by filling the groove; forming an insulating film pattern at both sides of the first gate electrode by removing the insulating film at both sides of the second gate electrode and to expose the semiconductor substrate; and forming a source/drain region on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the second gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Additional features of the invention will be set forth in part in the description which follows, and in part will be obvious from the description, or may be learned by practice of the invention. The features of the invention will be realized and attained by means of the elements and combinations particularly pointed out in the appended claims.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The present will be become better understood with reference to the accompanying drawings, which are given only by way of illustration and thus are not limitative of the present invention, wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d </italic></highlight>illustrate conventional methods of fabricating a transistor of a semiconductor device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagram illustrating a transistor consistent with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>are diagrams illustrating methods of fabricating a transistor consistent with the principles of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> A transistor of a semiconductor device and a method of fabricating the same in accordance with the present invention will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional diagram illustrating a transistor of a semiconductor device consistent with the principles of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> A gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is formed on a p-type semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a dual gate electrode formed on the gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The dual gate electrode may have different widths. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> The dual gate electrode may have a stacked structure comprising a first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> and a second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> may have a predetermined width formed on the gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> may have a width broader than the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> An oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is formed at a side wall of the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, which may also be an undercut portion of the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. LDD region <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is formed by ion-implanting, low concentration low energy n-type impurities on the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at both sides of the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A source/drain region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is formed using high concentration ion-implanting and high energy n-type impurities on the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at both sides of the second gate substrate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A channel width is determined by the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. A process margin of a contact in the gate electrode is determined by the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>through <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g </italic></highlight>are diagrams illustrating methods of fabricating a transistor consistent with the principles of the present invention. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, a gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a polysilicon layer, and a photoresist film are sequentially formed on a p-type semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A photoresist film pattern may be formed by selectively exposing and developing the photoresist film using a mask for the first gate electrode. The first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is formed by etching the polysilicon layer using the photosensitive film pattern as a mask. The photosensitive film pattern may then be removed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment, the polysilicon layer is formed thinner than for a conventional gate electrode but thicker than the depth of an LDD region formed in a subsequent process. Since the polysilicon layer is thinner, the photosensitive film may be thinly coated and, thus, allow the minimum patternable width to be decreased to less than a conventional photosensitive film pattern for etching a polysilicon layer for a gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In addition, since the polysilicon layer is thinner, etching may be more even during the process of forming the first gate electrode. Further, since the polysilicon layer is not overetched, it is possible to prevent damage to gate oxide <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the upper part of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, LDD region <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is formed at the surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at both sides of the first gate electrode by ion-implanting, low concentration low energy n-type impurities using the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> as a mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Referring to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c</italic></highlight>, an oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is formed on the whole surface of the resultant structure and planarized by a chemical mechanical polishing (&ldquo;CMP&rdquo;) process. In one embodiment, the planarized oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is thicker than a conventional gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Referring to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>d</italic></highlight>, a photoresist film <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> is formed on the planarized oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, and selectively exposed and developed to form a photosensitive film pattern <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The photosensitive film pattern <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> may have an opening that is wider than the first gate electrode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> A groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is formed by etching the oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> which is exposed through the opening to expose the first gate electrode <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. In one embodiment, the width of the groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is larger than a conventional gate electrode, but smaller than the conventional gate electrode and the insulating film spacer together. The width of groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> may be based on a design rule. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference><highlight><italic>e</italic></highlight>, a second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is formed by removing the photosensitive film <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> pattern, and coating a polysilicon layer on the whole surface of the structure to fill up the groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The polysilicon layer may be etched using a CMP process, using the oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> as an etch stop layer to have the polysilicon layer remain in groove <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Referring to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>f</italic></highlight>, the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is exposed by employing a plasma containing activated C<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>y </subscript></highlight>gas to etch the oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> using the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> as a mask. The oxide film <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be substituted with an insulator having a different etching selectivity from the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>g</italic></highlight>, a source/drain region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is formed at the surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> at both sides of the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> by ion-implanting a high concentration, high energy n-type impurities using the second gate electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> as a mask. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> The first and second gate electrodes may be formed of different materials such a silicide, a salicide, other than a polysilicon layer. The dual gate electrode may be formed with different widths using a damascene process. When the dual gate electrode is formed having a stacked structure comprising a lower first gate electrode and an upper second gate electrode having a broader width than the first gate electrode, the channel length may be decreased due to the first gate electrode having a smaller width. In addition, integration may be improved, and the surface resistance of the gate electrode may be decreased due to the second gate electrode having a larger width. In addition, other characteristics of the device, such as operational speed and process margin of the contact hole in the upper part of the gate electrode may be improved. Furthermore, short circuits between the gate electrode and the active region may be prevented. Thus, the yield and reliability of the device may be improved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As the present invention may be embodied in several forms without departing from the spirit or essential characteristics thereof, it should also be understood that the above-described embodiments are not limited by any of the details of the foregoing description, unless otherwise specified, but rather should be construed broadly within its spirit and scope as defined in the appended claims, and therefore all changes and modifications that fall within the meets and bounds of the claims, or equivalences of such meets and bounds are therefore intended to be embraced by the appended claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A transistor of a semiconductor device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a gate insulating film formed on a semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first gate electrode formed on the gate insulating film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a lightly doped drain (LDD) region formed on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the first gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an oxide pattern of a predetermined width formed at a side wall of the first gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second gate electrode formed at an upper portion of the first gate electrode and the oxide pattern; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a source/drain region formed on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the second gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The transistor according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gate electrode is thicker than a depth of the LDD region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A method of fabricating a transistor of a semiconductor device, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>sequentially forming a gate insulating film on a semiconductor substrate and a first gate electrode on the gate insulating film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a lightly doped drain (LDD) region on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the first gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulating film; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a groove exposing an upper portion of the first gate electrode by removing a portion of the insulating film at an upper portion of the first gate electrode, wherein a width of the removed portion of the insulating film is larger than that of the first gate electrode; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second gate electrode contacting the first gate electrode by filling the groove; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulating film pattern at both sides of the first gate electrode by removing the insulating film at both sides of the second gate electrode and to expose the semiconductor substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a source/drain region on the semiconductor substrate at both sides of the second gate electrode. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first gate electrode is formed thicker than a depth of the LDD region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the insulating film is formed of an oxide film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the oxide film is etched by using a plasma containing C<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>F<highlight><subscript>y </subscript></highlight>gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3E</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001205A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
