<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000716A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000716A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000716</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10168917</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020624</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>100 59 975.3</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20001202</filing-date>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B25D001/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>173</class>
<subclass>216000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>173</class>
<subclass>029000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Hand machine tool comprising at least one rotating cutting disk, in particular, a circular saw blade</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Albrecht</given-name>
<family-name>Hofmann</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Steinbronn</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Thomas</given-name>
<family-name>Schomisch</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Leinfelden-Echterdingen</city>
<country-code>DE</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Striker Striker &amp; Stenby</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>103 East Neck Road</address-1>
<city>Huntington</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>11743</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/DE01/03445</doc-number>
<document-date>20010907</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a power tool with at least one rotating cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), in particular a circular saw blade, having a housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) in which a drive motor (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is accommodated so that its driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) extends along the longitudinal housing axis (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), having at least one drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) that is supported in rotary fashion in the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and is aligned at right angles to the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>), which drive spindle protrudes laterally from the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and on the projecting end, supports a cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>), and having a set of gears for transmitting the rotating motion of the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) to the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>), in order to achieve an ergonomically favorable, tilting moment-free operation with the power tool, the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) in the vicinity of the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) and cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), and the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) with the cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) are embodied in such a way that the cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) lies in the same plane as the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">PRIOR ART </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The invention is based on a power tool with at least one rotating cutting wheel, in particular a circular saw blade, of the generic type defined in the preamble to claim 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> Power tools of this kind are known as so-called right angle grinders. Most often, they have an approximately cylindrical housing with a gear head that contains an angular gear mechanism and a cutting wheel, which is embodied as a grinding wheel and extends lateral to the gear head, parallel to the longitudinal housing axis and is driven by a drive spindle that protrudes from the top of the housing, lateral to the longitudinal housing axis. The gear head is usually connected to a recessed handle that is situated behind the cutting wheel and extends at right angles to a plane extending through the longitudinal housing axis and the drive spindle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The Wimutec Company of Remscheid produces a universal saw under the type designation ADAMANT, which has the external structural form of the known right angle grinder, but instead of the grinding wheel, is equipped with two saw blades that rotate in opposite directions resting directly against each other. Each saw blade is supported on one of two concentrically disposed drive spindles protruding from the angled head, which are driven by an electric motor in opposite directions by means of an angular gear mechanism. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">ADVANTAGES OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> The power tool according to the invention has the advantage that the central placement of the at least one cutting wheel in relation to the housing permits an ergonomically favorable, tilting moment-free operation of the power tool by both right- and left-handers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Advantageous modifications and improvements of the power tool disclosed in claim 1 are possible by means of the steps taken in the remaining claims. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, the capacity of the power tool according to the invention to be operated in a tilting moment-free manner is further improved in that the usual handle is disposed so that it lies in the same plane as the cutting wheel and the handle axis intersects with the axis of the drive shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, a guard is attached to the housing, which covers the rear region of the cutting wheel oriented toward the housing. In this case, the handle is preferably attached to the guard in order, by mounting it close to the cutting wheel, to achieve an optimal guidance of the power tool. A less optimized attachment of the handle to the machine housing, as close as possible behind the guard, can alternatively be provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, at one end, the housing has an extension arm, which extends parallel to the longitudinal housing axis and has a flat boundary wall that is oriented toward the longitudinal housing axis and extends parallel to this axis, spaced apart from it laterally. The at least one drive spindle is disposed in the frontal region of the extension arm so that it protrudes beyond the flat boundary wall with its projecting end, which supports the mount for the cutting wheel. The degree to which it projects is chosen so that the cutting wheel that is clamped to the cutting wheel mount lies in the same plane as the drive shaft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The power tool according to the invention can advantageously also be designed for the use of two coaxial cutting wheels rotating in opposite directions. In this instance, according to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, the housing has a second extension arm, which is embodied so as to be mirror symmetrical to the first extension arm in relation to a symmetry plane extending through the driven shaft and supports a rotating second drive spindle, which is aligned with the first drive spindle and can be driven in an opposite direction from it, so that with its projecting end that supports a mount for the second cutting wheel, it protrudes beyond the boundary wall of the extension arm, which is oriented toward the other extension arm. The two cutting wheel mounts on the two drive spindles are set so that the two coaxial cutting wheels that rotate in opposite directions rest against each other axially in such a way that they can still easily rotate in opposite directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, the mirror symmetrically embodied second extension arm is detachably connected to the housing so that with a modular design, the same components can be used to produce both a power tool with only one cutting wheel and a power tool with two cutting wheels rotating opposite directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the gearing for transmitting the rotating motion of the drive shaft to the drive spindle has a driven gear non-rotatably supported on the driven shaft and in each extension arm, a driving gear whose gear axis is oriented parallel to the drive spindle and whose gear rim meshes with the teeth of the driven gear, and a transmission, which couples the drive spindle to the driving gear. When there are two extension arms, the shafts that support the driving gears in a non-rotatable fashion are aligned with each other or concentrically engage in one another at their ends, where the inner shaft is supported against the outer shaft, which encompasses it, by means of at least one pivot bearing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the transmission is embodied as a belt drive, which includes a first belt pulley connected to the driving gear, a second belt pulley non-rotatably supported by the drive spindle, and a continuous belt that runs on the belt pulleys. A belt drive of this kind permits a very flat design of the extension arm and therefore a flat design of the housing thus allowing effective operation of this power tool even in tight quarters. In addition, the belt damps torque peaks that emanate from the cutting wheel during operation and therefore reduces wear on the gearing between the driven gear and the driving gear. The belt drive advantageously distributes the required high transmission ratio of the drive shaft to the work spindle over two transmission stages. For example, the speed of the driven shaft of 3000 min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>can be reduced to the speed of the drive spindle of 300 min<highlight><superscript>&minus;1 </superscript></highlight>with a transmission ratio of 1:5 in the angular gear mechanism between the driven gear and the driving gear and with a transmission ratio of 1:2 in the belt drive. The first belt pulley connected to the driving gear can be disposed on the shaft of the driving gear, in front of or behind this driving gear in terms of the symmetry plane or central plane of the housing. As a result, the diameter of the driven gear on the driven shaft can be modified and e.g. when the first belt pulley is placed in front of the driving gear, a smaller pinion can be used as the driven gear. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the case in which the power tool is embodied with two cutting wheels rotating in opposite directions, the cutting wheels can be easily removed from and clamped to the cutting wheel mounts if, according to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, each drive spindle is embodied as a hollow shaft with a polygonal, e.g. square, internal cross section, the cutting wheel mount has a flange, which is connected to an internal shaft guided so that it can move axially inside the drive spindle and has axially protruding insertion pins that engage in a form-fitting manner in receiving bores in the cutting wheel, and a compression spring is supported between the flange and the annular end of the hollow drive spindle. The inner shaft advantageously protrudes beyond the outer boundary wall of the extension arm that is oriented away from the cutting wheel mount and in this instance, has an actuating knob for manually sliding the inner shaft counter to the restoring force of the compression spring. If the inner shaft is pulled out, thus causing the compression spring to be compressed, then the insertion pins emerge from the receiving bores in the cutting wheel and the respective cutting wheel can be removed from the flange. When the inner shaft is released, the insertion pins are automatically inserted into the receiving bores in the cutting wheel and the two cutting wheels rest axially against each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment of the invention, the cutting wheels can also be changed by virtue of the fact that at least one extension arm is supported on the housing in pivoting fashion, the pivot axis being situated coaxial to the shafts of the driving gears. After the extension arm is pivoted away, both of the cutting wheels can be removed frontally from the cutting wheel mounts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In order to facilitate the installation and removal of the cutting wheels for the power tool that operates with two cutting wheels rotating in opposite directions, the two cutting wheels are connected to each other by means of a form-fitting engagement, which permits the two cutting wheels to easily rotate in relation to each other, and as a structural unit, constitute an easy-to-operate cutting tool, which is inserted, for example, between the above-described cutting wheel mounts disposed between the two extension arms, and is automatically locked in place there. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> According to an advantageous embodiment of this cutting tool, the one cutting wheel has tabs bent out from the plane of the wheel and the other cutting wheel has a guide groove, which is concentric to the wheel axis and has an undercut, where the form-fitting engagement is produced by bending the tabs over against the undercut. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In order to bend over the tabs, according to an advantageous embodiment of the invention, bores are provided in the cutting wheel that has the guide groove; these bores open out into the guide groove and are congruent with the tabs when the two cutting wheels are positioned correctly in relation to each other. Through these bores, from the back side of the cutting wheel oriented away from the other cutting wheel, the tabs, which at first protrude at right angles from the cutting wheel into the guide groove, can be bent onto the undercut by means of an accessory tool. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In an alternative embodiment of the cutting tool, the one cutting wheel has tabs which are bent out from the plane of the wheel and the other cutting wheel is comprised of two parts: a ring supporting the cutting means, which ring has a circumferential bevel and a seat incorporated into it, and a hub wheel that rests in the seat and is fastened to the ring. The form-fitting engagement here is produced by bending the tabs over against the bevel.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The invention will be explained in detail in the description below in conjunction with exemplary embodiments shown in the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a schematic side view of a power tool embodied as a handsaw, with a cutting wheel embodied as a circular saw blade, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a schematic view of the power tool in the direction of the arrow II in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a schematic view of the power tool in the direction of the arrow III in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a schematic detail of a section along the line IV-IV in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows a schematic detail of a longitudinal section through a power tool embodied as a handsaw, with two cutting wheels embodied as circular saw blades that rotate in opposite directions, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a depiction equivalent to that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> of a modified version of the power tool according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic side view of a power tool with two cutting wheels that rotate in opposite directions, in a cutting wheel replacement position, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic top view of the one cutting wheel of a cutting tool, which is comprised of two cutting wheels that rotate in opposite directions and is intended for use in the power tool according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic top view of the other cutting wheel of the cutting tool, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> shows a schematic section through the cutting tool, which is comprised of the two cutting wheels according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</cross-reference>, along the cutting line X-X in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic cross section through a cutting tool comprised of two cutting wheels according to another exemplary embodiment.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The power tool, various views of which are shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and a sectional view of which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, is embodied as a manual circular saw with a circular saw blade <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, whose serration is symbolized in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> by the partial circle <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of saw teeth indicated with a dot-and-dash line. If the power tool is to be used as a disc grinder, then the saw blade <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is replaced by a conventionally designed grinding blade. Thus in the following, the general term cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is used for both the saw blade and the grinding blade. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The power tool has a housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, in which an electric drive motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, which is depicted with dot-and-dash lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, is accommodated in such a way that its driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> extends coaxial to the longitudinal housing axis <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or extends parallel to and spaced slightly apart from this longitudinal housing axis <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A ventilating fan <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> supported on the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and an electric connecting cable <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, which both belong to the drive motor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, are also indicated. At one end, the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has an extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, which extends parallel to the longitudinal housing axis <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and has a flat boundary wall <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> that is oriented toward the longitudinal housing axis <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and extends parallel to this axis, spaced laterally apart from it. Close to the front end of the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, a drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is supported in rotary fashion by means of two radial bearings <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, which are embodied as ball bearings in this instance (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is aligned at right angles to the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and passes through the boundary wall <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight> by means of an opening <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> in the boundary wall <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>. At the projecting end of the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is provided, which in the exemplary embodiment is embodied as a contact flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> against which the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is centrally clamped by means of a locking screw <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The projecting end of the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> with the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is embodied so that the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> lies in the same plane as the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. As shown in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, a guard <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is fastened to the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, in fact on the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> of the housing, so that it covers the rear region of the cutting wheel oriented toward the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In order to achieve an ergonomically favorable, tilting moment-free operation of the power tool, a handle <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is fastened to the guard <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> so that the handle lies in the same plane as the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and a projection of it intersects the axis of the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The handle <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can also be fastened to the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, in which case it is aligned in the same manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> In order to drive the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, a set of gears is provided between the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which set of gears has a driven gear <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> non-rotatably supported on the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, a driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which is rotatably supported in the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> by means of a radial bearing <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> embodied as a ball bearing and by means of a radial bearing <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> embodied as a needle bearing, and a transmission <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, which is coupled to the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is disposed in the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which is preferably embodied as a crown wheel and is non-rotatably supported on a shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, has a gear rim <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> that meshes with the gearing <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> of the driven gear <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, which is embodied as a pinion or bevel gear. The drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are aligned parallel to each other. The transmission <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> in this instance is embodied as a belt drive, which includes a first belt pulley <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> affixed to the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a second belt pulley <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> non-rotatably supported on the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, and a continuous belt <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> running around the belt pulleys <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The first belt pulley <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is non-rotatably supported on the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, between the two radial bearings <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. In the exemplary embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the first belt pulley <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is placed against the rear side of the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> oriented away from the gear rim <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>. As alternatively indicated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the first belt pulley <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> can also be disposed in front of the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> so that the gear rim <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> of the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is oriented toward the first belt pulley <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. In this instance, the diameter of the driven gear <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> supported on the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> can be smaller. The speed of the drive shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is reduced to the desired speed of the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in two transmission stages by means of the angular gear mechanism constituted by the driven gear <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> and the driving gear <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the transmission <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> constituted by the belt drive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In the exemplary embodiments of the power tool according to FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, the power tool is embodied as a manual circular saw with circular saw blades that rotate in opposite directions. Here, too, the saw blades can be replaced by grinding wheels in order to use the power tool as a disc grinder. Therefore the synonym &ldquo;cutting wheels&rdquo; is once again used for the saw blades. The two coaxially disposed cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; rest with their blade planes against each other so that they can easily be rotated in opposite directions. The cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are once again disposed so that with their disc planes resting against each other, they lie in the plane running through the drive shaft <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, which plane constitutes the symmetry plane <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the exemplary embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> As described above, the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is clamped to the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which is supported in the extension arm of the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and is driven in the above-described manner by the driven shaft <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is clamped to a drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime; aligned coaxially to the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The drive train for the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime; is identical to the drive train for the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and is contained in a second extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;, which is disposed on the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> mirror-symmetrically to the first extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> so that the two boundary walls <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>&prime; of the two extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are oriented toward each other and are spaced the same lateral distance apart from the symmetry plane <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. All explanations relating to the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and its drive train also apply to the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; and its drive train; in the drawings, similar components are provided with the same reference numerals accompanied by a prime symbol. The shafts <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>&prime; supporting the driving gears <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime; are aligned with each other and are each supported in a radial bearing <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>&prime; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). In the exemplary embodiment of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>&prime; is embodied as a hollow shaft into which the shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> protrudes. The shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is supported inside the hollow shaft <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>&prime; by a ball bearing <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The two driving gears <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;, whose gear rims <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>&prime; mesh with the gearing <highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight> of the driven gear <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, are driven in opposite directions and transmit their rotating motion to the drive spindles <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime; via the belt drives, which constitute the transmissions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime; and are comprised of belt pulleys <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime; and continuous belts <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In a modification of the power tool, the second extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; can be designed so that it can be completely removed from the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. If the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; is removed, then the power tool that is designed to operate with two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; can be used as a manual circular saw with a saw blade or can be operated as a right angle grinder or disc grinder with a grinding blade, as described in conjunction with FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the power tool that operates with two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in opposite directions, for a simpler changing of the saw blades <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, at least one of the two extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; is fastened to the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in pivoting fashion, where the pivot axis <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is aligned with the axes of the two shafts <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>&prime; supporting the driving gears <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>&prime; and the belt pulleys <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime;. In the power tool shown in a schematic side view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, both of the extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are embodied as pivoting. In the operating position, both extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are aligned as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and are locked in place on the housing <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In order to change the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, the locking mechanisms of the two extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are released and the two extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are pivoted in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; on each extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; is now freely accessible and can be detached from the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The exemplary embodiment of the power tool shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, with two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; rotating in opposite directions, has a modification of the cutting wheel mounts <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;, which permits the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; to be easily replaced when the extension arms <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime; are fixed in place. The two cutting wheel mounts <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are embodied identically so that only the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is described here, but this description applies equally to the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; for the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;. The drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is embodied as a hollow shaft with a polygonal, e.g. square, internal cross section. The cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, which is once again embodied as a flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, is connected to an internal shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> guided so that it can move axially inside the hollow drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>; the flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can be of a unit with the internal shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The internal shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> protrudes beyond the outer boundary wall <highlight><bold>192</bold></highlight> of the extension arm <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and at its free end, has a grasping knob <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> for manually sliding the internal shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. On its front side oriented away from the internal shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> has a number of axially protruding insertion pins <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> that engage in a form-fitting manner in correspondingly embodied receiving bores in the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A compression spring <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is supported between the flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the annular end of the drive spindle <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, which spring slides the insertion pins <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> into the receiving bores in the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and holds them there with frictional engagement during operation of the power tool. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; in the operating position and the cutting wheel mount <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> for the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the released position. If the inner shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is pulled upward in the direction of arrow <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, counter to the restoring of the compression spring <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, then the insertion pins <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> on the flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are pulled out from the receiving bores in the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> can be removed and replaced with another cutting wheel. This new cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in turn is positioned so that the insertion pins <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are aligned with the receiving bores in the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> so that when the inner shaft <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is released, the insertion pins <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are inserted into the receiving bores again and the flange <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> presses the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> against the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;. The compressive force is of such a magnitude that the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; can still be easily rotated in opposite directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> on the one hand and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> on the other show respective exemplary embodiments of the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, which are intended for use in the power tool according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. For easy handling during the changing of the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are combined into one cutting tool, which is replaced as a compete unit. The two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are connected to each other by means of a form-fitting engagement, which permits the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; to easily rotate in opposite directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the exemplary embodiment of the cutting tool according to FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the one cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; has three tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> bent out from the plane of the wheel and the other cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a guide groove <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, which is concentric to the axis of the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and has an undercut <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is shown in a top view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is shown in a top view in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>; each of these Figs. shows the respective side of the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; that rests against the other. The depiction of the saw teeth that are customary on a saw blade has been omitted from FIGS. <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The three tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> of the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are disposed offset from one another by the same circumferential angle. Naturally, more tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> can be provided, but it is mandatory that there be at least two tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. As long as the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is still separate, the tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> protrude at right angles from the plane of the cutting wheel and can be inserted into the guide groove <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> when the other cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is set in place. In order to then produce the form-fitting engagement, the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has bores <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, which open out into the guide groove <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> and are situated so that they lie in the vicinity of the tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> when the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are correspondingly positioned in relation to each other. If the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are correctly placed one on top of the other, then an external accessory tool <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> can be used to bend the tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> through the bores <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> in the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, thus producing the form-fitting engagement that permanently secures the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; to each other. The amount of bending and the tolerances should be chosen so that after being attached to each other, the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; can still be easily rotated in opposite directions. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the right half of the drawing shows a tab <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> at a point when the form-fitting engagement with the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has not yet been produced. With the tab <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> shown in the left half of the drawing, the form-fitting engagement has been executed and the tab <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> overlaps the undercut <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In the exemplary embodiment of the cutting tool according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; once again has tabs which are bent out from the plane of the wheel. The other cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is embodied as composed of two parts. It is comprised of a ring <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> that supports the saw teeth or the grinding means (not shown), which ring, on its annular side oriented toward the other cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, has a continuous circumferential bevel <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> along the inner edge, and a seat <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> embodied on its annular side oriented away from the cutting wheel <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, as well as a hub wheel <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> that rests in the seat <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and is fastened to the ring <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The form-fitting engagement of the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; is once again produced by bending the tabs <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> over against the bevel <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> when the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; are resting against each other; the bending and the tolerances are chosen so that after being attached to each other, the two cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime; can still be easily rotated in opposite directions. Then, the hub wheel <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is inserted into the seat <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and affixed to the ring <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by means of a welding process, or by means of glue, rivets, pins, or screws. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> also show the receiving bores <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> provided in the cutting wheels <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;, which bores are used to achieve the above-described clamping of the cutting tool onto the cutting wheel mounts <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime; of the power tool according to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. These receiving bores <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> do not appear in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</cross-reference> as a result of the sectional paths chosen. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A power tool with at least one rotating cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;), in particular a circular saw blade, having a housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) in which a drive motor (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) is accommodated so that its driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) extends along the longitudinal housing axis (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), having at least one drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) that is supported in rotary fashion in the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and is aligned at right angles to the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>), which drive spindle protrudes laterally from the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) and on the projecting end, supports a cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;), and having a set of gears for transmitting the rotating motion of the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) to the at least one drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;), characterized in that the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) in the vicinity of the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) and cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;), and the at least one drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) with the cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;) are embodied in such a way that the at least one cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) lies approximately in the same plane as the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that at one end, the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) has an extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), which extends parallel to the longitudinal housing axis (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) and has a flat boundary wall (<highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>), which extends parallel to the longitudinal housing axis (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>) and is spaced apart laterally from this longitudinal housing axis (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>), and that the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) is disposed in the extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>) so that it protrudes beyond the flat boundary wall (<highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>) with its projecting end, which supports the cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>) </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) has a second extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;), which is embodied so as to be mirror symmetrical to the first extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>), where a symmetry plane (<highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>) extends through the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>), that a second drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;), which is aligned with the first drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>) and can be driven in an opposite direction from it, is supported in rotary fashion in the second extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;) so that with its projecting end that supports a second cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;), this second drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) protrudes beyond the boundary wall (<highlight><bold>191</bold></highlight>&prime;) of the second extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;), and that the cutting wheel mounts (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;) are set so that the two coaxial cutting wheels (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;) that rotate in opposite directions rest against each other axially. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, characterized in that the set of gears has a driven gear (<highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>) non-rotatably supported on the driven shaft (<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>) and preferably embodied as a pinion, has a driving gear (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;) disposed in each extension arm (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;), preferably embodied as a crown wheel, aligned with its gear axis parallel to the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;), with a gear rim (<highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>&prime;) that meshes with the gearing (<highlight><bold>291</bold></highlight>) of the driven gear (<highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>), and has a transmission (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime;) that couples the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) to the driving gear (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the transmission (<highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>&prime;) is embodied as a belt drive, which includes a first belt pulley (<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime;) affixed to the driving gear (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;), a second belt pulley (<highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;) non-rotatably supported on the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;), and a continuous belt (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>&prime;) running around the belt pulleys (<highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>; <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>&prime;, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>&prime;). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claims 3</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">5</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that each drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) is embodied as a hollow shaft with a polygonal, e.g. square, internal cross section, that the cutting wheel mount (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>&prime;) has a flange (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>&prime;), which is preferably connected in one piece to an internal shaft (<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>&prime;) axially guided inside the drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;) and has axially protruding insertion pins (<highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>&prime;) that engage in a form-fitting manner in receiving bores (<highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) in the cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;), and that a compression spring (<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>&prime;) is supported between the flange (<highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>&prime;) and the annular end of the hollow drive spindle (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&prime;). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The power tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, characterized in that at least one of the two extension arms (<highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>&prime;) on the housing (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>) is embodied so that it can pivot around a pivoting axis (<highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>) coaxial to the gear axes of the driving gears (<highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>&prime;). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A cutting tool with two cutting wheels (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;), which rotate in opposite directions and are in particular embodied as circular saw blades, particular intended for use in a power tool according to one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claims 3</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the two cutting wheels (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;) are connected to each other by means of a form-fitting engagement that permits them to easily rotate in relation to each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The cutting tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the one cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;) has tabs (<highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) bent out from the plane of the wheel and the other cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) has a guide groove (<highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>), which is concentric to the wheel axis and has an undercut (<highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>), and that the form-fitting engagement is produced by bending the tabs (<highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) over against the undercut (<highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>). </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The cutting tool according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, characterized in that the one cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;) has tabs (<highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) bent out from the plane of the wheel, that the other cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>) is comprised of a ring (<highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>) that supports the cutting means, preferably saw teeth, which ring has a circumferential bevel (<highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>) along the inner edge on its annular side oriented toward the other cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>&prime;), a seat (<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) embodied on its annular side oriented away from the other cutting wheel (<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>), and a hub wheel (<highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>) that rests in the seat (<highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>) and is fastened to the ring (<highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>), and that the form-fitting engagement is produced by bending the tabs (<highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>) over against the bevel (<highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>).</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030000716A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
