<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00016.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00017.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00018.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00019.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00020.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00021.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00022.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00023.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00024.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00025.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00026.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00027.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00028.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00029.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030004695A1-20030102-D00030.TIF SYSTEM "US20030004695A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030004695</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10150442</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020517</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G06G007/48</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B32B003/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>D04H011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B32B033/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G06K009/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>A47B081/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G09F011/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>D05C017/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>703</class>
<subclass>006000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>312</class>
<subclass>234100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>040</class>
<subclass>312000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>040</class>
<subclass>497000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>382</class>
<subclass>100000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multi-patterned surface covering sample elements, display systems, and methods</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>10150442</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20020517</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09860974</doc-number>
<document-date>20010518</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ronald</given-name>
<family-name>Magee</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jennifer</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Beedy</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Thorn</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Mechanicsville</city>
<state>VA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>J.</given-name>
<middle-name>Michael</middle-name>
<family-name>Hartley</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>R.</given-name>
<middle-name>Lee</middle-name>
<family-name>Burch</family-name>
<name-suffix>III</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Dane</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Owen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Debra</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Michalak</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>East Point</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ritchie</given-name>
<middle-name>D.</middle-name>
<family-name>Eisenhour</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Catawba</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shandra</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Shermerhorn</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marilyn</given-name>
<middle-name>F.</middle-name>
<family-name>McClanahan</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ellen</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Olsen</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>LaGrange</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Milliken &amp; Company</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P. O. Box 1927</address-1>
<city>Spartanburg</city>
<state>SC</state>
<postalcode>29304</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Surface covering display elements, systems and/or methods are provided. In accordance with one embodiment, a multi-patterned rug display sample, element or unit has at least two different geometric designs and/or coloration schemes across a common surface for simultaneous comparative evaluation by a potential purchaser. The rug display sample may be patterned to include two or more geometric or solid patterns corresponding to patterns available on floor covering products independent of the display sample. Also, the display unit may include a feature rug, color runner, color rug, and/or hang tag. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application claims priority to and is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/860,974, filed on May 18, 2001, hereby incorporated by reference herein.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to sample elements, display systems, and/or methods. Moreover, this invention relates to surface covering, such as a wall covering or floor covering, sample display elements, and more particularly to floor covering sample display elements, units or systems incorporating a multiplicity of design combinations across a common surface so as to reduce space requirements for the display of multiple available colors, patterns, and combinations thereof and/or such display elements, units or systems plus information relating to colors, sizes and/or shapes such as a hang tag. Also, certain embodiments of this invention may relate to methods, processes and/or systems of marketing, displaying, selling, and/or merchandising of products, such as surface covering, wall covering, or floor covering products, as well as improved methods, processes and/or systems. More particularly, at least certain particular embodiments of the present invention relate to carpet or rug display elements, units, systems or methods. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> It is well known to utilize floor covering elements of substantially planar configuration for disposition across flooring surfaces. Such floor covering elements may include broadloom carpeting, carpet tile, mats, runners, rugs, and area rugs. In the trade, the term &ldquo;area rugs&rdquo; refers to free laying floor covering elements or products ranging in shape (rectangular, oval, circular, etc.) and size from relatively small dimensions to substantial size in the range of 12 ft.&times;15 ft. or greater. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In the traditional marketing of area rugs, respective samples with each sample embodying one of various available patterns and color schemes are typically arranged in a hanging orientation on respective swinging rack elements so as to permit a potential purchaser to examine a large number of available styles and patterns in relatively close proximity to one another. In recent years, the variety of available patterns and color schemes has increased, as manufacturing techniques have become more versatile. Accordingly, the options available to a potential purchaser have been correspondingly expanded. In particular, the number of available patterns has increased each of which may be available in a number of different color combinations. The number of possible choices is increased still further by the availability of border patterns of different styles and colorations which may be incorporated around a basic pattern if desired. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> While the availability of a wide array of design combinations is believed to be beneficial to the consumer, the display of the various available options or combinations has proven to be problematic due to the cost and space requirements for a sufficient number of display racks to present each available combination. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As a possible resolution to this problem, it has been proposed to display area rug samples wherein one available color scheme is utilized within the interior portion of the sample area rug (display rug) and various alternative available bordering patterns are displayed in the form of separate attached smaller samples, pieces or corners. However, this sample display technique has the deficiency of requiring space allocation for the border sample elements. In addition, if the pattern for the main portion of the area rug is available in two or more colors, a corresponding number of samples are nonetheless still required to provide the potential purchaser with the ability to view those particular colors. Such combined area rugs and sample rugs or pieces form a substantial weight and bulk for each display rack. Also, it is difficult to attach multiple rugs or rug pieces (corners) to a single rack. Finally, the display system which utilizes sample rugs in combination with discrete samples of bordering patterns leaves open the possibility that the display rug itself may be intentionally or inadvertently sold to a perspective purchaser having an immediate desire for the article. Such a sale of the sample area rug may cause confusion and a lack of sales of that particular rug due to a potential purchaser&apos;s inability to pair the missing rug and the remaining discrete border pattern samples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is not uncommon for the sample area rug such as a 4 ft.&times;6 ft. or 6 ft.&times;9 ft. nominal size rectangular rug, to be sold when the inventory of that particular stock keeping unit (SKU) or product has been depleted. When the display rug is missing from the rack, sales of that particular rug can drop dramatically. It is not unheard of for a customer to purchase the display rug even though it has boltholes in it where it was bolted to the rack. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> At least one embodiment of the present invention offers advantages and/or alternatives over the prior art by providing a surface covering display element such as an area rug sample display element which may be viewed by a potential purchaser and which incorporates across a common surface a multiplicity of available patterns and/or color schemes which may be selected for incorporation within an area rug or other surface covering, wall covering or floor covering article for purchase. A single sample rug or display element may best be used to convey visual information to a perspective purchaser which previously required two or more discrete sample units. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Moreover, virtually any number of combinations of patterns and/or coloration schemes may be incorporated into the single sample rug thereby providing the potential purchaser with the ability to simultaneously view various alternatives across a common surface without having to move physically from one display unit to another and thereby further enhancing the ability to select an appropriate and desirable color and/or patterning scheme. In addition, rug, base, SKU, design, bar code, color, and/or pattern reference numbers and/or other information (text and/or numbers) may be incorporated integrally within the sample rug in a coordinated arrangement with each of the different displayed regions thereby enhancing the accuracy of the ordering process once a desired color and pattern arrangement is selected. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> These advantages are accomplished in a potentially preferred form of the invention by providing a multi-patterned rug sample or sample element embodying at least two different geometric designs and/or coloration schemes across a common surface. The display rug is preferably of a substantially full sized geometry such as a 6 ft.&times;9 ft. construction for display on a traditional sample rack (one side of the rack) although larger and smaller geometries may likewise be utilized if desired. The display rug also preferably includes integral display legends designating the patterns present in the various patterned regions to facilitate subsequent ordering of an area rug incorporating features of those defined regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In accordance with at least certain embodiments of the present invention, at least one sample display element such as a sample area rug or sample element is combined with other product information such as prices, shapes, sizes, bases, colors, finishes, edge treatments, and/or the like. Preferably, this increases the number of choices of options, combinations, products, or articles to the consumer or customer without increasing the space or weight required to display the product. For example, this additional product information is preferably provided on a hang tag, sheet, chart, page, brochure, or the like attached to the sample area rug. The consumer can look at and touch the sample display element to get an idea of the feel, size, shape and colors, and can then look at the hang tag to see other colors, sizes, shapes, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one example, an area rug sample display element includes a large feature rug area, one or more additional color areas, and a hang tag which shows the rug in one or more different shapes and/or sizes. The area rug sample display element alone gives the consumer or customer at least four different choices of the featured rug (one pattern or design, two shapes or sizes, two different colors). The addition of the hang tag gives the consumer additional choices (size, shape, color) of the selected pattern or design (rug). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The sample display elements and the combination of the sample display elements and additional product information of at least selected embodiments of the present invention, provide for improved or enhanced methods, processes, and/or systems of marketing, merchandising, selling, displaying, ordering, and/or the like products or articles such as surface covering products, wall covering products, floor covering products, and the like. Also, the sample display elements and/or combination of sample display elements and additional product information provide for a more enjoyable and efficient shopping experience, facilitate special ordering of products, reduce space requirements for displaying products, maximize or increase sales per square foot of floor space, reduce the likelihood that a customer will purchase the sample display element, and/or the like.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings which are incorporated in and which constitute a part of this specification illustrate several potentially preferred embodiments of the present invention and together with the general description of the invention given above and the detailed description set forth below, serve to explain the principles of the invention wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a representative side view of an exemplary area rug display rack; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of the display rack illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a surface plan view of an embodiment of an area rug sample display element according to one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view of the surface of another embodiment of a floor covering sample display element according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a plan view of the surface of yet another embodiment of a floor covering sample display element according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a plan view of the surface of still yet another embodiment of a floor covering sample element according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6B and 6C</cross-reference> are each schematic representations of respective 6 color and 8 color surface covering display elements (such as sample rugs); </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view which illustrates a geometric arrangement for the display of two substantially different patterned regions within a single sample display element; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view which illustrates a geometric arrangement for the display of four discrete patterns within a single sample display element; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view which illustrates a geometric arrangement for the display of two different major pattern elements or colors and available auxiliary pattern elements within a single sample display unit; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view which illustrates a geometric arrangement for the display of multiple major pattern elements (or colors) and dedicated auxiliary pattern elements associated with each of the major pattern elements within a single sample display unit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view illustration of an exemplary sample display unit like that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> with the addition of a hang tag like that of FIGS. <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view representation of two side by side sample display units in the form of runners each with five different colorations or patterns and each combined with a respective hang tag placed in a transparent cover or pouch; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view representation of two separate sample units and hang tags like that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> except that the sample display units (runners) combine to form substantially an entire area rug with ten different color choices; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view illustration of a rectangular sample display unit having a feature rug area, a four color smaller sample rug area, and a hang tag like that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> attached thereto; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a schematic plan view of a round sample display unit having four different color or pattern elements and a hang tag attached thereto; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a plan view representation of additional product and/or ordering information such as a hang tag in accordance with an exemplary embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a plan view representation of a hang tag in accordance with another embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a plan view representation of another embodiment of a hang tag like that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a plan view representation of an exemplary order form in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a plan view representation of an exemplary surface covering display system or unit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a plan view illustration of an exemplary feature rug; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a plan view illustration of an exemplary color rug; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22A</cross-reference> is a black and white copy of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been illustrated and generally described above and will hereinafter be described in connection with certain potentially preferred embodiments and practices, it is to be understood and appreciated that in no event is the invention to be limited to such illustrated and described embodiments and practices. On the contrary, it is intended that the present invention shall extend to all alternatives and modifications as may embrace the broad principles of this invention within the true spirit and scope thereof. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> there is illustrated a display rack <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as may be used to display floor covering samples such as area rug samples in a purchase environment like a retail store, home center, carpet or flooring specialty store, or the like. As shown, the display rack <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may include a pair of vertical posts <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and at least one horizontal bar element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> extending between the vertical posts <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> plurality of support rods, racks, or arms <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> project outwardly away from the horizontal element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The support rods or arms <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are preferably hingeable or rotatable relative to the horizontal bar element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so as to permit support rods <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> adjacent to one another to be hingeably separated in opposing directions thereby opening a viewing space between such adjacent support rods <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. In practice, a rug sample <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may extend downwardly away from either side of each support rod, rack, or arm <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> such that each support rod <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> carries two, oppositely facing, rug samples <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Each of the rugs or samples <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may be attached to one side or half of the rod, rack or arm <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> by, for example, clips, bolts, clamps, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Although only two rugs, elements, units, or samples <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> are shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, it is to be understood that in normal use, each of the rods, arms or racks <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> may support two samples, units, carpets, or rugs <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. One can calculate the total square footage of floor space (foot print) taken up by the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and can divide this total square footage by the number of products (SKUs, options, combinations) displayed to come up with a number of products displayed per square foot of floor space factor. Also, one can calculate the number of products shown per arm or per side of an arm.. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> While the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as illustrated represents one exemplary embodiment, it is to be understood and appreciated that the present invention is in no way to be limited to any particular embodiment of display or racks. To the contrary, it is contemplated that the present invention is useful in any display environment without regard to the actual means of display. For example, rugs may be displayed in drawers, shelves, or slides. Accordingly, the display rack <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> as illustrated and described is to be understood to be exemplary only and in no way limiting to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Regardless of the actual construction of the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or supports <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, in the past, sample rugs have typically been displayed in the form in which they are actually to be purchased and used. That is, the rug sample <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> has typically corresponded substantially to the rug which the purchaser is ultimately sold. However, such a display practice necessitates the allocation of sufficient space to house individual rug samples <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> corresponding to each available pattern and/or coloration scheme. As the number of available patterns and coloration schemes increases, so too does the space required to present corresponding samples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> For example, in the past, if a display had 10 arms, each arm held two sample rugs, to provide for the display of 20 sample rugs. If the display took up 72 square feet of floor space, then the product displayed per square feet of floor space factor is only 20 divided by 72 or about 0.28. If two surface covering sample display units of the present invention (like unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) are placed on each rack or arm <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of a 10 rack display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, and the display <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> takes up 72 square feet of floor space, then the product displayed per square foot factor is at least 7 times 20 divided by 72 or 1.94. The higher the product displayed per square foot factor the better. In other words, the greater the number of products one can display per square foot, the more opportunity for sales per square foot of display space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As will be appreciated, area rugs may incorporate either a substantially uniform pattern across their surface or may utilize a combination of patterns, colors, finishes, edge treatments, borders, and the like to achieve desired aesthetic characteristics. The most simple uniform pattern across the entire surface is a single solid color or heather extending across substantially the entire surface of the area rug. A substantially repeating geometric pattern such as a floral pattern or the like may also extend in a substantially uninterrupted manner across the entire surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In many area rugs, a substantially solid color pattern or a repeating geometric pattern or design may extend across the interior of the rug surrounded by color coordinated frame or border colors and/or patterns. The coordinated presentation of the bordering patterns in conjunction with the interior portion has a substantial influence upon the final appearance of the rug in the environment of use. Further, the interior may include one or more additional patterns, designs, or colors. In this regard, for any given interior pattern, it has been found that relatively minor changes in the coloration of the bordering patterns may give rise to fairly substantial changes in the final overall appearance of the rug. Also, changes in the size or shape of the rug can dramatically affect the look of the rug. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> In a first exemplary embodiment of the invention as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> surface covering display unit such as a sample rug or area rug sample <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is provided which incorporates across its show surface a representative pattern or design portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> which provides the viewer with an understanding of the character and arrangement of the various pattern elements in the full rug. In the illustrated embodiment, the representative pattern portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> includes a major interior pattern portion <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight> and a boundary portion <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight>. A plurality of alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> are present on the same surface or substrate as the representative pattern portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>. As illustrated, the alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> may display corners of various available rug patterns or designs incorporating the alternative patterns or colors so as to facilitate an understanding of relative spatial orientation of design components by the viewer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the exemplary sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, there are shown 7 different patterns, designs or colorations (Lapis, Rose Quartz, Garnet, Sandstone, Wheat, Dark Amber, Amethyst). The sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> gives a consumer the look and feel of the Lapis area rug, the true or actual color of the 7 different colorations, and gives the consumer at least 7 different choices of products to choose from rather than a single choice provided by a single display or feature rug. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> If the sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is combined with additional product and/or ordering information such as hang tags as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 16, 17</cross-reference> or <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, such as point of purchase (POP) hang tags, providing available shape and/or size information, then the consumer has many more choices per sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, per square foot of floor space, per rack, per side of support arm, per sample rug, etc. For example, 7 different colorations (patterns) times 9 different shapes or sizes gives 63 product choices per sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. Hence, the present invention can provide a multiplier effect of product choices per sample unit. It is preferred that the sample unit <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> provide two or more colorations (patterns), more preferably three or more colorations, most preferably <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> or more colorations (a feature rug portion plus at least one additional coloration portion). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Although the sample units or rugs of the present invention are especially well suited to be produced by printing or dyeing the colors, patterns, designs, text, and the like on a printable or dyeable base (cut pile, loop pile, tufted, bonded, woven, knit, etc.), such as by jet dyeing the colors, patterns, designs, text, and the like on a white yarn, cut pile tufted base using a Millitron&reg; jet dye machine marketed by Milliken &amp; Company of LaGrange, Ga., it is to be understood that the sample units or sample rugs of the present invention may be produced by weaving or tufting of pre-dyed or colored yarns, such as by hand tufting, graphics tufting, weaving, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> Printing or jet dyeing of the sample units or sample rugs of the present invention provides for mass production economics of manufacture (can be printed or dyed in broadloom form one after another or nested and then cut into separate units or rugs) and allow for one of (single items), no minimum order of rugs, and can provide for no inventory, special order, and shipment of product direct to customer, retailer, dealer, or the like within 24 hours, 3 days, 7 days, or the like. Also, the sample unit or rugs of the present invention avail themselves to a total special order no inventory system, a mixed inventory and special order system, or a total inventory system where all of the product choices are available from stock. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> According to the illustrated and potentially preferred practice, the rug sample element <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is a unitary structure formed by appropriate formation and patterning techniques. In this regard, it is contemplated that the alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> may be applied by patterned color tufting or weaving techniques, inlaying techniques, dyeing, and/or printing techniques. It is contemplated that dyeing or printing techniques may be particularly useful. Such printing techniques may include by way of example, screen printing, jet dye printing, transfer printing, and combinations thereof. Jet dye printing utilizing a plurality of fine dimension dye jet streams may be particularly preferred. Regardless of the mechanism utilized to apply the array of patterns across the rug sample element <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, the final resulting construction provides a potential purchaser with a view of multiple available combinations of coloration and/or geometric patterns (available products) which would otherwise have to be displayed on two or more separate rugs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As illustrated, according to the potentially preferred practice, both the representative pattern portion <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> as well as each of the alternate pattern portions <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> is preferably designated by a readable identifying legend <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. The identifying legend <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> may be in either machine readable or human readable form. Human readable form may be potentially preferred to facilitate the placement of orders by retail customers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> It is to be appreciated that the present invention permits various pattern portions to be disposed across the surface of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> according to a wide variety of arrangements. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> rug sample element <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> is illustrated wherein the alternate pattern portions <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight> are arranged across the upper portion of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> and the representative pattern portion <highlight><bold>422</bold></highlight> is disposed below and to the side of the arranged alternate pattern portions <highlight><bold>428</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> According to another potentially preferred embodiment of the present invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> rug sample element <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> may be patterned to include a representative pattern portion <highlight><bold>522</bold></highlight> including an interior pattern portion <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight> and a boundary portion <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>. In this embodiment, one or more alternate pattern portions <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> including interior portion <highlight><bold>524</bold></highlight>&prime; and boundary portions <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight>&prime; are arranged around at least a portion of the perimeter of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>520</bold></highlight> so as to provide the appearance of substantial continuity of the boundary portion <highlight><bold>526</bold></highlight> while nonetheless exhibiting a plurality of possible patterning combinations preferably (in a single sample rug). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> there is illustrated yet a further alternative embodiment of the present invention wherein a rug sample element <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> is subdivided into a plurality of substantially discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>652</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>654</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>656</bold></highlight> disposed in a coordinated pattern across the surface of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> such that each pattern portion occupies one quadrant of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight>. According to the illustrated embodiment, each of the substantially discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>652</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>654</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>656</bold></highlight> defines a substantially discrete pattern and/or color combination while simultaneously cooperatively defining a portion of an entire rug structure. As will be appreciated, while the rug sample element <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> incorporates four substantially discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>650</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>652</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>654</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>656</bold></highlight> such segmentation may result in either a greater or lesser number of discrete pattern portions if desired. Accordingly, by way of example only, and not limitation, it is contemplated that the rug sample element <highlight><bold>620</bold></highlight> may include as few as two substantially discrete pattern portions or any odd or even number in excess of two as may be desired and necessary to represent various patterning and/or color options including by way of example only, an arrangement of six or eight pattern portions as shown schematically in each of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6B and 6C</cross-reference>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> While each of the embodiments illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> illustrate rug sample elements used to display alternative coloration schemes applicable to common patterns, it is also contemplated that a single rug sample element according to the present invention may incorporate two or more substantially different patterns either in the same or different color schemes. Such an embodiment is illustrated in representative manner in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> wherein a single rug sample element <highlight><bold>720</bold></highlight> incorporates a first segment <highlight><bold>760</bold></highlight> and a second segment <highlight><bold>762</bold></highlight>. The pattern across the first segment <highlight><bold>760</bold></highlight> is distinct from the pattern across the second segment <highlight><bold>762</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8 a</cross-reference> further representative illustration of the ability to provide a multiplicity of patterns across a single rug sample element <highlight><bold>820</bold></highlight> is illustrated wherein four substantially discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>864</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>866</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>868</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>870</bold></highlight> are provided. Of course, it is likewise understood that any greater or lesser number of pattern portions may also be utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> and in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention, a rug sample element <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight> may be provide wherein discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>972</bold></highlight> may be arranged across the surface of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight>. In addition, one or more auxiliary pattern portions <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight> may be disposed in an arrangement across the surface of the rug sample element <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight>. It is contemplated that such an arrangement may be particularly useful in the event that the auxiliary pattern portions <highlight><bold>974</bold></highlight> are commonly available for both the discrete pattern portions <highlight><bold>970</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>972</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The present invention also enables the presentation of a number of discrete pattern portions and affiliated auxiliary pattern elements within a common structure. One such arrangement is illustrated in representative fashion in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. In the embodiment illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10, a</cross-reference> rug sample element <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight> is provided including a first pattern portion <highlight><bold>1080</bold></highlight> and a second pattern portion <highlight><bold>1082</bold></highlight> having a substantially different pattern. A plurality of auxiliary pattern portions <highlight><bold>1084</bold></highlight> available for use in conjunction with the pattern present across the first pattern portion <highlight><bold>1180</bold></highlight> are disposed adjacent to the first pattern portion <highlight><bold>1180</bold></highlight>. Likewise, a plurality of auxiliary pattern portions <highlight><bold>1186</bold></highlight> available for use in combination with the pattern displayed within the second pattern portion <highlight><bold>1182</bold></highlight> are disposed adjacent to the second pattern portion <highlight><bold>1182</bold></highlight> for use in the selection of an appropriate combination of patterning elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In the exemplary embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11, a</cross-reference> display unit or system <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight> includes a feature rug portion (representative pattern or design portion) <highlight><bold>1122</bold></highlight>, a color runner portion <highlight><bold>1123</bold></highlight> made up of a plurality of alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>1124</bold></highlight>, and a hang tag <highlight><bold>1126</bold></highlight> attached to the feature rug portion <highlight><bold>1122</bold></highlight> by a loop, ring, cord or tie <highlight><bold>1128</bold></highlight>. The feature rug portion <highlight><bold>1122</bold></highlight> and color runner <highlight><bold>1123</bold></highlight> provide at least 6 different coloration or pattern (product) options. The hang tag <highlight><bold>1126</bold></highlight> as shown provides at least 9 different shapes or sizes. Hence the display unit or system <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight> provides for at least 54 different product options or SKUs to a consumer, potential customer, retailer, or the like. Also, it is contemplated that the sample unit, element or system <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight> is a particular SKU in of itself that a dealer, retailer, distributor, or the like can order as needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>, there are shown two different sample units or systems <highlight><bold>1220</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>1222</bold></highlight> each including a color runner or rug <highlight><bold>1223</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1225</bold></highlight> made up of a plurality of alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>1224</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1226</bold></highlight>, and a hang tag <highlight><bold>1228</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1230</bold></highlight>, in a transparent cover or pouch <highlight><bold>1232</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1234</bold></highlight>, attached to the runner or rug by a clip, ring, cord, tie, or the like <highlight><bold>1236</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1238</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> The color runners or rugs <highlight><bold>1223</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1225</bold></highlight> are preferably sized so that the two runners can fit on one side of a single rack or arm of a display. Thus, the consumer has 10 different colorations, patterns, designs, or options presented by the runners themselves and with 9 different sizes and/or shapes presented by each hang tag, then the combination of units or systems <highlight><bold>1220</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>1222</bold></highlight> provide 90 different SKUs, options or products to the consumer. It is readily appreciated that 90 different SKUs per half of a rack in a display is quite a dramatic improvement over one SKU. Also, it is less likely that a customer will buy the color runner (than a feature rug) and leave the rack empty of half empty. If, however, the customer or dealer wants to buy the color runner <highlight><bold>1223</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>1225</bold></highlight>, the runner can be ordered or stocked and sold just like an area rug. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13, a</cross-reference> pair of sample units or systems <highlight><bold>1320</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>1322</bold></highlight> (like the systems <highlight><bold>1220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1222</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>) include respective color runners or rugs <highlight><bold>1323</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1325</bold></highlight>, each including a plurality of alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>1324</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1326</bold></highlight> (like pattern portions <highlight><bold>528</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>), and hang tags <highlight><bold>1328</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1330</bold></highlight>. The color runners <highlight><bold>1323</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1325</bold></highlight> are preferably each one-half of an area rug and yet provide as shown 10 different color, pattern, or design options to the consumer. Together, the units <highlight><bold>1320</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1322</bold></highlight> form a display system of a plurality of color runners and hang tags which provide a multitude of SKU, product, or combination options to the consumer, customer, retailer, or the like. Also, it is less likely that a consumer will purchase one of the color runners <highlight><bold>1323</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1325</bold></highlight> and leave the rack empty or half empty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Although it is preferred that there be a plurality (two or more) of color runners <highlight><bold>1223</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1225</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1323</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1325</bold></highlight> per rack or arm in a display, it is contemplated that a single runner or rug may provide two or more SKUs or options and when combined with a hang tag may provide three or more options or SKUs to the shopper, consumer or purchaser. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Even though the hang tags <highlight><bold>1126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1228</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1230</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1328</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1330</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1530</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1620</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1720</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1820</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>2226</bold></highlight> show 9 different sizes and/or shapes (4 rectangles, 1 runner, 1 square, 1 round, 2 ovals), it is to be understood that any plurality of different sizes, shapes, finishes, edge treatments, bases, backings, shipment options, payment options, or combinations thereof provide the consumer or customer with a multitude of product or SKU options within the spirit and scope of the present invention. It is preferred that the hang tag or other additional product and/or ordering information give the consumer or customer at least two product or SKU options, more preferably at least three, and most preferably at least six or more. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> For example, it is easy to envision adding additional options such as another rectangle, another runner, another round, another square, another oval, an ellipse, a hexagon, an octagon, a triangle, a diamond, and/or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one particular example of the present invention, 12 different color runners and associated hang tags are placed on each arm (6 on each side) of a large display rack, each runner having 5 different alternative pattern portions, and with each hang tag providing 9 different size and/or shape options, provides a consumer with 540 different SKUs or products to choose from per arm (270 SKUs or products per side of the arm). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, there is shown another alternative display unit or system <highlight><bold>1420</bold></highlight> including a large feature rug portion <highlight><bold>1422</bold></highlight>, a smaller color option rug portion <highlight><bold>1424</bold></highlight> having a plurality of alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>1426</bold></highlight>, and a hang tag <highlight><bold>1428</bold></highlight> (like that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>) attached to the feature rug portion <highlight><bold>1422</bold></highlight> (alternatively the hang tag may be attached to the color rug portion <highlight><bold>1424</bold></highlight>). The unit or system <highlight><bold>1420</bold></highlight> operates in the same fashion as units <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1220</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1222</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1320</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>1322</bold></highlight> in that it offers the shopper, consumer or purchaser the opportunity to see and feel the feature rug, to see the actual or true color options, and to select from a plurality of shapes, sizes, bases, finishes, prices, and/or the like. As shown, unit <highlight><bold>1420</bold></highlight> offers at least 5 or more different SKUs or products per one-half rack or arm of a display. Also, if feature portion <highlight><bold>1422</bold></highlight> and color rug portion <highlight><bold>1424</bold></highlight> are each separate rugs (feature rug and color rug), they may be ordered or purchased from stock or inventory. If the feature rug is purchased, the hang tag <highlight><bold>1428</bold></highlight> may be moved to the color rug <highlight><bold>1424</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15, a</cross-reference> sample unit or system <highlight><bold>1520</bold></highlight> includes a round sample rug <highlight><bold>1521</bold></highlight> having a plurality of different alternative pattern portions <highlight><bold>1522</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1524</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1526</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1528</bold></highlight> and a hang tag <highlight><bold>1530</bold></highlight> attached thereto. The hang tag may be releasably or permanently attached or affixed to the rug <highlight><bold>1521</bold></highlight>. As shown, the unit or system <highlight><bold>1520</bold></highlight> provides at least 36 different SKUs or options to the consumer (37 different options if they can purchase the rug <highlight><bold>1521</bold></highlight>, 45 different options if they can select each of the 9 sizes and/or shapes in the 4 color pattern of the rug <highlight><bold>1521</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> shows an exemplary hang tag <highlight><bold>1620</bold></highlight> (POP tag) explaining the 1, 2, 3 process of selecting and purchasing a rug in accordance with one example of the present invention. The steps include: 1) Pick Your Color; 2) Pick Your Size (and shape); and 3) Purchase the Rug (either purchase from inventory, stock, or special order for shipment within 7 days). The rugs shown in the hang tag are preferably shown to scale to allow the consumer to compare the different shapes, sizes and different appearances and designs therein. For example, the runner has a much different interior design than the rectangle, round, square, or oval. Also, it is preferred that the hang tag show the different colors of a particular pattern (rug) in a full view as well as the color runner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> The hang tag <highlight><bold>1620</bold></highlight> may be used with any feature rug, feature rug and color runner, feature rug and color rug, feature rug and runner, color runner, color rug, and/or the like alone or together with an order form <highlight><bold>1920</bold></highlight> as a rug sales or marketing system to facilitate and enhance the purchase and sales of rugs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 17 and 18</cross-reference> show respective hang tags <highlight><bold>1720</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1820</bold></highlight> which provide additional product, price and/or ordering information to the consumer. Again, it is preferred that the images of rugs or products on the hang tags be to scale and show the sometimes dramatic differences between the products (small versus large rectangle, runner versus rectangle, round versus square, etc.). The empty boxes below the different rugs may contain the price, SKU number, bar code, color code, and/or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> Note that the runner of hang tag <highlight><bold>1820</bold></highlight> is much different than the rectangular rugs (no interior design area). If a customer did not have access to the picture or image of the runner shown in hang tag <highlight><bold>1820</bold></highlight> and ordered the runner based on looking at a rectangular rug or even a round, square or oval rug, the consumer may be very disappointed in the runner and want to return it. Consequently, the hang tags <highlight><bold>1126</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1228</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1230</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1328</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1330</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1428</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1530</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1620</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1720</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1820</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>2026</bold></highlight> when used properly can reduce or prevent returns. This will reduce costs and provide the purchaser with a more enjoyable shopping experience. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> shows an exemplary order form <highlight><bold>1920</bold></highlight> which can be used by a customer, sales person, cashier, or the like in combination with the sample units, elements, systems, and/or hang tags to purchase and/or order one or more rugs. A similar form may be used to purchase other surface covering, wall covering or floor covering products. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> shows an exemplary marketing system name The Milliken Solution&trade; which provides a retailer, home store, carpet store, department store, or the like, a color runner <highlight><bold>2022</bold></highlight>, a feature rug <highlight><bold>2024</bold></highlight> and a hang tag <highlight><bold>2026</bold></highlight> which provide the consumer or retailer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> (one design or pattern, 6 colors, 9 shapes or sizes) different product options, to scale images on the hang tag, a simple selection and purchase system, and/or the like. The hang tag is shown enlarged so that the text and images are legible. It is to be understood that the hang tag may be about 8-&frac12; inches&times;11 inches on paper stock while the color runner may be about 2 ft.&times;9 ft. printed or dyed carpet, and the feature rug may be about 6 ft.&times;9 ft. printed or dyed carpet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> shows an exemplary feature rug <highlight><bold>2120</bold></highlight> that may be used in any of the systems or units of the present invention where the feature rug portion is a separate rug. The feature rug <highlight><bold>2120</bold></highlight> has text at the bottom &ldquo;For Display Purposes Only&mdash;Not For Resale&rdquo; to prevent the display rug from being sold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> shows an exemplary color rug <highlight><bold>2220</bold></highlight> which may be used as a full size feature rug or as a smaller color rug to be used in combination with a full sized feature rug (like color rug <highlight><bold>1424</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Although it is preferred that the feature rug portion or element and alternative pattern portion or element of the surface covering display unit or sample rug or area rug sample (such as <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>540</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>920</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1020</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1120</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>1420</bold></highlight>) of the present invention both form part of a single item or rug, it is contemplated that the feature rug element and the alternative pattern element may be separate rugs or separate carpet pieces which may be joined together or hung together on the same rack or arm of the display. It is preferred that they be a single item as this provides for reduced cost of materials, reduced weight, reduced shipping cost, ease of attachment to a rack, ease of ordering a single sample unit, can be printed or dyed as a single item, and/or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> For example, certain retailers, dealers, home centers, or the like may want the feature rug element and alternative pattern element (color runner, color rug) to be separate rugs so that the display rugs themselves may be purchased or sold. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one particular embodiment of the present invention, the display unit or system provides the customer or consumer with the look and feel of a feature rug, true color of a plurality of color options, a rug tag which shows to scale images of the alternative sizes and shapes, and provides for special order and direct shipment of selected products to the customer or store. Also, the rug tag may provide full color views of all of the color options. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In accordance with at least one embodiment, the present invention provides a merchandising concept which increases the number of options, decreases costs, and increases the sales of product per square foot of display space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> In accordance with at least one selected embodiment of the present invention, there is provided a business plan or method incorporating the display units or systems of the present invention, which drives or at least facilitates special order of products, and/or which gives the customer, store, dealer, or the like a combination of options, SKUs, products, units, systems, elements, and/or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> In accordance with at least one embodiment of the present invention, the rug tag, hang tag, POP tag, product information, or the like includes one or more of color choices, to scale images, images of alternative products, design or patterns to scale, easy order process steps or information, order form, product codes, bar codes, color codes, SKU numbers, prices, availability, shipping options, ordering options, payment options, contact information, web site information, help number, and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one aspect of the present invention, the product offering can be easily updated or changed by replacing the hang tag, color runner, color rug, feature rug, sample rug, sample unit, and/or the like. For example, if a particular color of the colors on the color runner is not selling, then a new color runner can be printed and installed in place of the old color runner. In this way, the product offering can be kept fresh, new, and/or include only best sellers. Likewise, the present invention provides for low cost marketing studies of new products by allowing numerous existing and/or new products to be offered on one side of a rack of a display. For example, 3 of the colors offered may be best sellers while the other 3 may be new test colors. Similarly, the hang tag may be modified as needed to add and/or drop sizes, shapes, colors, finishes, bases, edge treatments, prices, bar codes, and/or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one aspect of the present invention, consumers or customers may be provided with a multitude of choices or options from a product offering of only the best sellers of a particular product. For example, 10 best sellers (patterns, designs) may be offered in 6 different colors and in 9 different shapes and/or sizes. This provides the consumer with 540 options or choices while requiring the retailer or dealer to only display 10 sample units or rugs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> It has been discovered that rug customers want choices in color possibly more than choices in design or pattern when it comes to purchasing an area rug. Hence, the present invention provides color runners, alternative color elements, color rugs, and/or hang tags which give the customer what they want&mdash;choices of color so they can match other furnishings, flooring, walls, etc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> Also, in accordance with the present invention, it has been discovered that sales of product can be increased by increasing the choices or options of color, shape, and/or size while providing the customer the look and feel of the product, true colors of the product, and a convenient means to compare the choices or options. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Special order or custom order and direct shipment of products to the consumer or purchaser provide economies and efficiencies to the seller, retailer, dealer, and/or supplier. For example, no inventory cost, no obsolescence, no inventory labor, no inventory tracking, no stock space, no warehouse space, etc. This reduces the costs of the supplier or retailer and may lead to reduced prices for products. Hence, the present invention may provide for reduced inventory or no inventory and the benefits inherent therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of the present invention, a shopper, customer or consumer selects and purchases a rug by looking at selected feature rugs, color runners, and hang tags, selecting a particular rug (size, color, shape, pattern), takes the rug from stock, purchases the rug, and takes it home. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment, the customer looks at selected sample display units, selects two different rugs, fills out an order form, takes it to the cashier, pays for the order, and the rugs are shipped directly to the customer&apos;s home (for extra large rugs, the customer may have to pick them up at the store). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> In yet another embodiment, the customer looks at selected sample display units, selects a particular rug, has a sales associate help them fill out an order form, they pay for the order, and then the rug is manufactured and direct shipped to the customer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> In still yet another embodiment, the customer selects one rug out of inventory and special orders a second different rug. For example, the feature rug may be in inventory while one of the alternative shapes, sizes, or colors thereof must be special ordered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one example, the feature rug is about 5 ft.&times;8 ft., the color runner is about 2 ft.&times;8 ft., and the POP tag is about 7 inches&times;16-&frac12; inches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> It is, of course, to be understood that the present invention extends to any surface covering display element, such as wall covering or floor covering display elements which incorporate an arrangement of colored and/or patterned regions which display patterns and/or coloration schemes selectable by a potential purchaser. Such a floor covering element is useful in the simultaneous display of multiple pattern, border or color options for area rugs, as well as for other floor covering elements including floor mats, broadloom carpeting and carpet tile. Thus, the embodiments and practices which have been particularly illustrated and described herein are intended to be exemplary only and are in no event to be construed as in any manner limiting the scope of the invention. Accordingly, it is to be understood and appreciated that the present invention is intended to extended to all modifications and variations as may incorporate the broad aspects of the invention within the full spirit and scope of the appended claims and all equivalents thereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display element for use in selection of a floor covering product pattern, the sample display element comprising: a rug element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of floor covering products independent from the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element is of a size and shape substantially corresponding to said floor covering product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one inlayed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one color tufted pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one dyed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a screen printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a transfer printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a jet printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of three or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of four or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of six or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of eight or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially similar geometric designs but are different in color. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs of different colors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display element for use in selection of an area rug floor covering product pattern, the sample display element comprising: a rug element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of area rug floor covering products independent from the sample display element and wherein at least one of said at least two selectable patterns comprises an interior portion and a boundary portion and wherein said boundary portion includes a pattern different from the interior portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display element for use in selection of an area rug floor covering product pattern, the sample display element comprising: a rug element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of area rug floor covering products independent from the sample display element and wherein at least one of said at least two selectable patterns comprises a pattern corresponding to a corner portion of an area rug floor covering product independent from the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display element as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A display system for simultaneously presenting a plurality of floor covering product patterns comprising: a display rack and a plurality of sample rug elements supported on said display rack, wherein at least a portion of said plurality of sample rug elements comprise a patterned surface including an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of floor covering products independent from the sample rug element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The display system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said floor covering products independent from the sample rug element comprise area rugs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a portion of said plurality of sample rug elements are of a size and shape substantially corresponding to said area rugs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one inlayed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one color tufted pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one dyed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a screen printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a transfer printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 26</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a jet printed dye pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of three or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of four or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of six or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of eight or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products independent of the sample display element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially similar geometric designs but are different in color. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. A display system for simultaneously presenting a plurality of floor covering product patterns comprising: a display rack and a plurality of sample rug elements supported on said display rack, wherein at least a portion of said plurality of sample rug elements comprise a patterned surface including an arrangement of a plurality of selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of area rug floor covering products independent from the sample rug element and wherein at least a portion of said sample rug elements further include one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. A surface covering sample display unit for use in selection of a surface covering product, the sample display unit comprising: a rug element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of surface covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element is of a size and shape substantially corresponding to said surface covering product. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one inlayed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one color tufted pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one printed or dyed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one printed or dyed pattern portion comprises at least one of a screen printed or jet dyed pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one printed or dyed pattern portion comprises a transfer printed pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one dyed pattern portion comprises a jet dyed pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of three or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of four or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of six or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for floor covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface is t least one of a feature rug, color runner, and color rug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially similar geometric designs but are different in color. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 50</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs of different colors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a product information element providing information relating to at least one of product shape, size, color, pattern, price, finish, edge treatment, base, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said product information element comprises one of a hang tag, POP tag, rug tag, brochure, sheet, page, order form, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a feature rug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 53</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a feature rug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 37</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element comprises at least one of a color runner and color rug. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display unit for use in selection of an area rug floor covering product pattern, the sample display unit comprising: a rug element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of area rug floor covering products and wherein at least one of said at least two selectable patterns comprises an interior portion and a boundary portion and wherein said boundary portion includes a pattern different from the interior portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. The floor covering sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 58</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said rug element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display unit for use in selection of a floor covering product pattern, the sample display unit comprising: a carpet element including a patterned surface wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of floor covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. A floor covering sample display unit as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 60</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said carpet element further includes one or more integral readable pattern identification legends identifying at least a portion of said at least two selectable patterns. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. A display system for simultaneously presenting a plurality of surface covering product patterns comprising: a display rack and a plurality of sample elements supported on said display rack, wherein at least a portion of said plurality of sample elements comprise a patterned surface including an arrangement of at least two selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of surface covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The display system according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said surface covering products comprise area rugs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein at least a portion of said plurality of sample elements are of a size and shape substantially corresponding to said area rugs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one inlayed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one color tufted, woven, knitted, or bonded pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 63</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said arrangement of at least two selectable patterns comprises at least one printed or dyed pattern portion across said patterned surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 67</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least one printed or dyed pattern portion comprises a screen printed or jet dyed pattern. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of three or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for surface covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of four or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for surface covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said patterned surface includes an arrangement of six or more selectable patterns corresponding to patterns for surface covering products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially similar geometric designs but are different in color. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00073">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. The display system as recited in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00066">claim 62</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said at least two selectable patterns comprise substantially different geometric designs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00074">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. A display system for simultaneously presenting a plurality of floor covering product patterns comprising: a sample rug element adapted to be supported on a display rack, wherein at least a portion of said sample rug element comprises a patterned surface including an arrangement of a plurality of selectable patterns corresponding to patterns of floor covering products and product information attached to said sample rug element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00075">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 74</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a feature rug associated with said sample rug element and said product information. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00076">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 74</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said product information is a hang tag. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00077">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 74</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said product information includes to scale images of products. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00078">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>. The display system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 74</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said product information includes at least one of size, shape, price, SKU number, bar code, product code, finish, edge treatment, base construction, and combinations thereof. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00079">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. An area rug display and ordering system, comprising: 
<claim-text>a sample area rug, a color selection runner, and associated product offering information. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00080">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an order form. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00081">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the associated product information includes information on at least one of sizes, colors, and specifications. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00082">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the associated information includes information on at least one of product number, quantity, ship to address, and billing address. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00083">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the associated information is presented as a hang tag. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00084">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the area rug sample and runner are combined as one item. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00085">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said system provides at least 45 product choices. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00086">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. The system of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00077">claim 79</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said system provides at least 54 product choices.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>4</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00016">
<image id="EMI-D00016" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00016.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00017">
<image id="EMI-D00017" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00017.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00018">
<image id="EMI-D00018" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00018.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00019">
<image id="EMI-D00019" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00019.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00020">
<image id="EMI-D00020" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00020.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00021">
<image id="EMI-D00021" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00021.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00022">
<image id="EMI-D00022" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00022.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00023">
<image id="EMI-D00023" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00023.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00024">
<image id="EMI-D00024" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00024.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00025">
<image id="EMI-D00025" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00025.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00026">
<image id="EMI-D00026" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00026.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00027">
<image id="EMI-D00027" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00027.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00028">
<image id="EMI-D00028" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00028.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00029">
<image id="EMI-D00029" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00029.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00030">
<image id="EMI-D00030" file="US20030004695A1-20030102-D00030.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
