<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002604A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002604A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002604A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002604A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002604A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002604A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002604</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10180618</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020626</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0115628.0</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>0129077.4</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20011205</filing-date>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H04B007/10</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>375</class>
<subclass>347000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Frequency offset diversity receiver</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Robert</given-name>
<family-name>Fifield</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Redhill</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>David</given-name>
<middle-name>H.</middle-name>
<family-name>Evans</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Crawley</city>
<country-code>GB</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Corporate Patent Counsel</name-1>
<name-2>U.S. Philips Corporation</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>580 White Plains Road</address-1>
<city>Tarrytown</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10591</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A frequency offset diversity receiver comprises a first RF receiver branch (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>) and a second RF receiver branch (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>), an RF signal combiner (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) having first and second inputs (<highlight><bold>11,13</bold></highlight>) and an output, the first and second receiver branches being coupled to the first and second inputs (<highlight><bold>11,13</bold></highlight>), respectively, frequency shifting means (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) in the second receiver branch (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>) for shifting a received signal frequency by at least one channel bandwidth, an intermediate frequency (IF) stage (<highlight><bold>28,30</bold></highlight>) coupled to the output of the signal combining means (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>) for converting the combined RF signal to baseband, frequency demultiplexing means (<highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>) for recovering the baseband signals corresponding to the RF signals received by the first and second receiver branches (<highlight><bold>10,12</bold></highlight>) and a baseband signal combiner (<highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>) for combining the demultiplexed signals to provide an output signal (<highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="A-0002" lvl="0">The baseband signal combiner in one embodiment comprises at least one MIMO stage. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a frequency offset diversity receiver and has particular, but not exclusive, application to multiple input multiple output (MIMO) systems, such as HIPERLAN 2 systems, and receiver systems using antenna diversity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> A frequency offset diversity receiver is known from IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. VT-36, No. 2, May 1987, beginning at page <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, &ldquo;Frequency Offset Receiver Diversity for Differential MSK&rdquo; by Tatsuro Masamura. The described receiver diversity scheme is intended for the differential detection of MSK (Minimum Shift Keying) in a high quality mobile satellite communications system. The receiver comprises two receiving branches each having its own antenna. The signal from each receiving branch is translated to a different intermediate frequency (IF). The IF signals are summed and then detected by a common differential detector. The plurality of signals are combined at an IF stage without phase adjusters, signal quality measurement circuits or a switching controller. The IF signals differ in frequency by the carrier frequency offset f<highlight><subscript>s</subscript></highlight>. The frequency offset is chosen to be sufficiently large that any interference components in the products of mixing can be suppressed by a low pass filter following the differential detector. Each of the receiving branches effectively comprises two complete receiver chains which not only raises the component count and thereby the cost but also increases the power consumption which is undesirable in hand portable units. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention to reduce the component count in frequency offset diversity receivers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention there is provided a frequency offset diversity receiver having means for combining at least two modulated RF input signals to form a single RF offset diversity signal, a receive chain for converting the single RF signal to a baseband signal, means for frequency demultiplexing the baseband signal to provide the respective modulated baseband signals, and means for combining the demultiplexed signals to provide an output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The present invention also provides a frequency offset diversity receiver comprising spatial diversity means for picking-up respective ones of at least two modulated RF input signals, RF signal combining means having signal inputs and an output, the signal inputs being coupled to the spatial diversity means, RF offset diversity means in signal paths of all but one modulated RF input signals to shift the respective RF input signals into respective frequency channels adjacent a frequency channel containing said one of the modulated RF signals, an intermediate frequency (IF) stage coupled to the output of the signal combining means for mixing the combined signals down to baseband, frequency demultiplexing means coupled to the IF stage for recovering the respective baseband modulated signals and means for combining the demultiplexed signals to provide an output signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Unlike the known type of receiver described above, the input signals are essentially at RF when they are combined thus avoiding a duplication of components in the RF section of the receiver and their attendant cost. Frequency down conversion to baseband is done in a common stage and thereafter the signals which have been digitised undergo frequency demultiplexing to recover the originally received signals which are subsequently combined.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention will now be described, by way of example, with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block schematic diagram of a frequency offset diversity receiver made in accordance with the present invention, and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block schematic diagram of a MIMO receiver.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In the drawings the same reference numerals have been used to refer to corresponding features. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> The receiver shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> comprises first and second RF receiving branches <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> which are coupled to respective inputs <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of a combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The first receiving branch <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> comprises a first antenna <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which is coupled to the input <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The second branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> comprises a second antenna <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> which is spatially separated from the first antenna <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and which is coupled by way of a switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to a filter <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. An output of the filter <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is coupled to a first input <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> of a mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A local oscillator signal having a frequency FREQ.A is supplied to an input <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> in order to shift the signal on the first input <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to a frequency channel adjacent the channel occupied by the signal in the first receiving branch <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An output of the mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is supplied to the input <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> The combined signal output of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is frequency down-converted to baseband in two heterodyning stages which include a RF mixer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, which receives a RF local oscillator frequency FREQ.B from a suitable source to frequency down-convert the combined RF signal to an IF, and an IF mixer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, which receives an IF local oscillator frequency to frequency down-convert the IF signal on its other input to baseband. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Optionally a single mixer (not shown) may be substituted for the mixers <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in which case its local oscillator frequency is selected to convert the combined RF signal to baseband. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> An analogue to digital converter (ADC) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> digitises the baseband signal from the mixer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and supplies it to a baseband processing stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> comprises a frequency demultiplexer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which recovers the respective original modulating signals received by the first and second branches <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and provides them on respective outputs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The signal on the output <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> has had the frequency shift produced by the mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> reversed. These outputs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> are coupled to a phase align and combine stage <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> which provides a single maximally combined signal on an output <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The baseband processing stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes a scan adjacent channel stage <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> which has an input coupled to the output of the ADC <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The stage <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> has three outputs <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The output <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is used for selectively operating the switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, the output <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> provides the frequency FREQ.A which is used to shift the frequency of the RF signal in the second receiving branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and the output <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provides the frequency FREQ.B to the local oscillator input of the RF mixer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The operation of the illustrated receiver will now be described with the assistance of the inset waveform diagrams P, Q, R, S, T, V, W and X. In the diagrams the abscissa represents frequency and the ordinate represents power. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Diagram P illustrates a single channel signal received by the first antenna <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and diagram Q illustrates a single channel signal received by the second antenna <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Both the channels are centred on 5.2 GHz. Diagram R illustrates the signal which has been received by the second antenna <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> shifted in frequency by &plus;20 MHz so as to lie in a channel adjacent to that occupied by the signal on the first antenna <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The combined signal from the stage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is shown in diagram S which shows these signals located in adjacent frequency diversity channels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Diagram T shows the combined signals frequency down-converted to baseband. Diagrams V and W show the respective outputs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> from the frequency demultiplexer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. In the case of the diagram W, the signal has been shifted back in frequency and resembles that shown in the diagram Q. Finally diagram X shows the result of phase aligning and combining the signals shown in diagrams V and W into a single, largely undistorted pulse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In a preferred mode of operation, both adjacent channels are empty in which case the switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is closed and both signals are used. However if both of the adjacent channels are occupied, the receiver cannot operate with two frequency multiplexed signals and the switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is opened so that the receiver operates as an ordinary receiver which may still employ antenna switching similar to a classic receiver with antenna diversity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In the event of only one of the channels being occupied, the receiver may still employ frequency multiplexing but may need to adjust the frequencies FREQ.A and FREQ.B in order that the frequency multiplexed signal is not corrupted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> The illustrated receiver can investigate the status of the adjacent channels by baseband processing. In order to do this the switch <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is opened and the signal strengths of the demultiplexed signals are compared. To investigate the other adjacent channel, the frequencies FREQ.A and FREQ.B will have to be adjusted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> In a non-illustrated variant of the receiver made in accordance with the present invention, the frequency multiplexing could be carried out at IF after the IF channel filter. This will ensure that adjacent channels would always be empty. This non-illustrated variant would require two RF to IF frequency down-converters but only one IF to baseband frequency down-converter. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The signal in the second receiving branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> may be shifted by more than one channel spacing. In such a case the IF stage and the ADC <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> will have to operate over a greater frequency range. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an embodiment of a frequency offset receiver for use in a MIMO system. The illustrated MIMO receiver is in many respects a simple extrapolation of the receiver shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> having more channels or branches. Although four receiving branches have been shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the number is repeated to provide enough branches for the total number of MIMO branches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The receiver shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> comprises four receiving branches (or channels) <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C which are coupled to respective inputs <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>C of a combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A first of the receiving branches, branch <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, comprises a first antenna <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> which is coupled to the input <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The architecture of the remaining three branches <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C is substantially the same and for convenience of description only the second branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A will be described. The corresponding features in the third and fourth branches <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C will referred to in parentheses. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> The second branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A comprises an antenna <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>C) which is coupled to a filter <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C). An output of the filter <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C) is coupled to a first input <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>C) of a mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>C). A local oscillator signal having a frequency FREQ.A (FREQ.C and FREQ.D) is supplied to an input <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>C) of the mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>C) in order to shift the signal on the first input <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>C) to a frequency channel adjacent or close to the channel occupied by the signal in the first receiving branch <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. An output of the mixer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>C) is coupled to a respective input <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A (<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>C) of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. By way of example the first channel <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a centre frequency of 5.2 GHz and the respective local oscillator signals applied to the inputs <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>C of the mixers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>C are such that the respective signals applied to the inputs <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>C of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are &lsqb;5.25 GHz&plus;(1&times;20 MHz)&rsqb;, &lsqb;5.2 GHz&plus;(2&times;20 MHz)&rsqb; and &lsqb;5.2 GHz&minus;(1&times;20 MHz)&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The combined signal output of the combiner <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> comprising signals in four adjacent frequency channels is frequency down-converted to baseband in two heterodyning stages which include a RF mixer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which receives a RF local oscillator frequency FREQ.B from a suitable source for frequency down-converting the combined RF signal to an IF and an IF mixer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which receives an IF local oscillator frequency for frequency down-converting the IF signal on its other input to baseband. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Optionally a single mixer (not shown) may be substituted for the mixers <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in which case its local oscillator frequency is selected to convert the combined RF signal to baseband. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> An analogue to digital converter (ADC) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> digitises the baseband signal from the mixer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and supplies it to a baseband processing stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> comprises a frequency demultiplexer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which recovers the respective original modulating signals received by the four branches <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C and provides them on respective outputs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>C. The signals on the outputs <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>C have had the frequency shifts produced by the mixers <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>C reversed. These outputs <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>C are coupled to a first MIMO stage MIMO1. The MIMO1 stage is capable of carrying out some or all of the following elements or functions: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> (a) Radio channel estimation (to determine the coefficients of the M by N matrix that represents the performance of the channel where M is the number of transmitters and N is the number of receivers. This can be achieved by the use of either training sequences or coding techniques.). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> (b) Radio channel matrix inversion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> (c) Capacity estimation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> (d) Nulling or beam forming. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (e) Interference cancellation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> (f) Maximising SNR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> (g) Error detection and correction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Outputs <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>C of the MIMO1 stage are coupled to respective inputs of a second MIMO stage MIMO2 which is a multiplexer for recombining the individual data streams into a common stream which is supplied on an output <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The baseband processing stage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes a scan adjacent channel stage <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> which has an input coupled to the output of the ADC <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The stage <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> has four outputs <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The output <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> provides the frequency FREQ.A which is used to shift the frequency of the RF signal in the second receiving branch <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, the output <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> provides the frequency FREQ.B to the local oscillator input of the RF mixer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and the outputs <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> respectively provide FREQ.C and FREQ.D for shifting the frequencies of the RF signals in the third and fourth receiving branches <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Comparing <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> it will be noted that <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> there are no switches in the branches <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>B and <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>C because the multi-branch structure of MIMO must be available at all times for MIMO to operate. Nevertheless there may be occasions when some of the adjacent channels are occupied and the transmitter needs to be informed. This can be done by way of a reverse channel and the transmitter can in response limit the degree of MIMO increase which it is using. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In the present specification and claims the word &ldquo;a&rdquo; or &ldquo;an&rdquo; preceding an element does not exclude the presence of a plurality of such elements. Further, the word &ldquo;comprising&rdquo; does not exclude the presence of other elements or steps than those listed. </paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A frequency offset diversity receiver having means for combining at least two modulated RF input signals to form a single RF offset diversity signal, a receive chain for converting the single RF signal to a baseband signal, means for frequency demultiplexing the baseband signal to provide the respective modulated baseband signals, and means for combining the demultiplexed signals to provide an output. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the means for combining the at least two modulated RF input signals comprises means for shifting the frequency of at least one of the at least two input signals to a channel adjacent the other of the at least two modulated RF input signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> or <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, characterised by spatial diversity means for picking-up the at least two modulated RF input signals. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, characterised in that the means for combining the frequency demultiplexed signals includes phase aligning means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, characterised in that the means for combining comprises a first MIMO stage for combining at least two input signals into a single output and in that a second MIMO stage is coupled between the frequency demultiplexing means and the first MIMO stage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A frequency offset diversity receiver comprising spatial diversity means for picking-up respective ones of at least two modulated RF input signals, RF signal combining means having signal inputs and an output, the signal inputs being coupled to the spatial diversity means, RF offset diversity means in signal paths of all but one modulated RF input signals to shift the respective RF input signals into respective frequency channels adjacent a frequency channel containing said one of the modulated RF signals, an intermediate frequency (IF) stage coupled to the output of the signal combining means for mixing the combined signals down to baseband, frequency demultiplexing means coupled to the IF stage for recovering the respective baseband modulated signals and means for combining the demultiplexed signals to provide an output signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the means for combining the frequency demultiplexed signals includes phase aligning means. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised in that the means for combining comprises a first MIMO stage for combining at least two input signals into a single output and in that a second MIMO stage is coupled between the frequency demultiplexing means and the first MIMO stage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised by switching means coupled to each of the RF offset diversity means and means responsive to detecting that at least two adjacent frequency channels are already in use, for operating the switching means to interrupt the signal path. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A receiver as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, characterised by means for detecting the status of the adjacent frequency channels, said means causing the RF frequency offset diversity means and the IF stage to adjust their frequencies to avoid corruption of the combined signal.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002604A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002604A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002604A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
