<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003402A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003402A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003402</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09895394</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03F007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B05C011/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>313000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>311000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>430</class>
<subclass>323000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>118</class>
<subclass>058000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Method and apparatus to prevent pattern collapse of photoresist layer due to capillary forces</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Marina</given-name>
<family-name>Plat</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>ADVANCED MICRO DEVICES, INC.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>David A. Blumental</name-1>
<name-2>FOLEY &amp; LARDNER</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Washington Harbour</address-1>
<address-2>3000 K Street, N.W., Suite 500</address-2>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20007-5109</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">There is provided a method for forming a photoresist layer for photolithographic applications that reduces or eliminates pattern collapse due to capillary forces on photoresist structures during spin developing and/or spin rinsing. The photoresist layer is developed in a near vertical orientation with developer solution showered onto the photoresist layer. Rinse solution is showered onto the photoresist layer and the photoresist layer is dried by flowing air or nitrogen over the surface. Also provided are a semiconductor fabrication method and a semiconductor processing apparatus configured to accomplish the disclosed methods. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention is related generally to a method of making a semiconductor device and specifically to photolithographic methods for forming submicron features involving processing of the photoresist layer to prevent pattern collapse during developing and rinsing due to capillary forces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The semiconductor industry has progressively reduced the size of components and connectors on integrated circuits in the pursuit of increased computational power and device speed. State of the art semiconductor devices are approaching the limit of feature sizes that may be formed using conventional photolithography fabrication methods. One of the limits being approached involves the minimum dimension of photoresist structures that can be used during fabrication. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Photolithography employs photoresist to create a patterned structure that protects the underlying surface from subsequent fabrication steps, such as chemical etching. There are two types of photoresists in common use, positive photoresists and negative photoresists. Positive photoresists are sensitized when exposed to ultraviolet light so that exposed areas will dissolve in a developer solution leaving behind unexposed areas. Negative photoresists are hardened by exposure to ultraviolet light so exposed areas are inhibited from being dissolved by the developer solution while unexposed areas are dissolved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Using the example of a positive photoresist process, a conventional photolithography method for producing narrow line is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A and 1B</cross-reference>. Supported by a substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is provided a material layer that forms a surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in which it is desired to form a first and second narrow line. A positive photoresist layer <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is formed over the surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A first region <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and a second region <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> in the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are simultaneously exposed to electromagnetic radiation <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, such as ultraviolet or actinic light, through openings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in a mask or reticle <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</cross-reference>. The mask <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> comprises a pattern of lines and spaces of opaque material <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, which prevent transmission of light <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and transparent openings <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The terms mask and reticle are used interchangeably in the semiconductor arts, with the term reticle often referring to a mask used in step and repeat exposure systems. The photoresist layer <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is then developed wherein the exposed regions <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are removed (when employing a negative photoresist, the unexposed areas are removed), while the unexposed region <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> remains, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</cross-reference>. A gas or liquid etching medium is then permitted to reach the underlying surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> through the openings <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to etch narrow lines <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> in surface <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which are separated by an some distance <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1C</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the developing step, the exposed areas of a positive photoresist are removed by a developer solution to leave the desired pattern image on the surface. In many cases, the developing step is accomplished by spin coating a developer solution onto the photoresist layer. Spin coating is a process that involves rapidly revolving a wafer while depositing a solution on the wafer near the axis of revolution so the solution is distributed over the wafer by centrifugal force. At the end of the developing step, the surface must be rinsed to stop the developing reaction and remove the developer solution from the surface. In many cases, the rinsing step is accomplished by spraying a rinse solution onto the rapidly spinning surface. Typical positive photoresist developer solutions are alkaline solutions diluted with water, which require only a water rinse. Negative photoresist developer can be either an alkaline solution or organic solvents, which require rinsing with water or organic solvents (e.g. n-butlyl acetate) respectively. After rinsing, the substrate is dried in preparation for further processing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As the width of narrow lines is reduced, the width of the photoresist structures used to create the narrow lines must be reduced. A practical limit being approached in semiconductor feature sizes results from the photoresist structures becoming so thin in the width direction, e.g. the narrow line distance <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>C, with respect to the photoresist layer thickness that they lack the structural rigidity to withstand the forces induced by capillary forces of liquid between them when the surface is spin developed, spin rinsed and dried. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>A, as feature sizes are reduced, the spacing between opaque regions <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on the mask <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are reduced, which results in exposed regions <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, that are illuminated by light <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and unexposed regions <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> both having narrow widths. When developed, the photoresist features <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are thin to provide a narrow line <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, and are closely spaced to make the photoresist openings <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> narrow, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>C, as the photoresist pattern layer is spin coated, a capillary meniscus <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> of developer or rinse solution forms between the narrow spaces <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> adjacent photoresist structures <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, which pulls the structures together due to surface tension and the capillary forces induced during spin coating of the developer solution or the rinse solution, or during drying following spin coating of the rinse solution. Thin structures of relatively weak photoresist material can collapse under such capillary forces, as illustrated by photoresist structures <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, which renders the pattern on the surface unusable. Thus, the prior art methods of photolithography cannot form structures below a critical aspect ratio dimension which is limited by the mechanical strength of the photoresist when spin coating of developer and rinse solutions is employed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of forming a photoresist layer, comprising the steps of providing a surface depositing a photoresist layer on the surface, exposing the photoresist layer through a mask to create an exposed area of photoresist and an unexposed area of photoresist positioning the surface so the surface and the photoresist layer are approximately vertical, developing the photoresist layer by showering a developer solution on the photoresist layer, rinsing the photoresist layer by showering a rinse solution on the photoresist layer, and drying the photoresist layer by flowing a gas over the photoresist layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of making a semiconductor device, comprising the steps of forming at least one semiconductor device on a substrate forming an insulating layer over the semiconductor device forming a photoresist layer over the insulating layer, exposing the photoresist layer through a mask to create an area of exposed photoresist and an area of unexposed photoresist, positioning the substrate so the substrate and the photoresist layer are approximately vertical, developing the photoresist layer by showering a developer solution on the photoresist layer to form a line/space patterns in the photoresist layer, rinsing the photoresist layer by showering a rinse solution on the photoresist layer, drying the photoresist layer by flowing air or NO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>gas over the photoresist layer, forming a narrow line space resist pattern on top of the insulating layer using dry etch, for example, followed by forming a conductive layer in the narrow line space. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a semiconductor device made by using the methods described herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided an apparatus for processing semiconductor wafers, comprising a fixture configured to hold a semiconductor wafer comprising a surface, a means for rotating the fixture configured so the semiconductor wafer can be positioned so that the surface is approximately vertical, a first nozzle configured to shower a liquid on the surface of the semiconductor wafer while the fixture positions the semiconductor wafer so that the surface is approximately vertical, and a duct configured to flow a gas over the surface of the semiconductor while the fixture positions the semiconductor wafer so that the surface is approximately vertical. In an alternative to this embodiment the apparatus further comprises a first reservoir fluidically coupled to the first nozzle, and a second nozzle fluidically coupled to a second reservoir and configured to shower a liquid on the surface of the semiconductor wafer while the fixture positions the semiconductor wafer so that the surface is approximately vertical.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A, 1B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>C are side cross sectional views of a conventional method of making line space patterns for semiconductor devices </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A, 2B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>C are a side cross sectional view of a conventional method of making semiconductor lines where the narrow lines are closely spaced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a process block diagrams of a method of making a photoresist layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a side cross sectional view of a method of developing, rinsing and drying a photoresist layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 5B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C are side cross sectional views of a preferred embodiment method of making closely spaced narrow lines employing a positive photoresist. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a partial side cross sectional view of a completed semiconductor device made by the method of the preferred embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a diagram of an apparatus for accomplishing the methods of the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The present inventor has realized that the line density may be increased and the inter-line spacing may be reduced if photoresist patterns are not subjected to capillary forces when developed, rinsed and dried. By turning the surface containing a photoresist more or less vertical and showering developer and/or rinse solution onto the surface, the capillary forces induced in photoresist structures by spin coating can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> The present invention solves the problem of photoresist structure collapse during spin coating of developer and rinse solutions by changing the way these steps are accomplished and providing an apparatus for shower developing and shower rinsing. The developer solution and the rinse solution are applied to the photoresist while the layer is held in a near vertical position followed by an air, NO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or nitrogen drying step so that the photoresist structures are not subjected to the capillary forces that occur when the surface is spin coated with developer and/or rinse solution. By solving the problem of photoresist pattern collapse due to capillary forces, pattern dimensions can be reduced to dimensions smaller than achievable in the current state of the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> A preferred embodiment of the present invention method is diagrammed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Among the sequence of steps required to fabricate a finished semiconductor or integrated circuit are the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> providing (step <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight>) a surface to be photolithographically processed, which may involve preparing the surface with a dehydration bake and priming the surface with a pre-resist coating; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> applying (step <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>) a layer of positive photoresist to the surface, which may involve depositing the photoresist on the surface, such as by spin coating or vapor coating to form a uniform, adherent and defect free polymer film of the desired thickness, and performing a soft-bake to drive off the solvent component; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> exposing (step <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>) the photoresist to actinic or suitable ultraviolet light shown through a mask so only selected areas (the pattern) are illuminated; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> positioning (step <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>) the surface in a near vertical position; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> developing (step <highlight><bold>118</bold></highlight>) the photoresist by showering it with developer solution, such as an alkaline aqueous solution, to remove exposed areas of photoresist; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> rinsing (step <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight>) the photoresist layer by showering it with an aqueous solution (e.g. water) to remove the developer solution from the surface; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> drying (step <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight>) the photoresist layer by flowing air, N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight><highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or nitrogen over the surface; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> continuing on with subsequent semiconductor fabrication steps (step <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight>), such as etching the surface to form a narrow line in the open areas, adding layers of insulator or conductor material, and removing the photoresist. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> A preferred embodiment for shower developing and/or rinsing a positive photoresist followed by air, NO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or nitrogen drying is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A, 4B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>C. A photoresist layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, which has been deposited upon a surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> layered on a substrate <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, has been exposed to create exposed areas <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and unexposed areas <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>A, the surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is oriented in a near vertical position and developer solution <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> is showered from a first nozzle <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>, which is the developer nozzle, so that droplets of developer solution <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> fall onto the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The first nozzle <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is coupled to a reservoir <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> which holds the developer solution <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, with a valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and a pump <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> provided in some embodiments to control the flow of developer solution through the first nozzle <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>B, while the surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> remains in a near vertical position a rinse solution <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is showered from a second nozzle <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, which is the rinse nozzle, so that droplets of rinse solution <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> fall onto the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The second nozzle <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is coupled to a reservoir <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which holds the rinse solution <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>, with a second valve <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and a second pump <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> provided in some embodiments to control the flow of rinse solution through the second nozzle x<highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>C, while the surface <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> remains in a near vertical position, a gas <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, such as dry air, NO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or nitrogen, is flowed over the surface from a duct <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> to dry the photoresist layer. The duct is coupled to a source of the gas, such as a compressed nitrogen bottle (not shown), with a gas valve (not shown) provided for controlling the flow of the gas over the photoresist layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A, 5B</cross-reference> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C illustrate a method of forming narrow lines using a positive photoresist according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention. A positive photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is deposited on a layer that forms a surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> layered on a substrate <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. The photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> is then exposed to radiation <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, such as actinic light or other suitable UV radiation, through openings <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in the opaque pattern <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> in a mask or reticle <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> to form exposed regions <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> in the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</cross-reference>. In this step, the exposed regions <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> of the positive photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are rendered soluble to developer solution. Other regions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> of the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> are shielded by the opaque layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> of the mask <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> and are not exposed. The exposed photoresist regions <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> are separated by a non-exposed region <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, which remains insoluble to the developer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>B, after the exposing step, the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> oriented into a near vertical position and is developed by showering developer solution <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> from nozzle <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> onto the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> to remove the exposed photoresist regions <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> from the unexposed regions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight>, thereby providing first and second openings <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> to layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>. Photoresist regions <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> are not removed during development and are used in subsequent steps to resist processes such as etching or implanting of the underlying surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. Similarly, after developing is complete, rinse solution is showered onto the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> from rinse nozzle <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> while the surface is held in a near vertical position. Once the photoresist material has been so rinsed, the surface is dried by flowing a gas, such as air, NO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or nitrogen, over the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> from duct <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight>. Developer nozzle <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> is supplied with developer solution <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> from reservoir <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, impelled by pump <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and regulated by valve <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Similarly, rinse nozzle <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is supplied with rinse solution <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> from reservoir <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>, impelled by pump <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> and regulated by valve <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>C, with openings <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> provided in the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, narrow lines <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> are formed in surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> by providing an etching gas or an etching liquid to the surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> through the openings <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> in the photoresist layer <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</cross-reference>. Thus, narrow lines <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> separated by narrow spaces, region <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight>, are formed in surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> While FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C illustrate only a few narrow lines for ease of explanation, it should be understood that a semiconductor device contains a vast plurality of line and spaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, shown in the embodiment of FIGS. <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>C, containing the narrow lines may comprise any layer of material used in an electronic or semiconductor device, such as an insulating, metal or semiconductor layer. Preferably, surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> comprises an insulating layer in a semiconductor device, such as a first level insulating layer or an intermetal dielectric. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a completed semiconductor device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> containing the narrow lines made by the methods of a preferred embodiment. The semiconductor device <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> contains a substrate <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, which may be a semiconductor (such as silicon or gallium arsenide, etc.), a glass or a plastic material. One or more active elements <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> are formed on the substrate <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. The active element may comprise at least one of a MOSFET, a MESFET, a bipolar transistor, a capacitor, a resistor or any other desired device. For example, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates a MOSFET <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The MOSFET <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight> contains doped source and drain regions <highlight><bold>165</bold></highlight> in the substrate <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, a gate electrode <highlight><bold>167</bold></highlight> with sidewall spacers and a gate dielectric <highlight><bold>169</bold></highlight> between the gate electrode and the channel region in the substrate <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. At least one insulating layer overlies the active element <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>. For example, the at least one insulating layer includes a first level insulating layer <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and a first intermetal dielectric <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. It should be understood that there may be other plural intermetal dielectric layers above layer <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> that contain narrow lines. The insulating layers <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> may comprise any dielectric layer, such as at least one of silicon oxide, silicon nitride, silicon oxynitride, fluorinated silicon oxide, aluminum oxide, tantalum oxide, BPSG, PSG, BSG or spin on glass. It should be noted that the insulating layers <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>173</bold></highlight> may comprise plural sublayers of different dielectric materials, if desired. The MOSFET <highlight><bold>163</bold></highlight>, also includes conductive electrodes <highlight><bold>179</bold></highlight> made of a conductive material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Another preferred embodiment of the present invention comprising an apparatus <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> for accomplishing the methods disclosed herein is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. A fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is configured to securely holding a semiconductor wafer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> so the surface <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight> of the semiconductor wafer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> can be addressed. The fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is mechanically coupled to a pivot mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> which may be any mechanical assembly capable of rotating the fixture through at least approximately ninety (90) degrees (i.e. rotating from near horizontally to near vertically oriented), including a shaft <highlight><bold>208</bold></highlight> through a bearing <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight>, a hinge (not shown), or a bendable material (e.g. plastic or rubber&mdash;not shown). The pivot mechanism <highlight><bold>206</bold></highlight> and/or the fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> may be coupled to a mechanical device for rotating the fixture, such as a drive motor <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight>, or configured to be manually rotated, such as by a hand crank (not shown) or lever (not shown). A first nozzle <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> is positioned near the fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> so that when the semiconductor wafer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> is held in the fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> in a near vertical orientation a fine spray <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of liquid will contact the surface <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. In a preferred embodiment, the first nozzle expels a fine spray <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of developer solution <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> from a developer solution reservoir <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> via developer tubing <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight>, impelled by a developer solution pump <highlight><bold>228</bold></highlight> with fluid flow regulated by a developer solution valve <highlight><bold>230</bold></highlight>. A second nozzle <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> is positioned near the fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> when oriented in an approximately vertical position so that a fine spray <highlight><bold>234</bold></highlight> of rinse solution <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> will contact the surface <highlight><bold>216</bold></highlight>. The rinse solution <highlight><bold>236</bold></highlight> is provided from a reservoir <highlight><bold>238</bold></highlight> via rinse solution tubing <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>, impelled by a rinse solution pump <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> with fluid flow regulated by a rinse solution valve <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>. A duct <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> coupled to a gas source, such as a nitrogen bottle <highlight><bold>252</bold></highlight> and regulated by a gas valve <highlight><bold>254</bold></highlight>, is positioned so that gas from the duct <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> will flow across the semiconductor wafer <highlight><bold>204</bold></highlight> when the fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is positioned in a near vertical orientation. The fixture <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, nozzles <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>232</bold></highlight> and duct <highlight><bold>250</bold></highlight> may be positioned within an enclosure <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight> to confine, possibly for recycling, developer solution and/or rinse solution droplets and/or to control humidity during the drying step. Thus a vent <highlight><bold>262</bold></highlight> is included for venting gas from the enclosure <highlight><bold>260</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The terms &ldquo;near vertical&rdquo; and &ldquo;approximately vertical&rdquo; as used herein means oriented so the plane formed by the surface is within thirty-degrees (plus or minus) of the gravity vector, and preferably within fifteen degrees (plus or minus) of the gravity vector, and includes perfectly parallel to the gravity vector. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in detail and with reference to specific embodiments thereof, it will be apparent to one skilled in the art that various changes and modifications can be made therein without departing from the scope of the invention. Thus, the breadth and scope of the present invention should not be limited by any of the above-described exemplary embodiments, but should be defined only in accordance with the following claims and their equivalents. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a photoresist layer, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a photoresist layer on the surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the photoresist layer through a mask to create an exposed area of photoresist and an unexposed area of photoresist; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the surface so the surface and the photoresist layer are approximately vertical, and then performing the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) developing the photoresist layer by applying a developer solution on the photoresist layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) rinsing the photoresist layer by applying a rinse solution on the photoresist layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) drying the photoresist layer by flowing a gas over the photoresist layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas comprises air. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas comprises nitrogen dioxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rinse solution comprises water. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A method of making a semiconductor device, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>forming at least one semiconductor device on a substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulating layer over the semiconductor device; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a photoresist layer over the insulating layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the photoresist layer through a mask to create an area of exposed photoresist and an area of unexposed photoresist; </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the substrate so the substrate and the photoresist layer are approximately vertical, and then performing the steps of: 
<claim-text>(a) developing the photoresist layer by applying a developer solution on the photoresist layer to form an opening in the photoresist layer, </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) rinsing the photoresist layer by applying a rinse solution on the photoresist layer, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) drying the photoresist layer by flowing a gas over the photoresist layer; and </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a narrow line in the insulating layer; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas comprises air. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas comprises nitrogen dioxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the rinse solution comprises water. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the narrow line extends to the at least one semiconductor device or to a second conductive layer above the at least one semiconductor device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device made by the method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. An apparatus for processing semiconductor wafers, comprising: 
<claim-text>a fixture configured to hold a semiconductor wafer having a surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a means for rotating the fixture configured so the semiconductor wafer can be positioned so that the surface is approximately vertical; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one nozzle configured to shower at least one liquid on the surface of the semiconductor wafer while the fixture positions the semiconductor wafer so that the surface is approximately vertical; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a duct configured to flow a gas over the surface of the semiconductor while the fixture positions the semiconductor wafer so that the surface is approximately vertical. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one nozzle comprises a first nozzle fluidically coupled to a first reservoir, and a second nozzle fluidically coupled to a second reservoir. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the at least one fluid comprises a developer solution and a rinse solution, and wherein the first reservoir is configured to supply the developer solution to the first nozzle and wherein the second reservoir is configured to supply the rinse solution to the second nozzle. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the duct is fluidically coupled to a gas source. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas source comprises a source of air. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the gas source comprises a source of nitrogen. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a first pump fluidically coupled between the first reservoir and the first nozzle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first valve fluidically coupled to the first pump. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a second pump fluidically coupled between the second reservoir and the second nozzle; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second valve fluidically coupled to the second pump. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 18</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising an enclosure surrounding the fixture, the first nozzle, the second nozzle and the duct. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A method of forming a photoresist layer, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>providing a surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>depositing a photoresist layer on the surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing the photoresist layer through a mask to create an exposed area of photoresist and an unexposed area of photoresist; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the surface so the surface and the photoresist layer are approximately vertical during at least one of the following steps: 
<claim-text>(a) developing the photoresist layer by applying a developer solution on the photoresist layer; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) rinsing the photoresist layer by applying a rinse solution on the photoresist layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) drying the photoresist layer by flowing a gas over the photoresist layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003402A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
