<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002208A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002208A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002208</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10179872</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>194072/2001</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>87624/2002</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20020327</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B017/02</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>099040</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Flexible disk drive comprising an index detection hall element having an improved detection sensitive condition of a magnetic field</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Akira</given-name>
<family-name>Shibata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Murayama-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yoshihito</given-name>
<family-name>Otomo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Tendo-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Mitsumi Electric Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<postalcode>J</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>FRISHAUF, HOLTZ, GOODMAN &amp; CHICK, PC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>767 THIRD AVENUE</address-1>
<address-2>25TH FLOOR</address-2>
<city>NEW YORK</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10017-2023</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A motor rotatably driving a flexible disk has a rotor having an external peripheral side surface on which an index detection magnet is mounted. A main circuit board mounts a control circuit for carrying out a driving control of the motor and extends in a direction perpendicular to a rotation axis of the motor. Attached to the main circuit board, a sub circuit board extends in a direction in parallel with the rotation axis of the motor at a position close to the external peripheral side surface of the rotor. Mounted on the sub circuit board, an index detection Hall element has a magnetic field detection surface which is disposed so as to oppose to the external peripheral side surface of the rotor. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to a flexible disk drive for carrying out date recording and reproducing operation to and from a rotating disk-shaped magnetic recording medium of a flexible disk and, in particular, to an arrangement structure for a Hall element for generating an index signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> In the manner which is well known in the art, the flexible disk drives (which may be hereinafter called &ldquo;FDDs&rdquo; for short) of the type are devices for carrying out data recording and reproducing operation to and from disk-shaped magnetic recording media of the flexible disks (which may be hereinafter called &ldquo;FDs&rdquo; for short) loaded therein. In addition, such flexible disk drives are widely mounted or loaded in electronic devices such as a personal computer, a work station, a word processor, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Loaded in the flexible disk drive, the flexible disk is rotated by a motor. An index signal is used to determine a starting position of the rotating flexible disk. That is, the index signal is a pulse signal that is generated each time the disk-shaped magnetic recording medium in the flexible disk makes one revolution. For example, the index signal is used for generation of a &ldquo;Ready&rdquo; signal in the FDD. The &ldquo;Ready&rdquo; signal is a signal for notifying the system that writing/reading can be prepared and is generated by detecting that the disk-shaped magnetic recording medium or the motor is rotated by means of the index signal. In the system, the index signal is referred on starting of writing on track formatting, and the index signal is used for determining a point for stopping after one revolution. The index signal is used for management of processing time on writing and on reading. For example, a predetermined count is preliminarily defined and processing is made as an error if the processing for a designated sector is not carried out until counting the number of pulses of the index signal up to the predetermined count on writing/reading. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In order to generate such as an index signal, in an FDD for driving an FD of 5.25 inch type (which will be hereinafter called &ldquo;FDD of 5.25 inch type&rdquo;), an index hole bored in a flexible disk is used. More specifically, generation of the index hole was carried out by irradiating light beam through the index hole bored in a jacket or a cartridge and by detecting presence of the index hole by the light beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in an FDD for driving an FD of 3.5 inch type (Which will be hereinafter called (FDD of 3.5 inch type) which becomes presently mainstream, there is no index hole in the flexible disk. In the FDD of 3.5 inch type, driving of the flexible disk is carried out by rotating a driving pin projecting from a disk table (chucking table) toward the flexible disk. It is therefore possible to rotatably position among the disk table, a rotor of the motor, and the flexible disk. As a result, it is possible to detect rotation of the flexible disk by looking over rotation of the disk table or the rotor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In particular, in a flexible disk drive where a DD (direct-drive) motor such as a spindle motor is used for rotatably driving the flexible disk, the index signal is generated on the basis of operation in periphery of a rotor of the DD motor. More specifically, a notch portion is partially provided with a peripheral side surface of a disk-shaped casing composing the rotor while a magnet is disposed inside the casing so that only one magnetic pole (e.g. a north pole) is visible via the notch portion. Such a magnet is called an index detection magnet. In addition, on a main frame on which a stator of the DD motor and so one are mounted, a main printed wiring board on which a predetermined circuit is formed is disposed. A Hall element is located on the main printed wiring board at a predetermined position corresponding to the outside of the rotor. The Hall element is called an index detection Hall element. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Herein, the Hall element is a semiconductor element applying a Hall effect. The Hall element is a phenomenon where an electric field occurs in a conductor in a y-direction perpendicular to both of an x-direction and a z-direction when the electric current flows in the x-direction in the conductor and when the magnetic field is applied to the z-direction perpendicular to the x-direction. The electric field caused thereby is a Hall electric field and an output of the Hall element in response thereto is a Hall output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In addition, Hall elements are used not only as the index detection Hall element but also for detecting a position in the rotor of the spindle motor. Such Hall elements are called position detection Hall elements. A spindle motor using the position detection Hall elements is called a Hall motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In the manner which is described above, in prior art, a single-pole magnetized magnet is used as the index detection magnet. It is difficult to obtain a stable generation timing for the index signal. Accordingly, in order to obtain the stable generation timing for the index signal, the present co-inventors already proposes and files an application to use, as the index detection magnet, a double-pole magnetized magnet (that is, one where a south pole and a north pole are put side by side) (see Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication Tokkai No. 2001-190,055 or JP-A 2001-190055). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In addition, the index detection magnet mounted on the rotor and the index detection Hall element located on the printed wiring board are disposed so that they are apart from each other at a magnetic field detection position by a little distance. The printed wiring board is disposed so as to extend in a direction normal to a rotation axis of the spindle motor. Accordingly, a conventional index detection Hall element necessarily has a magnetic detection surface which is disposed to extend in parallel with a direction of the magnetic field generated by the index detection magnet. Therefore, the conventional index detection Hall element is disadvantageous in that it has a poor sensitive condition for the magnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in order to improve the sensitive condition for the magnetic field, it may be devised to use, as the index detection Hall element, a specific Hall element having a magnetic field detection surface extending in a lateral direction (namely, at a side surface instead of an upper surface) thereof. However, inasmuch as the specific Hall element is not generally commercially available and is a specific and rare one, it is disadvantageous in that cost rises. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a flexible disk drive which is provided with an index detection Hall element having an improved detection sensitive condition for a magnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Other objects of this invention will become clear as the description proceeds. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> On describing the gist of an aspect of this invention, it is possible to be understood that a flexible disk drive comprises a main frame in which a flexible disk is inserted. The main frame has a frame main surface and a frame back surface. Mounted on the frame main surface of the main frame, a motor rotatably drives the flexible disk inserted in the main frame. The motor has a rotation axis. The motor comprises a rotor rotatably disposed around the rotation axis and a stator combined with the rotor. The rotor has an external peripheral side surface on which an index detection magnet is mounted. Mounted on the frame back surface of the main frame, a circuit board mounts a control circuit for carrying out a driving control of the motor thereon. According to the aspect of this invention, the above-understood circuit board comprises a main circuit board for mounting the control circuit thereon and for extending in a direction perpendicular to the rotation axis of the motor and a sub circuit board mounted to said main circuit board at a position close to the external peripheral side surface of the rotor so as to extend in a direction in parallel with the rotation axis of the motor. Attached on the sub circuit board, an index detection Hall element has a magnetic field detection surface which is disposed so as to oppose to the external peripheral side surface of the rotor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In the above-mentioned flexible disk drive, the sub circuit board has a board main surface opposed to the rotor and a board back surface opposite to the board main surface. The sub circuit board may have a penetration for penetrating between the board main surface and the board back surface. In this event, the index detection Hall element may preferably be inserted in the penetration so that the magnetic field detection surface is faced to the board main surface of the sub circuit board. The main circuit board may have an edge close to the rotor. In this event, the sub circuit board may desirably be attached to the main circuit board at the edge of the main circuit board. The board back surface of the sub circuit board may serve as a soldering surface. In this event, the sub circuit board and the main circuit board may preferably be soldered with each other at the soldering surface with the board back surface of the sub circuit board and the edge of the main circuit board in contact with each other. The index detection Hall element may have terminals electrically connected to the soldering surface.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view showing a main part of a conventional flexible disk drive; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of the flexible disk drive illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a sectional view showing a relationship between a main frame and a direct-drive motor (spindle motor) mounted thereon in the flexible disk drive illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plan view for use in describing a structure of a stator in the direct-drive motor illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of a state where a main printed wiring board and a sub printed wiring board are mounted on a main frame for use in an embodiment of this invention as seen from the obliquely lower lateral side; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a view showing a state where leads are put on ditches of the sub printed wiring board illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a view showing an arrangement relationship between an index detection magnet attached to a rotor and an index detection Hall element mounted on the sub printed wiring board; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a view showing a state where the main printed wiring board and the sub printed wiring board on which the index detection Hall element illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> are attached to each other; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a plan view showing an external form of the sub printed wiring board on which the index detection Hall element illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is mounted; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a cross section showing an arrangement relationship of an index detection Hall element according to this invention in detailed.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, a conventional flexible disk drive of a 3.5-inch type will be described at first in order to facilitate an understanding of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an exploded perspective view of the conventional flexible disk drive. Although the conventional flexible disk drive has a front panel and a case, they are omitted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of the conventional flexible disk drive viewing from a front side. The case is omitted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The illustrated flexible disk drive is a device for driving a flexible disk of a 3.5-inch type (not shown). The flexible disk is loaded or inserted in the flexible disk drive from a direction indicated by an arrow A in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. The loaded flexible disk is held on a disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> having a rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In this event, the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>coincides with a center axis of the flexible disk. In the manner which will later be described, the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is rotatably supported on a frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has an axial direction B which extends in parallel with a thick direction of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is rotatably driven by a spindle motor or a direct-drive (DD) motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>, which is mounted on a frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, thereby a magnetic recording medium of the flexible disk rotates. In addition, on the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is attached a main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> on which a number of electronic parts (not shown) are mounted. Among the electronic parts, a control circuit carries out a driving control of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> The flexible disk drive comprises a pair of upper and lower magnetic heads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> (only the upper magnetic head is illustrated) for reading/writing data from/to the magnetic recording medium of the flexible disk. The magnetic heads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are supported in a carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> at a tip thereof that is laid in the flexible disk drive at a rear side. That is, the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> comprises an upper carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>U for supporting the upper magnetic head <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a lower carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>L for supporting the lower magnetic head. The carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is disposed over the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and is apart from the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the manner which will later be described. The carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> supports the magnetic heads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> at the tip therof movably along a predetermined radial direction (i.e. a direction indicated by an arrow C in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>) to the flexible disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In addition, the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has at the rear side a side wall <highlight><bold>131</bold></highlight> on which a stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is fixed. The stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> linearly drives the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> along the predetermined radial direction C. More specifically, the stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> has an axis of rotation (a driving shaft) <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> which extends in parallel with the predetermined radial direction C and which is threaded to form a male screw. The driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> has a tip <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which penetrates a hole <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>bored in a bent piece <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and which is provided with a steel ball <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight>. The bent piece <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> is raised from the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by cutting and bending. By the hole <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the steel ball <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, a position of the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> is defined so as to extend in parallel with the predetermined radial direction C and the tip <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is rotatably held. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> comprises an arm <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> which extends from the lower carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>L to the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. The arm <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> has a leading edge <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>which is bent so as engage with the root in the male screw of the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. Therefore, when the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> rotates, the leading edge <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the arm <highlight><bold>151</bold></highlight> moves along the root in the male screw of the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, thereby moving the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> along the predetermined radial direction C. At any rate, the stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> serves as a driving arrangement for linearly moving the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> along the predetermined radial direction C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Inasmuch as the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> of the stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is disposed at one side of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, the one side of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is movably supported by the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight> and is apart from the main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. However, because support occurs by the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>, it is difficult to dispose the whole of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> apart from the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. For this purpose, it is necessary to support and guide the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> at another side thereof. To guide the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is a guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. That is, the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is opposed to the driving shaft <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> of the stepping motor <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> with the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> inserted between the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the driving shaft <highlight><bold>161</bold></highlight>. The guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> extends in parallel with the predetermined radial direction C and has one end <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and another end <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> which are mounted on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the manner which later be described. The guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> guides the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> along the predetermined radial direction C. As a result, the whole of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is disposed apart from the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In addition, a flexible printed circuit (FPC) <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> extends from the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to the vicinity of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and the flexible printed circuit <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> attached to the back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is clamped on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by a guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is fixed on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at a center portion thereof by a binding small screw <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. More specifically, the guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> comprises a rectangular fixed member <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> having a length longer than that of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> by a short distance. In about the center of the rectangular fixed member <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight>, a hole <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is drilled through which a screw shaft <highlight><bold>190</bold></highlight> of the binding small screw <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> passes. The rectangular fixed member <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight> has one end <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and another end <highlight><bold>180</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>from which a pair of arms <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight> extend to clamp the one end <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and the other end <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> which the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> sandwiched between the arms <highlight><bold>181</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>182</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Inasmuch as the guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> merely clamps the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> cannot fixed on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by the guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> alone. For this purpose, a pair of locating members for locating the both ends <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is needed. As the pair of locating members, a pair of bent pieces <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> is used which are formed at the side of the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by cutting and bending parts of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. At any rate, the pair of bent pieces <highlight><bold>201</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight> locates both ends <highlight><bold>171</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> to mount the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in cooperation with the guide bar clamp <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The lower carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>L of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> serves as a supporting frame for supporting the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> slidably along the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The lower carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>L has a projecting portion (not shown) which projects into the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> at a side of the guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The guide bar <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is slidably fitted in the projection portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> The flexible disk drive further comprises an eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and a disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Each of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, and the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is formed to perform bending, press working, and bending of a metal plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is mounted on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> slidably along the insertion direction A of the floppy disk and an opposite direction. In the manner which will later become clear, the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> holds, in cooperation with the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the flexible disk on operating of the flexible disk drive. In addition, the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> holds the flexible disk slidably along the insertion direction A so as to allow the flexible disk drive to load the flexible disk therein along the insertion direction A and to allow the flexible disk drive to eject the flexible disk therefrom along the opposite direction. The eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> which are opposed to each other. Each of the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> has a pair of cam portions <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight>. In addition, the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has a bottom surface on which cut portions <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> are formed along the both side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> and a U-shaped cut portion <highlight><bold>213</bold></highlight> is formed at a center portion thereof so as to enclose the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Furthermore, the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> has a back surface on which a pin (not shown) is formed. The pin engages with a stop part of an eject lever which will later be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is disposed on the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> comprises a principal surface <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and a pair of side walls <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> which is formed at both side ends of the principal surface <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> and which is opposed to each other. The both side walls <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> have projection pieces <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> (only one is illustrated). The projection pieces <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are inserted in bores <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> through the cut portions <highlight><bold>212</bold></highlight> of the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Inasmuch as the projection pieces <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> are inserted in the bores <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is positioned against the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in the insertion direction A and the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is reciprocated in the axial direction B of the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Each of the both side walls <highlight><bold>221</bold></highlight> has a pair of pins <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight>. The pins <highlight><bold>223</bold></highlight> are inserted in the cam portions <highlight><bold>211</bold></highlight> formed in the side walls <highlight><bold>210</bold></highlight> of the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. Between the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, eject springs <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> bridge. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Although the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is provided with the projection pieces <highlight><bold>222</bold></highlight> and the bores <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight> are formed in the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in this example, restriction is not made to this and the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be provided with projection pieces and bores may be formed in the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> In addition, the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has a rectangular opening section <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> at a center portion in a back side in the insertion direction A. The rectangular opening section <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> is laid in a corresponding position of the upper carriage <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>U of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and extends in the predetermined radial direction C. So as to enclose the opening section <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight>, a U-shaped swelled portion <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight> is formed where the principal surface <highlight><bold>220</bold></highlight> of the disk holder swells at periphery upwards. On the other hand, the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> comprises a pair of side arms <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight> which extends in a lateral direction perpendicular to a longitudinal direction of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The side arms <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight> are located on or over the swelled portion <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>. In the manner which will later be described, in a state where the floppy disk is ejected from the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the side arms <highlight><bold>153</bold></highlight> engages with the swelled portion <highlight><bold>225</bold></highlight>, thereby the pair of upper and lower magnetic heads <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> are apart from each other. In addition, the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> has an additional opening section <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> at a right-hand side of the opening section <highlight><bold>224</bold></highlight> in the back side of the insertion direction A. The opening section <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> has a shape so as to allow a lever part of the eject lever (which will later be described) rotatably move. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In the vicinity of the carriage assembly <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> on the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, the eject lever depicted at <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is formed to rotatably move. More specifically, on the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a rod pin <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> stands up which extends from the frame main surface thereof upwards. The eject lever <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprises a cylindrical part <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in which the rod pin <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> is inserted, an arm part (the lever part) <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> extending from the cylindrical part <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> in a radial direction, a projection part <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> which is formed in the arm part <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> at a free end thereof and which extends upwards, and an arc-shaped stop part <highlight><bold>243</bold></highlight> which extends from a side of the free end of the arm part <highlight><bold>241</bold></highlight> in a circumferential direction. In the eject lever <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, an eject lever spring <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is attached around the cylindrical part <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight> and the eject lever spring <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> urges the eject lever <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in a counterclockwise direction on a paper of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. The projection part <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> of the eject lever <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is freely fitted in the opening section <highlight><bold>226</bold></highlight> of the disk holder <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The projection part <highlight><bold>242</bold></highlight> is engaged with an upper end of a right-hand side edge of a shutter in the flexible disk to control opening and shutting of the shutter. In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2, a</cross-reference> screw <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is thrust into a tip of the rod pin <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>, thereby preventing the eject lever <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> from falling off the rod pin <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> In addition, the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has a front end section on which a front panel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is attached. The front panel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> has an opening <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight> for taking the flexible disk in and out and a door <highlight><bold>272</bold></highlight> for opening and shutting the opening <highlight><bold>271</bold></highlight>. Into the front panel <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, an eject button <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> projects movably backward and forward. The eject button <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is fitted in a protrusion part <highlight><bold>214</bold></highlight> which protrudes from a front end of the eject plate <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> forwards. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> Referring now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the description will proceed to the spindle motor (DD motor) <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> for use in the above-mentioned flexible disk drive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The illustrated DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> comprises a rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and a stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> combined with the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> comprises a disk-shaped metallic casing <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> which has a protruding portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> formed at its center to protrude upward. The protruding portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> has an upper surface on which the above-mentioned disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is mounted. The main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has a circular opening <highlight><bold>135</bold></highlight> which allows only an upper part of the protruding portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> to pass therethrough and project on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. As a result, the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is projected on the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The rotation axis or shaft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>made of metal is integrally fixed to the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> at the center thereof to pass through the casing <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> and the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. When the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is injection-molded by the use of a plastic magnet, the casing <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> and the rotation shaft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are integrally assembled. The casing <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> has a cylindrical member <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> formed on its outer periphery to extend downward. A ring-shaped permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> is attached to an inner surface of the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> has a plurality of main magnetized elements along a circumferential direction thereof. In addition, the permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> has a bottom portion which has a plurality of motor-servo magnetized elements along a circumferential direction thereof. When the later-mentioned stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> has fifteen poles, the main magnetized elements are equal in number to twenty (that is, north poles N are equal in number to ten and south poles S are equal in number to ten). On the other hand, the motor-servo magnetized elements are equal to one hundred and twenty (that is, north poles N are equal in number to sixty and south poles S are equal in number to sixty) independently of the number of the poles of the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight>. The main magnetized elements are called driving magnetized portions while the motor-servo magnetized elements are called detection magnetized portions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the cylindrical member <highlight><bold>314</bold></highlight> or an external peripheral side wall of the casing <highlight><bold>311</bold></highlight> has a notch portion formed by cutting a part of the external peripheral side wall. A part of the main magnetized elements protrudes from the notch portion and is exposed as a magnetic pole <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. The exposed magnetic pole <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> is operable as the above-mentioned index detection magnet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> The protruding portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> is provided with an arm <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight> attached to a bottom surface thereof. A drive roller <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> is rotatably mounted on the arm <highlight><bold>316</bold></highlight>. Each of the protruding portion <highlight><bold>312</bold></highlight> and the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a generally rectangular hole (not shown) formed therein. Through these holes, the drive roller <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> projects upward from the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The flexible disk received in the flexible disk drive is placed on the disk table <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The drive roller <highlight><bold>317</bold></highlight> is inserted in and engaged with a hole (not shown) formed in a hub (not shown) of the flexible disk. Thus, the magnetic disk medium of the flexible disk is rotated following the rotation of the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is attached to the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> by means of a motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> made of metal. More specifically, the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> is formed on a printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> mounted on the principal surface of the metallic motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>. The stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> comprises a core assembly having a plurality of stator cores <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>, a plurality of stator coils <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>, and a center metal (bearing unit) <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. Each of the stator core <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> extends radially outwardly from an outer periphery of a ring-shaped member of the center metal <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight>. Each of stator coils <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight> is wound around an end portion of each corresponding stator core <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight>. The center metal <highlight><bold>323</bold></highlight> is formed at the center of the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> and rotatably supports the rotation shaft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> has a plurality of attaching elements <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of an inverted-L shape which extend upward from a peripheral edge of the motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> to abut against the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, on the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, a frequency generation pattern FGPT is formed around the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In other words, the frequency generation pattern FGPT is arranged to oppose to the motor-servo magnetized elements (detection magnetized portions) of the permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) such that a predetermined gap is formed distance left therebetween. In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates a case where the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> has eighteen poles. That is, the stator cores <highlight><bold>321</bold></highlight> (or the stator coils <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>) of the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> are equal in number to eighteen. In this event, the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) has the main magnetized elements which are equal in number to twenty-four. In this connection, as described above, when the stator <highlight><bold>320</bold></highlight> has fifteen poles, the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> has the main magnetized elements which are equal to twenty. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> When the motor-servo magnetized elements of the permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> rotate over the frequency generation pattern FGPT, a counterelectromotive force generates in the frequency generation pattern FGPT. Inasmuch as the motor-servo magnetized elements of the permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> are equal in number to one hundred and twenty for a round, a signal of sixty cycles generates from the frequency generation pattern FGPT when the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> makes one rotation. This signal is called an FG servo signal. When the number of revolutions of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is equal to 300 RPM, the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> makes five rotations per second. In this event, the FG servo signal has a frequency of (60&times;5) or 300 Hz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it is possible to control the rotation speed of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> by comparing the FG servo signal with a divided clock signal having a divided clock frequency of 300 Hz which is obtained by frequency dividing a reference clock signal having a reference clock frequency of 1 MHz by using a counter. In other words, a speed control of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is carried out by starting the counter in synchronism with a leading edge timing of the FG servo signal and by comparing a trailing edge timing of the FG servo signal with a trailing edge timing of the divided clock signal which is obtained by counting a fixed value in the counter. More specifically, if the trailing edge timing of the FG serve signal is earlier than the trailing edge timing of the divided clock signal, the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is controlled so as to decelerate the rotation speed of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Conversely, if the trailing edge timing of the FG serve signal is later than the trailing edge timing of the divided clock signal, the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is controlled so as to accelerate the rotation speed of the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> As described above, the conventional flexible disk drive requires the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> in order to compose the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. In addition, the conventional flexible disk drive further requires the motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> made of metal like the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to support the DD motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> on the side of the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. In the conventional flexible disk drive, it is easy to electrically connect the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> with the main printed board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> if they are arranged adjacent to each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, on the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight>, an index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is disposed. The index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and the above-mentioned index detection magnet <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> are arranged with they apart from each other by a little distance at a magnetic field detection position as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> is disposed on the motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> so as to extend perpendicular to the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. As a result, the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is necessarily disposed on the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> so that a magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>thereof extends in parallel with a direction D of a magnetic field generated from the index detection magnet <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> (i.e. a radial direction in regard to the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). This is because, structurally, the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is generally disposed (mounted) on the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> so that the magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>always extends in parallel with a main surface of the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> on which the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is mounted. In other words, a generally commercially available Hall element has a magnetic field detection surface so that normal to the magnetic field detection surface extends perpendicular to a mounting surface thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> As described above, in the conventional flexible disk drive, the direction D of the magnetic field generated from the index detection magnet <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> and the normal to the magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are perpendicular to each other. As a result, the conventional flexible disk drive is disadvantageous in that the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> has a poor detection sensitive condition of the magnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the description will proceed to a frame structure or a main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A for use in a flexible disk drive according to an embodiment of this invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a schematic perspective view of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A as view from lower side obliquely. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In the manner as apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the illustrated main frame (frame structure) <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A is composed of one piece in which the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A and a motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A are integrated. The flexible disk is inserted or loaded in the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A. The spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) for rotatably driving the inserted flexible disk is mounted on the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A. That is, the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A serves both as an original main frame (i.e. the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and an original motor frame (i.e. the motor frame <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A has a drawn-shape obtained by drawing the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A. The motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A protrudes into the back side of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A to form a top surface which is a part of the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A. In the top surface of the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A, an opening window <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> for drawing out leads of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> In addition, although the drawn-shape of the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A is a circular shape, it is not restricted to this and may be a polygonal shape or an oval shape in response to depth or material of the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A. In addition, a drawing shirked shape in the drawn-shape of the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A is also not restricted to that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> and may be various shapes. Furthermore, a connection way between the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A and the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A is also not restricted to that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> The flexible disk drive according to the embodiment of this invention can adopt the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A having the above-mentioned shape because the flexible disk drive does not have the frequency generation pattern FGPT (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) and the printed wiring board <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> which are necessary to control the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. Moreover, the motor-servo magnetized members formed at the bottom portion of the permanent magnet <highlight><bold>315</bold></highlight> of the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> are unnecessary because the flexible disk drive does not have the frequency generation pattern FGPT. Instead, the flexible disk drive comprises an electronic processing unit which functions as the combination of the frequency generation pattern FGPT and the motor-servo magnetized members. Operation of the electronic processing unit is similar to that described in Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication Tokkai No. 2001-178,185 or JP-A 2001-178185 which is already proposed by the present co-inventors. Inasmuch as the electronic processing unit only indirectly relates to this invention, the description thereof is omitted herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The flexible disk drive according to the embodiment of this invention comprises a main printed wiring board (a main circuit board) <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A which is attached to the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A like the conventional flexible disk drive. The main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A has a shape such as to avoid overlapping with the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A. The main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A has a supporting piece (not shown) which is raised from the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A by cutting and bending and which has a threaded hole formed in its tip portion. The main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A is fixed to the supporting piece by a screw <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> engaged with the threaded hole so that a main surface <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> of the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A is spaced at a predetermined distance from the back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A and a back surface <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A is nearer to the frame back surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A than the top surface of the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, on the side of the frame main surface of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A, end portions (i.e. leads) of rotor coils wound around stator cores of the spindle motor mounted on the motor frame part <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight>A are drawn out to the back side of the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A through the opening window <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> formed in the main frame <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>A and are connected to predetermined terminals on the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A. Generally, the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are equal in number to four. Three of the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> correspond to U, V and W phases of three phase alternating current. The remaining one of the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is connected to the other ends of the leads for the U, V and W phases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> The flexible disk drive according to the embodiment of this invention further comprises a sub printed wiring board (a sub circuit board) <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. The sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is for guiding the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. On the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is mounted in the manner which will later be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> The main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A extends in a direction perpendicular to the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is attached to the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A at a position close to an external peripheral side surface of the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight> so as to extend in a direction in parallel with the rotation axis <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the spindle motor <highlight><bold>300</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is attached on the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> so that a magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>thereof is opposed to the external peripheral side surface of the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. In addition, the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> has four terminals <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>which are electrically connected to wiring (not shown) on the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A via solder <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The solder <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> plays not only a role of such an electrically connection but also a role of a mechanical connection between the main printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A and the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Drawn out from the opening window <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight>, the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> are held and fixed on the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> with the leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> put on ditches <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The leads <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> have tips which are connected and fixed to the predetermined terminals <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> of the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> In the manner which is described above, according to this invention, a generally commercially available Hall element is used as the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> and the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is mounted on the sub printed wiring board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> so that the magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is opposed to the index detection magnet <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, it is possible to improve the detection sensitive condition of the magnetic field in the Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. Inasmuch as a specific Hall element having a magnetic field detection surface at a side surface thereof is not used as the index detection Hall element, costs are reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the description will be made as regards arrangement of the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> according to this invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> The sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has a board main surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>opposed to the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight> and a board back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>opposite to the board main surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. The sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> has a penetration <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>for penetrating between the board main surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the baord back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. The index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> is inserted in the penetration <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>so that the magnetic field detection surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is faced to the board main surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>of the sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, the main circuit board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A has an edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>Aa close to the rotor <highlight><bold>310</bold></highlight>. The sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is attached to the main circuit board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A at the edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>Aa of the main circuit board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A. The board back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> serves as a soldering surface. The sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the main circuit board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A are soldered with each other at the soldering surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>with the back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the sub circuit board <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the edge <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>Aa of the main circuit board <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>A in contact with each other. The four terminals <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the index detection Hall element <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> are electrically connected to the soldering surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> While this invention has thus far been described in conjunction with a preferred embodiment thereof, it is to be understood that modifications will be apparent to those skilled in the art without departing from the sprit of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A flexible disk drive comprising: 
<claim-text>a main frame in which a flexible disk is inserted, said main frame having a frame main surface and a frame back surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a motor, mounted on the frame main surface of said main frame, for rotatably driving said flexible disk inserted in said main frame, said motor having a rotation axis, said motor comprising a rotor rotatably disposed around the rotation axis and a stator combined with said rotor, said rotor having an external peripheral side surface on which an index detection magnet is mounted; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a circuit board, mounted on the frame back surface of said main frame, for mounting a control circuit for carrying out a driving control of said motor thereon, said circuit board comprising a main circuit board for mounting said control circuit thereon and for extending in a direction perpendicular to the rotation axis of said motor and a sub circuit board attached to said main circuit board at a position close to the external peripheral side surface of said rotor so as to extend in a direction in parallel with the rotation axis of said motor; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an index detection Hall element mounted to said sub circuit board, said index detection Hall element having a magnetic field detection surface which is disposed so as to oppose to the external peripheral side surface of said rotor. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A flexible disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said sub circuit board has a board main surface opposed to said rotor and a board back surface opposite to said board main surface, said sub circuit board having a penetration for penetrating between the board main surface and the board back surface, said index detection Hall element being inserted in said penetration so that the magnetic field detection surface is faced to the board main surface of said sub circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A flexible disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said main circuit board has an edge close to said rotor, said sub circuit board being attached to said main circuit board at the edge of said main circuit board. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A flexible disk drive as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the board back surface of said sub circuit board serves as a soldering surface, said sub circuit board and said main circuit board being soldered with each other at the soldering surface with the board back surface of said sub circuit board and the edge of said main circuit board in contact with each other, said index detection Hall element having terminals electrically connected to the soldering surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>6</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002208A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
