<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003692A1-20030102-D00015.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003692A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003692</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10164314</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020607</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-172761</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010607</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L029/30</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/322</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>473000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>617000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Semiconductor device and method of manufacturing the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Mikimasa</given-name>
<family-name>Suzuki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Toyohashi-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Shoji</given-name>
<family-name>Miura</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Aichi-ken</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Akira</given-name>
<family-name>Kuroyanagi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Okazaki-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Noriyuki</given-name>
<family-name>Iwamori</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Okazaki-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Takashi</given-name>
<family-name>Suzuki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Aichi-ken</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LAW OFFICES OF DAVID G. POSZ</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>2000 L STREET, N.W.</address-1>
<address-2>SUITE 200</address-2>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20036</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">In a semiconductor device such as MOSFET, a single crystal semiconductor substrate is provided. An epitaxitial layer is formed on the single crystal semiconductor substrate. A p-well regions are formed on the epitaxitial layer, respectively, and n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> source regions are formed on the p-well regions, respectively. A gate electrode is formed through a gate insulation film on a part of each p-well region and that of each n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> source region. The gate electrode is covered with an insulation film. On the insulation film, a source electrode is formed so that the n-channel MOSFET includes body diodes BD imbedded therein. A drain electrode is formed on the single crystal semiconductor substrate. A cluster-containing layer is implanted in the single crystal semiconductor substrate as a gettering layer so that the cluster-containing layer contains a cluster of nitrogen. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a semiconductor device and a method of manufacturing the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Conventional processes aiming at gettering effects include intrinsic gettering (hereinafter, referred to &ldquo;IG&rdquo;) which uses oxygen precipitate defects <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> of a semiconductor device, for example, an n-channel vertical MOSFET, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference>. The oxygen precipitate defects <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> are served as a gettering layer which can getter defects in an element formation region <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In the IG, in order to improve the gettering effects to make better the quality of gate film of the semiconductor device and the reliabilities of elements formed therein, it is necessary to increase the oxygen concentration in the semiconductor substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> This method, however, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference>, causes the resistance rate of the substrate to increase with the growth of the oxygen concentration of the substrate. This increase of the resistance rate makes increase the on-resistance of the vertical power semiconductor device, the substrate of which is served as a current path, causing the loss of the device to be increased. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is made on the background of the foregoing circumstances. Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provided a semiconductor device and a method of the same, semiconductor device which has an element formation region containing few defects and high performance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve such object, according to one aspect of the present invention, there is provided a semiconductor substrate on which an element is formed; and a cluster-containing layer implanted in the semiconductor substrate as a gettering layer, the cluster-containing layer containing a cluster of nitrogen. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In preferred embodiment of this one aspect, the semiconductor substrate has a single crystal semiconductor substrate member and an epitaxitial layer formed thereon, the cluster-containing layer being implanted in the epitaxitial layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In preferred embodiment of this one aspect, the cluster of nitrogen corresponds to doses of nitrogen ions, the doses of nitrogen ions are within the range substantially from 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve such object, according to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of manufacturing a semiconductor device comprising the steps of: preparing a semiconductor substrate with first and second surfaces; implanting nitrogen ions from one of the first and second surfaces of the semiconductor substrate therein; subjecting the semiconductor substrate to a thermal process so as to form a cluster-containing layer as a gettering layer in the semiconductor substrate at a predetermined depth direction thereof; and forming an element on/in the semiconductor substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In order to achieve such object, according to further aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of manufacturing a semiconductor device comprising the steps of: preparing a first semiconductor substrate; forming an insulating film on the first semiconductor substrate; implanting nitrogen ions from one surface of the insulating film into the first semiconductor substrate; subjecting the first semiconductor substrate to a thermal process so as to form a cluster-containing layer as a gettering layer in the first semiconductor substrate at a predetermined depth direction thereof; preparing a second semiconductor substrate; laminating the second semiconductor substrate through the insulating film on the first semiconductor substrate; and forming an element on/in the at least one of the first and second semiconductor substrates.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> Other objects and aspects of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of embodiments with reference to the accompanying drawings in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of an n-channel vertical MOSFET according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining another manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a view showing a result of a test representing a correlation between doses of nitrogen ions implanted into a substrate of a first sample of the MOSFET and a lifetime of the substrate; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a view showing the first sample of the MOSFET according to the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a view showing a concentration profile between nitrogen atoms and oxygen atoms in a substrate of a second sample according to the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a view showing the second sample of the MOSFET according to the first embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of a p-channel vertical MOSFET; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of an n-channel vertical MOSFET according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of another example of n-channel vertical MOSFET according to a modification of the second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> is a view showing a result of examination, that is, a correlation between dosages and life times of nitrogen ions implanted into a substrate of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the second embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> is a view showing a sample of the substrate according to the second embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> is a perspective view for explaining a manufacturing process of an n-channel vertical MOSFET according to a third embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference> is a perspective view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the third embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference> is a perspective view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the third embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference> is a perspective view for explaining a manufacturing process of an n-channel vertical MOSFET, which is compared with the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the third embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of an n-channel vertical MOSFET according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view for explaining a manufacturing process of the n-channel vertical MOSFET according to the fourth embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of an n-channel vertical MOSFET; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference> is a view for explaining a manufacturing process of a semiconductor device according to the fourth embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference> is a view for explaining a manufacturing process of a semiconductor device according to the fourth embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference> is a view for explaining a manufacturing process of a semiconductor device according to the fourth embodiment; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 30</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of a conventional n-channel vertical MOSFET; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 31</cross-reference> is a view showing a correlation between the resistance rate of the conventional n-channel vertical MOSFET and the oxygen concentration thereof.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> (First Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> A first embodiment substantially concretely representing the present invention will be described hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a vertical cross sectional view of an n-channel vertical MOSFET (hereinafter, sometimes referred simply to &ldquo;n-channel MOSFET&rdquo;) as an example of a semiconductor device according to the first embodiment. In the first embodiment, the n-channel MOSFET has a single crystal semiconductor substrate (wafer) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> made of Silicon (Si) and an epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, that is a drain region, is formed on a first surface (upper surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for example) of the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In addition, the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is formed by Czochralski (CZ) method so that the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is also called as &ldquo;CZ substrate&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> dopant doped therein so that the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is also called as &ldquo;n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>-type substrate&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The n-channel MOSFET includes p-well regions (p-base regions) <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> formed on a first surface portion of the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, respectively, and n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> source regions <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> formed on the p-well regions <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, respectively, first surface portion which is opposite to a second surface portion adjacent to the first surface of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> A gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> with a terminal shown as &ldquo;G&rdquo; is formed through a gate insulation film <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> on a part of each p-well region <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and that of each n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> source region <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is covered with an insulation film <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. On the insulation film <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, a source electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> whose terminal is shown as &ldquo;S&rdquo; is formed so that the n-channel MOSFET includes body diodes BD imbedded therein. A drain electrode <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> with a terminal shown as &ldquo;D&rdquo; is formed on a second surface (back surface in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> for example) of the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The n-channel MOSFET is provided with a cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen, which is implanted in the second surface side of the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a concentration T<highlight><subscript>P </subscript></highlight>whose half width T<highlight><subscript>P</subscript></highlight>/2 is approximately 10 &mgr;m in a depth direction of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and is locally arranged in the depth direction as a gettering layer so as to be close to the drain region <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> at a predetermined depth position of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> operates as a gettering layer. That is, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> permits defects to be removed, defects which exist in the gate insulation film <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> or the interface of the gate insulation film <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> with respect to the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, making it possible to improve the dielectric breakdown voltage of the gate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In addition, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> permits defects in the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to be removed, thereby reducing junction leak current in the p-well regions <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or the n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>source regions <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. This allows the manufacturing yield of the semiconductor device to be improved and the n-channel MOSFET (semiconductor device) with high reliability to be manufactured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Next, manufacturing method of the n-channel MOSFET according to the first embodiment will be described hereinafter with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> First, the single crystal semiconductor substrate (n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight>-type substrate) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is prepared and nitrogen ions (N ions) are implanted in the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> from the second surface thereof. The implanted nitrogen ions cause a crystal defect layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> to be formed in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> including the crystal defect layer <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is subjected to an annealing process (a thermal process) so that, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen (nitrogen atoms/nitrogen molecule) is formed as a gettering layer in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> at a predetermined depth position thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> After the gettering layer forming process, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the single crystal substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is subjected to an epitaxy process (epitaxitial growth process) so that the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which is the drain region is formed on the first surface of the single crystal substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, which is opposite to the second surface and corresponds to the upper surface of the substrate shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> After the epitaxitial layer forming step, elements (devices), for example, the gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, the source electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and so on, are formed on/in the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by using DMOS (Double-Diffused MOS) manufacturing technique, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> That is, the gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is formed through the gate insulation film <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> on the first surface (upper surface) of the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is subjected to a double-diffusion process with the gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> as a mask, causing the p-well regions <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the n<highlight><superscript>&plus;</superscript></highlight> source regions <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to be formed on the first surface portion of the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, thereby forming double body diodes BD within the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the gate electrode <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is coated with the insulating film <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and the source electrode <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is formed on the insulating film <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The drain electrode <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is formed on the second surface of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the n-channel MOSFET is disclosed as an example of the present invention, but the present invention is not limited to the above structure. That is, whichever an n-type single crystal semiconductor substrate and a p-type single crystal semiconductor substrate may be used to realize the present invention, and whichever an n-type epitaxitial layer and a p-type epitaxitial layer may be applied as the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In addition, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be formed on the first surface of the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, from which the nitrogen ions are implanted. That is, in the first embodiment, the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> may be formed on one of the first and second surfaces of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the elements may be formed on the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> showed the result of the test showing a correlation between doses of the nitrogen ions implanted into the single crystal semiconductor substrate (n-type CZ substrate) <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the lifetime thereof. The n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, was prepared as the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of a first sample of the n-channel MOSFET according to the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, the horizontal axis represented the nitrogen implantation doses (cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>) implanted in the n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the vertical axis represented the lifetime (sec) of the n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In addition, the lifetime data of a reference substrate in which no nitrogen ions are implanted was shown as &ldquo;ref-Si&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> represented that the lifetime was long with an increase of the implanted doses. In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> represented that, when the implanted doses were substantially over 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>, the lifetime decreased, and when the implanted doses were more increased, the decrease of the lifetime was stopped so that the lifetime was increased to be recovered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> This test result made clear that, in view of improving the recovery characteristic of the body diodes BD referred to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, that is, shortening the lifetime of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>), it was preferable to make large the implanted doses of the nitrogen ions over 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. Incidentally, the improvement of the recovery characteristic of the body diode BD will be explained in detail in a third embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> showed the result of the SIMS (Secondary Ion Mass Spectrometry) analysis which was applied to a second sample of the n-channel MOSFET according to the first embodiment. That is, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>was prepared as the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> of the second sample of the MOSFET. The epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>was formed on the n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>. In particular, the second sample was provided with a silicon oxide film (SiO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>) <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> formed in the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, which had approximately 0.03 &mgr;m in thickness in the depth direction of the substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The nitrogen ions with doses of 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>16 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>were implanted from the silicon oxide film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> in the n-type CZ substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>so that the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>was formed therein. After the implantation process, the second sample was subjected to an anneal process at 1170&deg; C. for 60 minutes. The ion implantation through the silicon oxide film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> could prevent the implanted nitrogen ions from being damaged by the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> After the annealing process, the SIMS analysis was applied to the second sample so that the result of the SIMS analysis was obtained, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the horizontal axis represented the depth D (&mgr;m) from an upper surface of the silicon oxide film <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, and the vertical axis represented the concentration (atoms/cc) of the implanted ions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>originally allowed oxide atoms to exist therein, which were no more than the detection limit value already determined on the basis of the SIMS analysis. In the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, however, the oxide atoms existed so that the profile of the concentration of the oxide atoms was substantially the same as that of the concentration of the nitrogen atoms. This meant that the oxide atoms were trapped in the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> As described above, according to the n-channel MOSFET of the first embodiment, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) containing a cluster of nitrogen enables to obtain the effects of removing contaminated defects in the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> (<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>) including an element formation region, making it possible to provide the n-channel MOSFET with high performance. That is, as described in the related art, using the conventional IG so as to increase the oxide concentration in the substrate causes the on-resistance to be increased. In the first embodiment, however, it is possible to improve the quality of gate film of the n-channel MOSFET and the reliability thereof without increasing the on-resistance of the n-channel MOSFET. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> (Second Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Next, a second embodiment of the present invention will be explained hereinafter with a focus on the different points of this embodiment from the first embodiment so that the expressions of the elements of the second embodiment which are the same as those of the first embodiment are omitted or simplified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> As compared with the first embodiment, the second embodiment discloses a semiconductor device, which has no epitaxitial layer, with a single crystal semiconductor substrate (wafer). The semiconductor device of the second embodiment is designed to make longer the lifetime of the single crystal semiconductor substrate so that the lifetime substantially equals to that of the epitaxitial layer on the basis of the effects of removing defects in the substrate by a cluster-containing layer containing a cluster of nitrogen, thereby improving yields of elements (devices) formed in the single crystal semiconductor substrate and high reliabilities thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> As related processes of aiming at the gettering effects, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>, the IG is known, which uses oxygen precipitate defects <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> in a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> of a semiconductor device. The oxygen precipitate defects <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are served as a gettering layer which can getter impurities in the substrate <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> The IG needs to add a special thermal process to the substrate for forming a denuded zone (DZ) which is a defect-free zone therein. In cases where the effects obtained by the IG are insufficient, the epitaxitial layer must be formed on the surface of the substrate. However, many processes must be required for forming the epitaxitial layer so that there is the possibility that using the epitaxitial wafer (Epi Wafer) which includes the epitaxitial layer causes the cost of manufacturing the semiconductor device to be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> Then, in this embodiment, the structure of the semiconductor device described hereinafter is used on the focus of the cluster-containing layer containing a cluster of nitrogen, which includes the gettering effects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows a vertical cross sectional view of a p-channel vertical MOSFET (p-channel MOSFET) as an example of a semiconductor device according to the second embodiment. The p-channel MOSFET has a single crystal semiconductor substrate (CZ substrate) <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> including n dopant doped therein so that the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is also called as &ldquo;n-type substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> In a first surface side (upper surface side) of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a p-source region <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, a p-drain region <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a gate insulating film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, a gate electrode <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, a source electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and a drain electrode <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are formed, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> Inside a second surface side (back surface side) of the single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, a cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen is implanted so as to be locally arranged in the depth direction as a gettering layer at a predetermined depth position of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> has effects of gettering defects which exist in the gate insulation film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> or the interface of the gate insulation film <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> with respect to the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, making it possible to improve the dielectric breakdown voltage of the gate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> permits defects in the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to be gettered, thereby reducing junction leak current in the source regions <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> or the drain regions <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This allows the manufacturing yield of the semiconductor device (p-channel MOSFET) to be improved and the semiconductor device with high reliability to be manufactured. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> Next, manufacturing method of the p-channel MOSFET according to the second embodiment will be described hereinafter with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> First, the single crystal semiconductor substrate (n single crystal semiconductor substrate) <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is prepared and nitrogen ions (N ions) are implanted in the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> from the second surface thereof, which corresponds to an upper side of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. At that time, the implanted doses of the nitrogen ions are within the range substantially from 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> The implanted nitrogen ions cause a crystal defect layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> to be formed in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> close to the second surface thereof. The substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> including the crystal defect layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is subjected to an annealing process so that, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen is formed as a gettering layer in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at a predetermined depth position thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> After the gettering layer forming process, elements, for example, the gate electrode <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, the source electrode <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and so on, are formed on/in the first surface (upper surface) side of the single crystal substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> by using a manufacturing process for usual semiconductor elements, thereby to obtain the semiconductor device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> In addition, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>, the p-channel vertical MOSFET is disclosed as an example of the present invention, but the present invention is not limited to the above structure. That is, either an n-type single crystal semiconductor substrate or a p-type single crystal semiconductor substrate may be used to realize the present invention. Moreover, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference>, the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> may be formed in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> at another predetermined depth position thereof, which is deeper than the element formation region in the second surface side, so that the elements may be formed on/in the second surface side of the substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, from which the ions are implanted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, in the second embodiment, the present invention is applied to the MOSFET, but the present invention is not limited to the application. That is, the present invention may be applied to a bipolar device, a diode, an IGBT (Insulated Gate Bipolar Transistor) or other similar devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> showed the result of the test showing a correlation between doses of the nitrogen ions implanted into the single crystal semiconductor substrate (CZ substrate) <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the lifetime thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the horizontal axis represented the nitrogen implantation doses (cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>) implanted in the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the vertical axis represented the lifetime (sec) of the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>. In addition, the lifetime data of a reference substrate in which no nitrogen ions were implanted was shown as &ldquo;ref-Si&rdquo;. Moreover, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference>, the data representing a correlation between doses of the nitrogen ions implanted into a CZ substrate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> on which an epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> was formed and the lifetime data of the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> was shown as a plot point &ldquo;&utrif;&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> represented that the longer the lifetime was, the more increasing the implanted doses were. In addition, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> represented that, when the implanted doses were substantially over 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>, the lifetime decreased. Then in cases where the implanted doses of the nitrogen ions were within the range from substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>, it was possible to make long the lifetime of the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, lifetime which was substantially close to that of the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> on which the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> was formed, which was shown as &ldquo;&utrif;&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> Therefore, setting, when implanting the nitrogen ions, the doses of the nitrogen ions within the range from substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>allowed the lifetime of the CZ substrate having no epitaxitial layer to be increased so that the lifetime thereof substantially equaled to that of the CZ substrate with the epitaxitial layer, making it possible to improve yields of elements (devices) formed in the CZ substrate (semiconductor substrate) and high reliabilities thereof. That is, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, the lifetime of the CZ substrate without the epitaxitial layer was more improved than the lifetime &ldquo;ref-Si&rdquo; of the reference substrate in which no nitrogen ions are implanted. Therefore, it was possible to provide a semiconductor substrate having a long lifetime even when not using the epitaxitial layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> As described above, as a problem of the gettering technique (IG), when using the epitaxitial layer, many processes must be required for forming the epitaxitial layer and the use of the epitaxitial wafer causes the cost of manufacturing the semiconductor device to be increased. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> However, in the second embodiment, implanting the nitrogen ions in the substrate having no epitaxitial layer permits the lifetime of the substrate to be increased. In particular, when the implanted doses of the nitrogen ions are within the range (preferable range) from substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>, it is possible to make long the lifetime of the CZ substrate having no epitaxitial layer so that the lifetime of the CZ substrate substantially equals to the same level of the CZ substrate with the epitaxitial layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> Incidentally, the doses of the nitrogen atoms according to the first embodiment, when executing the ion implanting process shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, may be set to those of the nitrogen atoms according to this embodiment, which are within the range from substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> (Third Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> Next, a third embodiment of the present invention will be explained hereinafter with a focus on the different points of this embodiment from the first embodiment so that the expressions of the elements of the third embodiment which are the same as those of the first embodiment are omitted or simplified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> This embodiment, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, discloses a DMOS device as an example of a semiconductor device. The DMOS device is provided with a single crystal semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> made of Silicon (Si) and a first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> formed thereon. The DMOS device also has a cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen formed in the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The DMOS device is further provided with a second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> formed on the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> Before making grow the second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> on the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> by implanting nitrogen ions in the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, an etching process is additionally applied to the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> so that the silicon of only approximately 300 &angst; (angstroms), referred to as &ldquo;t1&rdquo; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</cross-reference>, is etched away from the wafer surface of the epitaxitial layer (epi wafer) <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The etching process allows the second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> having few crystal defects to be realized without vanishing the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Hereinafter, the characteristics of the third embodiment will be explained in detail. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> A DMOS element (device) with the rated breakdown voltage of approximately 60&tilde;200 volts, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, is formed on the wafer having the n&plus;substrate on which the n epitaxitial layer (drift layer) <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with approximately 6&tilde;17 &mgr;m in layer thickness (film thickness) is formed. The reason of employing the structure is that the device breakdown voltage (BVdss) of the DMOS device is determined according to the film thickness of the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. When using the DMOS device for an inverter, the body diodes contained in the DMOS device are used as free wheeling diodes, because of reducing the cost of the inverter as compared with an inverter using private free wheeling diodes (external diodes). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> However, the body diode contained in the device has usually low recovery characteristic (reverse recovery characteristic), thereby causing a high recovery surge voltage and oscillation phenomenon (called as &ldquo;ringing phenomenon&rdquo;). These recovery surge voltage and the oscillation phenomenon cause the breakdown of the device and/or noises so that there is the possibility that it is hard to obtain the performance of the DMOS device required as a product. In order to prevent this problem, reducing the switching rate by, for example, adjusting the gate resistance may be employed for the DMOS device so as to control the surge voltage. In addition, in order to prevent this problem, adding a snubber circuit or the like may be employed for the DMOS so as to control the serge voltage and prevent the oscillation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> However, these prevention means cause the performance of the DMOS device to be decreased and the size thereof to be enlarged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in order to improve the recovery characteristic of the body diode, there are well-known methods which use an electron beam irradiation process, a He-ray irradiation process and a heavy metal diffusion process, respectively, so as to reduce the lifetime of the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>epitaxitial layer. However, because all of the methods make short the lifetime of the whole n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>epitaxitial layer, though it is possible to make faster the recovery characteristic, it is impossible to make soft it. That is, it is impossible to control the recovery serge of the body diode and prevent the oscillation thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> This reason is that, when the body diode is reversely recovered so that the di/dt of the reverse recovery current i equals to zero, that is, a voltage of power source of the device appears in the body diode, no carriers remain in an n region under a depletion layer in the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> Because, in the described methods for controlling the lifetime (the electron beam irradiation process, the He-ray irradiation process and the heavy metal diffusion process), the whole n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer has a short lifetime, it is hard to keep carriers in the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> region at the diode reverse recovery timing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the above problem, a cluster-containing layer containing a cluster of nitrogen, that is, the gettering layer described in the first and second embodiments is implanted in the DMOS device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer allows to be shortened the lifetime of a region in which the cluster-containing layer exits in the n<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight> epitaxitial layer, and other regions in which no cluster-containing layer exists have a normal lifetime. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> Therefore, when the body diode is subjected to the reverse recovery process, the carriers close to the base region <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> in the drift layer become extinct faster than other carriers far from the base region <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, making it possible to shorten the recovery time of the body diode. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> Moreover, the other carriers are accumulated in the other regions in which no cluster-containing layer exists, permitting the serge voltage and the oscillation at the recovery timing to be controlled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> In addition to the above characteristics, this embodiment has a feature for obtaining the epitaxitial layer having few crystal defects on the substrate on which the cluster-containing layer is formed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> Next, manufacturing processes of the MOSFET according to this embodiment will be explained hereinafter with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> First, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>, the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in which phosphorus of 3&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>(cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;3</superscript></highlight>) is doped is formed on the CZ substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in which arsenic is doped so that the thickness of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is substantially 6 &mgr;m in the depth direction of the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Nitrogen ions are implanted from an upper surface of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> thereinto and the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is subjected to a thermal process so that a cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is formed, as a gettering layer, at a predetermined depth position. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> The cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is capable of controlling the lifetime of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. In detail, the nitrogen ions with doses of substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>are implanted into the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> by an energy of approximately 90 keV, and the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is subjected to thermal process for approximately one hour at approximately 1170&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> These processes form the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> in the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> so that the concentration of the nitrogen atoms of the layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> has a concentration peak at a predetermined depth position at a distance of approximately 0.2&tilde;0.3 &mgr;m away from an upper surface (wafer surface) of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, thereby making short the lifetimes of holes (carriers) in the region in which the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> is arranged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> At the time of the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> being formed, defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> which are different from the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> and biasedly extracted from the nitrogen atoms exist to be scattered in the vicinity of the wafer surface of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. The defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> exist only within a range of approximately 300 &angst; (angstroms) from the wafer surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> When carrying out the vapor phase epitaxitial growth on the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> with the defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> on the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> left, the existence of the defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> causes defects <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> in the epitaxitial layer formed on the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> by the epitaxitial growth process. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> Then, in this embodiment, the etching process is applied to the upper side of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> before forming the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, thereby removing the defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. This makes it possible to make the surface portion of the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, before forming the second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>, into that having no defects, thereby making the second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> into a fine semiconductor layer having few crystal defects. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> In a case of explaining the manufacturing processes in detail, after forming the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> on the first epitaxitial (silicon) layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, the wafer (the substrate <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> with the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>) is cleaned, and the silicon surface portion of the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, which is within the range of approximately 300 &angst; (angstroms) from the wafer surface (upper surface) thereof, is etched to be removed from the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> The first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> from which the silicon surface portion including the defects <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> is removed is subjected to a smoothing process of H<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>at a temperature of 1150&deg; C. and, after the smoothing process, the epitaxitial growth process of H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;SiH<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>is applied to the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> at a temperature of 1150&deg; C. so that the second epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is formed on the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> As described above, removing a part of the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which is positioned within the range from the upper surface (wafer surface), from which the nitrogen ions are implanted, of the first epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to the predetermined depth position t<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> allows the epitaxitial layer <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> having few crystal defects to be obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> This removing process may be applied to the structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> according to the first embodiment and/or to the structure shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference> according to the second embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> That is, after implanting the nitrogen ions into the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, it may be possible to remove only a part of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, part which is positioned within the range from the upper surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the predetermined depth position t<highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and may include the defects different from the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, wherein the nitrogen ions are implanted from the upper surface of the substrate, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> Moreover, after implanting the nitrogen ions into the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, it may be possible to remove only a part of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, part which is positioned within the range from the back surface of the semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and may include the defects different from the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, wherein the nitrogen ions are implanted to the predetermined depth position t<highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> (Fourth Embodiment) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> Next, a fourth embodiment of the present invention will be explained hereinafter with a focus on the different points of this embodiment from the first embodiment so that the expressions of the elements of the fourth embodiment which are the same as those of the first embodiment are omitted or simplified. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> Manufacturing processes of the MOSFET according to this embodiment will be explained hereinafter with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>. In this embodiment, a semiconductor substrate comprises a first semiconductor substrate (silicon substrate) <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, an insulating film <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> formed thereon and a second semiconductor substrate (silicon substrate) <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> formed on the insulating film <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> First, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21, a</cross-reference> silicon oxide as the insulating film <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is formed on the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Next, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>, nitrogen ions are implanted from an upper surface of the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> thereinto. That is, the nitrogen ions with doses of substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>16 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>are implanted through the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> into the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by an energy of approximately 90 keV. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Further, the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> with the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> is subjected to anneal process for approximately one hour at approximately <highlight><bold>1150</bold></highlight>&deg; C., so that a cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> containing a cluster of nitrogen is formed, as a gettering layer, at a predetermined depth position from an upper surface of the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> After the forming process, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>, the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is bonded (laminated) through the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> on the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> While the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is laminated on the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>, an upper portion of the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> is polished in the range from an upper surface thereof to a predetermined length t<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in the depth direction, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</cross-reference>, thereby making the thickness of the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to a desired thickness in the depth direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Elements (devices) are formed on the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> which is made thin, that is, SOI (Silicon On Insulator) layer <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. In this case, the cluster-containing layer (gettering layer) <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is formed under the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> which is lower side of the SOI layer <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> As other method of manufacturing the semiconductor device with the structure according to this embodiment, in a state of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</cross-reference>, the wafer consisting of the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> including the cluster-containing layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> may be inverted so that, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, an upper portion of the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is polished in the range from an upper surface thereof to a predetermined length t<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the depth direction, thereby making the thickness of the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> to a desired thickness in the depth direction. The elements (devices) may be formed on the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> (SOI layer) which is made thin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> In this case, the cluster-containing layer (gettering layer) <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is implanted in a bottom region of the SOI layer <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, which gives no influence to the characteristics of the elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> As compared to the related art with respect to this embodiment, in the related art, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26, a</cross-reference> first silicon oxide <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is formed on a silicon substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> with its thickness of approximately 0.5&tilde;1 &mgr;m. Next, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27, a</cross-reference> second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is bonded (laminated) on the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. After the laminating process, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</cross-reference>, the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is polished so that its thickness in the depth direction is set to a desired thickness of approximately 0.5 &mgr;m&tilde;50 &mgr;m therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> In the related art, when forming an oxygen precipitate layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> in the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> by, for example, thermal process, the oxygen precipitate layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> is formed at a predetermined depth position of approximately 10&tilde;50 &mgr;m or over away from an upper surface (silicon surface) of the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> so that a denuded zone DZ which is a defect-free zone is formed between the silicon surface and the oxygen precipitate layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> Therefore, when polishing the upper portion of the second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> so as to set its thickness to a desired one, crystal defects appear in the second silicon substrate (SOI layer) <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> In order to avoid the appearance of the crystal defects in the SOI layer <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, when laminating a second silicon substrate <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> having no oxygen precipitate layer on the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> without thermal process, the wafer consisting of the first silicon substrate <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, the silicon oxide <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and the SOI layer <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> is formed without having the oxygen precipitate layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> (gettering layer, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 29</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> Because the gettering layer is not formed in the wafer, the crystal defects enter into the SOI layer due to thermal process, contamination of heavy metal and so on so that the SOI layer is affected to external disturbance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> On the contrary, in the embodiment shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</cross-reference> to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</cross-reference>, using the implantation of the nitrogen ions allows the gettering layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> to be precisely formed at a desired position, thereby making the element formation region of the SOI layer to denuded zone. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> As described above, the precisely formation of the gettering layer at the desired position permits the element formation region of the SOI layer to turn the denuded zone, making it possible to improve the performance of the semiconductor device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> In addition, the doses of the nitrogen atoms according to the fourth embodiment, when executing the ion implanting process shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</cross-reference>, may be set to those thereof according to this embodiment, which are within the range from substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to substantially 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> In each embodiment, the present invention is applied to the vertical semiconductor device, but the present invention is not limited to the application. The present invention may be applied to lateral semiconductor devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> In each embodiment, the present invention is applied to the single crystal semiconductor device, but the present invention is not limited to the application. The present invention may be applied to polycrystalline semiconductor devices. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> The above test results of the samples in the first and second embodiments are within the scope of the present invention. They are, of course, not to be considered in any way limitative of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> While there has been described what is at present considered to be the preferred embodiments and modifications of the present invention, it will be understood that various modifications which are not described yet may be made therein, and it is intended to cover in the appended claims all such modifications as fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device comprising: 
<claim-text>a semiconductor substrate on which an element is formed; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a cluster-containing layer implanted in the semiconductor substrate as a gettering layer, said cluster-containing layer containing a cluster of nitrogen. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semiconductor substrate has a single crystal semiconductor substrate member and an epitaxitial layer formed thereon, said cluster-containing layer being implanted in the epitaxitial layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semiconductor substrate has a substrate member, an insulating film formed thereon and a semiconductor layer formed on the insulating film. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semiconductor substrate comprises: 
<claim-text>a substrate member; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first epitaxitial layer formed on the substrate member, said cluster-containing layer being implanted in the first epitaxitial layer; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second epitaxitial layer formed on the first epitaxitial layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cluster-containing layer has a concentration T<highlight><subscript>P </subscript></highlight>whose half width T<highlight><subscript>P</subscript></highlight>/2 is approximately 10 &mgr;m in a depth direction of the semiconductor substrate and is locally arranged in the depth direction. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said cluster of nitrogen corresponds to doses of nitrogen ions, said doses of nitrogen ions being within the range substantially from 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>preparing a semiconductor substrate with first and second surfaces; </claim-text>
<claim-text>implanting nitrogen ions from one of the first and second surfaces of the semiconductor substrate therein; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subjecting the semiconductor substrate to a thermal process so as to form a cluster-containing layer as a gettering layer in the semiconductor substrate at a predetermined depth direction thereof; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an element on/in the semiconductor substrate. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semiconductor substrate has a substrate member and an epitaxitial layer formed thereon, and said element is formed on the epitaxitial layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said semiconductor substrate includes a substrate member with the first and second surfaces and a first epitaxitial layer formed on one of the first and second surfaces thereof, said cluster-containing layer being formed in the first epitaxitial layer, further comprising: 
<claim-text>forming a second epitaxitial layer on the first epitaxitial layer. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>removing a part of the semiconductor substrate from one of the first and second surfaces thereof, said nitrogen ions being implanted from the one of the first and second surfaces. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein doses of said implanted nitrogen ions are within the range substantially from 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>preparing a first semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an insulating film on the first semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>implanting nitrogen ions from one surface of the insulating film into the first semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>subjecting the first semiconductor substrate to a thermal process so as to form a cluster-containing layer as a gettering layer in the first semiconductor substrate at a predetermined depth direction thereof; </claim-text>
<claim-text>preparing a second semiconductor substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>bonding the second semiconductor substrate through the insulating film on the first semiconductor substrate; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>forming an element on/in the at least one of the first and second semiconductor substrates. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>polishing one surface of the at least one of the first and second semiconductor substrates, said element being formed on/in the one surface side thereof. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing a semiconductor device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein doses of said implanted nitrogen ions are within the range substantially from 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>14 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2 </superscript></highlight>to 1&times;10<highlight><superscript>15 </superscript></highlight>cm<highlight><superscript>&minus;2</superscript></highlight>.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>11,12</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00015">
<image id="EMI-D00015" file="US20030003692A1-20030102-D00015.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
