<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002372A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002372A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002372A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002372A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002372A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002372A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002372A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002372A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002372A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002372A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002372</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10179768</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020624</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-195518</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010627</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11C007/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>365</class>
<subclass>203000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Charging circuit and semiconductor memory device using the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Terufumi</given-name>
<family-name>Ishida</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Nara-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Madeline I. Johnston</name-1>
<name-2>Morrison &amp; Foerster LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>755 Page Mill Road</address-1>
<city>Palo Alto</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postalcode>94304-1018</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A charging circuit includes a charging driving circuit, a time constant circuit, a control circuit, a voltage detection circuit, and a delay and inversion circuit. The charging driving circuit starts a charging operation in accordance with a delay signal output from the delay and inversion circuit, and terminates the charging operation in accordance with a detection signal output from the voltage detection circuit. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a charging circuit and a semiconductor memory device using the charging circuit, and in particular, to a charging circuit for charging a load circuit to a prescribed voltage level, and a semiconductor memory device for charging a bit line using the charging circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> A semiconductor memory device includes a plurality of memory cells arranged in a matrix. Before reading information stored in one of the memory cells or writing information to one of the memory cells, a bit line connected to the memory cell needs to be charged. In the case of a nonvolatile semiconductor memory device, the charging operation is performed in order to raise the speed of reading the information from the memory cell. In the case of a volatile semiconductor memory device, the charging operation is performed in order to prevent inadvertent overwriting of the information stored in the memory cell when reading the information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows an exemplary charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> which is conventionally and generally used in a single bit semiconductor memory device. The charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> includes three N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to a power supply VCC via a resistor R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to ground VSS. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to a source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to a node <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> between the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to the power supply VCC. The gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to a gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, and the source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to a source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. The source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is also connected to an output node VPR, which is an output terminal of the charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight>. A drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is connected to the power supply VCC via a resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. A node <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> between the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is connected to a sense amplifier (not shown). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight>, a load circuit to be charged (not shown) is connected to the output node VPR. The node <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> connected to the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> conveys a change in the level of the charging current, which is output from the output node VPR, to the sense amplifier as a change in the voltage. An inverter, including the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the resistor R<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, detects the voltage level of the output node VPR from the gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Then, the inverter feeds back the voltage level of the output node VPR via the node <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, connected to the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, to the gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and to the gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Thus, the charging operation performed via the output node VPR and the operation of the sense amplifier are improved in speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows an exemplary charging circuit used for a semiconductor memory device including a pair of complementary bit lines (a bit line BIT and a bit line /BIT having a logic level inverted from the logic level of the bit line BIT). In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8, a</cross-reference> power supply VM is a power supply or an output terminal of an internal voltage drop circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The charging circuit <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> includes an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> between the power supply VM and the bit line BIT and an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> between the power supply VM and the bit line /BIT. The N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are load transistors. An N-type MOS transistor NEQ for equalizing the bit lines is provided between the bit lines BIT and /BIT (i.e., for charging the bit lines BIT and /BIT to an equal potential). In the case where a with stand voltage of the memory cell (not shown) connected to the bit lines BIT and /BIT is lower than the external supply voltage, the output terminal of the internal voltage drop circuit is used as the power supply VM. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Drains of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to the power supply VM. A source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is connected to the bit line BIT, and a source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is connected to the bit line /BIT. Gates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. A drain and a source of the N-type MOS transistor NEQ are respectively connected to the source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and the source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor NEQ is connected to the gates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The N-type MOS transistor NEQ is connected to the bit lines BIT and /BIT so as to equalize the bit lines BIT and /BIT. The gate of the N-type MOS transistor NEQ receives an equalizing signal EQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The equalizing signal EQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is also input to the gates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> While the equalizing signal EQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level, the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and NEQ are all in an ON state. The source and the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are conductive with each other, and the source and the drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are conductive with each other. Therefore, the voltage of the power supply VM is applied to the bit lines BIT and /BIT. Since the drain and the source of the N-type MOS transistor NEQ are also conductive with each other, the equalization operation is performed for charging the bit lines BIT and /BIT to an equal potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> As a result, while the equalizing signal EQ<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level, the voltage of the power supply VM is supplied to the memory connected to the bit lines BIT and /BIT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> As described above, the charging circuit <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> uses N-type MOS transistors. The threshold voltage drop function of the N-type MOS transistors is utilized to pre-charge the bit lines BIT and /BIT to &frac12; VCC. This provides the effect of reducing power consumption and noise while charging and discharging the bit lines BIT and /BIT. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A conventional single bit semiconductor memory device uses the charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> so as to charge the bit line utilizing a voltage drop corresponding to the threshold voltage Vth of the N-type MOS transistors. A semiconductor memory device integrally including an internal voltage drop circuit uses the charging circuit <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. The complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT connected to all the memory cells are charged, using the voltage of the output terminal VM of the internal voltage drop circuit as the power supply voltage of the N-type MOS transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The charging circuit <highlight><bold>700</bold></highlight> has the following problem. As the potential of the sources of the N-type MOS transistors increases during the charging operation, the difference in potential between the gate and the source of each N-type MOS transistor is reduced. This is accompanied by reduction in the driving capability of the N-type MOS transistors, which inevitably increases the charging time period. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The charging circuit <highlight><bold>800</bold></highlight> has the following problem. The load on the internal voltage drop circuit for supplying a voltage for charging is excessively high. Accordingly, an excessively large output capacity is required in order to obtain stable operation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the invention, a charging circuit for charging a prescribed load circuit to a prescribed potential includes a charging driving circuit connected to the load circuit for supplying a charging signal to the load circuit from an output end of the charging driving circuit; a time constant circuit for receiving the charging signal, changing a time constant of the charging signal and outputting a transition signal having a prescribed transition time period; a control circuit for outputting a control signal for setting a time constant of the time constant circuit in accordance with the prescribed load circuit; a voltage detection circuit for detecting that the transition signal output from the time constant circuit has reached the prescribed potential and outputting a detection signal; and a delay and inversion circuit for delaying, and inverting a logic level of, an externally input charging control signal, and outputting a delay signal. The charging driving circuit starts a charging operation in accordance with the delay signal output from the delay and inversion circuit, and terminates the charging operation in accordance with the detection signal output from the voltage detection circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the output end is grounded by the delay signal during a delay time period from the time when the charging control signal is input to the delay and inversion circuit until the time when the delay signal is output. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, an output section of the voltage detection circuit is a transfer gate which becomes conductive when the delay signal is placed into an active state. The transfer gate is connected to a gate of a P-type MOS transistor of the charging driving circuit. The gate of the P-type MOS transistor is connected to a pull-up circuit for placing the P-type MOS transistor into a non-conductive state when the delay signal is placed into an inactive state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the time constant circuit includes a plurality of P-type MOS transistors connected in series, and a plurality of N-type MOS transistors each having a source connected to a source of a respective P-type MOS transistor and a drain connected to a drain of the respective P-type MOS transistor. A gate of each of the plurality of P-type MOS transistors is connected to the ground. A well region of each gate is connected to a prescribed internal power supply of the charging circuit. Agate of each of the plurality of N-type MOS transistors receives a control signal output from the control circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, an ON resistance of each of the plurality of N-type MOS transistors is set to be smaller than an ON resistance of each of the plurality of P-type MOS transistors. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the invention, a semiconductor memory device includes the above-described charging circuit; a pair of complementary bit lines connected to a memory cell; and an equalizing circuit for equalizing the pair of complementary bit lines to an equal prescribed potential using an equalizing signal acting as a charging control signal. An output end of the charging driving circuit of the charging circuit is connected to the pair of complementary bit lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the semiconductor memory device includes at least one more pair of complementary bit lines, wherein the output end of the charging driving circuit of the charging circuit is connected to the pairs of complementary bit lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the equalizing circuit includes a pull-up circuit for charging the pair of complementary bit lines to a prescribed potential. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the equalizing circuit includes a pull-up circuit for charging the pair of complementary bit lines to a prescribed potential, and the delay and inversion circuit of the charging circuit provides a delay time period which is at least equal to a time period required for the pair of complementary bit lines, charged to the prescribed potential by the pull-up circuit, to be discharged via the output end of the charging driving circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In one embodiment of the invention, the delay and inversion circuit of the charging circuit provides a delay time period which is at least equal to a time period required for the pair of complementary bit lines, charged to the prescribed potential by the pull-up circuit, to be discharged via the output end of the charging driving circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Thus, the invention described herein makes possible the advantages of providing a charging circuit for performing a stable charging operation at high speed without deteriorating the driving characteristics of MOS transistors included therein, and a semiconductor memory device using the same. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> These and other advantages of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon reading and understanding the following detailed description with reference to the accompanying figures. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of a charging circuit according to an example of the present invention: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of a delay and inversion circuit included in the charging circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of a time constant circuit included in the charging circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a partial circuit configuration of a semiconductor memory device according to the present invention including the charging circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a timing diagram illustrating various signals used in the circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows a partial circuit configuration of another semiconductor memory device according to the present invention including the charging circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of a conventional charging circuit; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of another conventional charging circuit.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Hereinafter, the present invention will be described by way of illustrative examples with reference to the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a circuit configuration of a charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to an example of the present invention. The charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> includes a charging driving circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for supplying a charging current to a load circuit (not shown), a time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> for changing a time constant of a charging signal so as to determine a transition time period of the charging signal, a control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for generating a control signal for controlling the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (i.e., a voltage detection circuit) for detecting that a voltage which is output from the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has reached a prescribed potential, and a delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for delaying, and inverting a logic level of, a charging control signal input to the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> from an external device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> As described above, the charging driving circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> for outputting a charging current and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (pull-up circuit) for pulling up the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A source of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to a power supply VCC, and a drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to an output node VPR, connected the load circuit, for outputting a charging current. The load circuit is to be charged. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> directly drives the load circuit via the output node VPR. A gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is connected to a drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> via a node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A source of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is connected to the power supply VCC, and a gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is connected to an output end of the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Thus, a delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is used in a semiconductor memory device including complementary bit lines (a bit line BIT and a bit line /BIT having a logic level inverted from the logic level of the bit line BIT; not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). A pair of bit lines BIT and /BIT are provided for each memory cell of the memory device. The output node VPR is connected to the bit lines BIT and /BIT via an equalizing circuit (not shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The equalizing circuit equalizes the bit lines BIT and /BIT (i.e., charges the bit lines BIT and /BIT to an equal potential). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The output node VPR is connected to a drain of an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected to ground VSS. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected an output end of an inverter INV<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Thus, the gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> receives a signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> which is obtained by inverting the logic level of the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> by the inverter INV<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. The signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is obtained by delaying, and inverting the logic level of, an equalizing signal /EQ by using the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The equalizing signal /EQ is generated by an internal timing generation circuit (not shown) of the semiconductor memory device. While the equalizing signal /EQ is at a HIGH logic level, the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is also at the HIGH logic level. When receiving a HIGH logic level signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> at the gate thereof, the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is turned ON and thus the voltage level of the output node VPR is pulled down to the voltage level of the ground VSS. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> receives the equalizing signal /EQ and generates the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> based on the equalizing signal /EQ. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows an exemplary specific configuration of the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> includes inverters INV<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, INV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> in three stages, each having a CMOS structure. The inverter INV<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> includes a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The inverter INV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> includes a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> and an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The inverter INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> includes a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the first-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a gate region (or well region) having a length LP<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, which is sufficiently large to provide a sufficient delay time period with respect to a falling edge of a pulse of the equalizing signal /EQ. Similarly, the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the second-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a gate region having a length LN<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, which is sufficiently large to provide a sufficient delay time period with respect to a rising edge of a pulse of a signal <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> output from the first-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The third-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> shapes the waveform of a signal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> output from the second-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, such that the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is output from the third-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The N-type MOS transistor Nil of the first-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a gate region having a length LN<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> of the second-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> has a gate region having a length LP<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the third-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has a gate region having a length LP<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> of the third-stage inverter INV<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> has a gate region having a length LN<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The lengths LN<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, LP<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, LP<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, and LN<highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> are smaller than the lengths LP<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and LN<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> receives a HIGH logic level equalizing signal /EQ, and inverts the logic level of the HIGH logic level equalizing signal /EQ. As a result, after a prescribed delay time period, the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> outputs a LOW logic level delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The LOW logic level delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is input to the inverter INV<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), which then outputs a HIGH logic level signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The HIGH logic level signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> turns ON the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and thus pulls down the voltage level of the output node VPR to the voltage level of the ground VSS. Thus, the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> acts as a control signal for the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the output end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is connected to a gate of an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A drain of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to a node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, which is connected to an input end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and an output end of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A source of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the ground VSS. In such a configuration, when the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level, the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is turned ON and pulls down the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the voltage level of the ground VSS. Thus, the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> also acts as a control signal for the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to both drains of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is provided with a control signal CNTRL from a control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> for adjusting the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> As a result, when the equalizing signal /EQ input to the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level, the voltage level of the input end and the output end of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is pulled down to the voltage level of the ground VSS. Thus, the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, connected to the input end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and the output end of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, can be fixed to the voltage level of the ground VSS. Therefore, no wasteful current flows from the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, as it does when the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> is at an intermediate level. The operation of pulling down the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> to the voltage level of the ground VSS can be an initialization operation for starting a charging operation in the subsequent cycle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> An output end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, having the input end connected to the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, is connected to an input end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A signal <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is output from the output end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the input end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. An output end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to an input end <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> of a transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> includes an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Sources of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected to each other, and drains of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. An output end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is connected to the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, which is connected to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and the drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> is connected to the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is connected to the output end of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Thus, the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Therefore, when the equalizing signal /EQ is at a HIGH logic level, a LOW logic level delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> which is output from the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is input to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. Thus, the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is turned ON, and the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is pulled up to the voltage level of the power supply VCC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Owing to such a configuration, while the equalizing signal /EQ is at a HIGH logic level and the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is at a LOW logic level, the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is turned ON. Thus, the logic level of the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is raised to a HIGH logic level via the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned OFF. Therefore, no wasteful current flows from the output node VPR to the load circuit. A closed circuit including the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the output node VPR, the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> (output section of the voltage detection circuit), and the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> acts as the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> for supplying the voltage level of the output node VPR to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a function of a current detection circuit, as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Backgates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground VSS, and backgates of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are connected to the supply voltage VCC. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an exemplary specific configuration of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes a series circuit including transfer gates <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The transfer gate <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Sources of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. Drains of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. The transfer gate <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> receives a signal through the sources (input end) and outputs a signal through the drains (output end). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Similarly, the transfer gate <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> includes an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Sources of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. Drains of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. The transfer gate <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> receives a signal through the sources (input end) and outputs a signal through the drains (output end). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The transfer gate <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> includes an N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. Sources of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. Drains of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to each other. The transfer gate <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> receives a signal through the sources (input end) and outputs a signal through the drains (output end). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The output end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is connected to the input end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>, and the output end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> is connected to the input end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The input end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> acts an input (IN) end of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and the output end of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> acts as an output (OUT) end of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Backgates of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to a power supply <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and gates of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground VSS. Therefore, the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are always in an ON state (or active state). The power supply <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> may be connected to the power supply VCC (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). Alternatively, in a semiconductor memory device having an internal voltage drop circuit, the power supply <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> may be connected to an output end of the internal voltage drop circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> Backgates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are connected to the ground VSS. A gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is supplied with a control signal CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, a gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is supplied with a control signal CNTRL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and a gate of the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is supplied with a control signal CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The control signals CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, CNTRL<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are controlled to be ON or OFF by the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> operates as follows. When the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are all in an ON state, an ON resistance of the gate region of each transistor (channel resistance) acts as a resistance component. Similarly, when the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are all in an OFF state (or inactive state), a diffusion region provided as each of a source region and a drain region of each transistor acts as a capacitance component. Therefore, the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has a time constant, which is determined based on a resistance component in each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> and a capacitance component in each of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> acts as a time constant for the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The time constant can be adjusted by the ON/OFF control performed by the control signals CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> through CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, which are output from the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The reason for this is as follows. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> When at least one of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is in an ON state, the ON resistance of the N-type MOS transistor which is in the ON state shortcircuits the ON resistance of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, so as to reduce the time constant for the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The time constant for the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is reduced because the ON resistance of each of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is designed to be significantly smaller than the ON resistance of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is designed such that the time constant of the transfer gates <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, including the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, is matched to the time constant of the state transition time period of the bit lines BIT and /BIT connected to each memory cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> One bit line connected to a memory cell has, for example, a line resistance and a line capacitance of the material used for the line, a diffusion capacitance of the memory cell connected to the bit line, and an ON resistance and a capacitance component of a switching transistor for equalizing and charging the bit line. When, for example, there are 512 word lines, all the bit lines have a total resistance of about 4.6 k&OHgr; and a total capacitance of about 0.7 pF. The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is designed such that the time constant is substantially matched to the time constant of the bit lines having a total resistance of about 4.6 k&OHgr; and a total capacitance of about 0.7 pF. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> determines the driving time period of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and also determines the charging level provided by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> includes the three-stage transfer gates <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. By changing the number of stages of the transfer gates (number of transfer gates connected in series), the charging level can be changed. Even after the number of stages of the transfer gates is determined, the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be adjusted and thus the charging level provided by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be changed. The time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is adjusted by controlling the gates of the N-type MOS transistors connected in series to be ON or OFF using control signals output from the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. Such an adjustment in the time constant can be conducted without changing the number of stages of the transfer gates. In this manner, the charging level provided by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> can be adjusted in two stages while designing the charging circuit. This expands the freedom of design. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> In this example, the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> includes the transfer gates <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> connected in series as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Alternatively, a time constant circuit may include high resistance elements formed of polysilicon. Polysilicon has a high resistance and is used for the lines. A circuit having a time constant usually operates as follows. The time period in which the voltage level of the signal rises linearly is determined by a resistance component (R) of the time constant. The subsequent time period in which the voltage level of the signal increases non-linearly is determined by a capacitance component (C) of the time constant. A time constant is given by resistance component (R)&times;capacitance component (C). Even when the resistance component (R) increases, the time constant does not change if the capacitance component (C) decreases by the level of increase in the resistance component (R). The charging time period and the charging level of a load circuit to be charged are determined by the time constant of the load circuit. Therefore, as long as the time constant obtained by resistance component (R)&times;capacitance component (C) can be substantially matched to the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, any values of resistance component (R) and capacitance component (C) can be freely combined. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Therefore, when the high resistance elements are used for the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a desired time constant is obtained even when the capacitance component (C) of the high resistance elements is small. The time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> can be adjusted, for example, as follows. A high resistance element is divided into a plurality of parts by low resistance metal lines: and the high resistance element, the resistance value of which is divided, is combined with the metal lines. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows a partial circuit configuration of a semiconductor memory device <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> including the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> according to the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the output node VPR of the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is connected to a source of each of a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is connected to a bit line BIT, and a drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is connected to a bit line /BIT. The bit line /BIT has a logic level inverted from the logic level of the bit line BIT. A P-type MOS transistor PEQ is connected between the bit lines BIT and /BIT. In more detail, the drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is connected to a source of the P-type MOS transistor PEQ, and the drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> is connected to a drain of the P-type MOS transistor PEQ. The P-type MOS transistor PEQ is provided for equalizing the bit lines BIT and /BIT (i.e., for charging the bit lines BIT and /BIT to an equal potential). A gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, a gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>, and a gate of the P-type MOS transistor PEQ are connected together. Each of the gates receives an equalizing signal /EQ. A power supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is connected to an external power supply or an output end of an internal voltage drop circuit. The power supply <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> is also connected to backgates of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> The bit line BIT is connected to a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and the bit line /BIT is connected to a P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A source of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to an output end <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the internal voltage drop circuit, and a gate of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected the ground VSS. A drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is connected to the bit line BIT, and a drain of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is connected to the bit line /BIT. Since the gates of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are connected the ground VSS, the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are always in an ON state and thus constantly supply a current to the bit lines BIT and /BIT. Owing to such a structure, inadvertent overwriting of information stored in the memory cell connected to the bit lines BIT and /BIT is avoided while the information is being read from the memory. The P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are provided only for supplying a current for avoiding the inadvertent overwriting, and thus are designed so as to have a very small driving capability. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> The charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) operates as follows. For example, when the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is maximum, the control signals CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> through CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> output from the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> are all at a LOW logic level and the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are all in an OFF state. In this case, a charging operation performed by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) raises the voltages level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> from the voltage level of the ground VSS at a gradient corresponding to the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Such a rise is matched to a rise in the voltage level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT, connected to the output node VPR, caused by the charging operation performed by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Therefore, by the time when the bit lines BIT and /BIT are charged to a voltage level sufficient for a read or write operation, the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> has become HIGH, the logic levels of the outputs from the inverters INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> have been inverted, the HIGH logic level output from the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> has been input to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has been turned OFF, and thus the charging operation has been terminated. Therefore, the bit lines BIT and /BIT are charged to an optimum level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> In the case where the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is maximum, the charging time period to the load circuit is maximum. Therefore, the charging level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT is also maximum. This may change transistor characteristics due to dispersion during the production process of the semiconductor memory device, resulting in the load of the bit lines being substantially lighter (lower) than as designed. In this case, the bit lines may undesirably be overcharged. In order to avoid this, the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> controls at least one of the control signals CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> through CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to be at a HIGH logic level. Owing to such a control, the time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is maintained at a level lower than the level corresponding to the maximum charging level, and thus the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> inverts the logic level of the signal more rapidly. As a result, the operation time period of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is shortened, so that the bit lines BIT and /BIT are not overcharged. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> In order to restrict the charging level of the load circuit to be LOW, the control circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> may control at least one of the control signals CNTRL<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> through CNTRL<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to be at a HIGH logic level. As a result, again, the operation time period (charging time period) of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is shortened, and thus the charging level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT is lowered. As can be appreciated from the above, the charging level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT is adjustable by controlling the signals. Therefore, even after the semiconductor memory device is produced, the charging level can be adjusted in accordance with the characteristics of the semiconductor chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> The above-described manner of control is provided mainly for the purpose of preventing the charging level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT from exceeding the withstand voltage of the memory cell. A structure for setting the charging level relatively high is not adopted. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> The delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) is includes an odd number of inverters connected in series, each inverter having a CMOS structure as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. The delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> has the following function in a semiconductor memory device in the case where the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> are maintained at the voltage level which is supplied from the output end <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the internal voltage drop circuit via the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, having a small driving capability, and are charged by the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> provides a discharging time period which alleviates an inconvenience where the voltage level of the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT is raised by the charging operation performed by the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> to a level higher than the level before the charging operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Such a discharging time period is provided in the case where the bit lines are charged and equalized before a word line and a memory cell corresponding to the word line are selected in a semiconductor memory device. Namely, the discharging operation is provided by turning ON the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) and grounding the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT connected to the output node VPR and the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> during the time period by which the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> delays the output of the signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a timing diagram illustrating waveforms of various signals used in the circuits shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> When the equalizing signal /EQ (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) is at a HIGH logic level, the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is at a LOW logic level and the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level. The complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) maintain the voltage level which is supplied from the sources of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, which is supplied from the output end <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the internal voltage drop circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> The signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) at a HIGH logic level is input to the gates of the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>, and the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are in an ON state. Therefore, the output node VPR and the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are pulled down to the voltage level of the ground VSS. The delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> at a LOW logic level is input to the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is in an ON state, and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> an the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> are in an OFF state. Accordingly, the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> is at a HIGH logic level, and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is in an OFF state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> When the equalizing signal /EQ falls to a LOW logic level, the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) are placed into an ON state. Since the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are still in an ON state during the delay time period provided by the delay and inversion circuit <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT discharge, to the voltage level of the ground VSS, the voltage level maintained via the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> via the output node VPR and the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> After the delay time period, the delay signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> rises to a HIGH level. Then, the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> falls to a LOW level. Thus, the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> which receive the signal <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> via the gates thereof, and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> which receives the signal <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> via the gate thereof, are turned OFF. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the N-type MOS transistor N<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> of the transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are turned ON. The P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned ON. Thus, the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT are charged via the output node VPR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The charging current supplied by the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> flows to the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT and also to the feedback circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> including the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, via the output node VPR. The time constant of the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> which is set by the transfer gates <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, including the N-type MOS transistors N<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, N<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and N<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> and the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, is matched in advance to the time constant of each of the complementary bit lines BIT and/BIT. Thus, the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> rises with a distortion in the waveform equivalent to that of the voltages of the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT, which are connected to the memory cell via the output node VPR and an equalizing circuit EQ (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The equalizing circuit EQ is a part of the semiconductor memory device <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> excluding the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> When the voltage level of the node <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> keeps rising and exceeds the level of the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>), the signal <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> output from the inverter INV<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is inverted from a HIGH level to a LOW level, and the signal output from the inverter INV<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> becomes a HIGH level. This HIGH level signal is conveyed to the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> via the transfer gate <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. As a result, the node <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> goes from a LOW level to a HIGH level, and therefore, the gate of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> becomes a HIGH level and the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned OFF. As a consequence, the charging operation of the complementary bit lines BIT and /BIT is terminated via the output node VPR. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The termination of the charging operation is not related to the rising of the equalizing signal /EQ shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Therefore, the OFF state of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is controlled by detection of the charging level of the output node VPR. As a result, overcharging, due to the extension of the pulse width of the equalizing signal /EQ as a charging control signal, does not occur. Thus, the charging operation is entirely performed by the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and thus is performed at high speed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> When the equalizing signal /EQ rises to a HIGH level, the gate of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and PEQ (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>) becomes a HIGH level, and the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, P<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> and PEQ are turned OFF. Thus, the charging operation of the entire circuit shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is terminated. At this point, the voltage level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT is determined by the time constant which is set in the time constant circuit <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the driving capability of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. After the termination of the charging operation, the voltage level of the bit lines BIT and /BIT rises toward the voltage level of the output end <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the internal voltage drop circuit which is supplied to the source of each of the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). The reason is that the P-type MOS transistors P<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and P<highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> are always in an ON state. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> For charging a plurality of pairs of bit lines BIT and /BIT, the bit lines are connected to the output node VPR (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>) via equalizing circuits EQ. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows an exemplary circuit configuration in this case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, an output end of the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is connected to the output node VPR, which is connected to a plurality of equalizing circuits <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, . . . <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x. </italic></highlight>The equalizing circuit <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is connected to a pair of bit lines BIT<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> and /BIT<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. The equalizing circuit <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is connected to a pair of bit lines BIT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and /BIT<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. The equalizing circuit lx is connected to a pair of bit lines BITx and /BITx. Each pair of bit lines is connected to a respective memory cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> As described above, the equalizing circuits <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, . . . <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x </italic></highlight>each correspond to the equalizing circuit EQ shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, namely, the part of the semiconductor memory device shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> excluding the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>. The number of equalizing circuits connected to the charging circuit <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> is not limited and can be determined in consideration of, for example, the output current or other parameters representing the driving capability of the P-type MOS transistor P<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>). The charging operation in the equalizing circuits <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>,. . . <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>x </italic></highlight>can be performed in substantially the same manner as that described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</cross-reference>. Therefore, the present invention is sufficiently effective in charging a semiconductor memory device including a plurality of complementary bit lines as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> A charging circuit according to the present invention includes a charging driving circuit for supplying a charging signal to a load circuit from an output end of the charging circuit; a time constant circuit for receiving the charging signal, changing a time constant of the charging signal and outputting a transition signal having a prescribed transition time period; a control circuit for outputting a control signal for setting a time constant of the time constant circuit in accordance with the load circuit; a voltage detection circuit for detecting that the transition signal output from the time constant circuit has reached the prescribed potential and outputting a detection signal; and a delay and inversion circuit for delaying, and inverting a logic level of, an externally input charging control signal, and outputting a delay signal. The charging driving circuit starts a charging operation in accordance with the delay signal output from the delay and inversion circuit, and terminates the charging operation in accordance with the detection signal output from the voltage detection circuit. Owing to the above-described structure, the charging operation can be performed stably, at high speed, and without deteriorating the driving characteristics of MOS transistors included therein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> Various other modifications will be apparent to and can be readily made by those skilled in the art without departing from the scope and spirit of this invention. Accordingly, it is not intended that the scope of the claims appended hereto be limited to the description as set forth herein, but rather that the claims be broadly construed. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A charging circuit for charging a prescribed load circuit to a prescribed potential, the charging circuit comprising: 
<claim-text>a charging driving circuit connected to the load circuit for supplying a charging signal to the load circuit from an output end of the charging driving circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a time constant circuit for receiving the charging signal, changing a time constant of the charging signal and outputting a transition signal having a prescribed transition time period; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a control circuit for outputting a control signal for setting a time constant of the time constant circuit in accordance with the prescribed load circuit; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a voltage detection circuit for detecting that the transition signal output from the time constant circuit has reached the prescribed potential and outputting a detection signal; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a delay and inversion circuit for delaying, and inverting a logic level of, an externally input charging control signal, and outputting a delay signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the charging driving circuit starts a charging operation in accordance with the delay signal output from the delay and inversion circuit, and terminates the charging operation in accordance with the detection signal output from the voltage detection circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A charging circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the output end is grounded by the delay signal during a delay time period from the time when the charging control signal is input to the delay and inversion circuit until the time when the delay signal is output. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A charging circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>an output section of the voltage detection circuit is a transfer gate which becomes conductive when the delay signal is placed into an active state, </claim-text>
<claim-text>the transfer gate is connected to a gate of a P-type MOS transistor of the charging driving circuit, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>the gate of the P-type MOS transistor is connected to a pull-up circuit for placing the P-type MOS transistor into a non-conductive state when the delay signal is placed into an inactive state. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A charging circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the time constant circuit includes a plurality of P-type MOS transistors connected in series, and a plurality of N-type MOS transistors each having a source connected to a source of a respective P-type MOS transistor and a drain connected to a drain of the respective P-type MOS transistor, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate of each of the plurality of P-type MOS transistors is connected to ground, </claim-text>
<claim-text>a well region of each gate is connected to a prescribed internal power supply of the charging circuit, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a gate of each of the plurality of N-type MOS transistors receives a control signal output from the control circuit. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A charging circuit according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein an ON resistance of each of the plurality of N-type MOS transistors is set to be smaller than an ON resistance of each of the plurality of P-type MOS transistors. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a charging circuit according to claim <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of complementary bit lines connected to a memory cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an equalizing circuit for equalizing the pair of complementary bit lines to an equal prescribed potential using an equalizing signal acting as a charging control signal, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an output end of the charging driving circuit of the charging circuit is connected to the pair of complementary bit lines. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising at least one more pair of complementary bit lines, wherein the output end of the charging driving circuit of the charging circuit is connected to the pairs of complementary bit lines. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the equalizing circuit includes a pull-up circuit for charging the pair of complementary bit lines to a prescribed potential. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the equalizing circuit includes a pull-up circuit for charging the pair of complementary bit lines to a prescribed potential, and the delay and inversion circuit of the charging circuit provides a delay time period which is at least equal to a time period required for the pair of complementary bit lines, charged to the prescribed potential by the pull-up circuit, to be discharged via the output end of the charging driving circuit. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor memory device according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the delay and inversion circuit of the charging circuit provides a delay time period which is at least equal to a time period required for the pair of complementary bit lines, charged to the prescribed potential by the pull-up circuit, to be discharged via the output end of the charging driving circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002372A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002372A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002372A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002372A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002372A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
