<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002890A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002890A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002890A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002890A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002890A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002890A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002890A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002890A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002890</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10141254</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020508</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G03G015/08</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>399</class>
<subclass>258000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Mechanism for agitating the toner in the replenisher of an electrophotograpic machine</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60302163</doc-number>
<document-date>20010629</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Kenneth</given-name>
<middle-name>M.</middle-name>
<family-name>Patterson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Rochester</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Paul</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Thompson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Webster</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Laverne</given-name>
<middle-name>N.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lincoln</family-name>
<name-suffix>JR.</name-suffix>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Macedon</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>G.</middle-name>
<family-name>Blum</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Livonia</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>LAW OFFICES OF F. LINDSEY SCOTT</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite B</address-1>
<address-2>2329 Coit Road</address-2>
<city>Plano</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>75075</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A replenisher for facilitating flow of toner in an electrophotographic apparatus. The replenisher includes a sump for receiving the toner. An beater element having a plurality of blades is rotatably mounted within the sump wherein some of the blades impart a shear force and a normal force along the axis of rotation to the toner while others of the blades impart a shear force and a normal force towards or away from the axis of rotation to the toner as the beater is rotated through the toner. This effectively &ldquo;aerates&rdquo; the toner and keeps it mobile within the sump. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is entitled to and hereby claims the benefit of the filing date of U.S. provisional application No. 60/302,163 filed Jun. 29, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a mechanism for agitating the toner in the replenisher of an electrophotographic copier/printer machine and in one of its aspects relates to a replenisher for supplying toner in an electrophotographic machine wherein the replenisher has a specially designed &ldquo;beater&rdquo; element which effectively aerates the toner particles and keeps them in a fluid state so that they readily flow from the replenisher upon demand. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In a typical electrophotographic machine (e.g. copier, duplicator, printer, etc.), a continuous loop of photoconductor film is commonly used to transfer an image from an input section onto a receiving medium (e.g. a sheet of paper or the like). The film is charged and passed through an input section where an image (i.e. analog or digital) is projected onto the charged film. The film then moves through a developing section where toner (i.e. dry ink) is applied to the charged image before the image is transferred to the sheet of paper. The paper is subsequently passed through a fuser section where the toner is fixed to the paper by passing the paper between a pressure roller and a heated roller. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Before applying the toner to the charged image, many electrophotograpic machines mix the toner with a carrier to form a two-component developer. When using two-component developers, it is necessary to maintain a desired ratio of toner to carrier; this ratio being commonly known as &ldquo;toner concentration&rdquo; or &ldquo;TC&rdquo;. Typically, the TC may range from about 2% to about 14% by mass for general printing applications. However, as will be understood, the actual range of the TC may vary over different ranges depending on the densities and/or relative size of the particular toner and carrier particles being used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To maintain the proper TC in a particular machine, the toner typically flows from a source (e.g. a bottle or other container) into a mechanism known as a &ldquo;replenisher&rdquo; which, in turn, feeds the toner to the developer at a desired rate. Since the charge of toner dictates other process settings within the printing/copying machine, it is vital that the replenisher be capable of maintaining a consistent and controllable flow rate of toner to the developer throughout the printing operation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Unfortunately, however, it is sometimes difficult to maintain a constant flow rate of toner from the replenisher; especially when certain materials have to be added to the toner to alleviate other problems (i.e. &ldquo;toner rub-off&rdquo;) which may be encountered during operation. &ldquo;Toner rub-off&rdquo; is an image quality defect that is created when the friction between two sheets of paper causes some of the fused toner on a original sheet to &ldquo;rub-off&rdquo; onto second sheet as the second sheet moves across the original sheet. To alleviate rub-off, certain additives, such as waxes, are added to the toner before they are fed into the replenisher. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In doing this, problems arise in that typical additives which reduce rub-off often increase the cohesiveness between the toner particles to the extent that they sometimes tend to stick to one another. This, in turn, can cause &ldquo;bridging&rdquo; within the replenisher and/or the toner source (e.g. bottle) which feeds the replenisher. As will be understood, &ldquo;bridging&rdquo; is the phenomenon wherein abutting particles of toner adhere together to form a contiguous mass of toner which, in turn, blocks or inhibits the flow of toner particles past the &ldquo;bridge&rdquo;. Accordingly, bridging in the replenisher can prevent the necessary free flow of toner through the exit opening(s) in the replenisher thereby adversely affecting the TC needed for the successful operation of the developer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> To help in preventing bridging in the toner source and/or the replenisher, other additives, e.g. silica, powders, etc., are often added to the toner particles to reduce the unwanted cohesiveness therebetween. However, it has been found that in some cases where the cohesiveness between the toner particles has been reduced, the toner then flowed too well. This, in turn, unfortunately increases the packing density or &ldquo;volume fraction&rdquo; of the toner (i.e. volume of toner/volume of replenisher). If the volume fraction is increased beyond a set value, the toner becomes packed within the replenisher and often impedes the motion of the agitator element (e.g. oscillating basket, rotating wire or blade elements, etc.) which is provided in the replenisher to keep the toner particles in a fluid state. If the agitator becomes impeded, the ability of the replenisher to furnish fresh toner reliably is greatly compromised. In some known machines, stalling of the agitator mechanism is also likely to stall the associated feed apparatus, e.g. a feed auger, thereby halting all toner replenishment to the developer which, in turn, requires shut-down of the machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, those skilled in this art will readily appreciate the need for a replenisher, which has the capability to keep the toner in a state of flux as the toner is supplied from a source (e.g. toner bottle) into the developing station of an electrophotographic machine. This will allow the flow rate of the toner particles, hence the TC, to remain substantially constant throughout the operation of the machine thereby maintaining a high quality product throughout the printing operation. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides a replenisher for agitating particulate toner to facilitate flow of toner in an electrophotographic apparatus. Basically, the replenisher is comprised of a housing having a sump, which is adapted to receive and store the toner until needed. An agitator element is rotatably mounted within said sump and is adapted to impart both shear and normal forces to the toner as the agitator element is rotated through the toner. This effectively &ldquo;aerates&rdquo; the toner and keeps it mobile as it is fed to the developing station in the electrophotographic apparatus. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> More specifically, the agitator element of the present invention is a beater element having a hub, which is mounted on a shaft, which, in turn, is rotatably mounted in the housing of the replenisher and which extends through the sump. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A plurality of blades extend radially outwardly from the hub wherein all of the blades are designed to impart substantial shear force to the toner in said sump. Some of the blades are designed to impart a substantial normal force along the rotational axis of the beater element while others of the blades are designed to impart substantial normal force to the toner partially towards or away from the axis of rotation when the hub is rotated. The plurality of blades is aligned in first and second sets, each set being comprised of a pair of diametrically-opposed blades extending outwardly from the hub. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The first set(s) of blades are constructed to impart shear force and a normal force in the axial direction to the toner when rotated therethrough and the second set(s) of blades are constructed to impart shear force and a force normal to the rotation plane, towards or away from the axis of rotation, to said toner when rotated therethrough. The outer ends of all of the blades are twisted at a first angle (e.g. about 30&deg;) with respect to the radial plane of said beater element. However, only the outer ends of the second sets of blades are bent at a second angle (about 45&deg;) with respect to the respective radial axis of the blade with the ends of the blades in each set of the second sets of blades being bent outward from the radial axis in different directions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The replenisher also includes means for delivering an impact to the toner in the sump, which is basically the same as found in known replenishers of this type. This means is comprised of a cam, which is affixed onto one end of the shaft on which the beater element is mounted. An impact element comprised of a leaf spring having a weight thereon is mounted on the outside of said housing. The impact element is adapted to be engaged by the cam when said shaft is rotated to thereby push the impact element away from said housing and then release it so that the bias of the leaf spring will cause the weight to deliver an impact to said housing. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The actual construction operation, and apparent advantages of the present invention will be better understood by referring to the drawings, not necessarily to scale, in which like numerals identify like parts and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic view of an electrophotographic apparatus (e.g. copier/printer machine) in which the present invention can be incorporated; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a perspective view of the replenisher of the present invention useful for supplying toner to the developing station of the apparatus of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, rear view of the replenisher of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> showing the &ldquo;beater&rdquo; element of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross-sectional, side view of the replenisher of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is an enlarged, perspective view of a prior art beater element for a replenisher; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is an enlarged, perspective view of a prior art impact element which can be used in the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is an enlarged, perspective view of the beater element of the present invention removed from the replenisher.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> While the invention will be described in connection with its preferred embodiments, it will be understood that this invention is not limited thereto. On the contrary, the invention is intended to cover all alternatives, modifications, and equivalents which may be included within the spirit and scope of the invention, as defined by the appended claims. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Referring briefly to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> typical electrophotographic apparatus or machine <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> (e.g. copier, duplicator, printer) of the kind that has an endless photoconductor member <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> (e.g. photographic film) which moves through a closed loop past a charging station <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, an exposure or input station <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, a developing station <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a transfer station <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and an erase section <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A copy medium (e.g. a sheet S of paper) is fed from a supply (not shown) through transfer station <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> where the toner image on the film <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is transferred onto the paper S. The paper S is then fed between a fuser roller <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and a pressure roller <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in fuser section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> to fix the toner image on the paper S before the paper exits the machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> In an apparatus such as that illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, particles of a toner (e.g. a pigmented, thermoplastic, resinous material) is typically supplied from a source (e.g. a bottle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>, shown only in dotted lines in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; also see U.S. Pat. No. 5,995,783 for such a source) to developing station <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> through a replenisher <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> (FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>). An open end of bottle <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> is removably positioned onto the inlet <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> of the replenisher <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and toner is allowed to flow by gravity into the sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> where it is stored until needed. Unfortunately, however, it has been found that the rate at which the toner flows from the lower end of sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is often erratic and non-uniform. This is caused in part due to the nature and fine size of the toner particles which have a tendency to pack or adhere together to form bridge(s) in the sump which, in turn, impedes the free flow of toner therefrom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In the past, various approaches have been made to maintain free flow of the toner particles from the sump of the replenisher. These approaches have included the use of vibrators attached to the walls of the sump; rocking the sump, itself; various types of sifting devices; and agitator devices which are positioned within the sump and in contact with the toner. For example, one agitator device uses a basket-like structure which oscillates within the sump to aid in keeping the particles of toner in a loosened state; see U.S. Pat. No. 5,229,823. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Other agitator devices have included &ldquo;beater elements&rdquo; which rotate in contact with the toner in the sump to stir or &ldquo;beat&rdquo; the toner in an attempt to keep the toner particles from compacting. These beater elements have taken various forms, e.g. wire segments which extend from a hub which, in turn, is rotated by a drive shaft extending into the sump of the replenisher. Unfortunately, these wire segments are often unable to withstand the bending stresses and the shock forces typically imposed thereon during operation of the electrophotographic machine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Another type of known beater element is a shear force type agitator, such as the beater element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>. Element <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a pair of diametrically-opposed blades <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>, the ends of which are bent outwardly in opposed directions. While this type of beater element is sturdier that those having wire blades, the design of blades <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are such that they basically impart only a shear force to the toner as they rotate therethrough. Accordingly, blades <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>will loosen only the thin layer of toner with which they come into contact with little, if any, force being imparted normal to the blades. This results in substantially no toner being moved in the direction of rotation. Therefore, gravity must be relied as the primary force to move the loosen toner out of the sump of the replenisher. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the present invention, replenisher <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> is provided with a beater element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> which imparts both a shear force and a normal force to the toner in sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> as element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> rotates therein. This effectively &ldquo;aerates&rdquo; the toner and keeps it in a fluid state so that it can flow freely from replenisher <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> when needed. More specifically, beater element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is comprised of a hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> from which a plurality of blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> radiate outward therefrom. Preferably, element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is cast or machined as an integral component but it should be recognized that element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> could be made in parts and then assembled by welding or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> As best shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, preferably beater element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is formed with eight, radially-extending blades which are equally spaced around hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. First sets (i.e. pairs) of the blades, i.e. <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>are designed to impart shear force and a normal force along the axis of rotation to the toner upon rotation while second sets of the blades, i.e. <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are designed to impart a shear and a normal force towards and away from the axis of rotation to the toner as they pass therethrough. As used herein, a &ldquo;set&rdquo; of blades is comprised of two, diametrically-opposed blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which extend radially outward from hub <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> To impart the desired forces to the toner, the outer end of each of the plurality of the blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> of beater element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is twisted in relation to the radial plane P of the element <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> at an angle &agr; (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>). Then, only the outer ends of the second set of blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>are bent away from the radial axis x at an angle &bgr;. In bending the ends of blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b</italic></highlight>, one blade of a set of diametrically-opposed blades <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is bent away from axis x in one direction while the other blade of the set is bent away from axis x in the opposite direction (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). While both angles &agr; and &bgr; can vary in particular situation, preferably &agr; is equal to about 30&deg; while angle &bgr; is equal to about 45&deg;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Beater element is secured onto shaft <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> by a screw <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> or the like. Shaft <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> has a gear <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> at one end which is adapted to be driven by a motor (not shown). A cam <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is affixed about the other end of shaft <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and is adapted to engage impact element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> (see FIGS. <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> AND <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>). Impact element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is comprised of a leaf spring component <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> which has a weight <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> secured to its inside surface at one end and which is secured to the side of replenisher sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> by screws <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) or the like which extend through openings <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>). As shaft <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> rotates, the cam <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> engages the leaf spring <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to lift it away from the sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. When the leaf spring drops off the top of cam <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>, the bias of the spring forces the weight <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> into contact with the sump <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> to deliver an impact to the toner in the sump. The impact element <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and its operation are known and can be found in other replenishers of this type; see U.S. Pat. No. 5,229,823. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> By imparting both shear and normal forces to the toner, the beater is better capable of keeping the toner in a loosened state and alleviates the problem of bridging within the sump. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A replenisher for agitating particulate toner to facilitate flow of said toner in an electrophotographic apparatus; said replenisher comprising: 
<claim-text>a sump therein adapted to receive said toner; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>an agitator element rotatably mounted within said sump adapted to impart both shear and normal forces to said toner as said agitator element is rotated therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said agitator element comprises: 
<claim-text>a beater element comprising: 
<claim-text>a shaft rotatably mounted and extending through said sump; 
<claim-text>a hub mounted on said shaft for rotation therewith; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of blades extending radially outwardly from said hub wherein some of said plurality of blades impart a shear force and a force normal along the axis of rotation of said hub to said toner in said sump when said hub is rotated and wherein others of said plurality of blades impart a shear force and a normal force towards or away from said axis of rotation to said toner in said sump when said hub is rotated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said plurality of blades is comprised of first and second sets of blades, each of said sets comprising 
<claim-text>a pair of diametrically-opposed blades extending outwardly from said hub; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first set of blades constructed to impart said shear force and said force normal along the axis of rotation of said hub to said toner in said sump when rotated therethrough; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second set of blades constructed to said shear force and said normal force towards or away from said axis of rotation to said toner in said sump when rotated therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer end of each of said plurality of blades is twisted at a first angle with respect to the radial plane of said beater element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer end of each of said blades of said second set of blades is bent at a second angle with respect to the radial axis of said blade. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said outer ends of the blades in each set of the second sets of blades are bent outward from the radial axis in different directions from each other. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first angle is equal to about 30&deg; and said second angle is equal to about 45&deg;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The replenisher of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference> including: 
<claim-text>a cam affixed on one end of said shaft; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an impact element mounted on the outside of said sump and adapted to be engaged by said cam when said shaft is rotated to thereby lift said impact element away from said sump and then release said impact element whereby said impact element will deliver an impact to said sump. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A beater element for a replenisher in an electrophotographic apparatus, said beater element comprising: 
<claim-text>a hub adapted to be mounted on a shaft for rotation therewith; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of blades extending radially outwardly from said hub wherein some of said plurality of blades impart a shear force and a force normal along the axis of rotation of said hub to said toner in said sump when said hub is rotated and wherein others of said plurality of blades impart a shear force and a normal force towards or away from said axis of rotation to said toner in said sump when said hub is rotated. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The beater element of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said plurality of blades is comprised of first and second sets of blades, each of said sets comprising 
<claim-text>a pair of diametrically-opposed blades extending outwardly from said hub; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first set of blades constructed to impart said shear force and said force normal along the axis of rotation of said hub to said toner in said sump when rotated therethrough; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said second set of blades constructed to said shear force and said normal force towards or away from said axis of rotation to said toner in said sump when rotated therethrough. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The beater element of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer end of each of said plurality of blades is twisted at a first angle with respect to the radial plane of said beater element. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The beater element of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the outer end of each of said blades of said second set of blades is bent at a second angle with respect to the radial axis of said blade. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The beater element of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said first angle is equal to about 30&deg; and said second angle is equal to about 45&deg;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The beater element of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said outer ends of the blades in each set of the second sets of blades are bent outward from the radial axis in different directions from each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>3</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002890A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002890A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002890A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002890A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
