<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001046</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09898631</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010702</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B64C013/16</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>244</class>
<subclass>082000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Apparatus and method for flight control of an aircraft</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Billy</given-name>
<middle-name>R.</middle-name>
<family-name>Carpenter</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Springtown</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>James E. Bradley</name-1>
<name-2>BRACEWELL &amp; PATTERSON, LLP</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2900</address-1>
<address-2>711 Louisiana Street</address-2>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postalcode>77002-2781</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An apparatus and method for flight control of an aircraft provides a body with adjustable intake ports ducting air into an internal intake manifold. Adjusting the openings of the intake ports changes the amount of air flowing over the surfaces surrounding the intakes, changing the amount of lift created by those surfaces. The intake manifold feeds air to at least one engine, and an exhaust manifold communicates the exhaust of the engine to exhaust exit ports. The exhaust manifold contains a plurality of moveable components that direct exhaust within the exhaust manifold and to particular exhaust exit ports for producing various levels of force imbalance among the exit ports. A compressor powered by the engine provides air to bleed-air ports on the wings. Varying lift on the forward surfaces with the intake ports, vectored exhaust, and bleed air are used to control and stabilize the aircraft during flight, obviating the need for aerodynamic control surfaces </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention generally relates to aircraft and particularly relates to flight control of aircraft without external, aerodynamic control surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In a typical aircraft, moveable aerodynamic control surfaces are installed on wings or other portions of the aircraft that are exposed to the airflow during flight. These control surfaces are moveable relative to the aircraft and include, for example, ailerons, trim tabs, canards, and rudders. These surfaces use aerodynamic effects to cause moments in the yaw, pitch, and roll directions for controlling the orientation of the aircraft or for stabilizing the aircraft during flight. Moveable, external control surfaces are complicated, requiring many parts and adding to the weight of the aircraft. Another characteristic of external control surfaces which may be undesirable is that they create drag in operation. Also, the radar cross-section of an aircraft increases when the control surfaces are displaced from their nominal positions, reducing the stealth characteristics of the aircraft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Modern aircraft advances include vectored thrust and internal engines. Vectored thrust is used in vertical takeoff and landing (VTOL) or short-takeoff and vertical landing (STOVL) applications and for producing quicker maneuvers or allowing steeper angles of attack. Thrust vectoring is done externally, generally by using a rotating or articulating nozzle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In some military applications, engines are installed deep within the body of the aircraft. Though this tends to reduce the external heat signature and reduce the exposed surfaces that would increase the radar cross-section of the aircraft, it is more difficult to implement thrust vectoring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> An apparatus and method for flight control of an aircraft provides a body with adjustable intake ports ducting air into an internal intake manifold. Adjusting the openings of the intake ports changes the amount of air flowing over the surfaces surrounding the intakes, changing the amount of lift created by those surfaces. The intake manifold feeds air to at least one engine, and an exhaust manifold communicates the exhaust of the engine to exhaust exit ports. The exhaust manifold contains a plurality of moveable components that direct exhaust within the exhaust manifold and to particular exhaust exit ports for producing various levels of force imbalance among the exit ports. A compressor powered by the engine provides air to bleed-air ports on the wings for creating roll moments. Varying lift on the forward surfaces with the intake ports, vectored exhaust, and bleed air are used to control and stabilize the aircraft during flight, obviating the need for aerodynamic control surfaces. </paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The novel features believed to be characteristic of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. The invention itself however, as well as a preferred mode of use, further objects and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description of an illustrative embodiment when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view of an aircraft constructed in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of the aircraft in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the components in a second orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a top view of the aircraft in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the components in a third orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a rear view of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the components in a second orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the components in a third orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a sectional view of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> showing the components in a fourth orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a top view of a second embodiment of an aircraft constructed in accordance with the present invention, the aircraft being a VTOL or STOVL configuration. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a front view of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> is a sectional view of a second embodiment of the rear portion of the aircraft of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> has a diamond-shaped body and integrated wings with no external aerodynamic flight control surfaces. The right side of the figure shows the upper exterior of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, whereas the left side of the figure shows the upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> removed, exposing the inner portion of lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and the internal components. A cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is located in the front portion of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for containing a pilot. Alternatively, aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> may be an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV), in which the cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> may contain computers for controlling aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and payload, or the computers maybe located elsewhere in aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, obviating the need for cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Air intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> are positioned to either side of cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and on upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and on lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. For each surface, the number of intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on each side of cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> is equal, though the number of intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> may differ. Also, the number and size of intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> may differ for various aircraft configurations and sizes. Each intake port <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> has a sliding door (not shown), like those shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 8</cross-reference>, for modulating the amount of airflow entering intake port <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and passing into an intake manifold <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> located in the forward section of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. By modulating the amount of airflow entering intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, the remaining airflow over surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> is altered, changing the amount of drag and lift created by surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and causing pitch moments to develop. These pitch moments cause aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to move toward a nose-down or nose-up attitude. For example, restricting air entering the intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> causes more air to travel over lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, creating more lift on lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. This lift creates a pitch moment, tending to cause the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to move downward. Closing ports on one side of upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and the opposite side of the lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> produces a roll moment, the side of upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> with the closed ports tending to move upward, the opposite side of lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> tending to move downward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Intake manifold <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> provides intake air to one or more engines, which, in multiple engine configurations, may be spaced apart and equidistant from the longitudinal centerline. Air in intake manifold <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> divides and passes into two engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, the axes of engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> being oriented longitudinally and offset to either side of the longitudinal centerline of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The air first enters a compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, preferably oversized, which pressurizes the air using rotating, bladed fans (not shown), then passes into a combustion section <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. Fuel is added to the pressurized air, and the mixture is ignited to produce a rearward-directed exhaust of hot gases. These gases pass through bladed rotors (not shown) in a turbine section <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>, causing the rotors to rotate. The fans and the rotors are attached to a shaft (not shown) passing through engine. As the gases cause the rotors to rotate, the shaft rotates, causing the fans in compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to rotate for pressurizing the air entering engine. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> Air from each compressor <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> can also pass laterally into a bleed-air manifold <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> leading to bleed-air ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> on surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and into a crossover passage <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> connecting manifold <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. Two sets of two bleed-air ports are located on each surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, and each set is laterally located equidistant from and on opposite sides of the longitudinal centerline of aircraft. Because bleed-air ports are located away from the centerline, air passing out of bleed-airports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> creates roll moments, tending to cause aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to rotate about a longitudinal line. For example, air passing out of the bleed-air ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> on the right side of lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> creates a roll moment tending to cause the right side of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to move upward. Each port also has a sliding door, like those shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 8</cross-reference>, for covering the ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> and controlling the amount of bleed air passing through ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Adjustable vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> and wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> are located within an exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> for vectoring exhaust exiting from turbines <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The left side of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> show the forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, left and right trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and exhaust wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. Forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is between and immediately behind the exhaust exits of engines <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, whereas rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is located at the rear of the exhaust manifold directly behind vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. Vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> are bisected by a vertical plane passing through the central longitudinal axis of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Two sets of secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, one set being on each side of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, each comprise inner, middle and outer vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are located along the trailing edges of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, downstream of primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> pivot on vertical axes, whereas wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> pivot on a horizontal axes. Primary vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> and secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> have a symmetric, teardrop-shaped horizontal cross-section with a rounded end and a tip. Trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> have a curved, airfoil-shaped horizontal cross-section and also have a rounded end and a tip. Wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> have a shape as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 8</cross-reference>. The tips of vanes <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are pointed upstream (toward the engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>), whereas the tip of primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> points downstream. Manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> also has fixed vanes <highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight> which direct airflow and provide structural support for manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Though not shown, excess bleed air from bleed-air manifold <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> can be vented rearward along surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> over exhaust manifold to cool surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and further reduce the heat signature of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> depicts vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in their orientation for forward flight with both engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> operating properly. Tips of primary vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> are oriented to bring their tips into alignment, wherein the tips are as near as possible to each other and are along the vertical plane passing through the longitudinal centerline. This orientation allows much of the exhaust from engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> to pass directly to primary exit ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, causing a forward force on aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> being located to the rear of and on each side of rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. Primary ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> have an opening on each surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 8</cross-reference>. Secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> are rotated to divert some of the exhaust exiting engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> toward trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, and trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are rotated to redirect the exhaust out of trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> are located to each side of trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>, ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> comprising an opening on upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and an opening on lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, each opening having a door (not shown), like those for intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>, for closing each opening on each port <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Corresponding vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> on both sides of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> have the same orientation during normal forward flight. Because the exhaust exiting trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> is exiting at an angle relative to the longitudinal axis of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, the longitudinal vector component provides additional forward thrust, and the lateral component provides yaw stabilization of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. To cool the exhaust exiting ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, excess bleed air may also be vented around ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> to reduce the infrared signature of the exhaust. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> The orientation of vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> for left yaw is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> yaws when a moment is created by more exhaust being directed out of trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> on one side of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> than out of ports on the other side. To direct more exhaust out of trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> on the right side, as shown in the figure, secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> on the left side are rotated to restrict exhaust from passing forward of vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, causing more exhaust to pass into the center of manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The tips of all trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are rotated to the left to allow more exhaust to exit trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> at greater angles relative to the longitudinal axis. The tip of forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is rotated to the right side, causing more exhaust from the right engine to be diverted away from right primary exit port <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and toward right trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. Likewise, the tip of rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is rotated to the left, diverting more exhaust from the left engine to the right portion of manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and away from left trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The thrust imbalance between the trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight> causes the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to rotate to the left. To cause the nose to yaw to the right, the orientations of vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> are moved to positions that are the mirror of those of vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> in a left yaw orientation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> A serious situation occurs when one of engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> is not operating, causing an imbalance in the amount of exhaust in the two sides of the exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts the orientation of vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>,<highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> when thrust from only one engine is available. In this instance, only the right engine is operating, and thrust must be provided throughout exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> to prevent aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from uncontrollably yawing to the left. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> To prevent exhaust of the right engine from passing forward through left engine, the tip of forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is rotated to the left, and the inner left secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is rotated so that its tip is near the tip of forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The tip of forward primary vane <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> is rotated to the left for a much greater angle than is used during yaw maneuvers. The middle secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is rotated to position its tip near the rounded, downstream end of inner secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, and outer secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is rotated to position its edge near the rounded, downstream end of the middle secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. Vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> act as a block, preventing exhaust from passing out of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> and forward through left engine. The tip of rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> is also rotated for a much greater angle than in yaw maneuvers, but to the right. Much of the exhaust moving toward the right primary exit port <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> is diverted by rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> toward the left side of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The inner, right-hand secondary vane <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> is positioned to divert exhaust from the right side of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, working together with rear primary vane <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> for this purpose. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 through 8</cross-reference> show details of one of the movable exhaust wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> located at the primary exit ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 3</cross-reference>. Exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> has an upper surface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and a lower surface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, each being concave in longitudinal cross-section, convex in lateral cross-section, and converging to an edge at the forward end of exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The rear surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is in sliding contact with the inner surface <highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight> of the rear outer wall of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> rotates about a horizontal axis <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> for moving the tip of each exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> up or down to control the amount of exhaust directed through an upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and a lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> of each primary exit port <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Each opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> has a sliding door <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> for covering opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> when exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is moved to a position that seals one of the openings <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, though only one opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> can be sealed at a time. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</cross-reference> show exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in the forward flight position and doors <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> in their retracted positions. Exhaust exits both openings <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, providing forward thrust and vertical thrust vector components, the vertical thrust component assisting in pitch control and stability of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> To cause the maximum downward pitch moment (for quickly rotating the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> downward), the tip of exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is rotated upward, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. Upper surface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> near the leading end contacts a protrusion <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> on the upper inner surface of primary exit port <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to seal upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, preventing exhaust from exiting upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>. Door <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> for upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is closed. The intersection of lower surface <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and rear surface <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> aligns with the rear portion of lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, causing all exhaust to be directed to lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, door <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> being completely retracted. The imbalance of force due to exhaust passing through lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> without an opposing force through upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> causes a pitch moment, tending to cause the rear of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to move upward. This positioning of exhaust wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> may also be used in a VTOL aircraft to provide some forward thrust, while also assisting in upward thrust. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> in an upward-pitch orientation for causing the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to pitch upward. Wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is rotated to position the leading end near a protrusion <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight> on the lower inner surface of primary exit port <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, diverting more exhaust toward upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> than in forward flight (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). This causes an imbalance in thrust between openings <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, causing a moment tending to rotate the rear of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> downward, pitching the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> upward. Exhaust wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> can be rotated to seal the lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>, as described above for upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>. Upper surface <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> of exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> is in contact with protrusion <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>, providing maximum force to pitch the nose upward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Referring to the <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 8</cross-reference>, in operation, a pilot or computer controls the flight of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> from cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. Air for engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> flows into intake manifold <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> through the open doors on intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. In level flight, the doors for the intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on each side of the cockpit <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> will be open the same amount, though the doors on the upper surface <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> may be open a different amount than those on the lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The intake doors may be fully open or may be partially closed. Air travels from intake manifold <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> into compressor sections <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> of engine <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, where the air is pressurized. A portion of the air is ducted to bleed-air ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> on the upper and lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of wings. Bleed air may be released during normal, level flight to endure roll stability of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Thrust is produced when exhaust passes rearward from the turbine sections <highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight> of engines <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, into exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>, and exits aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Exhaust exits out of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> through primary exit ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>, the amount of exhaust being equal on both sides of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> for straight and level flight. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> To perform a roll maneuver in which the right wing move downward, the doors of intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> on the upper left and lower right portions of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> are closed, producing greater lift on the surfaces <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> surrounding these intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. Additionally, bleed air is released from the upper right and lower left bleed-air ports <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The combination of the increased lift and bleed air cause aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to roll, the right wing moving downward. Only one of the forces are needed to roll aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, but using all of the available force sources causes a higher roll rate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> To yaw aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, primary vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> rotate in opposite directions to divert exhaust from on side of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight> to the other side and from one primary exhaust exit <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> to the other exit <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. Secondary vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> rotate to positions which prevent exhaust from passing forward of vanes <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> on the side where less thrust is desired. Trailing edge vanes <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> also rotate to change the direction that trust moves out of trailing edge ports <highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The combination of the orientation of vanes <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> causes a larger amount of exhaust to exit on one side of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>, causing aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to rotate about a vertical axis, the nose moving to the side opposite the larger thrust. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Pitch is induced through changes in lift at intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and through changes in the orientation of exhaust wedge <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> at primary exit ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. As described above for causing roll, the doors on intake ports <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> can be closed to produce more lift on the surrounding surface. When the intake doors on either the upper or lower surface <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> are closed, a lift force is created on that surface, causing the nose to move in the direction of that surface. Also, exhaust wedges <highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight> move to direct more or less flow out of upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> or lower opening <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> at the primary exit ports <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. For example, as more exhaust is passed out of upper opening <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, the nose of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> pitches upward. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An optional embodiment for the internal ducting of exhaust is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</cross-reference>. A vertical takeoff and landing (VTOL) aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> is shown in the figures. Aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> has two engines <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> which feed exhaust into an exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>. Exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight> has moveable, internal vanes like those shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 3</cross-reference> and four exhaust ports <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> in the lower surface <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight> of aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. Ports <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> direct exhaust downward to lift the rear portion of aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, ports <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> having sliding doors (not shown) for closing ports <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>. A gear-driven, ducted lift fan <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is located in the forward portion of aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> for providing additional upward thrust. A gear box <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> located forward of engines <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> transfers torque from engines <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight> to lift fan <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. The air for lift fan <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is not in communication with intake manifold <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight>; the air is drawn from above aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> through an opening <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> in upper surface <highlight><bold>89</bold></highlight>, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>. The air passes through lift fan <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> and exits aircraft <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> through an opening <highlight><bold>91</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) in lower surface <highlight><bold>79</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> An alternate embodiment of a primary exit port <highlight><bold>93</bold></highlight> is depicted in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. A center exhaust port <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> is located in the rear surface <highlight><bold>97</bold></highlight> and near the vertical center of the aircraft. An upper opening <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight> and a lower opening <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> are positioned adjacent to center exhaust port <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>, each opening <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> having a sliding door <highlight><bold>103</bold></highlight> near the outer surface of aircraft <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. Between center exhaust port <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and each opening <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> is a moveable vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, each rotating on a horizontal axis <highlight><bold>109</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>111</bold></highlight>. Vanes <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> rotate between inner and outer positions, the leading ends of vanes <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> being in contact when vanes <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> are in their inner positions. Vanes <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> are shown in the figure in their inner position, diverting exhaust to openings <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> and preventing exhaust from exiting through center exhaust port <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight>. When upper vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is in the inner position, upper vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> diverts exhaust upward toward upper opening <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>. When upper vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is in the outer position, exhaust passes to the center exhaust port <highlight><bold>95</bold></highlight> and is prevented from passing into upper opening <highlight><bold>99</bold></highlight>, the inner end of which is covered by upper vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> as the leading end of vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> contacts an upper, inner surface <highlight><bold>113</bold></highlight> of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Lower vane <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> operates in the same manner as upper vane <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight>, but lower vane <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> does not rotate to a position in which the tip of vane <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> contacts the lower, inner surface <highlight><bold>115</bold></highlight> of exhaust manifold <highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. Instead, lower opening <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight> always remains at least partially open, allowing exhaust to pass through lower opening <highlight><bold>101</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The present invention allows an aircraft to be controlled in flight without the use of external aerodynamic control surfaces. The many advantages include reduced complexity and weight, reduced radar cross-section, reduced drag, and higher maneuver rates. Control of the aircraft when an engine is out is greatly improved by a means for balancing thrust between the left and right sides of the aircraft. Also, the various embodiments provide for VTOL capability with little or no changes to aircraft. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been shown in only a few of its forms, it is not thus limited but is susceptible to various changes and modifications without departing from the spirit thereof. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An aircraft, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an engine within the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an exhaust manifold within the body and in communication with exhaust produced by the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right exit ports spaced laterally from a longitudinal axis of the body and in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>moveable components within the exhaust manifold for varying the amount of exhaust passing out of the left and right exit ports relative to each other for changing an orientation of the aircraft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the moveable components comprise at least one primary vane located near the longitudinal axis and being pivotally mounted for directing exhaust selectively toward the left exit ports and toward the right exit ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>the moveable components comprise left and right vanes located near the left and right exit ports, respectively, the left and right vanes being pivotal to change the direction of the exhaust passing out of the left and right exit ports, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one primary vane located near the longitudinal axis and being pivotally mounted for directing exhaust selectively toward the left exit ports and toward the right exit ports; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right sets of secondary vanes located inboard of the left and right vanes, respectively, the left secondary vanes movable to divert varying amounts of exhaust toward the left vanes, the right secondary vanes movable to divert varying amounts of exhaust toward the right vanes. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>at least one primary exit port; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a primary vane located upstream of the primary exit port and pivotal in left and right directions to vary the direction of the exhaust passing out of the primary exit port. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>upper and lower rear exit ports in communication with the exhaust manifold; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable member located near the upper and lower rear exit ports, the moveable member varying the amount exhaust flowing through the upper and lower rear exit ports relative to each other to cause a nose of the aircraft to move up or down. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a compressor for compressing air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right bleed-air ports spaced laterally from the longitudinal axis of the body and located on at least one outer surface of the body, the bleed-air ports being in communication with the compressor for selectively discharging compressed air through the bleed-air ports to control orientation of the aircraft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a closure member over each of the bleed-air ports for selectively opening and closing the bleed-air ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a crossover passage connecting the left and right bleed-air ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>exhaust ports on a lower surface of the aircraft and in communication with the exhaust manifold for directing exhaust from the engine in a generally-downward direction to cause the aircraft to move upward. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a closure member over each of the left and right exit ports for selectively opening and closing the left and right exit ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>intake ports located on a forward surface of the aircraft for directing air to the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>intake-port doors located near the intake ports, the intake-port doors moving from an open position, in which the intake ports are open, to a closed position, in which the intake ports are closed; and wherein 
<claim-text>moving the intake-port doors between the open and closed positions causes a change in an airflow over the forward surface, the change in airflow changing an amount of lift created by the forward surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. An aircraft, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an engine within the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a exhaust manifold within the body and in communication with exhaust produced by the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>upper and lower exit ports spaced laterally to the left and to the right from a longitudinal axis of the body and in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right vanes located near the left and right exit ports, respectively, the left and right vanes being pivotal to change the direction of the exhaust passing out of the left and right exit ports, respectively. </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one primary vane within the exhaust manifold, the primary vane being pivotally mounted for directing exhaust selectively toward the left exit ports and toward the right exit ports, the primary vane being located near the longitudinal axis; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right sets of secondary vanes located inboard of the left and right vanes, respectively, the left secondary vanes movable to divert varying amounts of exhaust toward the left vanes, the right secondary vanes movable to divert varying amounts of exhaust toward the right vanes; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a moveable member located near the upper and lower rear exit ports, the moveable member varying the amount of exhaust flowing through the upper and lower rear exit ports relative to each other to cause a nose of the aircraft to move up or down. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a compressor powered by the engine for compressing air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right bleed-air ports spaced laterally from the longitudinal axis of the body and located on at least one outer surface of the body, the bleed-air ports being in communication with the compressor; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a crossover passage connecting the left and right bleed-air ports; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a bleed-air blocking member located at each of the bleed-air ports; and wherein 
<claim-text>compressed air from the compressor is selectively released from the bleed-air ports by opening and closing the bleed-air ports for causing the aircraft to roll to the left or to the right. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a closure member over each of the left and right exit ports for selectively opening and closing the left and right exit ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>intake ports located on a forward surface of the aircraft for directing air to the engine; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>intake-port doors located near the intake ports, the intake-port doors sliding from an open position, in which the intake ports are open, to a closed position, in which the intake ports are closed; and wherein 
<claim-text>moving the intake-port doors between the open and closed positions causes a change in an airflow over the forward surface, the change in airflow changing an amount of lift created by the forward surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. An aircraft, comprising: 
<claim-text>a body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an engine within the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an intake manifold within the body and in communication with intake ports on a forward surface of the body for directing air to the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>intake-port doors located near the intake ports, the intake-port doors moving from an open position, in which the intake ports are open, to a closed position, in which the intake ports are closed; and wherein 
<claim-text>moving the intake-port doors between the open and closed positions causes a change in an amount of airflow over the forward surface, the change in airflow changing an amount of lift created by the forward surface. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an exhaust manifold within the body and in communication with exhaust produced by the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>upper and lower rear exit ports in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right exit ports spaced laterally from a longitudinal axis of the body and in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>moveable members located near the upper and lower rear exit ports and the left and right exit ports, the moveable members varying the amount of exhaust flowing through the upper and lower rear exit ports and the left and right exit ports relative to each other to directionally control the aircraft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>a compressor for compressing air; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right bleed-air ports spaced laterally from a longitudinal axis of the body and located on at least one outer surface of the body, the bleed-air ports being in communication with the compressor for selectively discharging compressed air through the bleed-air ports to control flight direction. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an exhaust manifold within the body and in communication with exhaust produced by the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right exit ports spaced laterally from a longitudinal axis of the body and in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a closure member over each of the left and right exit ports for selectively opening and closing the left and right exit ports. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The aircraft of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>an exhaust manifold within the body and in communication with exhaust produced by the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>left and right exit ports spaced laterally from a longitudinal axis of the body and in communication with the exhaust manifold for discharging a portion of the exhaust of the engine; </claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one primary vane located near the longitudinal axis and being pivotally mounted for directing exhaust selectively toward the left exit ports and toward the right exit ports; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>moveable members located near the left and right exit ports, the moveable members varying the amount of exhaust flowing through the left and right exit ports relative to each other to directionally control the aircraft. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method of controlling the flight of an aircraft, the method comprising: 
<claim-text>(a) providing an aircraft having a body and an exhaust manifold within the body; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) passing exhaust from at least one engine into the exhaust manifold; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) discharging the exhaust from the exhaust manifold out of a plurality of exhaust ports; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) selectively moving components within the exhaust manifold to vary the exhaust flowing out of the exhaust ports relative to each other to change a direction of flight. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (d) comprises selectively flowing more exhaust out of the exhaust ports on one side of a longitudinal axis than on the other side. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein: 
<claim-text>step (d) comprises selectively flowing a different amount of exhaust out of exhaust ports on an upper surface than out of exhaust ports on a lower side of the body. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>compressing air and releasing the compressed air through bleed-air ports on at least one surface of the aircraft to cause the aircraft to roll to the left or right. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising: 
<claim-text>delivering intake air to the engine through a plurality of intake ports; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>altering the air flow over at least one exterior surface of the body by varying an amount of airflow into the intake ports relative to each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001046A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001046A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001046A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001046A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001046A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
