<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002218A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002218A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002218</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09973295</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20011009</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-180573</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010614</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G11B005/60</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>235600</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>235800</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>236000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>236100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>360</class>
<subclass>236300</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Negetive pressure type head slider and disk drive employing same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ryosuke</given-name>
<family-name>Koishi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kawasaki</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>FUJITSU LIMITED</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Patrick G. Burns, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>GREEN, BURNS &amp; CRAIN, LTD.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 2500</address-1>
<address-2>300 South Wacker Dr.</address-2>
<city>Chicago</city>
<state>IL</state>
<postalcode>60606</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A head slider having a disk opposing surface, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end. The head slider includes a front rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air inlet end, the front rail having an air bearing surface and a step surface lower in level than the air bearing surface; a transducer formed in the vicinity of the air outlet end; and a first groove for expanding air once compressed by the front rail to generate a negative pressure. The head slider further includes a second groove formed on the step surface near the air inlet end except opposite side portions of the step surface. The step surface reaches the air inlet end at the opposite side portions. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to a negative pressure type magnetic head slider, and more particularly to a negative pressure type magnetic head slider for a load/unload type magnetic disk drive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In a recent magnetic disk drive, the flying height of a head slider from the surface of a magnetic disk is reduced more and more to increase a recording density. Further, a large acceleration is applied in an access direction to obtain a high access speed. It is accordingly desired to provide a head slider excellent in flying stability. Further, in association with size reduction of the disk drive and simplification of a mechanism in the disk drive, a rotary positioner is widely used. It is accordingly desired to provide a head slider in which variations in the flying height due to changes in yaw angle are suppressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To reduce the flying height of the head slider, the surface roughness of the surface of the magnetic disk must be reduced. In a contact start and stop (CSS) type magnetic disk drive heretofore widely used, a flying surface of a magnetic head slider comes into contact with a magnetic disk upon stoppage of rotation of the magnetic disk, and flies above the surface of the magnetic disk during rotation of the magnetic disk by the action of an air flow produced in concert with the rotation of the magnetic disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> However, if the surface roughness of the magnetic disk in the CSS type magnetic disk drive is reduced, the contact area between the flying surface (air bearing surface) of the magnetic head slider and the surface of the magnetic disk upon stoppage of rotation of the magnetic disk becomes large. Accordingly, there is a possibility of stiction between the magnetic head slider and the magnetic disk at starting rotation of the magnetic disk. As measures against this stiction problem, it has been proposed to apply texture forming by laser to a CSS zone of the magnetic disk or provide a plurality of pads (projections) on the flying surface of the head slider in the CSS type magnetic disk drive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> A portable personal computer such as a notebook personal computer is often carried, and it is therefore required to have high shock resistance. Accordingly, such a personal computer generally employs a load/unload type magnetic disk drive designed so that a head slider is unloaded from the surface of a magnetic disk when the computer is powered off or put into a sleep mode and that the head slider is loaded to the surface of the magnetic disk when the computer is operated. That is, when the computer is powered off or put into a sleep mode, a horn portion formed at the front end of a suspension is seated on a ramp (inclined portion) of a ramp member provided near the outer circumference of the magnetic disk to retract the head slider flying a microscopic height above the disk surface from the magnetic disk. Accordingly, even when the computer receives shock, it is possible to avoid the possibility that the head slider may collide with the magnetic disk to damage the magnetic disk. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Such a magnetic disk drive having a load/unload mechanism is required to have a highly reliable magnetic head slider that is prevented from coming into contact or collision with a magnetic disk not only while the head slider is flying above the disk, but also when the head slider is loaded to the disk. A negative pressure type magnetic head slider is widely used in recent magnetic disk drives, so as to reduce the flying height of the magnetic head slider from the magnetic disk. As a negative pressure type magnetic head slider excellent in flying stability, there has been proposed a head slider in which a yaw angle dependence of flying height is reduced by increasing the widths of two rails from an air inlet end toward an air outlet end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Further, variations in the flying height due to changes in yaw angle can be suppressed by reducing the width of a rail near the air inlet end. In these head sliders, a negative pressure (attraction force) is generated by changing only the width of each rail, thereby allowing simplification of a manufacturing process. Further, Japanese Patent Laid-open No. 2000-173217 includes a negative pressure type head slider which can further reduce the flying height, suppress variations in the flying height, and increase the rigidity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a recent magnetic disk drive, there is a tendency to reduce a magnetic disk spacing, in order to increase a storage capacity. To this end, the surface roughness of each magnetic disk is reduced, so that in the CSS type the stiction by the contact of the magnetic disk and the magnetic head slider in the rest condition becomes remarkable. To avoid this stiction problem, a load/unload type magnetic disk drive tends to be used not only in a portable personal computer such as a notebook personal computer, but also in a desktop personal computer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A conventional negative pressure type magnetic head slider is mounted on a suspension so that the flying surface of the head slider becomes parallel to the magnetic disk at the instant when the head slider is loaded from the ramp member to the magnetic disk. Accordingly, there is a possibility that the head slider may come into contact with the disk because of a negative pressure generated on the head slider at the instant of loading. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Particularly in the case that a groove for generating a negative pressure is formed on the flying surface of the head slider so as to extend from a position upstream of the longitudinal center of the head slider to an air outlet end of the head slider, the head slider is inclined so that an air inlet end of the head slider is drawn to the magnetic disk by the negative pressure at the instant of loading, causing the contact of the air inlet end with the magnetic disk. To prevent this problem, there has been proposed a magnetic head slider mounted on a gimbal bent from a suspension so that the disk opposing surface of the head slider is inclined with respect to the disk surface at a given pitch angle in such a direction of raising the air inlet end from the disk surface. This pitch angle is set in the range of 1&deg;&plusmn;1&deg;, for example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In the case that the angle of incidence of the magnetic head slider mounted on the gimbal falls outside the above range, a negative pressure is generated on the magnetic head slider upon loading and the air inlet end of the head slider is rapidly lowered to cause a possibility of the contact of the air inlet end and the disk. To avoid this problem, there has been proposed a head slider in which a step surface formed on the disk opposing surface at a portion near the air inlet end is cut to form a groove for generating a positive pressure near the air inlet end in the case of loading the head slider at a negative pitch angle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> However, when the step surface is cut, the flying attitude of the head slider largely changes. Particularly, a peripheral speed dependence of pitch angle becomes large. This is due to the fact that the pressure at the air inlet end becomes unsaturated at low peripheral speeds because of cutting of the step surface. Accordingly, a reduction in negative pressure and rigidity occurs. Further, there occurs a reduction in performance such that a flying loss (a difference in level between a lowest flying point of the slider and a flying point of the head element) becomes large because of an increase in pitch angle depending on a peripheral speed. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a negative pressure type magnetic head slider which can avoid the collision with a magnetic disk upon loading and can suppress the peripheral speed dependence of pitch angle. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an aspect of the present invention, there is provided a head slider having a disk opposing surface, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, the head slider comprising a front rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air inlet end, the front rail having a first air bearing surface and a first step surface lower in level than the first air bearing surface; a transducer formed in the vicinity of the air outlet end; a first groove for expanding air once compressed by the front rail to generate a negative pressure; and a second groove formed on the first step surface near the air inlet end except opposite side portions of the first step surface; the first step surface reaching the air inlet end at the opposite side portions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Preferably, each of the opposite side portions of the first step surface has a width less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m. More preferably, the width of each side portion is in the range of 50 to 150 &mgr;m. Preferably, the head slider further comprises a rear center rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air outlet end at a substantially central position in the lateral direction of the head slider, the rear center rail having a second air bearing surface and a second step surface lower in level than the second air bearing surface; the transducer being formed on the second air bearing surface of the rear center rail near the air outlet end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a head slider having a disk opposing surface, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, the head slider comprising a front rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air inlet end, the front rail having a first air bearing surface and a first step surface lower in level than the first air bearing surface; a transducer formed in the vicinity of the air outlet end; a first groove for expanding air once compressed by the front rail to generate a negative pressure; and a pair of second grooves formed on the first step surface near the air inlet end except a laterally central portion of the first step surface; the first step surface reaching the air inlet end at the laterally central portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the first step surface reaches the air inlet end also at opposite side portions of the first step surface. In this case, the laterally central portion has a width less than or equal to 700 &mgr;m, and each of the opposite side portions has a width less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m. More preferably, the width of the laterally central portion is in the range of 500 to 700 &mgr;m, and the width of each side portion is in the range of 50 to 150 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Preferably, the head slider further comprises a rear center rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air outlet end at a substantially central position in the lateral direction of the head slider, the rear center rail having a second air bearing surface and a second step surface lower in level than the second air bearing surface; the transducer being formed on the second air bearing surface of the rear center rail near the air outlet end. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further aspect of the present invention, there is provided a disk drive comprising a housing having a base; a negative pressure type head slider having a transducer for reading/writing data from/to a disk having a plurality of tracks, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, and a disk opposing surface; an actuator for moving the negative pressure type head slider across the tracks of the disk; means for controlling the actuator to load/unload the negative pressure type head slider to/from the disk; and a ramp member fixed to the base for supporting the negative pressure type head slider unloaded from the disk; the actuator comprising an actuator arm rotatably mounted on the base; a suspension fixed at a base end portion thereof to a front end portion of the actuator arm; and the negative pressure type head slider mounted on a front end portion of the suspension; the negative pressure type head slider comprising a front rail formed on the disk opposing surface in the vicinity of the air inlet end, the front rail having a air bearing surface and a step surface lower in level than the air bearing surface; a transducer formed in the vicinity of the air outlet end; a first groove for expanding air once compressed by the front rail to generate a negative pressure; and a second groove formed on the step surface near the air inlet end except opposite side portions of the step surface; the step surface reaching the air inlet end at the opposite side portions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The second groove may be replaced by a pair of second grooves formed on the step surface near the air inlet end except a laterally central portion of the step surface. In this case, the step surface reaches the air inlet end at the laterally central portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> In each configuration mentioned above, the step surface reaches the air inlet end. Accordingly, even if the head slider comes into contact with a disk medium upon loading, the relatively broad end of the step surface formed by photolithography rather than a sharp edge of the step surface formed by cutting comes into contact with the disk medium, thereby exhibiting an additional effect that the damage to the disk medium due to the contact of the head slider and the disk medium upon loading can be reduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The above and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention and the manner of realizing them will become more apparent, and the invention itself will best be understood from a study of the following description and appended claims with reference to the attached drawings showing some preferred embodiments of the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a plan view of a magnetic disk drive with a cover removed; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</cross-reference> is a side view of a ramp member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</cross-reference> is a plan view of the ramp member; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a magnetic head slider according to a first preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross section taken along the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a magnetic head slider according to a second preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a magnetic head slider according to a third preferred embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a magnetic head slider as a comparison; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a graph showing changes in pitch angle from the inner zone to the outer zone of a disk; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a graph showing changes in negative pressure from the inner zone to the outer zone of a disk.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, there is shown a plan view of a magnetic disk drive according to a first preferred embodiment of the present invention in the condition where a cover is removed. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> denotes a housing consisting of a base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and the cover (not shown) fixed to the base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A shaft <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> is fixed to the base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, and a spindle hub (not shown) is rotatably mounted on the shaft <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The spindle hub is driven by a DC motor (not shown) to rotate about the shaft <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A plurality of magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> and spacers (not shown) are mounted on the spindle hub so as to be alternately stacked. That is, the plural magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> are fixedly mounted on the spindle hub by securing a disk clamp <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> to the spindle hub by means of a plurality of screws <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and are equally spaced a given distance by the spacers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Reference numeral <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> denotes a rotary actuator consisting of an actuator arm assembly <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and a magnetic circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The actuator arm assembly <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is rotatable about a shaft <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> fixed to the base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The actuator arm assembly <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> includes an actuator block <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> rotatably mounted on the shaft <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> through a pair of bearings (not shown), a plurality of actuator arms <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> extending horizontally from the actuator block <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in one direction, and a head assembly <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> fixed to a front end portion of each actuator arm <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Each head assembly <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes a negative pressure type head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> having a magnetic head element (transducer) for reading/writing data from/to the corresponding magnetic disk <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, and a suspension (load beam) <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> having a front end portion supporting the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and a base end portion fixed to the corresponding actuator arm <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A coil <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is supported on the opposite side of the actuator arms <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> with respect to the shaft <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The coil <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> is inserted in a gap of the magnetic circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The magnetic circuit <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> and the coil <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> constitute a voice coil motor (VCM) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> denotes a flexible printed circuit board (FPC) for supplying a write signal to the magnetic head element and for taking a read signal from the magnetic head element. One end of the flexible printed circuit board <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is fixed to a side surface of the actuator block <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> A ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is fixed to the base <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> at a position adjacent to the outer circumferences of the magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A and 2B</cross-reference>, the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> has a plurality of ramps (inclined portions) <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> whose number corresponds to the number of the head sliders <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of parking portions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> each for allowing a horn portion <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> formed at the front end of each head assembly <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to be stably parked thereon. Further, a plurality of side projections <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> for preventing the unloaded head sliders <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from interfering with each other are formed on a side surface of the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Reference numeral <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> denotes a latch mechanism for latching a projecting portion <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> of the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> in its unloaded condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The condition shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is an unloaded condition where the head sliders <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> have been unloaded from the magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. In this condition, the horn portions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the head assemblies <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are parked on the parking portions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, and the projecting portion <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> of the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is latched by the latch mechanism <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. When a computer connected to this magnetic disk drive is powered on or a sleep mode is canceled in this unloaded condition, the magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> first start to be rotated. Thereafter, the latch mechanism <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is released to rotate the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> counterclockwise as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, so that the horn portions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> slide down on the ramps <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and the head sliders <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are loaded to the magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> When the computer is powered off or put into the sleep mode, control means such as an MPU mounted on a main printed circuit board (not shown) in the magnetic disk drive controls the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> so that the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is rotated clockwise as viewed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to move the head sliders <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> from the loaded condition through the outer circumferences of the magnetic disks <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> to the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, the horn portions <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> of the head assemblies <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> slide up on the ramps <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and are then parked on the parking portions <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> of the ramp member <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. In this unloaded condition, the projecting portion <highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight> of the actuator <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is latched by the latch mechanism <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, there is shown a perspective view of the negative pressure type magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> according to the first preferred embodiment of the present invention. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a cross section taken along the line <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. The magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the form of a rectangular parallelepiped, and has an air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and an air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The size of the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is 1.25 mm long, 1 mm wide, and 0.3 mm thick, for example. The magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is formed of Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>O<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;TiC, and it is produced by forming a plurality of electromagnetic conversion elements (electromagnetic transducers) on a wafer, next cutting the wafer into a plurality of bars, and processing a side surface of each bar to form a rail surface (disk opposing surface). The formation of the rail surface is performed by using photolithography. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is of a negative pressure type, and it has a front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> formed near the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a rear center rail <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> formed near the air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is formed with an air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and a step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> lower in level than the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> by a given difference <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. Similarly, the rear center rail <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> is formed with an air bearing surface <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and a step surface <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> lower in level than the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> by a given difference <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. An electromagnetic conversion element (transducer) <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> is formed on the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> at a position near the air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> A pair of side rails <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> extend downstream from the opposite side portions of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> toward the air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. The side rails <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> have upper surfaces <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, respectively. Each of the upper surfaces <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> of the side rails <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> has the same level as that of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. A groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is formed on the upper surface (disk opposing surface) of the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> at a position just downstream of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> so as to be surrounded by the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> and the side rails <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. The depth of the groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> from the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is about </italic></highlight>1.4 &mgr;m, and the difference <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> between the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> is about 0.2 &mgr;m. Similarly, the difference <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> between the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> is about 0.2 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> A pair of collision prevention pads <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are formed on the upper surface of the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> at its two corners near the air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The height of each of the collision prevention pads <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is the same as that of each of the step surfaces <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. The collision prevention pads <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> function to prevent that the two corners of the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> near the air outlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>may collide with the disk facing the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. A pair of stiction prevention pads <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> are formed on the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The height of each of the stiction prevention pads <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> from the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is about 30 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> A groove <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is formed on the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> near the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>except opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. That is, the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> reaches the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>The depth of the groove <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is similar to that of the groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. The width of each of the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m, preferably in the range of 50 to 150 &mgr;m. Further, the length of the groove <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> in the longitudinal direction of the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is in the range of 10 to 80 &mgr;m, preferably 40 to 60 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> When the magnetic disk is rotated to generate an air flow along the disk surface, the air flow collides with the difference <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> between the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and the difference <highlight><bold>59</bold></highlight> between the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, and thereafter acts on the air bearing surfaces <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. As a result, flying forces for flying the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> above the disk surface are generated on the air bearing surfaces <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. While such flying forces are generated also on the step surfaces <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, these flying forces are not so large. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, the area of the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is relatively large, so that a relatively large flying force is generated on the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> during rotation of the magnetic disk. As a result, the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is maintained in an inclined attitude at a pitch angle &agr; such that the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>is tilted up. The pitch angle &agr; is an angle of inclination of the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> along the flow direction of the air flow. The groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> is formed just downstream of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, when passing the air bearing surface <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, the air flow is expanded in the groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight> in a direction perpendicular to the disk surface, thereby generating a negative pressure in the groove <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. This negative pressure comes into balance with the above-mentioned flying forces applied to the air bearing surfaces <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>, thereby defining a flying height of the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the groove <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> is formed on the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> at a portion near the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>except the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b. </italic></highlight>Accordingly, the positive pressure (flying force) generated by the combination of the groove <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be suppressed. As a result, an increase in pitch angle at high peripheral speeds can be suppressed. If the width of each of the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (i.e., the width of a portion of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> reaching the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) is too large, a collision prevention margin upon loading the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is reduced. Accordingly, the width of each of the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is set preferably less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m, more preferably in the range of 50 to 150 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference>, there is shown a perspective view of a magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A according to a second preferred embodiment of the present invention. Substantially the same parts as those of the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> according to the first preferred embodiment mentioned above are denoted by the same reference numerals. In the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A, a pair of grooves <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> are formed on the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> near the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>except a laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>That is, the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> reaches the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>at the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>only. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> Also in the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A, a positive pressure generated by the combination of the grooves <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> can be suppressed by the formation of the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>so that an increase in pitch angle at high peripheral speeds can be suppressed. If the width of the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> (i.e., the width of a portion of the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> reaching the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a</italic></highlight>) is too large, a collision prevention margin upon loading the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>A is reduced. Accordingly, the width of the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is set preferably less than or equal to 700 &mgr;m, more preferably in the range of 500 to 700 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, there is shown a perspective view of a magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B according to a third preferred embodiment of the present invention. The magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>B is configured by combining the structures of the first and second preferred embodiments. That is, the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> reaches the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>both at the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and at the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>With this structure, a groove <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> is formed between the side portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c, </italic></highlight>and a groove <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> is formed between the side portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>and the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c. </italic></highlight>The width of the laterally central portion <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>c </italic></highlight>is less than or equal to 700 &mgr;m, preferably in the range of 500 to 600 &mgr;m, and the width of each of the opposite side portions <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m, preferably in the range of 50 to 150 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, there is shown a perspective view of a magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> as a comparison. In the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>, a groove <highlight><bold>94</bold></highlight> is formed on the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of the front rail <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> near the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>so as to laterally extend over the width of the head slider <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, a large positive pressure can be generated by the combination of the groove <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> and the step surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a graph showing a peripheral speed dependence of pitch angle. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, the horizontal axis represents the radius of the magnetic disk (the radial distance from the inner zone to the outer zone of the magnetic disk), and the vertical axis represents the pitch angle. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, symbol A corresponds to the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the first preferred embodiment, and symbol B corresponds to the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the comparison. As apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference>, an increase in pitch angle at the outer zone relative to at the inner zone is 40 &mgr;rad in the first preferred embodiment, whereas it is 110 &mgr;rad in the comparison. This result shows that the collision of the air inlet end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>with the disk upon loading the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in the first preferred embodiment can be prevented and that an increased change in flying attitude of the head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> can be suppressed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a graph showing a peripheral speed dependence of negative pressure. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, symbol A corresponds to the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> of the first preferred embodiment, and symbol B corresponds to the magnetic head slider <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> of the comparison. As apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, an increase in negative pressure at the outer zone relative to at the inner zone is 0.44 gf in the first preferred embodiment, whereas it is 0.04 gf in the comparison. This result shows that a larger negative pressure can be generated at the outer zone of the disk in the first preferred embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Table 1 shows variations in parameters indicating the flying attitude of the head slider at the outer zone in the first preferred embodiment and the comparison, where the value of each parameter is 1 in the first preferred embodiment and the values in the comparison are relative values.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="77PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="28PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="56PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="21PT" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="35PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="4" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>crown</entry>
<entry>camber</entry>
<entry>pitch</entry>
<entry>roll</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="6">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="28PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="56PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="21PT" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="35PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>First Preferred</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Embodiment</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>Comparison</entry>
<entry>1.14</entry>
<entry>2.35</entry>
<entry>1.25</entry>
<entry>1.11</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> As apparent from Table 1, variations in all the parameters at the outer zone in the first preferred embodiment are improved over those in the comparison. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention as described above, it is possible to provide a head slider which can avoid the collision with a disk upon loading and can suppress an increase in pitch angle at the outer zone of the disk. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A head slider having a disk opposing surface, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, said head slider comprising: 
<claim-text>a front rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air inlet end, said front rail having a first air bearing surface and a first step surface lower in level than said first air bearing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transducer formed in the vicinity of said air outlet end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first groove for expanding air once compressed by said front rail to generate a negative pressure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second groove formed on said first step surface near said air inlet end except opposite side portions of said first step surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first step surface reaching said air inlet end at said opposite side portions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A head slider according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said opposite side portions of said first step surface has a width less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A head slider according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a rear center rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air outlet end at a substantially central position in the lateral direction of said head slider, said rear center rail having a second air bearing surface and a second step surface lower in level than said second air bearing surface; 
<claim-text>wherein said transducer is formed on said second air bearing surface of said rear center rail near said air outlet end. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. A head slider having a disk opposing surface, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, said head slider comprising: 
<claim-text>a front rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air inlet end, said front rail having a first air bearing surface and a first step surface lower in level than said first air bearing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transducer formed in the vicinity of said air outlet end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first groove for expanding air once compressed by said front rail to generate a negative pressure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second grooves formed on said first step surface near said air inlet end except a laterally central portion of said first step surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said first step surface reaching said air inlet end </claim-text>
<claim-text>at said laterally central portion. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. A head slider according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said first step surface reaches said air inlet end also at opposite side portions of said first step surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. A head slider according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said laterally central portion has a width less than or equal to 700 &mgr;m, and each of said opposite side portions has a width less than or equal to 200 &mgr;m. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A head slider according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a rear center rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air outlet end at a substantially central position in the lateral direction of said head slider, said rear center rail having a second air bearing surface and a second step surface lower in level than said second air bearing surface; 
<claim-text>wherein said transducer is formed on said second air bearing surface of said rear center rail near said air outlet end. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A disk drive comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a negative pressure type head slider having a transducer for reading/writing data from/to a disk having a plurality of tracks, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, and a disk opposing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said negative pressure type head slider across said tracks of said disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for controlling said actuator to load/unload said negative pressure type head slider to/from said disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ramp member fixed to said base for supporting said negative pressure type head slider unloaded from said disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said actuator comprising: 
<claim-text>an actuator arm rotatably mounted on said base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a suspension fixed at a base end portion thereof to a front end portion of said actuator arm; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative pressure type head slider mounted on a front end portion of said suspension; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative pressure type head slider comprising: 
<claim-text>a front rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air inlet end, said front rail having a air bearing surface and a step surface lower in level than said air bearing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transducer formed in the vicinity of said air outlet end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first groove for expanding air once compressed by said front rail to generate a negative pressure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second groove formed on said step surface near said air inlet end except opposite side portions of said step surface; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said step surface reaching said air inlet end at said opposite side portions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A disk drive comprising: 
<claim-text>a housing having a base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a negative pressure type head slider having a transducer for reading/writing data from/to a disk having a plurality of tracks, an air inlet end, and an air outlet end, and a disk opposing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an actuator for moving said negative pressure type head slider across said tracks of said disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>means for controlling said actuator to load/unload said negative pressure type head slider to/from said disk; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a ramp member fixed to said base for supporting said negative pressure type head slider unloaded from said disk; </claim-text>
<claim-text>said actuator comprising: 
<claim-text>an actuator arm rotatably mounted on said base; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a suspension fixed at a base end portion thereof to a front end portion of said actuator arm; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative pressure type head slider mounted on a front end portion of said suspension; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said negative pressure type head slider comprising: 
<claim-text>a front rail formed on said disk opposing surface in the vicinity of said air inlet end, said front rail having a air bearing surface and a step surface lower in level than said air bearing surface; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transducer formed in the vicinity of said air outlet end; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first groove for expanding air once compressed by said front rail to generate a negative pressure; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of second grooves formed on said step surface near said air inlet end except a laterally central portion of said step surface; </claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>said step surface reaching said air inlet end at said laterally central portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030002218A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
