<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001531A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001531A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001531A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001531A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001531A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001531A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001531A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001531A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001531A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001531A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001531</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10178509</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020625</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-191384</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010625</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H02P001/18</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>318</class>
<subclass>254000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Current limiting circuit of brushless DC fan motor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Junnan</given-name>
<family-name>Xi</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Miyota-machi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>MINEBEA CO., LTD.</organization-name>
<address>
<city>Miyota-machi</city>
<country>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</country>
</address>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>OLIFF &amp; BERRIDGE, PLC</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. BOX 19928</address-1>
<city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22320</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">There is provided a current limiting circuit to eliminate any harsh grating noise attributable to the decrease in an ON-OFF frequency of an electrified current from a normal range, for example, below 1 kHz when starting a brushless DC fan motor. In the current limiting circuit to limit the current by shutting off field coils to be electrified for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of a comparator in which a current-detecting resistor is interposed in electrified passages of the field coils of the brushless DC fan motor to compare the voltage according to the voltage produced across the current-detecting resistor as the control voltage with the reference voltage according to the current to be limited when the motor is started or the like, a differential amplifier is interposed between the current-detecting resistor and the comparator to improve the comparative accuracy between the control voltage with the reference voltage in the comparator so that the accuracy is not easily affected by malfunction factors. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a brushless DC fan motor suitable for a fan radiating heat from a housing of an OA appliance, and more particularly to a current limiting circuit thereof. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In an electronic appliance such as OA appliances including personal computers and copiers, a large number of electronic components are accommodated in a small housing, whereby heat is generated from the electronic components and accumulated in the housing so as to have a possibility to damage the electronic components. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> To solve this problem, a ventilation hole is provided in a wall or a ceiling of the housing, and a fan motor is mounted in the ventilation hole so as to radiate heat outside of the housing. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> In the fan motor of the above, a noise occurs when the fan motor is started (hereinafter referred to as a &ldquo;starting noise&rdquo;), and the starting noise will be maximum when relatively large fan motor is provided, causing the harsh grating noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> When the brushless DC fan motor is used for the fan motor, the staring noise becomes prominent especially when the ON-OFF frequency of the starting current is less than 1 kHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The brushless DC fan motor is not exceptional among other motors so that a current limiting circuit is provided as a countermeasure in order to prevent the excess current from being occurred when the fan motor is started or in an overload condition. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Although the current limiting circuit is employed in such a manner as to shut off field coils to be electrified to suppress the excess current, such a ON-OFF frequency of the starting current largely depend on the configuration of the current limiting circuit. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows the current limiting circuit of a conventional brushless DC fan motor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In the figure, numeral <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> denotes current limiting circuit of a brushless DC fan motor (circuit) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Here shows the current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> in the two-phase motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> As shown in the figure, the brushless DC fan motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> comprises field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a drive circuit DRV. The field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are mounted on a stator (not shown), and conducted by the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in an alternately switching manner to form the rotating magnetic field. A rotor (not shown) rotates by means of the rotation of a permanent magnet provided thereon following the above rotating magnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> The current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> comprises resistors R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, capacitors C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a comparator COM, a PNP transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, an NPN transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, which is a current-detecting resistor connected in series to the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so as to detect the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, detects the current by converting into a voltage VA produced across the resistor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> The comparator COM compares a control voltage VB from the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> side with a reference voltage Vf and outputs a L (Low) level signal when the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf. The reference voltage Vf is the voltage corresponding to an allowable maximum value If of the preset starting current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> When an output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the L level, the transistors Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned on, and the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are forward-biased to realize the conduction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> As a result, each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is grounded via the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and the transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and thus, the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off irrespective of the state of the control signal from the drive circuit DRV and shut off the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to be electrified. This means that the current is limited when the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> exceeds the allowable maximum value If of the starting current. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The OFF state of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is continued so long as the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf and limits the starting current. When the control voltage VB is less than the reference voltage Vf, the output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the H (High) level, the transistors Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off, and the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are reverse-biased to realize the non-conduction. As a result, each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is released from the grounded state, and the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are controlled by the signal from the drive circuit DRV. This means that the rotation is returned to normal one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> However, In the above conventional technology, the ON-OFF frequency of the starting current is less than 1 kHz when the motor is started, and a problem regarding the harsh grating noise of the starting noise remains. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> This problem will be described below. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> waveform (I) shows a normal waveform of the electrified current of the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> in the brushless DC fan motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. However, this waveform (I) is the synthesized current waveform of the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, in other words, the waveform of the electrified current in the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. The ON-OFF frequency of the starting current shown in the waveform (I) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is not less than 1 kHz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In such a waveform (I) of the electrified current, the waveform of the output signal VC of the comparator COM (the voltage waveform of the anode of the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) is shown in (VC) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> if the current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> works normally where the level If is the allowable maximum level of the predetermined current, i.e., the starting current. This means that the frequency of the output signal VC of the comparator COM (the inverting frequency on the L and H levels) is maintained to be at least 1 kHz, and the starting noise does not form any harsh grating noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> However, in the conventional technology, the reference voltage Vf is set to be a small value. This is because the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> cannot be increased over a predetermined value, and as a result, the voltage VA detectable by the resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> cannot be increased either for the reason that the magnitude of the electrified current to the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is not limited. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> As a result, both the control voltage VB and the reference voltage Vf for the comparator COM are decreased, and the comparison of high accuracy cannot be realized in the comparator COM. Thus, the comparator is easily affected by various kinds of operation disturbance factors such as the change in temperature, the change in source voltage and the noises from the inside and outside of the current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and the waveform of the output signal VC of the comparator COM actually becomes what is shown in (VC&prime;) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> This means that the H-level portion in the waveform shown in (VC) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> becomes a randomly-chipped waveform, which means that the ON-OFF frequency of the starting current is decreased, i.e., less than 1 kHz, causing the starting noise. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Similar phenomena occur when the motor is forcibly stopped by the external force or the like, and the improvement of these problems has been requested. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the present invention has been made in light of the above problems, and an object of the present invention is to provide a current limit circuit of a brushless DC fan motor to eliminate the harsh grating noise attributable to the reduction of the current ON-OFF frequency from a normal range, for example, below 1 kHz when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In order to solve the above problem, there is provided a current limiting circuit in a first aspect of the present invention which limits the current in field coils of a brushless DC fan motor comprising a stator having a plurality of the field coils and a rotor having a permanent magnet in which the rotor is rotated by alternately switching the current in the field coils and rotating the permanent magnet following the rotating magnetic field formed by the field coils by shutting off the field coils to be electrified for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of a comparator which compares the control voltage as the voltage according to the voltage produced across a current-detecting resistor interposed in electrified passages of the field coils with the preset reference voltage, and comprises a differential amplifier which is interposed between the current-detecting resistor and the comparator, amplifies the voltage produced across the current-detecting resistor and applies the voltage to the comparator as the control voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> There is provided a current limiting circuit in a second aspect of the present invention which limits the current in field coils of a brushless DC fan motor comprising a stator having a plurality of the field coils with each switching element connected in series thereto and a rotor having a permanent magnet in which the rotor is rotated by alternately switching the current in the field coils by turning ON/turning OFF the switching elements and rotating the permanent magnet following the rotating magnetic field formed by the field coils by shuting off the field coils to be electrified for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of a comparator which compares the control voltage as the voltage according to the voltage produced across a current-detecting resistor interposed in electrified passages of the field coils with the preset reference voltage, and comprises a differential amplifier which is interposed between the current-detecting resistor and the comparator, amplifies the voltage produced across the current-detecting resistor and applies the voltage to the comparator as the control voltage, and switch elements which arc provided corresponding to each of the switching elements, receive the output signal of the comparator and shut off the field coils to be electrified with a control input terminal of the switching elements connected in series to the field coils on the supply side of the current to produce the control voltage exceeding the reference voltage for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a current limiting circuit diagram according to a first embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a current limiting circuit diagram according to a second embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows a conventional circuit diagram; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a signal waveform chart explaining the operation of the current limiting circuit.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The embodiment of the present invention will be described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a current limiting circuit diagram of a brushless DC fan motor according to a first embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In the figure, numeral <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> denotes a current limiting circuit of a brushless DC fan motor (circuit) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Here shows the current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the two-phase motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> As shown in the figure, the brushless DC fan motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> comprises field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, switching elements respectively connected in series to the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, i.e., FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and a drive circuit DRV. The field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are mounted on a stator (not shown) and electrified in an alternately switching manner by the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to form the rotating magnetic field. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> A rotor (not shown) is rotated by making a permanent magnet provided thereon rotated following the above rotating magnetic field. The drive circuit DRV gives the ON signal (H level) to gates (control input terminals) G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> according to the position of rotation of the rotor, and alternately turns ON/turns OFF the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> comprises resistors R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and R<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, a differential amplifier AMP, a converter COM, a capacitor C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, a PNP transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, an NPN transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is a current-detecting resistor which is connected in series to the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to detect the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and detects the current in the coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> by converting the current into the voltage VA produced therebetween. The capacitor C<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is used for removing the noise, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> The differential amplifier AMP comprises an operational amplifier, and the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> is applied between a non-inverting input terminal &plus; and an inverting input terminal &minus; via the resistors R<highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and R<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The non-inverting input terminal &plus; is located on the brushless DC fan motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> side, and the inverting input terminal &minus; is located on the ground side. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> This means that the differential amplifier AMP amplifies the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to allow a large set value of the reference voltage Vf which will be described below. In addition, the differential amplifier AMP achieves the amplifying operation without being affected by the change in temperature, the change in power source voltage, etc. on the whole since the effects of the change in temperature, the change in power source voltage, etc. on the voltage signals of the non-inverting input terminal &plus; and the inverting input terminal &minus; are canceled by each other. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> The comparator COM comprises an operational amplifier, and the voltage (the control voltage) according to the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, i.e., the output voltage VB of the differential amplifier AMP is applied to the inverting input terminal &minus;, and the reference voltage Vf set by resistance voltage dividers (resistors R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) is applied to the non-inverting input terminal &plus;, respectively. The reference voltage Vf is the voltage corresponding to the allowable maximum value of the preset current, for example, the allowable maximum value If of the excess current when the motor is started or forcibly stopped by the external force or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The comparator COM compares the control voltage VB from the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> side with the reference voltage Vf when the motor is driven, and outputs the L (Low) level signal for the period in which the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf. When the output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the L level, a transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is turned on, a transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is accordingly turned on, and thus diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are forward-biased to realize the conduction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is grounded through the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and between the collector-emitter of the transistor Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Thus, the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off irrespective of the state of the control signal from the drive circuit DRV, and the electrification to the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is shut off. This means that the current is limited when the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> exceeds the allowable maximum value If of the excess current when the motor is started or forcibly stopped by the external force or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The OFF state of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is continued so long as the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf, and the current is limited when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> When the control voltage VB is below the reference voltage Vf, the output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the H (High) level, the transistors Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off, the diodes D<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are reverse-biased to realize no conduction. Each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is released from the grounded state, and the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are controlled by the signal from the drive circuit DRV. This means that the rotation is returned to the normal one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiment, the control voltage VB to the comparator COM is obtained by amplifying the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> by the differential amplifier AMP and can be set to be a large value without limiting the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, i.e., without increasing the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> As a result, the reference voltage Vf can be set to be a large value, and the comparison of high accuracy can be realized in the comparator COM. As a result, the comparator is less easily affected by various kinds of disturbance factors such as the change in temperature, the change in power source voltage or the noise from the inside and outside a current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, and the waveform of the output signal VC of the comparator COM is not expressed by the waveform VC&prime; shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, but the waveform VC shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> can be maintained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> This means that the ON-OFF frequency of the current when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force (the starting current, and the current in the forcible stop), etc. is not decreased, i.e., the current can be maintained to be not less than 1 kHz, and any harsh grating noise is not generated when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, symbols &plus;V and &plus;Vcc denote a motor drive power supply source and a current limiting circuit driving power supply source, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a current limiting circuit diagram of the brushless DC fan motor according to a second embodiment of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> In the figure, numeral <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> denotes a current limiting circuit of the brushless DC fan motor (circuit) <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The current limiting circuit <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> in the two-phase motor <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is also shown here similar to that in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> The second embodiment is similar to the above first embodiment except that the voltage signal applied to the inverting input terminal &minus; of the comparator COM comprising the operational amplifier is reverse to the voltage signal applied to the non-inverting input terminal &plus;, and the circuit configuration between the output terminal of the comparator COM and the gates (control input terminals) G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is different. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, parts and components which are identical to or correspond to those in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> are represented by the same reference numerals and symbols, a detailed description thereof is omitted, and the above differences are mainly described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> In the second embodiment, the reference voltage Vf set by resistance voltage dividers (resistors R<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and R<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) and the voltage (the control voltage) VB according to the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> are applied to the inverting input terminal &minus; of the comparator COM and the non-inverting input terminal &plus;, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The configuration between the output terminal of the comparator COM and the gates (control input terminals) G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> comprises diodes D<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, resistors R<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> to R<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and switching elements, i.e., transistors Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In the diode D<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, an anode and a cathode are connected to the output terminal of the comparator COM and a base of the NPN transistor Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> via the resistor R<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, respectively. In the transistor Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, a collector is grounded via the resistor R<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and connected to the gate G of the FET T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, and an emitter is grounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> In the diode D<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, an anode and a cathode are connected to the output terminal of the comparator COM and a base of the NPN transistor Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> via the resistor R<highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>, respectively. In the transistor Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, a collector is grounded via the resistor R<highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and connected to the gate G of the FET T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, and an emitter is grounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> Next, the operation of the second embodiment will be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> It is similar to the first embodiment that the control voltage VB to the comparator COM is obtained by amplifying the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> by the differential amplifier AMP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> The comparator COM compares the control voltage VB from the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> side with the reference voltage Vf when driving the motor, and outputs the H (High) level signal for the period in which the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> When the output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the H level, the diodes D<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are forward-biased to realize the conduction, and the bases of the transistors Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are set to be on the H level via the resistors R<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and R<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Thus, when the ON signal (the control signal on the H level) is given from the drive circuit DRV to each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, the gate G of the FET T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> with the ON signal (on the H level) given thereto is grounded via the collector-emitter of the transistor Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> or Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. This means that the gate G of the FET T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> connected in series to the field coil L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on the supply side of the current to generate the control voltage VB (the voltage VA) exceeding the reference voltage Vf is grounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> As a result, the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned off irrespective of the state of the control signal from the drive circuit DRV for the period in which the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf and shut off the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> to be electrified. This means that the current is limited when the current in the field coils L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> exceeds the allowable maximum value If of the excess current when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> The OFF state of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is continued so long as the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf, and the current is limited when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> When the control voltage VB is below the reference voltage Vf, the output signal VC of the comparator COM is on the L (Low) level, the diodes D<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and D<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are reverse-biased to realize no conduction, and the bases of the transistors Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are set on the L level, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> As a result, each gate G of the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is released from the grounded state, and the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are controlled by the signal from the drive circuit DRV. In other words, the rotation is returned to be normal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> As described above, also in the second embodiment, the control voltage VB to the comparator COM is obtained by amplifying the voltage VA produced across the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, and can be set to be a large value without increasing the current-detecting resistor R<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> As a result, the reference voltage Vf can be set to be a large value, and the comparison of high accuracy can be realized in the comparator COM, and thus, any harsh grating noise is not generated when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force similar to the first embodiment. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> In particular, the second embodiment includes the transistors Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> which ground the gate G of the FET T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> connected in series to the field coil L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on the supply side of the current to produce the control voltage VB exceeding the reference voltage Vf for the period in which the control voltage VB exceeds the reference voltage Vf, and shut off the electrification to the field coil L<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or L<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. As a result, the transistors Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> are individually, i.e., alternately turned ON/turned OFF to the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> Thus, according to the second embodiment, the factors of generating the harsh grating noise can be reduced more than the configuration of a conventional technology or in the above first embodiment in which both the transistors Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are turned on commonly to the FETs T<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and T<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, i.e., continuously so long as the control voltage VB is not less than the reference voltage Vf. In addition, all current limiting functions are not lost when one switch element (the transistor Q<highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> or Q<highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the transistor Q<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or Q<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>) is failed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> In the above embodiments, the FET, the transistor and the operational amplifier are employed for the switching element, the switch clement, and the comparator and the differential amplifier, respectively; but the embodiments are not limited to this example. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> Further, the brushless DC fan motor is not limited to the two-phase one. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> As described above, in the present invention, the accuracy in comparison in the comparator is improved between the control voltage according to the current in the field coil and the reference voltage according to the current to be limited when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force by interposing the differential amplifier between the current-detecting resistor of the field coil and the comparator. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> As a result, when the motor is started, or forcibly stopped by the external force, the ON-OFF frequency of the current is less than 1 kHz when limiting the current by shutting off the field coil to be electrified for the period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of the comparator, and the harsh grating noise can be prevented. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> In addition, the switch element is provided corresponding to the switching element connected in series to the field coil, and the control input terminal of the switching element connected in series to the field coil on the supply side of the current to produce the control voltage exceeding the reference voltage for the period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage is grounded. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> In this configuration, the switch element is turned ON/turned OFF individually to a plurality of switching elements, and the factors of generating the harsh grating noise in this configuration can be reduced more than the configuration in which the switch element common to a plurality of switching elements is turned ON/turned OFF, and the harsh grating noise can be further eliminated thereby. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A current limiting circuit to limit the current running in field coils of a brushless DC fan motor comprising a stator having a plurality of the field coils and a rotor having a permanent magnet in which the rotor is rotated by alternately switching the current running in the field coils and rotating the permanent magnet following the rotating magnetic field formed by the field coils by shutting off the field coils to be electrified for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of a comparator which compares the control voltage as the voltage according to the voltage produced across a current-detecting resistor interposed in electrified passages of the field coils with the preset reference voltage comprising: 
<claim-text>a differential amplifier which is interposed between the current-detecting resistor and the comparator, amplifies the voltage produced across the current-detecting resistor and applies the voltage to the comparator as the control voltage. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A current limiting circuit to limit the current in field coils of a brushless DC fan motor comprising a stator having a plurality of the field coils with each switching element connected in series thereto and a rotor having a permanent magnet in which the rotor is rotated by alternately switching the current in the field coils by turning ON/turning OFF the switching elements and rotating the permanent magnet following the rotating magnetic field formed by the field coils by shutting off the field coils to be electrified for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage by the output signal of a comparator which compares the control voltage as the voltage according to the voltage produced across a current-detecting resistor interposed in electrified passages of the field coils with the preset reference voltage comprising: 
<claim-text>a differential amplifier which is interposed between the current-detecting resistor and the comparator, amplifies the voltage produced across the current-detecting resistor and applies the voltage to the comparator as the control voltage; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>switch elements which are provided corresponding to each of the switching elements, receive the output signal of the comparator and shut off the electrification to the field coils with a control input terminal of the switching elements connected in series to the field coils on the supply side of the current to produce the control voltage exceeding the reference voltage for a period in which the control voltage exceeds the reference voltage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001531A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001531A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001531A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001531A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001531A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
