<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001811</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10182479</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020730</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>G09G003/36</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>345</class>
<subclass>090000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Drive circuit for improved brightness control in liquid crystal displays and method therefor</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Eugene</given-name>
<middle-name>Murphy</middle-name>
<family-name>O&apos;Donnell</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Fishers</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Joseph S Tripoli</name-1>
<name-2>Thomson Multimedia Licensing Inc</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO Box 5312</address-1>
<city>Princeton</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>08543-5312</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
<international-conventions>
<pct-application>
<document-id>
<doc-number>PCT/US01/44745</doc-number>
<document-date>20011129</document-date>
<country-code>WO</country-code>
</document-id>
</pct-application>
</international-conventions>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A display driver for a display unit having a memory element and a liquid crystal cell includes a first display driver circuit having a first storage capacitor and a first differential amplifier coupled between the first storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell and a second display driver circuit having a second storage capacitor (<highlight><bold>14&prime;</bold></highlight>) an a second differential amplifier (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;) coupled between the second storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell. The display driver also includes a first switching mechanism enabling the switching of the display driver between the first display driver circuit during a positive frame and a second display driver circuit during a negative frame and a second switching mechanism coupled to a supply voltage. The second switching mechanism is controlled by at least one global address line. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to the field of video systems utilizing a liquid crystal display (LCD) or liquid crystal on silicon (LCOS), and in particular, to a driver circuit for improving brightness control in LCOS/LCD projection systems. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Related Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Liquid crystal on silicon (LCOS) can be thought of as one large liquid crystal formed on a silicon wafer. The silicon wafer is divided into an incremental array of tiny plate electrodes. A tiny incremental region of the liquid crystal is influenced by the electric field generated by each tiny plate and the common plate. Each such tiny plate and corresponding liquid crystal region are together referred to as a cell of the imager. Each cell corresponds to an individually controllable pixel. A common plate electrode is disposed on the other side of the liquid crystal. The drive voltages are supplied to plate electrodes on each side of the LCOS array. Each cell, or pixel, remains lighted with the same intensity until the input signal is changed, thus acting as a sample and hold (so long as the voltage is maintained, the pixel brightness does not decay). Each set of common and variable plate electrodes forms an imager. One imager is typically provided for each color, in this case, one imager each for red, green and blue. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> It is typical to drive the imager of an LCOS display with a frame-doubled signal to avoid 30 Hz flicker, by sending first a normal frame in which the voltage at the electrodes associated with each cell is positive with respect to the voltage at the common electrode (positive picture) and then an inverted frame in which the voltage at the electrodes associated with each cell is negative with respect to the voltage at the common electrode (negative picture) in response to a given input picture. The generation of positive and negative pictures ensures that each pixel will be written with a positive electric field followed by a negative electric field. The resulting drive field has a zero DC component, which is necessary to avoid image sticking, and ultimately, permanent degradation of the imager. It has been determined that the human eye responds to the average value of the brightness of the pixels produced by these positive and negative pictures so long as the frame rate is above 120 Hertz. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The present state of the art in LCOS requires the adjustment of the common-mode electrode voltage, denoted VITO, to be precisely between the positive and negative field drive for the LCOS. The subscript ITO refers to the material indium tin oxide. The average balance is necessary in order to minimize flicker, as well as to prevent a phenomenon known as image sticking. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> In the current art, the LCOS drive cell looks much like a conventional Active Matrix LCD driver. This does not work well, due to the various artifacts discussed in the literature. The main causes are parasitic capacitance cross-talk, residual voltage in the LC cell, and voltage droop of the LC, due to ionic leakage and bulk resistivity of the LC material. Mainly, this has been solved by: 1. Increasing the cell capacitance (limited by physical area), 2. Changing to higher resistivity LC materials (limits flexibility and response time), 3. Increasing the frame scan rate to more than 60 Hz (expensive, and costs more bandwidth), 4. Strongly controlling the temperature of the device, to maintain high voltage holding ratio (VHR). All these detriments also have an impact on the ability to control brightness in a liquid crystal or LCOS display. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> The prior method for implementing brightness control in a display consists of performing a mathematical add function on the digital data prior to applying it to the display. The problem with this method is that depth of color is greatly impacted, since all of the brightness range must be accommodated in the pre-processing. Moreover, there is no way to blank the display without destroying the data in the typical architecture. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> In a first aspect of the present invention, a display unit having an array of liquid crystal cells, comprises an array of display drivers, where a given display driver being associated with a given liquid crystal cell comprises a driver circuit including a memory cell for the given liquid crystal cell and a switching arrangement coupled to the driver circuit and to at least a supply voltage source, where the switching arrangement globally controls the supply voltage to the array of display drivers and when the voltage from the memory cell for the given liquid crystal cell gets applied to the liquid crystal cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> In a second aspect of the present invention, a display driver for a display unit having a memory element and a liquid crystal cell comprises a first display driver circuit having a first storage capacitance and a first amplifier coupled between the first storage capacitance and the liquid crystal cell and a second display driver circuit having a second storage capacitance an a second amplifier coupled between the second storage capacitance and the liquid crystal cell. The display driving also preferably comprises a first switching arrangement enabling the switching of the display driver between the first display driver circuit during a positive frame and a second display driver circuit during a negative frame and a second switching arrangement coupled to at least a supply voltage, wherein the second switching mechanism is controlled by at least one global address line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In a third aspect of the present invention, a display driver for a display unit which includes a plurality of display elements arranged in a matrix of rows and columns and a memory element and a liquid crystal cell comprises a driver for switchably outputting one of a plurality of voltages to the display elements on at least one of the matrix of rows and columns, said driver including a decoder and a plurality of analog switches, each analog switch being controlled by the decoder. The display driver further comprises a first switching mechanism enabling the switching of the display driver between a first display driver circuit during a positive frame and a second display driver circuit during a negative frame and a second switching mechanism coupled to at least a supply voltage, wherein the second switching mechanism is controlled by at least one global address line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> In a fourth aspect of the present invention, a method for driving a liquid crystal on silicon display having a plurality of driver circuits for a liquid crystal cell comprises the steps of switching between the plurality of driver circuits using a first switching mechanism comprising a first pair of transistors and controlling a blanking function using a second switching mechanism comprising a second pair of transistors coupled to at least a supply voltage and wherein the second switching mechanism is controlled by at least one global address line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In a fifth aspect of the present invention, a method for driving a display having a plurality of driver circuits comprises the steps of providing isolation between a storage capacitor and a liquid crystal cell using a differential amplifier in each of the plurality of driver circuits and switching between the plurality of driver circuits for the liquid crystal cell using a first switching mechanism. The method of driving a display further comprises the step of controlling functions using a second switching mechanism, wherein the functions are selected among the group of functions comprising brightness control, dynamic range control for a digital to analog converter, or a global fast blanking of the display.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a liquid crystal cell driver in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a block diagram of another liquid crystal cell driver in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a display unit utilizing a liquid crystal cell driver in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating a method of driving a display in accordance with the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a flow chart illustrating another method of driving a display in accordance with the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the inventive arrangements, two globally controlled transistors (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) are added to form the driver cell or circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. By doing this, it is possible to apply a forced black or white state to all of the LCOS or liquid crystal (LC) cells by controlling the on time via the globally controlled transistors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. When either transistor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are conductive, then transistors <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> must be non-conductive. These additional devices (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>) can perform various functions. First, they can apply a fixed global amount of RMS voltage or offset to the LC. This offset is equivalent to a brightness function. Second, by controlling the on time of the upper transistor <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or lower transistor <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, it is possible to make the entire display white, or black, without having to overwrite the data stored in the storage cells (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;) resulting in the effect of global fast blanking of the display. The usage of the brightness offset to level shift the RMS voltage from the data cells upward into the useful active region increases the dynamic range of the digital to analog converter (DAC) (not shown) that provides column data containing video information to corresponding storage cells <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> improves the range of brightness control systems in LCOS and LCD displays and further incorporates a driver circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates a circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> in conjunction with a known driver circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the form of a matrix switch (FET). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> With reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the driver circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is shown in the dashed block. The basic advantage of circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and method for driving LCOS or LC displays is that it uses two separate storage elements (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;) and drive circuits that are switched to drive the LC cell. This allows for a fast switching frequency, which makes the flicker rate of the LC cell much above frequencies detectable by the human eye. It also allows for the possibility of switching the common electrode voltage (VITO) to help to increase the possible RMS voltage on the LC cell for a given operating voltage of the silicon back plane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> The upper cell driver that includes transistor <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> contains the voltage to drive the LC during the &ldquo;positive&rdquo; frame, the lower cell driver that includes transistor <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> contains the voltage to drive the LC in the &ldquo;negative&rdquo; frame. These must be balanced with VITO in order to avoid a net DC voltage on the LC cell, and resultant imager retention and reliability issues. VDD and VSS are the upper and lower operating voltages for the CMOS devices. VNN is set to regulate the current through the transistors <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and controls the power dissipation of the amplifier (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;). V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> are global switching voltages that determine which amplifier (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;) is driving the liquid crystal cell. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> The inventive arrangements use a global switch preferably using two transistors (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>), shown to the right of the dashed block, to apply a fixed RMS voltage to the LC cell which is identical or in common for all of the LC cells in the display. The effect of this global switch is to provide three new and advantageous features for the device. The first advantage is an improvement in contouring, because the unusable portion of the typical transfer function can be excluded without using analog DAC range. This improvement can be achieved by manipulating the amount of time that V<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> are on to force the LC to be driven to a certain brightness level near a full brightness level or to bring up a darkness level as examples. The second advantage is a net luminance offset voltage, which can emulate a brightness control, again without consuming dynamic range in the DACs. The third advantage is a mechanism for making the entire display either black or white, without changing the underlying video data. This applies to analog drives for both LCD and LCOS displays. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> In circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> shown in the dashed block, the differential amplifiers <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime; respectively advantageously decouple the LC cell from the memory element (<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;). In conjunction with that idea, the inventive arrangements add a pair of additional transistors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> connected to VDD and VSS respectively, and which are respectively controlled by two global addressing lines V<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. These two additional control switches in the form of transistors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> allow for implementing a brightness control, improving dynamic range of the drive DAC, and blanking of the display (either white or black). The brightness function can be implemented independently of the isolation amplifiers, but the other functions of improved dynamic range and blanking need the isolation provided by the differential amplifiers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The voltages V<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and V<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> control the time for which VDD and VSS are applied to the LC cell. The voltage V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> controls the time for when the voltage at the memory cell or storage capacitance <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is applied to the liquid crystal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and the voltage V<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> controls the time for when the voltage at the memory cell or storage capacitance <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime; is applied to the liquid crystal <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Only one of the voltages V<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through V<highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> should be active at any given time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In a system where Vito is fixed, the present invention limits the maximum and minimum RMS voltage being applied to the LC by limiting the amount of time that Vdd, Vss, and the voltage in the respective storage capacitors are applied. Thus, with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the effective voltage applied to the LC is the product of 4 time intervals and 4 voltages. If Tv<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>, Tv<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, Tv<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, and Tv<highlight><subscript>4 </subscript></highlight>are the respective time intervals when the respective transistors <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> are switched on, and V<highlight><subscript>14 </subscript></highlight>and V<highlight><subscript>14&prime; </subscript></highlight>are the respective voltages in storage capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and storage capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>&prime;, then the effective voltage on the LC could be computed as follows: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Tv<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&times;(Vdd&minus;Vito)&plus;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Tv<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&times;(V<highlight><subscript>14</subscript></highlight>&minus;Vito)&plus;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Tv<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>&times;(Vss&minus;Vito)&plus;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="1"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Tv<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&times;(V<highlight><subscript>14&prime;</subscript></highlight>&minus;Vito) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> wherein the RMS voltage is determined by dividing the result above by (Tv<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>&plus;Tv<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&plus;Tv<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&plus;Tv<highlight><subscript>4</subscript></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The inventive arrangements can also be used in conjunction with a prior art matrix switch (FET) driver circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> as shown in the circuit <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The inventive arrangements taught herein can be used with a control system wherein VITO is held constant or wherein VITO varies. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1, a</cross-reference> differential amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is preferably added between the internal storage capacitor or memory element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and the LC cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in order to overcome some of the problems described above. In other words, a drive amplifier is added to the driving cell. This adds isolation between the storage capacitor and the LC cell. The added current drive capability ensures that the voltage on the pixel will rapidly become that desired. It also allows for very low leakage current from the storage capacitor (FET has very high input impedance), and allows for a continuous refresh of the voltage on the LC, which eliminates the &lsquo;droop&rsquo; problem, as well as the residual voltaic potential stored in the cell. This should improve both the flicker issue, as well as the &lsquo;image sticking&rsquo; problem which is associated with the inability to achieve DC balance in the cell. It should also allow the cell to work well even at somewhat elevated temperatures. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The disadvantage of this technique is that it increases the DC current through the LC cell. This can be overcome in part by gating the current source in the bottom of the differential amplifier. This can use the &lsquo;pixel select&rsquo; bit in the device. In this way, a periodic refresh of the voltage can be achieved, while reducing the power consumption by 1/nrow, where nrow is the number of rows in the device. Since heating is uniform, this gating in some situations may not be needed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A typical implementation in CMOS of the driver <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> is shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> and will be explained in further detail. The components are schematic representations, and alternate configurations can be used without loss of generality. Note that the circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> illustrates an upper driver circuit and a lower driver circuit, but each of these driver circuits is preferably substantially the same with comparable components shown for the lower driver circuit with an additional &ldquo;&prime;&rdquo; designation. The key points are the buffer amplifier (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;), which applies a closed loop correction voltage to the LC cell, and the gated current source which allows reduction of power consumption. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Typically amplifier (<highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>&prime;) could be implemented with 3 transistors, which can be placed under the LC cell in an LCOS display device. In the arrangement of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> decouples the LC cell from the memory element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a liquid crystal cell driver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> for a liquid crystal display. The liquid crystal cell driver preferably comprises a plurality of transistors (<highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>), a storage capacitance such as a storage capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, and a plurality of resistors <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> and the liquid crystal cell represented by liquid crystal capacitance <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. Preferably, three (3) transistors, such as transistors <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> form the amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, preferably in the form of a differential amplifier. The differential amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is preferably comprised of N-Channel transistors having respective sources coupled and the drain of transistor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> serving as an output to the liquid crystal cell (<highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>). Additionally, the respective sources of the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> are coupled and driven by a current source which is another N-Channel transistor such as transistor <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> that sets the balance current in the differential amplifier. As previously explained, the differential amplifier <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> is coupled between the storage capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and provides isolation between the storage capacitor <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and a liquid crystal cell <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> or pixel. As shown, the circuit <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> further comprises two globally controlled transistors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> which among other functions previously discussed enable a forced black or white state to all of the LCOS or liquid crystal (LC) cells by controlling the on time of the two additional switched transistors (<highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, another liquid crystal cell driver <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is shown similar to the liquid crystal cell driver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. In this instance, the known brightness control circuit <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in the form of a matrix switch replaces the circuit <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> disclosed with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. Once again, as with the liquid crystal cell driver <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>, the liquid crystal cell driver <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> also preferably comprises the two globally controlled transistors <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and the liquid crystal capacitance <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> as shown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> display unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> is shown that can utilize the display drivers <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> as previously described above. The display unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> preferably includes a plurality of display elements arranged in a matrix of rows and columns and a memory element and a liquid crystal cell. The driver preferably switchably outputs one of a plurality of voltages to the display elements on at least one of the matrix of rows and columns, the display unit including a conventional decoder <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> and the driver controlled by the decoder <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The driver includes a storage capacitor or memory element <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> coupled between the decoder and the semiconductor switch and a differential amplifier coupled between the storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell, whereby the differential amplifier provides isolation between the storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell. This driver can include a decoder and a plurality of switches controlled by an output of the decoder. As shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, the display unit <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> can include a row drive circuit having a plurality of row (scanning) address lines <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and a column drive circuit <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> having a plurality of column (data) address lines <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. This matrix of rows and columns are on a substrate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and sandwiched between another substrate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4, a</cross-reference> flow chart is shown illustrating a method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> of driving a display in accordance with the present invention where a plurality of driver circuits are used to drive a liquid crystal cell. The method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> preferably comprises the step <highlight><bold>402</bold></highlight> of providing isolation between a storage capacitor and a liquid crystal cell using a differential amplifier, the step <highlight><bold>404</bold></highlight> of switching between the plurality of driver circuits for the LC cell using a first switching mechanism, and the step <highlight><bold>406</bold></highlight> of controlling functions using a second switching mechanism where the functions are selected among the group of functions comprising brightness control, dynamic range control for a DAC, or a global fast blanking of the display. The method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may further comprise the alternative function described in step <highlight><bold>408</bold></highlight> or blanking to white or blanking to black without having to overwrite data stored in a storage capacitor or a memory cell or the step <highlight><bold>410</bold></highlight> of ensuring rapid desired voltage levels on a pixel or cell using additional current provided by the differential amplifier. Additionally, the method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may alternatively comprise the step <highlight><bold>412</bold></highlight> of continuously refreshing the voltage on the LC cell or the step <highlight><bold>414</bold></highlight> of gating a current source provided to the differential amplifier in each of the plurality of driver circuits or the step <highlight><bold>416</bold></highlight> of applying a fixed global amount of RMS voltage to the LC display. Another alternative function comprises the control of the on time of a first transistor and a second transistor in the first switching mechanism using the second switching mechanism as shown in step <highlight><bold>418</bold></highlight>. This enables the control of blanking without having to overwrite data stored in a storage cell as previously explained. Finally, method <highlight><bold>400</bold></highlight> may also comprise the alternative or optional step <highlight><bold>420</bold></highlight> of increasing the dynamic range of a DAC used to modulate video by moving the RMS voltage from a data cell into an active region. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5, a</cross-reference> flow chart is shown illustrating a alternative method <highlight><bold>500</bold></highlight> of driving a display in accordance with the present invention. In this instance, the method preferably comprises the step <highlight><bold>502</bold></highlight> of switching between a plurality of driver circuits using a first switching mechanism comprising a first pair of transistors and the step <highlight><bold>504</bold></highlight> of controlling a blanking function using a second switching mechanism. The second switching mechanism preferably comprises a second pair of transistors coupled to at least a supply voltage and wherein the second switching mechanism is controlled by at least one global address line. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Although the present invention has been described in conjunction with the embodiments disclosed herein, it should be understood that the foregoing description is intended to illustrate and not limit the scope of the invention as defined by the claims. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A display driver for a display unit having a memory element and a liquid crystal cell, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first display driver circuit having a first storage capacitor and a first differential amplifier coupled between the first storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second display driver circuit having a second storage capacitor an a second differential amplifier coupled between the second storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first switching arrangement coupled to the liquid crystal cell enabling the switching of the display driver between the first display driver circuit during a positive frame and the second display driver circuit during a negative frame; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second switching arrangement coupled to the liquid crystal cell and coupled to at least a supply voltage, wherein the second switching arrangement is controlled by at least one global address line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first and second differential amplifiers provides isolation between the first storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell and the second storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first switching arrangement comprises a first transistor driven by a first global switching voltage and a second transistor driven by a second global switching voltage. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second switching arrangement comprises a first transistor driven by a first global address line and a second transistor driven by a second global address line. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the first and second differential amplifiers comprises a pair of N-Channel transistors having respective sources coupled and a drain from one of the pair of N-Channel transistors serving as an output to the liquid crystal cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of the first and second differential amplifiers comprises a pair of N-Channel transistors having respective sources coupled and a current source which is gated by another N-channel transistor that gates the current source and ensures a predetermined voltage on a pixel. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. A method for driving a liquid crystal on silicon display having a plurality of driver circuits for a liquid crystal cell, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>switching between the plurality of driver circuits using a first switching arrangement comprising a first pair of transistors; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a blanking function using a second switching arrangement comprising a second pair of transistors coupled to at least a supply voltage and wherein the second switching arrangement is controlled by at least one global address line. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. A display unit having an array of liquid crystal cells, comprising: 
<claim-text>an array of display drivers, a given display driver being associated with a given liquid crystal cell and including: 
<claim-text>a driver circuit for the given liquid crystal cell, wherein the driver circuit includes a memory cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a switching arrangement coupled to the liquid crystal cell and to at least a supply voltage source, wherein the switching arrangement globally controls a voltage developed in the given liquid crystal cell via a signal path that bypasses the driver circuit for the given liquid crystal cell. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching arrangement enables the display driver circuit to control blanking without having to overwrite data stored in the memory cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the array of display drivers comprises a matrix switch driver. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the driver circuit comprises a first display driver circuit having a first storage capacitor and a first differential amplifier coupled between the first storage capacitor and a liquid crystal cell, a second display driver circuit having a second storage capacitor an a second differential amplifier coupled between the second storage capacitor and the liquid crystal cell, and a first switching arrangement enabling the switching of the display driver between the first display driver circuit during a positive frame and a second display driver circuit during a negative frame. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The display driver of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the switching arrangement comprises a first transistor controlled by a first global address line that determines when a supply voltage Vdd is applied to the liquid crystal cell and a second transistor controlled by a second global address line that determines when a supply voltage Vss is applied to the liquid crystal cell. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus for an array of liquid crystal cells arranged in rows and columns, comprising: 
<claim-text>a source of row select signals coupled to row select lines of said array of liquid crystal cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a source of column signals containing picture information coupled to column lines of said array of liquid crystal cells; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a first plurality of switches, a given switch of said first plurality of switches being responsive to a corresponding row select signal for coupling a corresponding column signal to a given liquid crystal cell to produce a voltage containing picture information in said given liquid crystal cell; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second plurality of switches, a corresponding switch of said second plurality of switches having an output coupled to said given liquid crystal cell for varying said given liquid crystal cell voltage via a signal path that excludes said corresponding column signal that is coupled to said given liquid crystal cell. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second plurality of switches are responsive to a common control signal and are controlled in common. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein each of said second plurality of switches changes state in common with the other switches of said second plurality of switches. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second plurality of switches apply a common voltage to each of said liquid crystal cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second plurality of switches vary in common a brightness level in each of said liquid crystal cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second plurality of switches produce in common a full brightness level in each of said liquid crystal cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said second plurality of switches produce in common a darkness level in each of said liquid crystal cells. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. A video display apparatus according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising a capacitance, wherein said given switch of said first plurality of switches that is coupled to said given liquid crystal cell is coupled to said capacitance for developing a second voltage in said capacitance that is coupled to said given liquid crystal cell via an amplifier.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001811A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
