<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001380A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001380A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001380</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09896756</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B42D015/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>283</class>
<subclass>060100</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Multi-purpose business form for invoicing, for payment of invoice, for reorder, for shipping, for remittance of payment and for even stacking of the form</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Gary</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Stewart</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Tod R. Nissle, Esq.</name-1>
<name-2>TOD R. NISSLE, P.C.</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>P.O. Box 55630</address-1>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<postalcode>85078</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A method and apparatus forms stacks of paper sheets. The sheets each have areas of different thickness. The sheets also include lines of prominence formed in thinner areas of the sheets. The lines of prominence function to increase the thickness of the thinner areas of each so the sheets stack evenly. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to business forms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> More particularly, the invention relates to business forms having die cut label areas and areas separable from the form along lines of weakening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In a further respect, the invention relates to a business form which can be utilized by a vendor to mail an invoice to a customer, can be used by the customer to pay the invoice, and can be used by the customer to reorder goods from the vendor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> In still another respect, the invention relates to a method and apparatus for forming stacks of business forms which are level and which do not tilt because of labels, backings, or other materials which are attached only to a portion of the business form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Business forms with address labels which can be peeled from the form are well known, as are business forms with lines of perforation which permit the forms to be torn along the lines of weakening. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> One function of a business form is to provide a mailing label which can used to address a package containing the business form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Another function of a business form is to provide an invoice which a customer can pay on receipt of the business form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A further function of a business form is to provide a means for reordering goods provided by a vendor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> Still another function of a business form is to provide a means for mailing a payment or order to a vendor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> A single business form which functions to fulfill each of the functions noted above apparently has not been provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> Another problem associated with business forms and other sheets of materials which are stacked is the formation of stacks which tilt to one side or another. The sheets tilt because labels or other materials are applied to only a portion of the sheet, making that portion of the sheet thicker. When a plurality of such sheets are stacked, the portion of the stack including the thicker portion of each sheet is higher than the portion of the stack which does not include the thicker portion of each sheet. As a result, the stack tilts. Tilting of the stack of sheets is undesirable because it adversely affects the ease with which the sheets feed into a printer, perforator, or other piece of processing equipment. When the stack of sheets tilts, it is more likely that one of the sheets will jam in the feeder on the piece of equipment being used to process the sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, it would be highly desirable to provide an improved multi-purpose unitary business form which would provide an invoice, a mailing label, means for paying the invoice, and means for reordering product from a vendor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> It would also be highly desirable to provide an improved method and apparatus for processing sheets of paper or other material which are not of uniform thickness and which tend to form a stack which tilts. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is a principal object of the instant invention to provide an improved business form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Another object of the invention is to provide an improved method for providing and using a business form to invoice and mail a customer and for the customer to pay the invoice and to reorder product from a vendor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A further object of the invention is to provide an improved method and apparatus for stacking sheets which each have an equivalent shape, contour, and dimension, and which each have portions that are thicker than other portions of the sheet. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Still another object of the invention is to provide an improved method and apparatus for stacking sheets of non-uniform thickness in a level stack such that each sheet in the stack generally lies in a flat plane parallel to the other sheets in the stack.</paragraph>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The foregoing and other, further and more specific objects and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following detailed description of the invention, taken in conjunction with the drawings, in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a top view illustrating a business form constructed in accordance with the principles of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a back view further illustrating construction details of the business form of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a section view of the business form of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> taken along section line <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> thereof and further illustrating construction details thereof; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a section view of a stack of business forms illustrating how lines of prominence formed in the business forms facilitate the formation of a level stack of forms; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a business form identical to the form of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> except for lines of prominence formed therein; and, </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a section view of a stack of business forms illustrating how lines of prominence formed in the business forms facilitate the formation of a level stack of forms.</paragraph>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Briefly, in accordance with the invention, I provide an improved business form comprising a first leaf having a front side, a back side, a width, a height, an outer peripheral edge; spaced apart first and second lines of weakening dividing the leaf into first, second, and third sections; an imprinted die cut area lying in the second section within the outer peripheral edge; a mailing label formed on the front side in the die cut area; an envelope address imprinted on the front side in the first section; an invoice imprinted on the front side in the third section; a sheet of material attached along three sides to the first section on the back side such that the sheet of material and the first section form an envelope; a third line of weakening in the first section forming a flap for the envelope; and, a sheet of liner material attached to portions of the first and second sections on the back side, the liner material extending over the flap of the envelope and including an adhesive layer which separates from the liner and adheres to the die cut area and the flap of the envelope. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> In a further embodiment of the invention, I provide an improved business form comprising a first leaf having a front side, a back side, a width, a height, and an outer peripheral edge; spaced apart first and second lines of weakening dividing the leaf into first, second and third sections; an imprinted die cut area lying in the second section within the outer peripheral edge; a mailing label formed on the front side in the die cut area; an envelope address imprinted on the front side in the first section; an invoice imprinted on the front side in the third section; a sheet of material attached along three sides to the first section on the back side such that the sheet of material and the first section form an envelope; a third line of weakening in the first section forming a flap for the envelope; and, a sheet of liner material attached to portions of the first and second sections on the back side, the liner material extending over the flap of the envelope and including an adhesive layer which separates from the liner and adheres to the die cut area and the flap of the envelope. The business form also includes at least one line of prominence extending outwardly from the front side of the third section. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, I provide a plurality of sheets of material of equivalent size. Each of the sheets has a plurality of lines of prominence. The lines of prominence for one of the sheets are at different locations on the sheet than are the lines of prominence on the remaining sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Turning now to the drawings, which depict the presently preferred embodiment of the invention for the purpose of illustrating the practice thereof and not by way of limitation of the scope of the invention, and in which like reference characters refer to corresponding elements throughout the several views, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates the front of a business form constructed in accordance with the invention. Form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a rectangular face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> extending between peripheral edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. Lines of weakening <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> divide form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> into rectangular sections <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. Section <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> is intermediate sections <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Section <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> includes an envelope mailing address <highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight> imprinted or otherwise formed on face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and includes return address block <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> formed on face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Section <highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight> includes a mailing label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> circumscribed by die-cut line <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. Label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is peeled off in the direction of arrow A. The words &ldquo;INVOICE AND RETURN ENVELOPE ENCLOSED&rdquo; are imprinted or otherwise formed on face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> on the face of label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A mailing address can be imprinted on the face of label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. When label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is peeled off, adhesive adheres to the back of label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and is used to fasten label <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to an envelope or package. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> includes an invoice imprinted or formed on face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and on the face of section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The invoice includes the words &ldquo;THIS IS YOUR INVOICE&rdquo;, &ldquo;PAYMENT DUE WITHIN 7 DAYS OF RECEIPT&rdquo;, &ldquo;PLEASE REMIT&rdquo;, &ldquo;INVOICE DATE&rdquo;, &ldquo;YOUR ACCOUNT NO.&rdquo;, and the address of American Handicapped and Disadvantaged Workers, Inc. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> also include a payment stub <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> imprinted or formed on face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> and on the face of stub <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. The payment stub includes the words &ldquo;RETURN THIS PART WITH PAYMENT&rdquo;, &ldquo;INDICATE AMOUNT ENCLOSED&rdquo;, and &ldquo;PUT BELOW ACCOUNT NO ON CHECK TO HELP US&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates the back of business form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> constructed in accordance with the invention. Form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes a rectangular back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> extending between peripheral edges <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Rectangular sheet of material <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes peripheral edges <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. Edge <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> lies along a portion of edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. Edge <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> lies along a portion of edge <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. Edge <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> lies along a portion of edge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. A reorder form is imprinted or otherwise formed on the face <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> of sheet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The portions of back surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> of sheet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> which are beneath peripheral portions <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> are adhered to back surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> by adhesive <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> such that sheet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> form an envelope. Since the portion of surface <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> beneath edge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> is not adhered to surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>, a piece of paper can be slid past edge <highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight> and between section <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> and sheet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> into the envelope. The envelope is detached from business form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> along line of weakening <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. Backing <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> is peeled off to expose adhesive <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> on the portion of surface <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> on envelope flap <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> Business form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> includes salient lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> formed in the section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. These lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> protrude and extend outwardly from the generally flat planar surface defined by section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and by the front surface of section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The purpose of lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is, when business forms are stacked, to give section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> a thickness which is closer to or is about equivalent to the increased thickness in the other sections of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which results when backing <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, sheet <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, adhesive <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and adhesive <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> are applied to selected portions of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> Lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> can extend any desired distance D above section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>). In many instances, however, the distance D is typically in the range of one to three thousandths of an inch. The width W can vary as desired. The distance T between lines of prominence can vary as desired, but it is presently preferred that within a distance T there are at least three lines of prominence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> can be formed by any desired means. Simply scoring a sheet of material along a line may form a line of prominence on the side of the sheet opposite the side on which the sheet was scored. Embossing techniques can be used to form lines of prominence. When the sheet is originally manufactured, it can be made with lines of prominence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> It is critical in the practice of the invention that at least every other sheet of material have lines of prominence formed at different places on the sheet. If each sheet of material has lines of prominence formed at the same locations on each sheet, then the lines of prominence will tend to nest one on top of the other, and the purpose of the invention will be defeated. In the practice of the invention, the lines of prominence are intended to function in the manner shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> and to act as spacers which function to level out sections <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A, and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B with respect to the portions of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> which have increased thickness due to layers of adhesive <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, layer of material <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, and backing layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, business form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> is identical to business forms <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. Forms <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B are stacked on top of and in registration with form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. Consequently, edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>A of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A is equivalent to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>B of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B is equivalent to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; sections <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B are each equivalent to section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; and, faces <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>B are equivalent to face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> Lines of prominence (or projections) <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> function to lift section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A into an orientation in which section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A is generally parallel to the remainder of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A. Lines of prominence <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> function to lift section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B into an orientation in which section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B is generally parallel to the remainder of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. If another form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C (not shown) identical to form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B were placed on top of and in registration with form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, lines of prominence <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> would function to maintain the section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C in an orientation in which section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C was generally parallel to the remainder of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B. It is important to note that the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> in form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are formed at different locations than and are offset from the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> of forms <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B and that, as a result, the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> do not nest with lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, nor would lines of prominence <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> nest with lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> or with lines <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. As noted earlier, it not necessary that each sheet have lines of prominence which are located at different positions that the lines of prominence of every other sheet. In general, it is of primary importance that the lines of prominence in each adjacent pair of sheets in a stack of sheet do not nest. It is probably also advantageous, however, to have at least three or four different locations for lines of prominence so that there are in each stack at least three or four sheets where the location of the lines of prominence for each of the three or four sheets is different from the location of the lines of prominence in each of the other sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> to <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> each extend upwardly in the same direction from a section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B. The lines of prominence can, if desired, extend downwardly from a section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>B. A single sheet may also, if desired, have one or more lines of prominence which extend upwardly and have one or more other lines of prominence which extend downwardly. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> While it is possible to form a line of prominence in a thicker section (for example, in the section of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> including backing <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> of a form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> or other sheet), the principal purpose of lines of prominence dictates that they be formed in portions of a sheet which are thinner and which ordinarily (if lines of prominence were not formed therein) would tend to cause a stack of the sheets to tilt because the thicker portions of the sheets would make one side of the stack of sheets higher than the other side of the stack formed by the thinner portions of the sheets in the stack. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>, business forms <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D, and <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E are identical to business form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> except for the location of lines of prominence formed therein. Consequently, edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>C of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>CA is equivalent to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>D of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D is equivalent to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight> of form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>; sections <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>D, and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>E are each equivalent to section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>; and, faces <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> C, <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> D, and <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>E are equivalent to face <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, forms <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C to <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E are stacked in registration with each another. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, lines of prominence <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> extend continuously across the form from edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to edge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. In conjunction with this feature, the location of lines of prominence on one form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are, as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>, offset along the form from the location of lines of prominence on another form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>B, <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> In contrast to the lines of prominence illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</cross-reference>, the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference> do not extend continuously from edge <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> to edge <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Instead, each line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> extends only a partial distance between edges <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. Further, the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> for form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C are formed along axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is a line which is parallel to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>C and is a distance L1 from edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> Similarly, for form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>), axis X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is a line which is parallel to edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E and is a distance L3 from edge <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>E. Distance L3 equals distance L1 and the position of axis X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E is identical to the position of axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C. There is an axis X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> (not shown) for form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D which is at a position on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D which is identical to the position of axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C. In other words, in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, axis X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is directly above, is in registration with, and is generally parallel to axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Axis X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is directly above, is in registration with, and is generally parallel to axes X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The lines of prominence formed along axis X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D (not visible) will not nest with the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight> formed in form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C along axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> because the lines of prominence formed in form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> are, at least in part, laterally offset from the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>&mdash;in the same manner that lines of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> are laterally offset from lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> One way to offset laterally&mdash;at least partially&mdash;a line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> from a line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is to have the shape and dimension of line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> be identical to the shape and dimension of line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> and to offset or move the position of line of prominence along axis X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> so that the position of line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>E is different from the position of line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> on form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Another way to offset&mdash;at least partially&mdash;a line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> from a line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is to make the length or width or other shape or dimension of line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> smaller than that of line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> such that line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> can not nest in line of prominence <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> An advantage of the embodiment of the invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference> is that all the lines of prominence on each business form can be made along a line (or lines) which is at the same location on each business form. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference>, each business form has lines of prominence formed along only one axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> of each business form. As would be appreciated by those of skill in the art, lines of prominence can be formed along two or more axes on each form or piece of material. In addition, lines of prominence formed on a business form need not be parallel to axes X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, but can be formed along a line or axis which is normal to or at some other angle to axes X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, X<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> each have a flat plateau or upper surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight>, respectively. Such flat upper surfaces <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>73</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>75</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>77</bold></highlight> facilitate the support of a business form or other sheet stacked on top of and contacting said surfaces. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The shape, contour, dimension of each line of prominence and the number of lines of prominence necessary to support in a level orientation a business form or other sheet stacked on top of the lines of prominence depends on a variety of factors including the stiffness and thickness of the stacked sheet and the strength of the lines of prominence (especially when a high stack of sheets is anticipated). A desired shape, contour, and dimension of each line of prominence, along with the number of and location of the lines of prominence, can be determined for various kinds of forms and sheets. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> Another advantageous feature of the lines of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>71</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>76</bold></highlight> is that the transition from, for example, section <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>C to line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight> is accomplished by curved concave radii surfaces <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> to reduce the likelihood that the form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C will be torn during formation of line of prominence <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. Curved convex radii surfaces <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>83</bold></highlight> also transition from sides <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>85</bold></highlight> to flat surface <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> In another embodiment of the invention, a line or lines of prominence are formed along an axis X<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> which also functions as a line of weakening used in folding or tearing a form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C. In this embodiment of the invention, the line or lines of prominence serve the dual function of leveling a stack of paper and of facilitating the folding or tearing of the form <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>C or other sheet of material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> Having described my invention in such terms as to enable those of skill in the art to make and practice it, and having described the presently preferred embodiments thereof,</paragraph>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A business form comprising 
<claim-text>(a) a first leaf having a front side, a back side, a width, a height, an outer peripheral edge; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b spaced apart first and second lines of weakening dividing said leaf into first, second and third sections; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) an imprinted die cut area lying in said second section within said outer peripheral edge; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a mailing label formed on said front side in said die cut area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) an envelope address imprinted on said front side in said first section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) an invoice imprinted on said front side in said third section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) a sheet of material attached along three sides to said first section on said back side such that said sheet of material and said first section form an envelope; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) a third line of weakening in said first section forming a flap for said envelope; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) a sheet of liner material attached to portions of said first and second sections on said back side, said liner material extending over said flap of said envelope and including an adhesive layer which separates from said liner and adheres to said die cut area and said flap of said envelope. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. A business form comprising 
<claim-text>(a) a first leaf having a front side, a back side, a width, a height, an outer peripheral edge; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(b spaced apart first and second lines of weakening dividing said leaf into first, second and third sections; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) an imprinted die cut area lying in said second section within said outer peripheral edge; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a mailing label formed on said front side in said die cut area; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) an envelope address imprinted on said front side in said first section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) an invoice imprinted on said front side in said third section; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) a sheet of material attached along three sides to said first section on said back side such that said sheet of material and said first section form an envelope; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) a third line of weakening in said first section forming a flap for said envelope; </claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) a sheet of liner material attached to portions of said first and second sections on said back side, said liner material extending over said flap of said envelope and including an adhesive layer which separates from said liner and adheres to said die cut area and said flap of said envelope; and, (j) at least one line of prominence extending outwardly from said front side of said third section. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. A plurality of sheets of material of equivalent size, each of said sheets having a plurality of lines of prominence, the line of prominence for one of said sheets being at different locations than the lines of prominence of the remaining sheets.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001380A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
