<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030000595A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030000595A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030000595</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10133559</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010601</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B65B003/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>B65B001/04</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>141</class>
<subclass>002000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Ever-flow water delivery system</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>James</given-name>
<middle-name>Victor</middle-name>
<family-name>Culberson</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Moyock</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Ricky</given-name>
<middle-name>E.</middle-name>
<family-name>Lloyd</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Moyock</city>
<state>NC</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>James Victor Culberson</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO Box 87</address-1>
<city>Moyock</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postalcode>27958</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An improved water input method for recreational vehicles utilizing the convenience of automatic fill valve technology. Water from a pressurized source is directed to a water tank that is equipped with an automatic fill valve which efficiently regulates a continuous supply of water to the recreational vehicle through a static water tank. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Not applicable. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> This invention relates to recreational vehicles, specifically to an improved water input method for recreational vehicles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Persons have various ways by which they get away from the hustle and bustle of every day life. One very popular diversion is the use of recreational vehicles. People who use recreational vehicles are referred to as &ldquo;campers.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Campers have been limited to conventional water tanks, which do nothing more than hold water, for their recreational vehicles. Upon arrival at a campsite, campers must decide whether to use the pressurized hook-up or to fill the static water tank in the camper. Some recreational vehicles are only equipped with static water tanks based on their size. In such cases, the camper must hook to the campsite water supply and wait outside, sometimes in less than favorable weather conditions, until the tank is full and then turn off the water. It is not uncommon for campers to make numerous trips outside to the faucet depending upon size of the water tank and the amount of water required by the campers. Some tanks are so small that a couple of sinks of dishes and a few drinks of water completely deplete the water in the tank. Multiple trips to the faucet has been part an inconvenient part of the camping experience ever since the development of recreational vehicles. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The Ever-Flow Water Delivery System is a single connection for recreational vehicles that combines the maximum benefits of static water tanks and pressurized water systems. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS AND ADVANTAGES </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, besides the objects and advantages of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery system described in our above patent, several objects and advantages of the present invention are: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> (a) to provide a continuous supply of water, to any type of pump system, for any type of recreational vehicle by utilizing automatic fill valve technology; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> (b) to eliminate the need for manufacturers to engineer multiple types of water hook-ups for recreational vehicles; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> (c) to utilize automatic fill valve technology in water tanks of varying size; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> (d) to allow campers the convenience of a single trip to the faucet for the duration of their onsite camping experience.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DRAWING FIGURES AND PHOTOS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows a side-view schematic of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> shows the external view of the working invention of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> shows the internal components of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> shows the external fixtures associated with water in-flow. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a side-view schematic for moving the water from the outside of the tank to the inside of the tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> shows the application of moving the water from outside of the tank to the inside of the tank. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> shows the internal apparatus of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> shows the external fixtures associated with water out-flow the the pump system of the recreational vehicle. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Photos <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> and FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>&mdash;Working Embodiment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> A standard garden hose quick-disconnect assembly is threaded into a {fraction (3/4)}&Prime; (three-quarter inch) PVC coupling which is glued to a {fraction (3/4)}&Prime; to {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (three-quarter inch to one-half inch) PVC reducer with female threads on the {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) side. A {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC coupling is threaded into the reducer. An 8.5 inch section of {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC pipe is then glued into the other side of the {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) coupling. (Photos <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> A {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) 90-degree PVC elbow is glued to the distal end of the 8.5 inch son of {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC pipe. The {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC elbow is inserted into the lid of the water container through a 1&Prime; (one inch) hole. (Photo <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> A 7.5 inch section of {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC pipe is glued to the end of the {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) 90-degree elbow and enters the inside of the water container through a {fraction (7/8)}&Prime; (seven-eighths inch) hole on the under-side of the lid. The External Fixtures are secured to the lid by one {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch). PVC &ldquo;cradle&rdquo; which is secured through 1&Prime; (one-inch) hole in top of the lid. (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Photos <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> And <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> A {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; to {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch to one-half inch) coupling, with male threads on the distal end, is glued to the distal end of the 7.5 inch section of {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC pipe which is passed through lid. A valve with these specifications ({fraction (1/2)}&Prime;I.P. or {fraction (3/8)}&Prime;I.P.&times;{fraction (3/8)}&Prime; O.D.) is threaded onto the distal end (male end) of the {fraction (1/2)}&Prime; (one-half inch) PVC coupling. A {fraction (3/8)}&Prime; (three-eighths inch) compression&times;{fraction (7/8)}&Prime; (seven-eighths inch)&times;11&Prime; (eleven inch) toilet supply hose is secured to-valve. The toilet supply hose is attached to an automatic water closet float valve (automatic toilet tank fill valve) which is secured to a 1.5 inch-wide aluminum brace by a coupling nut after threading the proximal end of the water closet float valve through a 1 &amp; {fraction (1/8)}&Prime; (one and one-eighths inch) hole. Aluminum brace is secured to water container lid by 2 (two) &frac14;&Prime;&times;1.5&Prime; (one-quarter inch by one and one-half inch) machine bolts, nuts and washers. (Photos <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> Photo <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> Out-spout is fitted with {fraction (5/8)}&Prime; O.D.&times;{fraction (1/2)}&Prime;I.D.&times;1&prime; (five-eighths inch O.D. by one-half inch I.D. by one foot) section of vinyl tubing. Distal end of tubing is clamped to &frac14;&Prime;&times;2&Prime; (one-quarter inch by 2 inch) galvanized nipple which is threaded on both ends. Distal end of galvanized nipple is attached to shut-off valve which is fitted with another &frac14;&Prime;&times;2&Prime; (one-quarter inch by 2 inch) galvanized nipple which is fitted with a section of {fraction (5/8)}&Prime; O.D.&times;{fraction (1/2)}&Prime; I.D. (five-eighths inch O.D. by one-half inch I.D.) vinyl tubing of sufficient length which leads to the pump system. (Photo <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> Alternative Embodiments </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> The working embodiment of the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System utilized a 68 quart ice chest as the water tank. The water tank itself may or may not have a hinged lid and various sizes of water tanks might be used. The automatic fill valve utilized in the working embodiment is the one disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 4,703,653 although a different type of automatic fill valve might also be used. Accordingly, it is to be appreciated that various changes may be made in the structure and materials of the apparatus of the invention by those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the idea for the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System was spawned in response to a need to replace the conventional water tank in a slide-in recreational vehicle. Therefore, it is also to be appreciated that various types of changes may be made in the structure and materials of the apparatus of the invention by those skilled in the art for any type of vehicle which connects to and disconnects from pressurized water sources without departing from the spirit of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> Operation </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The Ever-Flow Water Delivery System is placed in operation when the camper connects the recreational vehicle to a pressurized water source. The water travels through the in-flow fixtures (Photos <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) and into the tank. The desired water level of the tank is regulated by the automatic fill valve (Photos <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>). The water exits the tank via the out-flow fixtures (Photo <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>) and travels to the pump system of the recreational vehicle. When it is time for the recreational vehicle to move, the camper disconnects the pressurized water source from the recreational vehicle. The camper could leave from the pressurized water source with a filled tank should the camper so choose. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">CONCLUSION, RAMIFICATIONS, AND SCOPE </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, the reader will see that the Ever-Flow Water Delivery System will provide a convenient means by which campers (and others) will enjoy a continuous stream of water with one simple hook-up regardless of the size of the recreational vehicle. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A water input method for recreational vehicles comprising: 
<claim-text>a. a recreational vehicle equipped with a water tank, and </claim-text>
<claim-text>b. an automatic fill valve mounted in said water tank, whereby the water supply in said water tank is maintained by said fill valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030000595A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
