<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.CDX SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.CDX" NDATA CDX>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.MOL SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.MOL" NDATA MOL>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.CDX SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.CDX" NDATA CDX>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.MOL SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.MOL" NDATA MOL>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.CDX SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.CDX" NDATA CDX>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.MOL SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.MOL" NDATA MOL>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.CDX SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.CDX" NDATA CDX>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.MOL SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.MOL" NDATA MOL>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030003480A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030003480A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030003480</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10126781</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020422</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-122577</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010420</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-168968</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010605</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-168969</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010605</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-168982</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010605</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>2001-168983</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010605</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>C12Q001/68</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/53</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>G01N033/542</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>C12M001/34</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>006000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>287200</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>435</class>
<subclass>007900</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Reactive solid support and DNA fragment detection tool</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroko</given-name>
<family-name>Inomata</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Asaka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Masayoshi</given-name>
<family-name>Kojima</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Asaka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Yukio</given-name>
<family-name>Sudo</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Asaka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Shinoki</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Asaka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Osamu</given-name>
<family-name>Seshimoto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Asaka-shi</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>BIRCH STEWART KOLASCH &amp; BIRCH</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>PO BOX 747</address-1>
<city>FALLS CHURCH</city>
<state>VA</state>
<postalcode>22040-0747</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">Objects of the present invention are to provide a reactive solid support capable of particularly advantageously being used for stably binding and fixing a previously prepared nucleotide derivative such as an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide, or a peptide nucleic acid or their analogs in a high density state on the surface of the solid support. According to the present invention, there is provided a reactive solid support having convex and concave portions on its surface, to which a group of vinyl sulfonyl groups or their reactive precursor groups are fixed by covalent bond via a linking group, respectively. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a detection tool useful for analyzing a structure of a biopolymer substance, and particularly relates to a detection tool useful for efficiently analyzing the expression, mutation, polymorphism and the like of a gene, wherein a large number of polymer substances originally from organisms or their analogs are aligned and fixed on the surface of a solid support having convex and concave portions. The present invention particularly relates to a high density array type detection tool (DNA detection chip) useful for analyzing a base sequence of a DNA fragment sample wherein a number of nucleotide derivatives or their analogs are aligned and fixed to the surface of a solid support having convex and concave portions, and a reactive solid support capable of advantageously being utilized for preparing the high density array type detection tool. Furthermore, the present invention relates to a chip useful for proteome analysis/proteomics wherein a protein or protein binding substance (except for nucleic acid) is fixed on the surface of the solid support, a method for detecting using said chip, and a method of manufacturing it. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The technological development for efficiently analyzing gene functions of a variety of organisms has been rapidly progressed, and a detection tool called as a DNA chip where nucleotide derivatives such as a large number of DNA fragments or synthesized oligonucleotides or the like are fixed on the surface of a solid phase substrate has been employed in order to analyze the base sequence of the DNAs or DNA fragments. A molecule for detection such as a DNA or its fragments or a synthesized oligonucleotide like a nucleotide derivative bound to the surface of such a solid phase substrate is also referred to as a probe molecule. A representative DNA chip is a microarray in which a large number of probe molecules are aligned and fixed to a solid support such as a slide glass or the like. DNA chip related technologies relating to manufacturing of a DNA chip and its use are considered to be capable of also utilizable for detecting a biomolecules other than DNA. Therefore, these are expected to provide a new means for aiming at drug discovery research, development of a method of diagnosis of diseases or preventing the disease, or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The DNA chip related technologies has been materialized since the fact that the method for determining the base sequence of a DNA by hybridization with an oligonucleotide was developed. Although this method could overcome the limitation of the method for determining the base sequence using gel electrophoresis, initially it did not come into practice. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> Subsequently, by developing the DNA chip configured as described above and its preparation technique, the expression, mutation, polymorphism or the like of a gene has been capable of efficiently being examined in a short period of time. Specifically, a DNA fragment sample showing the complementarity to a DNA fragment or an oligonucleotide on the DNA chip prepared (which is also referred to as a target DNA fragment) is, in general, detected by utilizing the hybridization of the DNA fragment or the oligonucleotide on the DNA chip with the labeled DNA fragment sample. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> In order to put the DNA chip preparation technique into practical use, a technology for aligning a large number of DNA fragments and oligonucleotides to surface of a solid support in high density and stable state is required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> As for a method for preparing a DNA chip, there are known a method for directly synthesizing oligonucleotide on the surface of the solid support (referred to as &ldquo;on-chip method&rdquo;) and a method in which a DNA fragment or an oligonucleotide previously prepared is bound to the surface of the solid support. As for the on-chip method, a method for selectively synthesizing an oligonucleotide in the predetermined minute matrix region by combining use of a protective group selectively removable using photoirradiation, the photolithography technology used for fabricating a semiconductor device and y a technology for synthesizing a solid phase (referred to as &ldquo;masking technology&rdquo;) is representative. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> As a method for binding and fixing a DNA fragment or an oligonucleotide previously prepared on the surface of the solid support, following methods are known corresponding to kinds of DNA fragments and kinds of solid supports. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> (1) In the case where a DNA fragment to be fixed is a cDNA (complementary DNA synthesized by utilizing a mRNA as a template) or PCR products (DNA fragment obtained by amplifying the cDNA by a PCR method) , in general, the cDNAs or PCR products are dotted to the surface of the solid support which was surface-treated with a polycationic compound (poly-lysine, polyethyleneimine or the like) using a spotter device provided in a DNA chip preparation device, and are electrostatically bound to the solid support by utilizing the charge held in the DNA fragments. As a method for treating the surface of the solid support, a method of employing a silane coupling agent containing an amino group, an aldehyde group, an epoxy group or the like is also utilized. In the surface treatment using the silane coupling agent, since the amino group, the aldehyde group or the like is fixed on the surface of the solid support by covalent bond, it is more stably fixed on the surface of the solid support, as compared with the case of surface treatment with a polycationic compound. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> As a modified method for utilizing the charge of the DNA fragments described above, there is reported a method wherein PCR products modified with an amino group is suspended in SSC (standard salt-citric acid buffer solution), dotted to the surface of the sililated slide glass, incubated, and then treated with sodium boron hydride and then with heating. However, there is a problem that it is difficult to necessarily obtain the sufficient fixation stability of the DNA fragments by this fixation method. In DNA chip technologies, detection limit is important. Therefore, binding and fixing of DNA fragments on the surface of the solid support in a sufficient amount (i.e., in a high density) and in a stable state has a direct influence on increase of the detection limit of hybridization of DNA fragment probes and labeled nucleic acid fragments samples. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> (2) In the case where an oligonucleotide (probe molecule) to be fixed is a synthesized oligonucleotide, there is known a method, in which an oligonucleotide into which a reactive group has been introduced is synthesized, then the oligonucleotide is dotted to the surface of the solid support surface-treated so as to previously form the reactive group, thereby binding and fixing the oligonucleotide to the surface of the solid support by covalent bond. For example, there are known a method in which an amino group-introduced oligonucleotide is reacted with the surface of the slide glass to which an amino group is introduced in the presence of PDC (p-phenylene diisothiocyanate), and a method in which an aldehyde group-introduced oligonucleotide is reacted with said slide glass. These two methods are more advantageous from the viewpoint that an oligonucleotide is stably bound and fixed to the surface of the solid support, as compared with the above-described method (1) for electrostatically binding by utilizing the charge of the DNA fragments. However, there are problems that in a method of performing the reaction in the presence of PDC, the reaction of PDC and an amino group-introduced oligonucleotide is slow, and in a method of using an aldehyde group-introduced oligonucleotide, the stability of Schiff base which is a reactive product is low (that is, hydrolysis is easily occurred). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> In recent years, a technology employing an oligonucleotide analog which is referred to as PNA (peptide nucleic acid) instead of an oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide (also including a synthesized oligonucleotide or polynucleotide and a DNA molecule and DNA fragment, and a RNA molecule and RNA fragment) as a probe molecule of a DNA chip has also been proposed. As a method for fixing PNA to the solid phase substrate by covalent bond, a method of using the combination of avidin and biotin is also known (Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. H11-332595 gazette). In this publication gazette, a technology utilizing a surface plasmon resonance (SPR) biosenser as the solid phase substrate is also described. Utilizing the DNA chip in which a probe molecule is fixed on the surface plasmon resonance biosenser, a DNA fragment bound to its surface via hybridization can be detected by utilizing the surface plasmon resonance phenomenon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> Moreover, as a substrate of the DNA chip, use of a charge coupled device (CCD) is also known (Nucleic Acid Research, 1994, Vol. 22, No. 11, pp. 2124-2125). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> In Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. H04-228076 gazette (corresponding to U.S. Pat. No. 5,387,505), a technology for isolating a target DNA is describe. In this technology, the target DNA having biotin molecule is bound to a substrate, the surface of which an avidins molecule is fixed on. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> Japanese Patent Publication No. H07-43380 gazette (corresponding to U.S. Pat. No.5,094,962) describes a detection tool used for ligand-receptor assay, that is, an analyzing tool that an receptor molecule is bound to surface of a microporous polymer particle having a reactively active group on its surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in recent years, since the genomic analysis has been almost completed, the &ldquo;proteome/proteomics&rdquo; research, that provides essential information in order to finally understand meanings of the gene information and to simulate the life-activities of the cells, has been progressed. The term &ldquo;proteome&rdquo; means the all sets of proteins which are translated and produced in a specific cell, an apparatus and an organ, and the research field of high-level information analysis of chemical structure, total amount, expression period, modification after translation, formation of aggregation and the like are referred to as &ldquo;proteomics&rdquo;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The proteome research includes a profiling of proteins, an identification and precise analysis of proteins, a interaction network analysis and construction of a proteome data base, and is a field where these technologies are applied to the life science researches. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> Among these, as the interaction network analysis method, a yeast two-hybrid method and a phage display method have been performed, and as a method of utilizing affinity capture, an immunoprecipitation method, a BIA-MA method, a column switching-mass spectrometry method and the like have been performed (&ldquo;Proteome analysis method&rdquo;, pp. 163-211, published by Yodosha, Co., Ltd. ,2000). However, any of these interaction network analyses listed above has not achieved a high throughput analysis. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> The report has been made by Schreiber et al. on a protein microarray for a high throughput analysis of interaction of proteins (Science 289: 1760-1763, 2000). This is a method in which protein aqueous solution is dotted to the slide glass having an aldehyde group, blocked with BSA solution, then reacted with the protein solution to carry out detection by a fluorescence scanner. In this case, there is a problem that the stability of Schiff base which is a reaction product between an aldehyde group and an amino group is low (usually, hydrolysis is easily occurred). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> In addition to these, as a method of fixing protein to the solid phase, a method, in which a hydrophobic polypeptide is introduced into the end of the protein, is described in Japanese Patent Publication No. H07-53108 gazette. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In Japanese Patent No. 2,922,040, a method of fixing an antibody protein with protein A molecule film is described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> In the international publication WO 00/61282,the description on a porous solid support is disclosed. The thickness from the supporting body is made in the range from 0.01 to 70 &mgr;m and the porosity is in the range from 10 to 90% by coating particles mainly made of inorganic substances. When this porous solid support is employed, there is a merit that a fixation amount of an organism polymer is increased because its surface area is enlarged. However, in this case, there are problems such that (1) in the case where detection is carried out by fluorescence, luminescence, RI or the like, background level is increased since scattering by exciting light, emitting substances or the like is increased; (2) since impregnation amount of liquid at the time of spotting is increased, it is difficult to decrease the diameter of the spot, and to prepare a high density array; and (3) since the labeled specimen intrudes into a cavity between particles, it is necessary to sufficiently perform a washing step, and in the case of an insufficient washing, the background level is often increased. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Objects of the present invention are to provide a reactive solid support capable of particularly advantageously being used for stably binding and fixing a previously prepared nucleotide derivative such as an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide, or a peptide nucleic acid or their analogs in a high density state on the surface of the solid support, and to provide a detection tool for detecting DNA, RNA or their fragments having a specific base sequence portion, in which the nucleotide derivative or its analog has been bound and fixed on the reactive solid support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Further objects of the present invention are to provide a chip in which at least one protein or protein binding substance is bound and fixed to a reactive solid support which can achieve rapid and stable binding and fixing, and to provide a detection method for detecting a specifically binding target substance by utilizing the chip. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The present invention provides the following (1) to (58). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> (1) A reactive solid support having convex and concave portions on its surface, to which a group of vinyl sulfonyl groups or their reactive precursor groups are fixed by covalent bond via a linking group, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> (2) The reactive solid support of above (1) , wherein the convex and concave portions comprise particles formed by an inorganic substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> (3) The reactive solid support of above (2), wherein the convex and concave portions comprise a particle of silicon, alumina or titanium having the average diameter of 50 &mgr;m or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> (4) The reactive solid support of above (1), wherein the convex and concave portions are formed by an organic substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> (5) The reactive solid support of above (4), wherein the organic substance is a macromolecular polymer or an aggregate of a macromolecular polymer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> (6) The reactive solid support of above (1), wherein a linked body of the vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group and the linking group is represented by the following formula: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> in the above-described formula, X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L represents a linking group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> (7) The reactive solid support of above (6), wherein X represents a vinyl group represented by &mdash;CH&boxH;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> (8) The reactive solid support of above (6), wherein L represents a linking group containing an atom of a bivalence or more except for carbon atom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> (9) The reactive solid support of above (6), wherein L represents a linking group having a linking portion selected from the group consisted of &mdash;NH&mdash;, &mdash;S&mdash; and &mdash;O&mdash;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> (10) The reactive solid support of above (6) , wherein L represents a linking group represented by &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;NH&mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; or &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;S&mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; wherein R<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents the same meanings as described above, L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group, and n represents either 0 or 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> (11) The reactive solid support of above (6), wherein L represents a linking group represented by &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;NHCH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; wherein L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group, and n represents either 0 or 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> (12) The reactive solid support of above (10), wherein L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group containing a group represented by &mdash;OSi-&mdash;and n represents 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> (13) The reactive solid support of above (1) , wherein said solid support is a substrate in a sheet shape selected from the group consisted of a glass substrate, a resin substrate, a glass substrate or a resin substrate surface-treated with a silane coupling agent and a glass substrate or a resin substrate having a covering layer on its surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> (14) The reactive solid support of above (13), wherein said solid support is a substrate in a sheet shape selected from the group consisted of a silicate glass substrate, a silicate glass substrate surface-treated with a silane coupling agent and a silicate glass substrate covered by an organic covering layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> (15) A method of manufacturing the reactive solid support of above (6) , wherein a disulfone compound represented by the following formula is brought into contact with a reactive solid support to the surface of which a reactive group is introduced: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight></in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> in the above-described formula, each of X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> (16) The method of manufacturing a reactive solid support of above (15), in which the reactive group introduced to the surface of said solid support is an amino group, a mercapto group or a hydroxyl group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> (17) A manufacturing method of a solid support comprising a nucleotide derivative or its analog bound to the surface of the support via a linking group having a sulfonyl group, wherein a surface of a reactive solid support having a convex and concave portion on which each of a group of vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group is fixed by covalent bond, is contacted with a nucleotide derivative or its analog having a reactive group which is capable of reacting with said reactive group to form a covalent bond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> (18) The manufacturing method of above (17), wherein said nucleotide derivative or its analog is selected from the group consisted of an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide and a peptide nucleic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> (19) The manufacturing method of above (17), wherein a reactive solid support that a linked body of a vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group represented by the following formula and a linking group is bound to and fixed on, is used as a reactive solid support having a convex and concave portion: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> in the above-described formula, X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L represents a linking group or a single bond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> (20) The manufacturing method of above (19), wherein X represents a reactive group represented by &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>wherein each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents the same meanings as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> (21) A solid support having a convex and concave portion, in which a nucleotide derivative or its analog obtained by a manufacturing method of any one of above (17) to (20) is bound and fixed to surface of the solid support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> (22) A method of binding and fixing a complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide, wherein the solid support having the convex and concave portion to which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound of above (21) is contacted with an oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity to said fixed nucleotide derivative or its analog in the presence of an aqueous medium. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> (23) The method of above (22) , wherein a detectable label is bound to said complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> (24) A solid support to which a oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity is bound and fixed wherein the solid support having the convex and concave portion to which, to the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound as in (21) , a oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity to said nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound in a complementary manner. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> (25) The solid support of above (24) , wherein a detectable label is bound to said oligonucleotide or polynucleotide having the complementarity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> (26) A method of identifying or screening a gene, wherein the solid support having a convex and concave portion to the surface of which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound and fixed as in above (20), or the solid support to which the complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide is bound and fixed as in above (22) is utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> (27) A biological material chip, wherein A, which represents a residue of at least one protein or protein binding substance, is bound to a solid support having a convex and concave portion by covalent bond via a sulfonyl group as the following formula (I): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Solid support-L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&mdash;A &emsp;&emsp;(I) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> in the formula (I) , L represents a linking group; X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;; each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and A represents a residue of a protein or protein binding substance except for nucleic acid. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> (28) The chip of above (27), wherein said protein or protein binding substance bounded to the surface is an antibody, an antibody fragment, a ligand, an antigen, a hapten or a receptor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> (29) The chip of above (27), wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is avidins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> (30) The chip of above (29), in which avidins are an avidin, a streptoavidin or altered bodies thereof which are capable of forming a stable complex with a biotin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> (31) The chip of above (27) , wherein said protein bound to the surface is a nucleic acid recognition protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> (32) The chip of above (31) , in which said nucleic acid recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> (33) The chip of above (32) , wherein said double stranded DNA. recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition antibody. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> (34) The chip of above (32) , wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a DNA transcription factor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> (35) The chip of above (32) , wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a protein having a Zinc finger motif or a Ring finger motif. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> (36) The chip of any one of above (27) to (35), wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle formed by an inorganic substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> (37) The chip of above 36, wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle containing silicon, alumina or titanium of which average particle diameter is 50 &mgr;m or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> (38) The chip of any of above (27) to (35) , in which said convex and concave portion is formed by an organic,substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> (39) The chip of above (38) , wherein said organic substance comprises a high molecular polymer or an aggregate of a high molecular polymer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> (40) The chip of above (27) , wherein said solid support is a glass, a plastic, an electrode surface or a sensor chip surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> (41) A method of detecting a target substance, comprising the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> contacting the chip of above (27) with a sample containing a target substance which specifically binds to said protein or protein binding substance except for nucleic acid supported on the surface of said chip; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> detecting formation of reciprocal binding between said protein or protein binding substance and said target substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> (42) The method of detecting a target substance of above (41), wherein said target substance is labeled with at least one component capable of generating a detectable signal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> (43) The method of detecting a target substance of above (41) , comprising a step of performing blocking processing of the chip with an aqueous solution of an amino acid, a peptide or a protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> (44) The method of manufacturing the chip of above (27) comprising a step in which a solid support having a convex and concave portion containing a vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group represented by the following formula (II) on its surface is contacted with at least one protein or protein binding substance having a reactive group which forms a covalent bond by reacting with said vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group: </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime;&emsp;&emsp;(II) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> in the above-described formula (II), L represents a linking group which binds &mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime; to a solid support; X&prime; represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) or &mdash;CH(R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>)(Y); each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and Y represents a group which is substituted by a neucleophilic reagent or a group which is eliminated as a &ldquo;HY&rdquo; by a base </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> (45) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is an antibody, an antibody fragment, a ligand, an antigen, a hapten or a receptor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> (46) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is avidins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> (47) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (46), wherein avidins are an avidin, a streptoavidin or altered bodies thereof which are capable of forming a stable complex with a biotin. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> (48) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), wherein said protein bound to the surface is a nucleic acid recognition protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> (49) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (48), wherein said nucleic acid recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> (50) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (49), wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition antibody. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> (51) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (49), wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a DNA transcription factor. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> (52) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (49), wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a protein having a Zinc finger motif or a Ring finger motif. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> (53) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle formed by an inorganic substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> (54) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (36), wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle containing silicon, alumina or titanium of which average particle diameter is 50 &mgr;m or less. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> (55) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), in which said convex and concave portion is formed by an organic substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> (56) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (55), wherein said organic substance is a high molecular polymer or an aggregate of a high molecular polymer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> (57) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), in which a solid support is a glass, a plastic, an electrode surface or a sensor chip surface. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0089" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0089&rsqb;</number> (58) The method of manufacturing a chip of above (44), comprising the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0090" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0090&rsqb;</number> fixing at least one protein or protein binding substance to a solid support having convex and concave portions by contacting said protein or protein binding substance to said solid support; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0091" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0091&rsqb;</number> performing blocking process of a free vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group located on the surface of said solid support with an amino acid, a peptide or a protein aqueous solution.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0092" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0092&rsqb;</number> The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate presently preferred embodiments of the invention, and together with the general description given above and the detailed description of the preferred embodiments given below, serve to explain the principles of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0093" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0093&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing a representative oligonucleotide fixed solid support of the present invention and a representative method of the present invention for fixing an oligonucleotide; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0094" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0094&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing the configuration of a protein chip, which is a representative embodiment of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0095" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0095&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a schematic diagram showing a fixation method of Example 1; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0096" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0096&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a graphical representation showing the results of detecting a ligand using an antibody fixed slide according to the present invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0097" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0097&rsqb;</number> A reactive solid support of the present invention has the configuration in which a group of vinyl sulfonyl groups or their reactive precursor groups are bound and fixed on the surface of the solid support having convex and concave portions via a linking group by covalent bond. The reactive solid support of the present invention can be manufactured by preparing the solid support having convex and concave portions to the surface of which a reactive group has been previously introduced, and bringing this solid support into contact with a compound having a reactive group capable of forming a covalent bond by reacting with a reactive group provided to the surface of the support at one of end portions or nearby the end portion and having a vinyl sufonyl group or a reactive precursor group of the vinyl sufonyl group at the other end portion or nearby the end portion. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0098" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0098&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that the solid support is a particularly hydrophobic or lower hydrophilic substrate having a flat and smooth surface. Moreover, a substrate having a surface of lower degree of flatness with convex and concave portions can be also employed. As a substance for the solid support, a variety of porous substances such as glass, cement, ceramics or new ceramics such as potteries or the like, polymers such as polyethylene terephthalate, cellulose acetate, polycarbonate of bisphenol A, polystyrene, polymethyl methacrylate or the like, silicon, activated carbon, porous glass, porous ceramics, porous silicon, porous activated carbon, woven fabric, knitted fabric, non-woven fabric, filter paper, short fiber, membrane filter or the like can be listed. It is preferable that the size of a fine hole of a porous substance is in the range from 2 to 1000 nm, and particularly preferable in the range from 2 to 500 nm. It is particularly preferable that the substance of a solid support is a glass or silicon. This is because of the easiness of surface treatment and the easiness of analysis by an electrochemical method. It is preferable that the thickness of the solid support is in the range from 100 to 2000 &mgr;m. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0099" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0099&rsqb;</number> As for the solid support having convex and concave portions used for manufacturing a reactive solid support of the present invention, a variety of solid supports conventionally used for manufacturing DNA chips or proposed for manufacturing the DNA chip can be preferably utilized. As an example of such a solid support, a glass substrate, a resin substrate, a glass substrate or resin substrate surface treated by a silane coupling agent, or a glass substrate or a resin substrate having a covering layer on the surface, or the like can be listed. As for the solid support, a silicate glass substrate, a silicate glass substrate surface treated by a silane coupling agent, or a silicate glass substrate covered by an organic covering layer is particularly preferable. Moreover, it may be an electrode substrate used as a substrate of a DNA chip used for an electrochemical analyzing method. Moreover, it may be a variety of functional substrates such as a substrate used for the above-described surface plasmon resonance (SPR) biosensor, a charge coupled device (CCD) or the like. Furthermore, adding to these substances, a solid support in a particle shape can be also employed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0100" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0100&rsqb;</number> As a substance having convex and concave properties,. a particle formed by an inorganic substance is preferable. For example, a metal oxide such as colloidal silica, alumina sol, titanium oxide, ZrO<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>or the like, a plastic having a hydroxyl group, latex or the like is listed. Preferably diameter of the particle is 50 &mgr;m or less. Particularly in the case where a co-focal laser fluorescence detection is carried out, it is preferable to use particles whose diameter is 100 &mgr;m or less in order to suppress the background level. As a method of coating a substance having the convex and concave properties on the solid support, a method can be used in which the substance having the convex and concave properties is mixed with a silane coupling agent, and brought into contact with the solid support to bring about reaction. Thus the convex and concave properties can be easily given to the solid support. Particularly in the case where the solid support is a glass, this method is particularly effective. It can be also prepared by bringing the substance having the convex and concave properties into contact with the solid support, drying it, and then treating it with a silane coupling agent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0101" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0101&rsqb;</number> Generation of the convex and concave portions by coating the solid support with a particulate substance provides considerably increased surface area compared with that of flat and smooth surface, resulting in an advantage such that bonded amount of DNA fragments to be fixed on the solid support can be increased to a large extent. Furthermore, the form of single layer is more advantageous than the form of laminated layers from the following reasons: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0102" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0102&rsqb;</number> 1. In the case where detection is carried our by fluorescence, luminescence, RI or the like, the scattering due to the exciting light, emitting substance or the like is decreased, and the background level is lowered. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0103" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0103&rsqb;</number> 2. Since the impregnation of the liquid at the time of spotting is slight, the diameter of spot is capable of being made smaller, and an array having a high density can be prepared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0104" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0104&rsqb;</number> 3. In an operation after the hybridization, a post-treatment washing step for removing an un-reacted labeled specimen is easily performed. In the case of the laminated layers, the labeled specimen intrudes into the cavity between particles. Therefore, it is necessary to sufficiently carry out the washing step, and in the case where it is not sufficient, the background level may be often heightened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0105" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0105&rsqb;</number> As for an organic substance having the convex and concave properties, monosaccharides such as glucose, fructose and the like or their derivatives, polysaccharides such as dextran, amylose, starch and the like or their derivatives, for example, carboxymethyl starch, and high molecular polymers such as PVA, polyacrylic acid, cellulose, carboxymethyl cellulose, polyacetal and the like can be listed. Particularly, an organic substance having a hydroxyl group can form an aggregation by using it in combination with a silane coupling agent, and the convex and concave portions can be easily formed. The size of convex and concave portions (height) is preferably 50 &mgr;m or less, particularly in the case where detection is carried out by the co-focus laser fluorescence, it is preferable to use the particle of 100 nm or less in order to suppress the background level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0106" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0106&rsqb;</number> Using an aminated silane coupling agent, it is possible to introduce both the convex and concave portions and an amino group to the surface at the same time. Further, using TMOS or TEOS, it is also possible to initially introduce the convex and concave portions, then to introduce the amino group to the surface by reacting the aminated silane coupling agent. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0107" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0107&rsqb;</number> It is desirable to perform the covering treatment on the surface of the solid support having the convex and concave portions by a polymer containing an amino group such as a polycationic compound on side chain (for example, poly-L-lysine, polyethyleneimine, polyalkylamine or the like is preferable, and poly-L-lysine is more preferable) in order to bind and fix bifunctional reactive compounds such as divinyl sulfone compound or the like by covalent bond (in this case, the reactive group introduced to the surface of the solid support is an amino group). Alternatively, the surface of the solid support may be brought into contact and treated with a surface treatment agent having a reactive group such as a silane coupling agent which reacts with the surface of the solid support and a reactive group such as an amino group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0108" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0108&rsqb;</number> In the case where the covering treatment is performed with a polycationic compound, an amino group or a mercapto group is introduced to the surface of the solid support having the convex and concave portions by electrostatically binding between the polymer compound and the surface of the solid support. On the other hand, in the case where the surface treatment is performed by a silane coupling agent, the amino group or mercapto group stably exists on the surface of the solid support since it is bound and fixed to the surface of the solid support by covalent bond. In addition to an amino group or a mercapto group, an aldehyde group, an epoxy group, a carboxyl group or a hydroxyl group may be also preferably introduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0109" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0109&rsqb;</number> As a silane coupling agent having an amino group, it is preferable to use &ggr;-aminopropyltriethoxy silane, N-&bgr;(aminoethyl)-&ggr;-aminopropyltrimethoxy silane, or N-&bgr;(aminoethyl)-&ggr;-aminopropylmethyldimethoxy silane, and particularly it is preferable to use &ggr;-aminopropyl triethoxy silane. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0110" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0110&rsqb;</number> The treatment with a silane coupling agent may be performed in combination with the treatment using a polycationic compound. Using this method, an electrostatical interaction between a hydrophobic- or a low hydrophilic-solid support and DNA fragments can be promoted. A layer consisted of a hydrophilic polymer having a charge or the like or a layer consisted of a crosslinking agent may be further provided on the surface of the solid support treated by a polycationic compound. As a result of providing such a layer, the height of the convex and concave portions of the solid support treated by the polycationic compound can be reduced. Depending on the types of the solid supports, it is possible that a hydrophilic polymer is contained in the support, and the solid support subjected to such a treatment can be also preferably used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0111" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0111&rsqb;</number> On the surface of the usually utilized solid support for a DNA chip, a large number of regions previously fractioned or expected are set and provided, and in each region, as described above, a reactive group which is capable of reacting with bifunctional reactive compound such as divinyl sulfone compound or the like has been previously introduced. A reactive group such as the above-described amino group, mercapto group or hydroxyl group or the like is provided on the surface of each region of the solid support which is to be employed. However, on a solid support not having such a reactive group, as described above, the introduction of a reactive group is performed by surface treatment using a silane coupling agent, or by utilizing a method of coating and covering a polymer or the like having a reactive group such as an amino group on side chain on the surface of the solid support . </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0112" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0112&rsqb;</number> In the solid support equipped with a reactive group, as a result of bringing it into contact with a bifunctional reactive compound such as divinyl sulfone compound or the like, the reactive group and bifunctional reactive compound are reacted to form a covalent bond, the reactive group portion of the solid support is extended, and a reactive chain having a vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group at its end or nearby the end is formed, thereby providing a reactive solid support of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0113" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0113&rsqb;</number> In a reactive solid support of the present invention, a linked body of a vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group and a linking group introduced on the surface of the solid support is desirably a linked body represented by the following formula (1): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X &emsp;&emsp;(1) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0114" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0114&rsqb;</number> In the above-described formula (1), X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y (reactive precursor group). Each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms. Examples of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms include a methyl group, an ethyl group, an n-propyl group, an n-butyl group, and an n-hexyl group. A methyl group is particularly preferable. Aryl groups include a phenyl group and a naphthyl group. It is preferable that each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents a hydrogen atom, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0115" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0115&rsqb;</number> Y represents a group which is substituted by a nucleophilic reagent such as &mdash;OH, &mdash;OR<highlight><superscript>0</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;SH, NH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, NH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>0 </superscript></highlight>(wherein R<highlight><superscript>0 </superscript></highlight>represents a group such as alkyl group except for hydrogen atom), or a group which is eliminated as &ldquo;HY&rdquo; by base. Examples thereof include a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M, or a quaternary pyridinium group (R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms or halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents a hydrogen atom, an alkaline metal atom, or an ammonium group). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0116" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0116&rsqb;</number> L represents a bivalent or more than bivalent linking group for linking the solid support or a linking group binding to the solid support with the above-described &mdash;SO2-X group. However, Lmaybe a single bond. Examples of the bivalent linking groups include an alkylene group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aliphatic cyclic group having 3 to 16 carbon atoms, an arylene group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, a heterocyclic group having 2 to 20 carbon atoms containing 1 to 3 hetero atoms selected from the group consisted of N, S and P, a group containing one group or the combination of a plurality of groups selected from the group consisted of &mdash;O&mdash;, &mdash;S&mdash;, &mdash;SO&mdash;, &mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;, &mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>&mdash;, &mdash;NR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>&mdash;,&mdash;CO&mdash; and their combinations are preferable. R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>is preferably a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 15 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 21 carbon atoms containing an alkyl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, and more preferably a hydrogen atom or an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, and particularly preferably a hydrogen atom, a methyl group or an ethyl group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0117" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0117&rsqb;</number> In the case where L represents a group containing the combination of two or more of the groups selected from the group consisted of &mdash;NR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>&mdash;, &mdash;SONR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>&mdash;, &mdash;CONR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>&mdash;, NR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>COO&mdash;, and &mdash;NR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>CONR<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>&mdash;, these R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>may bind each other to form a ring. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0118" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0118&rsqb;</number> An alkyl group of R11, an aryl group of R11 and an aralkyl group of R11 may have a substituent. Such substituents include an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydroxyl group, an alkoxy group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an alkenyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, a carbomoyl group having 2 to 7 carbon atoms, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aralkyl group having 7 to 16 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, an sulfamoyl group (or its Na salt, K salt or the like) , a sulfo group (or its Na salt, K salt or the like) a carboxylic acid group (or its sodium salt, potassium salt or the like), a halogen atom, an alkenylene group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an arylene group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, sulfonyl group and their combinations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0119" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0119&rsqb;</number> The preferable examples of the above-described &ldquo;&mdash;X&rdquo; group will be indicated below. Moreover, examples of a group which can be used as &ldquo;&mdash;L&mdash;SO2-X&rdquo; will be indicated as described later.  
<chemistry-cwu id="CHEM-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<image id="EMI-C00001" he="692.4771" wi="174.26745" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.TIF"/>
<chemistry-chemdraw-file id="CHEMCDX-00001" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.CDX"/>
<chemistry-mol-file id="CHEMMOL-00001" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00001.MOL"/>
</chemistry-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0120" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0120&rsqb;</number> In the above-described examples, it is preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&rdquo; represents (X1), (X2), (X3), (X4), (X7), (X8), (X13) or (X14). It is more preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&rdquo; represents (X1) or (X2) It is particularly preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&rdquo; represents a vinyl group represented by (X1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0121" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0121&rsqb;</number> Preferable examples of L will be indicated below. &ldquo;a&rdquo; represents an integer of 1 to 6, preferably 1 or 2, and particularly preferably 1. &ldquo;b&rdquo; represents an integer of 0 to 6, and preferably either 2 or 3.  
<chemistry-cwu id="CHEM-US-00002">
<number>2</number>
<image id="EMI-C00002" he="278.6805" wi="195.3882" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.TIF"/>
<chemistry-chemdraw-file id="CHEMCDX-00002" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.CDX"/>
<chemistry-mol-file id="CHEMMOL-00002" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00002.MOL"/>
</chemistry-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0122" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0122&rsqb;</number> As for L, in addition to the above-described bivalent linking groups, a group that a hydrogen atom of the alkylene group in the above-described formula is substituted with a &mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH&boxH;CH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>group is also preferable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0123" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0123&rsqb;</number> As for a bifunctional reactive compound utilized for obtaining a solid support to which a vinyl sulfonyl group represented by the foregoing formula (1) or its reactive precursor group is fixed by covalent bond, a disulfone compound represented by the following formula (2) can be advantageously utilized. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>&emsp;&emsp;(2) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0124" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0124&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;In the above-described formula, each of X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>independently from each other represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y (reactive precursor group); each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>independently from each other represent an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and ammonium group; and L<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0125" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0125&rsqb;</number> Specifically, a reactive solid support of the present invention can be easily manufactured by bringing a disulfone compound represented by the above-described formula (2) into contact with the above mentioned solid support, for example in the aqueous atmosphere. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0126" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0126&rsqb;</number> The representative examples of disulfone compound preferably used in the present invention will be shown in the followings. It should be noted that a disulfone compound might be used by mixing two types or more. (Si) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;C -S0<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH&equals;CH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(S2) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;C tSC<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>0CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-S0<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH&equals;CH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(S3) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;C IS0<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH&equals;CH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(S4) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;CH-SC<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-C H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C H(OH)CH <highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-S &deg; <highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-C H&equals;C H<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(S5) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;C ~SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C ONHC H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>NH COC H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-S &deg; <highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>- CH&equals;C HH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>(S6) H<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C&equals;C FhSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>C ONHCH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>NHCOCH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-S O<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-CH&equals;CH<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight> 
<chemistry-cwu id="CHEM-US-00003">
<number>3</number>
<image id="EMI-C00003" he="328.60485" wi="450.05625" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.TIF"/>
<chemistry-chemdraw-file id="CHEMCDX-00003" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.CDX"/>
<chemistry-mol-file id="CHEMMOL-00003" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00003.MOL"/>
</chemistry-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0127" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0127&rsqb;</number> Representative examples of disulfone compound represented by the above-described formula (2) include 1,2-bis(vinylsulfonylacetamide)ethane &lsqb;corresponding to the above-described S1&rsqb;. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0128" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0128&rsqb;</number> As for a method for synthesizing a disulfone compound used in the present invention, the details have been described in a variety of gazettes, for example, such as Japanese Patent Publication No. S47-2429, Japanese Patent Publication No. S50-35807, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. S49-24435, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. S53-41551, Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. S59-18944 or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0129" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0129&rsqb;</number> In order to prepare a detection tool (in general, referred to as a DNA chip) for detecting by fixing a polynucleotide or an oligonucleotide originally from the nature such as DNA, RNA, DNA fragments, RNA fragments or the like by utilizing the reactive solid support obtained as described above, a method for bringing the above-described reactive solid support into contact with a nucleotide derivative or its analog equipped with a reactive group such as amino group which reacts with a vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group on the above-described support surface to form a covalent bond is utilized. That is to say, in this way, a detection tool equipped with a probe molecule of the desired nucleotide derivative or its analog (what is called a DNA chip) can be prepared. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0130" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0130&rsqb;</number> A vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group bound via covalent bond to the surface of a solid phase substrate of the present invention can be readily preserved in a stable state since it has a high resistance to the hydrolysis, and can form a stable covalent bond by rapidly reacting with a nucleotide derivative or a reactive group of its analog in which amino group has been previously provided or a reactive group such as amino group has been introduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0131" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0131&rsqb;</number> Representative examples of a nucleotide derivative and its analog used as a probe molecule include an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide, and a peptide nucleic acid. These nucleotide derivatives or their analogs may be originally from the nature (DNA, DNA fragment, RNA or RNA fragment), or may be a synthetic compound. Moreover, nucleotide derivatives or its analog include a variety of analogous compounds such as what is called a LNA having a crosslinking group at its sugar unit portion (J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1998, 120:13252-13253) are included. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0132" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0132&rsqb;</number> In the case where DNA fragments are used as a probe molecule, these are divided into two types depending on purposes. In order to examine the expression of a gene, it is preferable to use a polynucleotide such as cDNA, one portion of cDNA, or EST. Functions of these polynucleotides may be unknown, but in general, these are prepared by amplifying cDNA library, genomic library, or the total genome as a template on the basis of the sequences registered on a data base by a PCR method (hereinafter, referred to as &ldquo;PCR product&rdquo;). Ones not amplified by a PCR method can be also preferably used. In order to examine the mutation and polymorphism of a gene, it is preferable to synthesize a variety of oligonucleotides corresponding to mutation and polymorphism based on the known sequence which is to be the standard, and use them. Furthermore, in the case where the purpose is to analyze the base sequence, it is preferable to synthesize 4<highlight><superscript>n </superscript></highlight>(n represents the length of the base) species of oligonucleotides and use them. As for the base sequence of a DNA fragment, it is preferable that its sequence has been previously determined by a general base sequence determination method. The size of the DNA fragment is preferably from dimmer to 50-mer, and particularly preferably from 10- to 25-mer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0133" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0133&rsqb;</number> On one end of a nucleotide derivative such as an oligonucleotide and a DNA fragment, or its analog, a reactive group which forms a covalent bond by reacting with the foregoing vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group is introduced. Such reactive groups include an amino group, an imino group, hydrazino group, carbomoyl group, hydrazinocarbonyl group or carboxyimido group, and the amino group is particularly preferable. The reactive group is usually bound to an oligonucleotide or a DNA fragment via a crosslinker. As the crosslinker, for example, an alkylene group or a N-alkylamino-alkylene group is utilized, and a hexylene group or a N-methylamino-hexylene group is preferable, and a hexylene group is particularly preferable. It should be noted that since a peptide nucleic acid (PNA) has an amino group, usually it is not necessary to introduce another reactive group. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0134" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0134&rsqb;</number> Bringing a nucleotide derivative or its analog having a reactive group into contact with a reactive solid support is usually carried out by dotting the aqueous solution of the nucleotide derivative or its analog to the surface of the reactive solid support. Concretely, it is preferable that after an aqueous solution is prepared by dissolving or dispersing the nucleotide derivative or its analog having a reactive group in an aqueous medium, the aqueous solution is pipetted into 96 wells or 384 wells plastic plate, and the pipetted aqueous solution is dropped on the surface of the solid support using a spotter device or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0135" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0135&rsqb;</number> In order to prevent the nucleotide derivative or its analog from being dried after the dotting, a substance having a high boiling point may be added in the aqueous solution in which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is dissolved or dispersed. The substance having a high boiling point is preferably a substance that can be dissolved in the aqueous solution in which the nucleotide derivative or its analog to be dotted is dissolved or dispersed, does not hinder hybridization with a sample such as a nucleic acid fragment sample (target nucleic acid fragment) which is an object of the detection, and has a not very high viscosity. Such substances include glycerin, ethylene glycol, dimethyl sulfoxide and a hydrophilic polymer having a lower molecular weight. Examples of the hydrophilic polymers include polyacrylamide, polyethylene glycol and sodium polyacrylate. Preferable molecular weight of this polymer is in the range from 10<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight>. As the substance having a high boiling point, it is more preferable to use glycerin or ethylene glycol, and particularly preferable to use glycerin. Preferable concentration of the substance having a high boiling point is in the range from 0.1 to 2% by volume, and particularly preferably 0.5 to 1% by volume in the aqueous solution of the nucleotide derivative or its analog. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0136" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0136&rsqb;</number> Moreover, for the sake of the same purpose, it is also preferable to place the solid support after the dotting of a nucleotide derivative or its analog under the circumstances where the humidity is 90% or more and the temperature is in the range from 25 to 50&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0137" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0137&rsqb;</number> A post-treatment by ultraviolet ray, sodium borohydride or Schiff reagent may be carried out after the dotting of the nucleotide derivative or its analog having a reactive group. These post-treatments may be carried out by combining a plurality kinds of them, and the combination of heating treatment and the ultraviolet ray treatment is particularly preferable. These post-treatments are particularly effective in the case where the surface of the solid support is treated only by a polycationic compound. Incubation after the dotting is also preferable. After the incubation, removal of unreacted nucleotide derivatives or its analogs by washing is preferable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0138" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0138&rsqb;</number> A preferable fixed amount (numerical quantity) of nucleotide derivatives or its analogs with respect to the surface of the solid support is in the range from 10<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>per cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. A preferable amount of nucleotide derivatives or its analogs is in the range from 1 to 10<highlight><superscript>&minus;15 </superscript></highlight>mol, and is several ng or less in weight. By dotting, the aqueous solution of nucleotide derivatives or its analogs is fixed in a dot shape to the surface of the solid support. The shape of the dot is nearly circular. No variation in the shape is important for the quantitative analysis of a gene expression and the analysis of single nucleotide polymorphism. A preferable distance between each dot is in the range from 0 to 1.5 mm, and a particularly preferable distance is in the range from 100 to 300 &mgr;m. As for the size of a dot, a preferable diameter of it is in the range from 50 to 300 &mgr;m. A preferable amount of the solution containing nucleotide derivatives or its analogs for dotting to the surface of the solid support is in the range from 100 pL to 1 &mgr;L, and a particularly preferable amount is in the range from 1 to 100 nL. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0139" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0139&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> schematically shows a method for manufacturing an oligonucleotide fixed solid support which is a representative aspect of the present invention and a configuration of a representative oligonucleotide fixed solid support. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0140" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0140&rsqb;</number> As a method for manufacturing a solid support having convex and concave portions of the present invention to which an oligonucleotide is fixed, in the case where a disulfone compound represented by the foregoing formula (2) is employed, four types of methods for manufacturing can be utilized depending on X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and X<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0141" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0141&rsqb;</number> FIG. I shows (a) a method for manufacturing a solid support (C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) to which the oligonucleotide is fixed using a disulfone compound of the formula (2) of which both of X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represent &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y (reactive precursor group), and (b) a method for manufacturing an oligonucleotide fixed solid support (C2) using the disulfone wherein X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y and X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>. Here, supposing that X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a group reacting in the first place with a reactive group (R) introduced on the surface of the solid support 1, a method for manufacturing the solid support using the disulfone where X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represent &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>may also be useful. Hereinafter, description will be made supposing that &ldquo;X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&rdquo; is a group reacting in the first place with a reactive group (R) introduced on the surface of the solid support 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0142" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0142&rsqb;</number> The manufacturing methods (a) and (b) will be described below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0143" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0143&rsqb;</number> Step (1): A &mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>group is introduced to the solid support by bringing a disulfone compound represented by the formula (1) into contact with the surface of the solid support 1 into which the reactive group (R) is introduced &lsqb;solid support (A)&rsqb;, and substituting &mdash;Y portion of X1 with a reactive group (R). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0144" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0144&rsqb;</number> Step (2): A reactive group (Z) is added by bringing an oligonucleotide 2 having a reactive group (Z) at one end into contact with X<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>of &mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>group introduced in the Step (1), or &mdash;Y of the X<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>is substituted with the reactive group (Z) by bringing the oligonucleotide 2 into contact with Y. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0145" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0145&rsqb;</number> A support of the present invention for fixing a probe molecule may be manufactured by the following method using &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>as X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, supposing that X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>is a group reacting in the first place with the reactive group (R) introduced to the surface of the solid support 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0146" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0146&rsqb;</number> Step (1): A &mdash;R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>C&mdash;R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>HC&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>group is introduced to the surface of the solid support by bringing a disulfone compound represented by the formula (I) into contact with the surface of the solid support (A) consisted of solid support having the convex and concave portions (solid support 1) to the surface of which the active group (R) is introduced, and adding the reactive group (R) to &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>of X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0147" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0147&rsqb;</number> Step (2): The reactive group (Z) is added by bringing an oligonucleotide having the reactive group (Z) at one end into contact with X2 of &mdash;R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>C&mdash;R<highlight><subscript>1</subscript></highlight>HC&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>group introduced in the Step (1) , or &mdash;Y of the X<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>is substituted with the reactive group (Z) by bringing the oligonucleotide 2 into contact with Y. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0148" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0148&rsqb;</number> The oligonucleotide having the reactive group (Z) at one end is a compound shown by the reference numeral 2 in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. A crosslinker (Q) , though it is not essential, exists in general between the reactive group (Z) and phosphate ester group as a matter of convenience for preparation. A-phosphate group-NNNN,,,NN represents an oligonucleotide. R represents a group determined by the reaction between the reactive group (R) and X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, and Z<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a group determined by the reaction between X and the reactive group (Z), respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0149" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0149&rsqb;</number> When the oligonucleotide 2 having the reactive group (Z) is dotted to the surface of the solid support (B) having the convex and concave portions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, although the reaction between X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;Y of X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and the reactive oligonucleotide fragment 2 is occurred, an unreacted X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>to which the oligonucleotide 2 is not bound also exists on the surface of solid support (B). In this case, there is a possibility that such X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>reacts in a non-specific manner with a labeled nucleic acid fragment sample in a hybridization to be performed later resulting in a problem that non-specific binding may be measured. Therefore, it is preferable that the X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>(i.e., a halogen atom of X<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, for example) has been previously subjected to a masking treatment. It is preferable that the masking treatment is performed by bringing an anionic compound having an amino group or a mercapto group into contact with the surface of the solid support (C) (or (C2)). Since the oligonucleotide 2 has a negative charge, the oligonucleotide 2 can be prevented from reacting with the unreacted X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>by generating negative charge also on the surface of the solid support (C). As for such an anionic compound, any one can be used if it reacts with a halogen atom of X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and has a negative charge (COO<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, SO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, PO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, or PO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>). Among them, an amino acid is preferable, and glycine or cysteine is particularly preferable. Further, taurine is also preferably used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0150" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0150&rsqb;</number> The shelf life of a solid support manufactured according to the present invention, in which a nucleotide derivative or its analog is fixed, is usually several weeks for a cDNA fixed solid support to which cDNA is fixed, and the shelf life of a solid support to which a synthesized oligonucleotide is fixed is further longer. A solid support of the present invention to which an oligonucleotide or its analog is fixed is utilized for monitoring the gene expressions, determining the base sequences, analyzing the mutations, analyzing the polymorphism or the like. The principle of the detection is based on the hybridization with the labeled sample nucleic acid fragment, which will be described later. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0151" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0151&rsqb;</number> As a labeling method, an RI method and a non-RI method (fluorescence method, biotin method, chemiluminescence method or the like) are known, and in the present invention, use of the fluorescence method is preferable. As for a fluorescent substance utilized for a fluorescent labeling, although any can be used if it can bind to the basic portion of nucleic acid. For example, a cyanine dye (e.g., Cy3, Cy5 or the like of Cy Dye&trade; series, which is commercially available), rhodamine 6G reagent, N-acetoxy-N2-acetylaminofluorene (AAF) or AAIF (iodine derivative of AAF) can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0152" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0152&rsqb;</number> As a nucleic acid fragment sample, usually, a nucleic acid fragment sample such as a DNA fragment sample or a RNA fragment sample whose sequence and function is not known is used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0153" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0153&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that a nucleic acid fragment sample is isolated from the cell or tissue sample of eucaryote for the purpose of examining the gene expression. In the case where the sample is a genome, it is preferably isolated from any given tissue sample except for red blood cell. It is preferable that any given tissue except for red blood cell is peripheral blood lymphocyte, skin, hair, sperm or the like. In the case where the sample is an mRNA, it is preferable that it is extracted from the tissue sample in which the mRNA is expressed. It is preferable that a labeled cDNA is prepared from mRNA by incorporating a labeled dNTP (&ldquo;dNTP&rdquo; means a deoxyribonucleotide in which the base is adenine (A), cytosine (C), guanine (G) or thymine (T)) using reverse transcription reaction. As a dNTP, use of dCTP is preferable because of chemical stability. Although the amount of the mRNA required for one hybridization is different depending on the amount of liquid to be spotted, and the type of labeling material, it is several &mgr;g or less. It is desired that the nucleic acid fragment sample has been previously depolymerized in the case where a DNA fragment on the nucleotide derivative or its analog fixed solid support is an oligoDNA. In the case of aprokaryotic cell, since the selective extraction of an mRNA is difficult, it is preferable that the total RNA is labeled. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0154" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0154&rsqb;</number> As for a nucleic acid fragment sample, for the purpose of examining the mutation and polymorphism of a gene, it is preferable to obtain it by performing PCR of the target region in a reaction system containing the labeled primer or the labeled dNTP. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0155" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0155&rsqb;</number> It is preferable that hybridization is carried out by dotting an aqueous solution, which is previously pipetted into a 96 wells or 384 wells plastic plate, in which labeled nucleic acid fragment samples are dissolved or dispersed, to the solid support of the present invention to which nucleotide derivatives or its analogs are fixed. The preferable amount of the solution for dotting is in the range from 1 to 100 nL. The hybridization is preferably carried out in the temperature range from room temperature to 70&deg; C., and for the period from 6 to 20 hours. After the completion of hybridization, it is preferable that washing are performed using a mixed solution of a surfactant and a buffer solution to remove unreacted nucleic acid fragment samples. As a surfactant, it is preferable to use sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS). As a buffer solution, citrate buffer solution, phosphate buffer solution, borate buffer solution, Tris buffer solution, Good&apos; buffer solution or the like can be used. It is particularly preferable to use citrate buffer solution. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0156" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0156&rsqb;</number> The hybridization using the solid support to which nucleotide derivatives or its analogs are fixed is characterized in that the amount of usage of the labeled nucleic acid fragment samples can be decreased to a very minute amount. Therefore, it is necessary to set the optimal conditions of the hybridization depending on the length of chain of the nucleotide derivatives or its analogs fixed to the solid support and the types of the labeled nucleic acid fragment samples. For the analysis of gene expression, it is preferable that a hybridization for a long time period is performed so as to be capable of sufficiently detecting even a lower expressing gene For the detection of a single nucleotide polymorphism, it is preferable that a hybridization for a short period is performed. Moreover, it is also characterized in that comparison or quantitative determination of the expression amount are made possible using a single solid support to which DNA fragments are fixed by previously preparing two types of the nucleic acid fragment sample labeled by fluorescent substances different from each other and using them in a hybridization at the same time. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0157" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0157&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the present invention relates to a biological material chip characterized in that the residue A of at least one protein or protein binding substance is bound to the solid support having the convex and concave portions by covalent bond via sulfonyl group as is shown in the following formula (I). </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Solid phase support-L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&mdash;A &emsp;&emsp;(I) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0158" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0158&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;In the above-described formula, L represents a linking group; X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;; each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>represents, independently from each other, a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and A represents a residue of a protein or a protein binding substance (except for nucleic acid)&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0159" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0159&rsqb;</number> Representative examples of a protein or a protein binding substance to be fixed include an antibody or antibody fragment, a ligand, an antigen, an antigenic determinant such as a hapten or the like, a receptor, a ligand, avidins and a nucleic acid recognition protein, but are not limited thereto. Representative examples of a nucleic acid recognition protein include double strand recognition protein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0160" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0160&rsqb;</number> Avidins include avidin, streptavidin and these altered bodies that can form a stable complex with biotin. The phrase &ldquo;can form a stable complex&rdquo; means that a complex having a dissociation constant approximate to the dissociation constant of biotin-avidin complex (10<highlight><superscript>&minus;15</superscript></highlight>M) can be formed. The altered body means a body being modified or its fragment of avidin or streptavidin originally from the nature, or recombinants of these. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0161" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0161&rsqb;</number> The nucleic acid recognition proteins include a double stranded DNA recognition substance, but are not limited thereto. The double stranded DNA recognition substances include a substance which recognizes a double stranded DNA and specifically binds to it. Examples of the double stranded DNA recognition substance include a DNA transcription factor, a mismatch repairing protein, a double stranded DNA recognition antibody, or a peptide nucleic acid. Furthermore, the double stranded DNA recognition substances include substances having Zinc Finger motif or Ring finger motif. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0162" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0162&rsqb;</number> The DNA transcription factor is a substance that binds to the promoter region on gene and controls the transcription from DNA to mRNA (Takaaki, Tamura: Transcription Factor, published by Yodosha, Co., Ltd., 1995). Accordingly, it is known that the transcription factor specifically binds to a double stranded DNA of the specific sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0163" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0163&rsqb;</number> Among a large number of transcription factors, Zinc Finger Protein, that is, a transcription factor group having Zinc finger and Ring Finger motifs, shows a very high occurrence rate in eucaryote, and 1% of the genome seems to code for them. Plabo et al. have analyzed the tertiary structure of Zinc Finger motif and elucidated the mechanism of its binding to DNA (Science 252:809 (1991)). Further, Choo et al. have succeeded in preparing a Zinc Finger Protein group which binds to the specific sequence but which does not exist in the nature, by a gene recombinant method (Nature 372: 642 (1994), PNAS 91: 11163 (1994)). Furthermore, the Scripps Research Institute group has succeeded in preparing a novel Zinc Finger Protein group by Phage Display (PNAS 95: 2812 (1998); 96: 2758 (1999)). As described above, the DNA transcription factor group represented by Zinc Finger Protein originally has the nature of binding to a double stranded DNA, and according to the researches in recent years, it has been made possible to prepare a recombinant which recognizes a given DNA sequence. It is possible to efficiently capture a double stranded DNA on a support by fixing such proteins. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0164" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0164&rsqb;</number> Besides these, the nucleic acid binding substances include a helix-loop-helix protein and a substance having an Ets domain. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0165" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0165&rsqb;</number> The protein binding substances to be fixed (except for nucleic acid) include hapten, biotins (biotin, biocytin, desthiobiotin, oxybiotin or their derivatives that can form a stable complex with avidin). The phrase &ldquo;can form a stable complex&rdquo; means that a complex having a dissociation constant approximate to the dissociation constant of biotin-avidin complex (10<highlight><superscript>&minus;15</superscript></highlight>M) can be formed. Furthermore, peptides, sugars, hormones, pharmaceuticals, antibiotics and the like are listed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0166" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0166&rsqb;</number> A protein or a protein binding substance to be fixed to the solid support having the convex and concave portions forms a covalent bond via sulfonyl group with its amino group or mercapto group existing within it. Further, the covalent bond via sulfonyl group may be formed by introducing an amino group, an imino group, a hydrazine group, a carbomoyl group, a hydrazinocarbonyl group, a mercapto group or a carboxyimido group and the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0167" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0167&rsqb;</number> A chip consisted of the solid support having the convex and concave portions to which a protein or a protein binding substance (e.g., antibody, avidins and nucleic acid recognition protein) is fixed, can fix the target substance on it, by bringing the chip into contact with a target substance (e.g., ligand, biotins and nucleic acid) that specifically react with the fixed protein or protein binding substance in the presence of an aqueous medium. It is desirable that a detectable label (e.g., fluorescene label, enzyme label or the like) is bound to the target substance of specific binding character to be fixed (e.g., ligand, biotins, and nucleic acid) so as to be capable of detecting its fixation from the exterior. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0168" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0168&rsqb;</number> As for a solid support, any form, for example, a plate, a microwell, beads, stick or the like can be employed if it does not have an adverse effect on the binding formation between members of the specific binding partners. As the solid support, supports described above in the present specification can be used. For the convenience of operation, the solid support may be processed in a form of magnetic material or an electrode. The substance having the convex and concave properties is also as described above in the present specification. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0169" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0169&rsqb;</number> In the present invention, a protein or protein binding substance A on the chip is bound to the solid support having the convex and concave portions by covalent bond via sulfonyl group as shown in the following formula (I): </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>Solid phase support-L&mdash;SO2-X&mdash;A &emsp;&emsp;(I) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0170" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0170&rsqb;</number> In the formula (I), L represents a linking group; X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;; each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other, a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and A represents a residue of a protein or a protein binding substance (except for nucleic acid). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0171" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0171&rsqb;</number> In the formula (I) , L represents a bivalent or more linking group for binding &mdash;SO2-X&mdash;A and the solid support. Examples of a &mdash;L&mdash;include any linking group selected from aliphatic, aromatic or heterocyclic compounds, hydrocarbon chains that may be interrupted by a hetero atom, or combinations of them. Furthermore, L may be a singl bond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0172" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0172&rsqb;</number> In the formula (I), examples of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms include a methyl group, an ethyl group, a n-propyl group, a n-butyl group, and a n-hexyl group, and the methyl group is preferable. Examples of an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms include a phenyl group and a naphthyl group. It is preferable that each of R1, R2 and R3 represents a hydrogen atom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0173" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0173&rsqb;</number> Examples of an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms include the combination of the examples of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and the examples of an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0174" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0174&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the present invention relates to a method for detecting a target substance comprising the steps of: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0175" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0175&rsqb;</number> bringing the chip in accordance with the present invention described above into contact with a specimen containing a target substance that specifically binds to a protein or a protein binding substance supported on the surface of the chip; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0176" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0176&rsqb;</number> detecting formation of reciprocal binding between the protein or protein binding substance and the target substance. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0177" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0177&rsqb;</number> The type of &ldquo;specimen&rdquo; referred to in the present invention is not particularly limited, and includes, for example, a blood such as peripheral venous blood, white blood cell, serum, urine, stool, sperm, saliva, a cultured cell, a tissue cell such as a variety of cells of organs, and any other sample containing nucleic acid. As for the specimen, the sample such as the tissue cell as described above may be used as it is. However, preferably, nucleic acid, ligand or the like which has been released by destructing the cell in the specimen sample is used as a specimen. The destruction of the cell in the specimen sample can be performed according to the conventional manner. For example, it can be performed by adding a physical action such as shaking, supersonic treatment from the exterior. The nucleic acid also can be released from the cell using a nucleic acid extraction solution (e.g., solution containing a surfactant such as SDS, Triton-X, Tween-20 or the like, or saponin, EDTA, protease or the like, or the like) . In the case where the nucleic acid is eluted using a nucleic acid extraction solution, the reaction can be promoted by incubation at the temperature of 37&deg; C. or higher. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0178" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0178&rsqb;</number> Furthermore, the present invention relates to a method for manufacturing the chip according to the present invention comprising the step of contacting the solid support having the convex and concave portions that contains a vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group represented by the following formula (II) on the surface, with at least one protein or protein binding substance having a reactive group which forms a covalent bond by reacting with the vinyl sulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group. </paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime;&emsp;&emsp;(II) </in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0179" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0179&rsqb;</number> &lsqb;In the formula (II), L represents a linking group for binding &mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime; and the solid support; X&prime; represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>)or &mdash;CH(R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) (Y); each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other, a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and Y represents a group substituted by a nucleophilic reagent, or a group which is eliminated as &ldquo;HY&rdquo; by base&rsqb;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0180" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0180&rsqb;</number> In the formula (II), examples of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms include a methyl group, an ethyl group, a n-propyl group, a n-butyl group, and a n-hexyl group, and the methyl group is particularly preferable. Examples of an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms include a phenyl group and naphthyl group. It is preferable that each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents a hydrogen atom. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0181" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0181&rsqb;</number> Examples of an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms include the combination of the examples of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and the examples of an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0182" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0182&rsqb;</number> In the formula (II), Y represents a group substituted by a nucleophilic reagent such as &mdash;OH, &mdash;OR<highlight><superscript>0</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;SH, NH<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, NH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>0 </superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>0 </superscript></highlight>represents a group such as alkyl group or the like except for hydrogen atom), or a group which is eliminated as &ldquo;HY&rdquo; by base. Examples thereof include a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M, or a quaternary pyridinium group (R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms or halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents a hydrogen atom, an alkali metal atom, or an ammonium group) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0183" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0183&rsqb;</number> An alkyl group of R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, an aryl group of R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>and an aralkyl group of R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>may have a substituent. Examples of such a substituent include an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydroxyl group, an alkoxy group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an alkenyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, a carbamoyl group having 2 to 7 carbon atoms, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aralkyl group having 7 to 16 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, an sulfamoyl group (or its sodium salt, potassium salt or the like), a sulfo group (or its sodium salt, potassium salt or the like), a carboxylic acid group (or its sodium salt, potassium salt or the like) a halogen atom, an alkenylene group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an arylene group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, sulfonyl group and their combinations. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0184" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0184&rsqb;</number> In the formula (II) , L represents a bivalent or more linking group for linking &mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime; group and the solid support. Examples of a &mdash;L&mdash; include any linking group selected from aliphatic, aromatic or heterocyclic compound and a hydrocarbon chain that may be interrupted by a hetero atom, and a linking group selected from their combinations. Further L may be a single bond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0185" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0185&rsqb;</number> Preferable examples of the above-described &ldquo;&mdash;X&prime;&rdquo; group are shown thereinafter:  
<chemistry-cwu id="CHEM-US-00004">
<number>4</number>
<image id="EMI-C00004" he="447.6465" wi="174.49425" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.TIF"/>
<chemistry-chemdraw-file id="CHEMCDX-00004" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.CDX"/>
<chemistry-mol-file id="CHEMMOL-00004" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-C00004.MOL"/>
</chemistry-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0186" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0186&rsqb;</number> In the above-described concrete examples, it is preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&prime;&rdquo; represents (X1) , (X2) , (X3) , (X4), (X7) (X8) , (X13) or (X14), and more preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&prime;&rdquo; represents (X1) or (X2) . And it is particularly preferable that &ldquo;&mdash;X&prime;&rdquo; represents a vinyl group represented by (X1). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0187" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0187&rsqb;</number> Since a covalent bond via a sulfonyl group utilized in the present invention has a high resistance to hydrolysis, it can be readily stored in a stable state, and can rapidly react with the protein in which an amino group or a mercapto group has been previously provided to form a stable covalent bond. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0188" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0188&rsqb;</number> Usually, it is not necessary to introduce another reactive group, since the protein has an amino group or a mercapto group. However, since the tertiary structure of the protein largely participates in its function, in the case where the activity of the protein is lowered, it is preferable to introduce a reactive group at the specific position having no influence on the activity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0189" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0189&rsqb;</number> Dotting of the protein or protein binding substance is carried out by dotting an aqueous solution to the surface of the reactive solid support. Concretely, it is preferable. to carry out the dotting along the following steps of: dissolving or dispersing the protein or protein binding substance into the aqueous medium to prepare an aqueous solution; pipetting the aqueous solution into a 96 wells or 384 wells plastic plate; dropping the aqueous solution thus pipetted to the surface of the solid support using a spotter device or the like. As is described above, although the spotter device can be used for dropping the protein or protein binding substance, there is a possibility of lowering the activity of the protein or protein binding substance depending on the property of a pin-head. In this case, it may be more preferable to use an ink jet device or the like depending on a case. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0190" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0190&rsqb;</number> In order to prevent the protein or protein binding substance from being dried after the dotting of it, a substance having a high boiling point may be added in the aqueous solution. As a substance having a high boiling point, the substance that can be dissolved in the aqueous solution in which protein or protein binding substance to be dotted is dissolved or dispersed, does not hinder reaction with a sample which is an object of the detection, and has a not very high viscosity is preferably used. Examples of such substances include glycerin, ethylene glycol, dimethyl sulfoxide and a hydrophilic polymer having a lower molecular weight. The hydrophilic polymers include polyacrylamide, polyethylene glycol and sodium polyacrylate. Preferable molecular weight of this polymeris in the range from 10<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>to 10<highlight><superscript>6</superscript></highlight>. As the substance having a high boiling point, it is more preferable to use glycerin or ethylene glycol, and particularly preferable to use glycerin. Preferable concentration of the substance having a high boiling point can be adjusted depending on the activity of the protein after the dotting. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0191" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0191&rsqb;</number> Moreover, for the sake of the same purpose, it is also preferable to place the solid support after the dotting of the protein or protein binding substance under the circumstances where the humidity is 90% or more and the temperature is in the range from 25 to 40&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0192" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0192&rsqb;</number> A preferable fixed amount (numerical quantity) of the protein or protein binding substance with respect to the surface of the solid support is in the range from 1 to 10<highlight><superscript>5 </superscript></highlight>per cm<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>. By the dotting, the aqueous solution of the protein or protein binding substance is fixed in a dot shape to the surface of the solid support. The shape of the dot is nearly circular. The distance between the respective dots, the size of the dot and the volume of the aqueous solution when it is dotted vary depending on its intended use. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0193" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0193&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> schematically shows a configuration of a protein chip, which is the representative aspect of the present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0194" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0194&rsqb;</number> When the protein A having the reactive group (Z) is dotted to the surface of the solid support (P1) having the convex and concave portions shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, the reaction between X and the protein occurs. However, an unreacted X to which the protein is not bound also exists on the surface of the solid support (P1). In this case, there is a possibility that such X reacts in a non-specific manner with a labeled ligand sample and the like in a reaction to be performed later, resulting in a problem that non-specific binding may be measured. Therefore, it is preferable that the X has been previously subjected to a blocking treatment. It is preferable that the blocking treatment is performed by bringing a compound having an amino group or a mercapto group into contact with the surface of the solid support (P2). In order to prevent the non-specifical binding of a ligand to be reacted, it is preferable to perform the blocking treatment using a protein blocking agent, specifically, BSA, casein, gelatin or the like. As the result of the blocking, BSA or the like exists on the surface of the solid support (P2) which has not been dotted, thereby preventing the binding of the ligand. Moreover, in the case where the nucleic acid is to be reacted, the blocking treatment can be carried out by contacting an anionic compound having an amino group or a mercapto group other than the above-described protein blocking agent. In the case where the substance with which the protein is reacted is a nucleic acid, since the nucleic acid has a negative charge, it can prevent the nucleic acid from reacting with an unreacted X by generating the negative charge also on the surface of the solid support (P2). As for such an anionic compound, any compound can be used if it reacts with X and has a negative charge (COO<highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, SO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, PO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>, or PO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight><highlight><superscript>&minus;</superscript></highlight>) Among them, an amino acid is preferable, and glycine or cysteine is particularly preferable. Further, taurine is also preferably used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0195" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0195&rsqb;</number> A protein chip which is a representative aspect of the present invention is utilized for the analysis of protein interactions, the analysis of the protein expression and the drug development search. Furthermore, in the case where the protein is a nucleic acid binding protein, it can be utilized for the mutation analysis and the nucleotide polymorphism analysis depending on its recognition nucleic acid sequence. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0196" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0196&rsqb;</number> The principle of the detection is based on the reaction with the labeled ligand or nucleic acid. As labeling methods, although a RI method and a non-RI method (fluorescence method, biotin method, chemiluminescence method or the like) are known, it is not particularly limited. For example, in the case of the fluorescence method, as a fluorescent substance utilized for a fluorescence labeling, any can be used if it can bind to the basic portion of nucleic acid or protein amino acid residue. For example, cyanine dye (e.g., Cy3, Cy5 or the like of Cy Dye&trade; series, which is commercially available) , rhodamine 6G reagent, N-acetoxy-N2-acetylaminofluorene (AAF) or AAIF (iodine derivative of AAF) can be used. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0197" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0197&rsqb;</number> In the case of a protein chip in which a nucleic acid recognition protein is fixed, it is preferable that the target nucleic acid in the specimen is directly detected without amplifying it by a PCR method or the like. However, it may be detected after it has been previously amplified. The target nucleic acid or its amplified body can be easily detected by previously labeling it. In order to label the nucleic acid, a method of using an enzyme (Reverse Transcriptase, DNA polymerase, RNA polymerase, Terminal deoxy trasferase or the like) is often used. Further, the labeling substance may be directly bound by chemical reaction. Such labeling method has been described in some books as the known technology (Shintaro Nomura: De-isotope Experiment Protocol 1, published by Shujun Sha, Co., Ltd., 1994; Shintaro Nomura: De-isotope Experiment Protocol 2, published by Shujun Sha, Co., Ltd., 1998; Masaaki Muramatsu: DNA Microarray and Advanced PCR Method Labeling Material, published by Shujun Sha, Co., Ltd., 2000). It is preferable that the labeling material is a material capable of making a detectable signal. In the case where the labeling material is a material having an amplifying ability of signal such as an enzyme and a catalyst, the detection sensitivity of DNA is largely enhanced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0198" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0198&rsqb;</number> However, since the labeling operation described above is generally troublesome, a method of measuring the nucleic acid in the specimen without previous labeling of the nucleic acid can be used as a more preferable method of detection. For the purpose of it, for example, a DNA intercalating agent which recognizes a double stranded DNA, that is, what is called a DNA intercalator can be used. By the use of a DNA intercalator, not only the operation of the detection is made easier, but also the sensitivity of the detection is enhanced. For example, in the case where a DNA of 1000 bp is to be detected, although a labeling method can introduce several labeling materials at most, in the case where the intercalator is used, 100 or more labeling materials can be introduced. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0199" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0199&rsqb;</number> The DNA intercalator may be a material which can form a detectable signal in itself, or the signal formation material may be bound to the side chain of intercalator, or bound to the intercalator via a specific binding pair such as a biotin-avidin, an antigen-antibody or a hapten-antibody. It is preferable that the detectable signal used in the present invention is the signal detectable by a fluorescene detection, a luminescence detection, a chemiluminescence detection, a bioluminescence detection, an electrochemiluminescence detection, a radiation detection, an electrochemical detection or a calorimetric detection, but it is not limited to them. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0200" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0200&rsqb;</number> In the case where a ligand is a target, there can be used a substance obtained by reacting a succinimide body of a cyanine dye (e.g., Cy3, Cy5 or the like of Cy Dye&trade; series, which is commercially available), rhodamine 6G reagent, N-acetoxy-N<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>-acetylaminofluorene (AAF) or AAIF (iodine derivative of AAF) with an amino group existing inside. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0201" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0201&rsqb;</number> The present invention will be more concretely described below by the following Examples, but the present invention is not limited by these Examples. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLES </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 1 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of DNA Fragment Fixed Slide, and Measurement of Fixed Amount of DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0202" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0202&rsqb;</number> The preparation and its performance of a reactive solid support having the convex and concave properties, and the comparison with a reactive solid support not having the convex and concave properties as a comparative control are shown below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0203" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0203&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of Solid Support (A) Having Convex and Concave Properties onto Which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group Has Been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0204" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0204&rsqb;</number> 200 ml of the suspension of 5% by weight of a colloidal silica (Snowtechs PS-S (Nissan Chemical Industries Co., Ltd.&rsqb;/average particle diameter about 10 nm) was prepared. In the suspension, 20 pieces of glass slides previously washed, being contained in a basket commercially available, were immersed for 30 seconds. After drawing up them, draining off was performed and dried for 10 minutes by a drier at 45&deg; C. Next, each glass slide was reacted with 200 ml of 2% by weight solution of Shinetsu Silicone KBE 903 (Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) for 3 minutes using a commercially available slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, it was washed for 1 minute (using slide washer) with 200 ml of ultrapure water. While exchanging the ultrapure water, washings were repeated more two times under the above-described washing conditions. After the completion of washings, and after it had been dried for 10 minutes by the drier at 45&deg; C., it was put into the oven set at 110&deg; C. was thermally treated for 10 minutes. After cooling it, 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution was reacted for 120 minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. to obtain a solid support (A) having the convex and concave properties. When the surface of (A) was observed using an atomic force microscope (AFM) , it was confirmed that the thickness of the layer containing vinyl sulfonyl groups was about 10 nm, and the glass slide was coated with a single layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0205" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0205&rsqb;</number> (2) Dotting of DNA Fragment and Measurement of Fluorescence Intensity </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0206" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0206&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution (1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6</superscript></highlight>M, 1 &mgr;L) consisted of dispersion of the DNA fragment (3&prime;-TCCTCCATGTCCGGGGAGGATCTGACACTTCAAGGTCTAG-5&prime;), of which 3&prime; end and 5&prime; end were modified with an amino group and a fluorescence labeling reagent (Fluoro Link Cy5-dCTP, made by Amersham Pharmacia Biotech, Co., Ltd.) respectively, in 0.1M carbonate buffer solution (pH 9.3) , was dotted on the slide (A) obtained in the above-described (1). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left for 1 hour at the temperature of 25&deg; C. and humidity of 90%. The solid support was washed with the mixed solution of 0.1 wt % SDS (sodium dodecyl sulfate) and 2&times;SSC (2&times;SSC: solution in which the stock solution of SSC is diluted into 2-fold; SSC: standard salt-citric acid buffer solution) two times, and washed with 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution once. Then, the slide after the above-described washings was immersed in 0.1 M glycine aqueous solution (pH 10) for 1 hour and 30 minutes, washed with distilled water, and dried at room temperature to obtain a solid support (B) to which DNA fragments were fixed. The fluorescence intensity of the surface of this solid support (B) measured by a fluorescence scanning device was 15,250. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0207" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0207&rsqb;</number> (3) Preparation of a Comparative Control Slide, and Its Performances </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0208" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0208&rsqb;</number> The glass slide was reacted with 200 ml of 2% by weight solution of Shinetsu Silicone KBE 903 (Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) for 3 minutes using a commercially available slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, it was washed for 1 minute (using the slide washer) with 200 ml of ultrapure water. While exchanging the ultrapure water, washings were repeated more two times under the above-described washing conditions. After the completion of washings, it was dried for 10 minutes by the drier at 45&deg; C., then put into the oven set at 110&deg; C. and thermally treated for 10 minutes. After cooling it, 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution was reacted for 120 minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. Evaluation similar to the above-described (2) was performed, and 2300 of the fluorescence intensity was obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0209" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0209&rsqb;</number> The above-described results are summarized in the following Table.  
<table-cwu id="TABLE-US-00001">
<number>1</number>
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="119PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="98PT" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="1" align="center">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>fluorescence intensity</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="OFFSET" colwidth="14PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="105PT" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="98PT" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>solid support having convex</entry>
<entry>15250</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>and concave properties</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(Invention: Example 1(1) and (2))</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>comparative control slide</entry>
<entry>2300</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry>(Comparative: Example 1(3))</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry></entry>
<entry namest="OFFSET" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</table-cwu>
</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0210" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0210&rsqb;</number> As seen from the results of Table 1, it is understood that, according to the fixation method of the present invention, DNA fragments are efficiently fixed in a high density on the slide glass. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 2 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0211" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0211&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of DNA Fragment Fixed Solid Support Having Convex and Concave Properties </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0212" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0212&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution (1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6</superscript></highlight>M, 1 &mgr;L) consisted of dispersion of 40 mer of the DNA fragment (3&prime;-TCCTCCATGTCCGGGGAGGATCTGACACTTCAAGGTCTAG-5&prime;), of which 3&prime; end was modified with an amino group, in 0.1M carbonate buffer solution (pH 9.3) , was dotted on the solid support having the convex and concave properties (A) obtained in the above-described (1) of Example 1. Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left for 1 hour at the temperature of 25&deg; C. and humidity of 90%. The solid support was washed with the mixed solution of 0.1 wt % SDS (sodium dodecyl sulfate) and 2&times;SSC (2&times;SSC: solution in which the stock solution of SSC is diluted into 2-fold; SSC: standard salt-citric acid buffer solution) two times, and washed with 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution once. Then, the slide after the above-described washings was immersed in 0.1 M glycine aqueous solution (pH 10) for 1 hour and 30 minutes, washed with distilled water, dried at room temperature to obtain a solid support (C) to which DNA fragments were fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0213" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0213&rsqb;</number> (2) Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0214" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0214&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution consisted of dispersion of 22 mer of the sample oligonucleotide (CTAGTCTGTGAAGTTCCAGATC-5&prime;), of which 5&prime; end was bound with Cy5, in the solution for hybridization (mixed solution of 4&times;SSC and 10% by weight of SDS) (20 &mgr;L) was dotted on the solid support (C) obtained in the above-described (1). Then, the surface was protected by a cover glass for microscopy, and incubated at 60&deg; C. for 20 hours within a moisture chamber. After the incubation, it was washed with the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 2&times;SSC, the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 0.2&times;SSC, and 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution in turn, centrifuged at 600 rpm for 20 seconds, and dried at room temperature. Fluorescence intensity of the surface of the glass slide measured by a fluorescence scanning device was 10350. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0215" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0215&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the detection of the sample DNA fragment was performed using the comparative control slide, the fluorescence intensity was 1500. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0216" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0216&rsqb;</number> It is understood that a sample DNA fragment having the complementarity to the fixed DNA fragment can be detected in a high sensitivity by employing the DNA fragment fixed solid support having the convex and concave properties prepared according to a fixation method of the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 3 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of a DNA Fragment Fixed Slide, and Measurement of Fixed Amount of DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0217" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0217&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of a Solid Support Having Convex and Concave Properties to which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group has been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0218" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0218&rsqb;</number> A coated slide glass for DNA microarray (Type 2 highly densified amino group introduced type &lsqb;Matsunami Glass Industry, Co., Ltd.&rsqb;) was reacted for 120 minutes with 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by a drier set at 25&deg; C. An evaluation was performed similarly to (2) of Example 1, and 3600 of the fluorescence intensity was obtained. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 4 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0219" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0219&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of DNA Fragment Fixed Support Using the Slide Glass Made by Matsunami Glass, Co., Ltd. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0220" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0220&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution (1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6</superscript></highlight>M, 1 &mgr;L) consisted of dispersion of 40 mer of the DNA fragment (3&prime;-TCCTCCATGTCCGGGGAGGATCTGACACTTCAAGGTCTAG-5&prime;), of which 3&prime; end was modified with an amino group, in 0.1M carbonate buffer solution (pH 9.3) was dotted on the solid support having the convex and concave properties obtained in the above-described (1) of Example 3. Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left for 1 hour at the temperature of 25&excl;&excl;degree&excl;&excl; and humidity of 90%. The solid support was washed in turn with the mixed solution of 0.1 wt % SDS (sodium dodecyl sulfate) and 2&times;SSC (2&times;SSC: solution in which the stock solution of SSC is diluted into 2-fold; SSC: standard salt-citric acid buffer solution) two times, and washed with 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution once. Then, the slide after the above-described washings was immersed in 0.1 M glycine aqueous solution (pH 10) for 1 hour and 30 minutes, washed with distilled water, dried at room temperature to obtain a solid support (D) to which DNA fragments were fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0221" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0221&rsqb;</number> (2) Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0222" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0222&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution consisted of dispersion of 22 mer of the sample oligonucleotide (CTAGTCTGTGAAGTTCCAGATC-5&prime;) , of which 5&prime; end was bound with Cy5, in the solution for hybridization (mixed solution of 4&times;SSC and 10% by weight of SDS) (20 &mgr;L) was dotted on the solid support (D) obtained in the above-described (1) . Then, the surface was protected by a cover glass for microscopy, and incubated at 60&deg; C. for 20 hours within a moisture chamber. After the incubation, it was washed with the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 2&times;SSC, the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 0.2&times;SSC, and 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution in turn, centrifuged at 600 rpm for 20 seconds, and dried at room temperature. Fluorescence intensity of the surface of the glass slide measured by a fluorescence scanning device was 15360. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 5 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Preparation of DNA Fragment Fixation Slide, and Measurement of Fixed Amount of DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0223" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0223&rsqb;</number> The preparation and its performance of a reactive solid support having the convex and concave properties, and the comparison with a reactive solid support not having the convex and concave properties as a comparative control are shown below. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0224" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0224&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of Solid Support (A) Having Convex and Concave Properties to Which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group has been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0225" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0225&rsqb;</number> 75 mg of polyvinyl alcohol was dissolved in 1000 ml of ultrapure water. After the dissolving, 500 &mgr;l of a silane coupling agent (KBE 903; made by Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) was added, and stirred for 10 minutes by a magnet stirrer. The glass substrate (76 mm&times;26 mm) was immersed in the solution for 30 seconds, then drawn up. After its excessive liquid was drained off, it was dried by the drier at 45&deg; C. Next, this glass substrate was heated in an oven set at 110&deg; C. for 10 minutes to fix the silane on the glass substrate. Further, after cooling the above-described glass substrate, it was reacted with 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution for 120 minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was carried out three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0226" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0226&rsqb;</number> (2) Dotting of DNA Fragment and Measurement of Fluorescence Intensity </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0227" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0227&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution (1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6</superscript></highlight>M, 1 &mgr;L) consisted of dispersion of the DNA fragment (3&prime;-TCCTCCATGTCCGGGGAGGATCTGACACTTCAAGGTCTAG-5&prime;), of which 3&prime; end and 5&prime; end were modified with an amino group and a fluorescence labeling reagent (Fluoro Link Cy5-dCTP, made by Amersham Pharmacia Biotech, Co., Ltd.) respectively, in 0.1M carbonate buffer solution (pH 9.3) was dotted on the slide (A) obtained in the above-described (1). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left for 1 hour at the temperature of 25&deg; C. and humidity of 90%. The solid support was washed in turn with the mixed solution of 0.1 wt % SDS (sodium dodecyl sulfate) and 2&times;SSC (2&times;SSC: solution in which the stock solution of SSC is diluted into 2-fold; SSC: standard salt-citric acid buffer solution) two times, and washed with 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution once. Then, the slide after the above-described washings was immersed in 0.1 M glycine aqueous solution (pH 10) for 1 hour and 30 minutes, washed with distilled water, dried at room temperature to obtain a solid support (B) to which DNA fragments were fixed. The fluorescence intensity of the surface of this solid support (B) measured by a fluorescence scanning device was 22,250. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0228" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0228&rsqb;</number> (3) Preparation of Comparative Control Slides and Their Performances </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0229" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0229&rsqb;</number> The glass slide was reacted with 200 ml of 2% by weight solution of Shinetsu Silicone KBE 903 (Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) for 3 minutes using a commercially available slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, it was washed for 1 minute (using the slide washer) with 200 ml of ultrapure water. While exchanging the ultrapure water, washings were repeated more two times under the above-described washing conditions. After the completion of washings, it was dried for 10 minutes by the drier at 45&deg; C., then put into the oven set at 110&deg; C. and thermally treated for 10 minutes. After cooling it, 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH8.0borate buffer solution was reacted for 120minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. Evaluation similar to the above-described (2) was performed, and 1750 of the fluorescence intensity was obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0230" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0230&rsqb;</number> As seen from the above mentioned results, it is understood that, according to the fixation method of the present invention, DNA fragments are efficiently fixed in a high density on the slide glass. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 6 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0231" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0231&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of DNA Fragment Fixed Solid Support Having Convex and Concave Properties </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0232" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0232&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution (1&times;10<highlight><superscript>&minus;6</superscript></highlight>M, 1 &mgr;L) consisted of dispersion of 40 mer of the DNA fragment (3&prime;-TCCTCCATGTCCGGGGAGGATCTGACACTTCAAGGTCTAG-5&prime;), of which 3&prime; end was modified with an amino group, in 0.1M carbonate buffer solution (pH 9.3) was dotted on the solid support having the convex and concave properties (A) obtained in the above-described (1) of Example 5. Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left for 1 hour at the temperature of 25&deg; C. and humidity of 90%. The solid support was washed in turn with the mixed solution of 0.1 wt % SDS (sodium dodecyl sulfate) and 2&times;SSC (2&times;SSC: solution in which the stock solution of SSC is diluted into 2-fold; SSC: standard salt-citric acid buffer solution) two times, and washed with 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution once. Then, the slide after the above-described washings was immersed in 0.1 M glycine aqueous solution (pH 10) for 1 hour and 30 minutes, washed with distilled water, dried at room temperature to obtain a solid support (C) to which DNA fragments were fixed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0233" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0233&rsqb;</number> (2) Detection of Sample DNA Fragment </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0234" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0234&rsqb;</number> The aqueous solution consisted of dispersion of 22 mer of the sample oligonucleotide (CTAGTCTGTGAAGTTCCAGATC-5&prime;) , of which 5&prime; end was bound with Cy5, in the solution for hybridization (mixed solution of 4&times;SSC and 10% by weight of SDS) (20 &mgr;L) was dotted on the solid support (C) obtained in the above-described (1). Then, the surface was protected by a cover glass for microscopy, and incubated at 60&deg; C. for 20 hours within a moisture chamber. After the incubation, it was washed with the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 2&times;SSC, the mixed solution of 0.1% by weight SDS and 0.2&times;SSC, and 0.2&times;SSC aqueous solution in turn, centrifuged at 600 rpm for 20 seconds, and dried at room temperature. Fluorescence intensity of the surface of the glass slide measured by a fluorescence scanning device was 18400. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0235" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0235&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, when the detection of the sample DNA fragment was performed using the comparative control slide, the fluorescence intensity was 1500. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0236" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0236&rsqb;</number> It is understood that a sample DNA fragment having the complementarity to the fixed DNA fragment can be detected in a high sensitivity by employing the DNA fragment fixed solid support having the convex and concave properties prepared according to the present invention. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 7 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Ligand by Antibody Fixed Slide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0237" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0237&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of Solid Support Having Convex and Concave Properties (A) to which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group has been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0238" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0238&rsqb;</number> 200 ml of the suspension of 5% by weight of a colloidal silica (Snowtechs PS-S&lsqb;Nissan Chemical Industries Co., Ltd. &rsqb;/average particle diameter about 10 nm) was prepared. In the suspension, 20 pieces of glass slides previously washed, being contained in a basket comercially available, were immersed for 30 seconds. After drawing up them, draining off was performed and dried for 10 minutes by a drier at 45&deg; C. Next, each glass slide was reacted with 200 ml of 2% by weight solution of Shinetsu Silicone KBE 903 (Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) for 3 minutes using a commercially available slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, it was washed for 1 minute (using slide washer) with 200 ml of ultrapure water. While exchanging the ultrapure water, washings were repeated more two times under the above-described washing conditions. After the completion of washings, and after it had been dried for 10 minutes by the drier at 45&deg; C., it was put into the oven set at 110&deg; C., and was thermally treated for 10 minutes. After cooling it, 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution was reacted for 120 minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. to obtain a solid support (A) having the convex and concave properties. When the surface of (A) was observed using an atomic force microscope (AFM), it was confirmed that the thickness of the layer was about 10 nm, and the glass slide was coated with a single layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0239" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0239&rsqb;</number> (2) Fixation of Antibody </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0240" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0240&rsqb;</number> Goat Anti-Human IgG (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with PBS (100, 20, 4, 0.8, 0.16 ng/&mgr;L, 1 &mgr;L) , and dotted on the solid support (A) prepared in the above-described (1). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left at 25&deg; C. for 3 hours in a saturated common salt chamber. Then the blocking treatment was performed by immersing it in 1% BSA/0.05% Tween 20-PBS (PBS-T) for 1 hour to obtain an antibody slide (B) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0241" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0241&rsqb;</number> (3) Reaction with Ligand and Detection of It </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0242" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0242&rsqb;</number> HybriWell (Grace Bio-Labs) was intimately contacted to the antibody slide (B) prepared in the above-described (2). Human IgG-Cy5 (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with 1% BSA/PBS-T into 2 &mgr;g/ml. After 100 &mgr;L of the diluted solution was added within HybriWell, it was incubated at 25&excl;&excl;degree&excl;&excl; for 1 hour within a moisture chamber. Subsequently, it was washed with PBS-T three times, rinsed with PBS, and dried by a centrifuge treatment at 700 rpm for 5 minutes. When the fluorescence intensity of the slide glass surface was measured by a fluorescence scanning device, it was 39.2 at the position where the antibody was spotted with 100 ng/&mgr;L, indicating a large increase from a background fluorescence intensity. Therefore, it is understood that by employing the antibody fixation solid support of the present invention consisted of the solid support having the convex and concave properties to which antibodies have been bound via, sulfonyl group, a ligand having reactivity with the antibody fixed on the antibody fixation solid support can be efficiently detected. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 8 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Ligand by Antibody Fixed Slide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0243" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0243&rsqb;</number> (1) Fixation of Antibody </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0244" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0244&rsqb;</number> Rabbit Anti Streptavidin (Polysienece) was diluted with PBS (100 ng/&mgr;L), and each 10 &mgr;L of it was pipetted into 384 -wells plate. It was dotted on the solid support (A) prepared in the above-described Example 7 (1) using an arrayer made by Cartecyan (PixSys 5500). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left at 25&deg; C. for 3 hours in a saturated common salt chamber, then the blocking treatment was performed by immersing it in &frac14;&times;Block Ace (Dainippon Pharmaceuticals)/0.05% Tween 20-PBS (PBS-T) for 1 hour to obtain an antibody slide (C). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0245" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0245&rsqb;</number> (2) Labeling of Ligand </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0246" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0246&rsqb;</number> 1 mg of Streptavidin (Wako Junyaku) was dissolved in 400 &mgr;l of 0.1 M NaHCO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>(pH 8.0). It was transferred to a Cy3-monofunctional tube (Amershan Pharmacia Biotech) and incubated at room temperature for 30 minutes. 100 &mgr;l of 1 M Tris/HCl (pH 8.0) was added to it, and further incubated at room temperature for 30 minutes to stop the reaction. The reacted solution was purified by NAP-5 column (Amersham Pharmacia Biotech), and Cy3-labeled Streptavidin was obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0247" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0247&rsqb;</number> (3) Reaction with Ligand and Detection of It </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0248" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0248&rsqb;</number> SecureSeal Hybridization Chamber (SA 500, Grace Bio-Labs) was intimately contacted to the antibody slide (C) prepared in the above-described (1). Cy3-labeled Streptavidin obtained in the above-described (2) was diluted with &frac14;&times;Block Ace/PBS-T into 2&mgr;g/ml. After 500 &mgr;L of it was added within SA 500, it was incubated at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour within a moisture chamber. Subsequently, it was washed with PBS-T three times, rinsed with PBS, and dried by a centrifuge treatment at 700 rpm for 5 minutes. When the fluorescence intensity of the slide glass surface was measured by a fluorescence scanning device, it was 19,320, indicating a large increase from the background fluorescence intensity. Therefore, it is understood that by employing the antibody fixation solid support of the present invention consisted of the solid support having the convex and concave properties to which antibodies have been bound via sulfonyl group, a ligand having reactivity with the antibody fixed on the antibody fixed solid support can be efficiently detected also in a microarray system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 9 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Ligand by Antibody Fixed Slide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0249" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0249&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of Solid Support (D) to which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group has been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0250" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0250&rsqb;</number> 20 pieces of coated slide glass for DNA microarray (Type 2 highly densified amino group introduced type &lsqb;Matsunami Glass Industry, Co., Ltd.&rsqb;) contained in a commercially available basket, were reacted for 120minutes with 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was repeated three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by a drier set at 25&deg; C. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0251" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0251&rsqb;</number> (2) Fixation of Antibody </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0252" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0252&rsqb;</number> Goat Anti-Human IgG (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with PBS (100 ng/&mgr;L), and each 10 &mgr;L of it was pipetted into 384 wells plate. It was dotted on the solid support (D) prepared in the above-described Example 9 (1) using an arrayer made by Cartecyan (PixSys 5500). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour in a saturated common salt chamber, then the blocking treatment was performed by immersing it in &frac14;&times;Block Ace (Dainippon Pharmaceuticals)/0.05% Tween 20-PBS (PBS-T) for 1 hour to obtain an antibody slide (E). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0253" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0253&rsqb;</number> (3) Reaction with Ligand and Detection of It </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0254" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0254&rsqb;</number> SecureSeal Hybridization Chamber (SA 500, Grace Bio-Labs) was intimately contacted to the antibody slide (E) prepared in the above-described (1). Human IgG-Cy5 (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with &frac14;&times;Block Ace/PBS-T into 5, 2, 1, 0.2, 0.1 &mgr;g/ml. After 500 &mgr;L of each diluted solution was added within SA500, it was incubated at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour within a moisture chamber. Subsequently, it was washed with PBS-T three times, rinsed with PBS, and dried by a centrifuge treatment at 700 rpm for 5 minutes. When the fluorescence intensity of the slide glass surface was measured by a fluorescence scanning device, they were 33525, 23629, 15001, 8667 and 6053, respectively, on the slides to which 5, 2, 1, 0.2, 0.1 &mgr;g/ml of Human IgG-Cy5 were added. And approximate linearity was confirmed in the range from 0.2 to 2 &mgr;g/ml (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>). </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 10 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Ligand by Antibody Fixed Slide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0255" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0255&rsqb;</number> (1) Preparation of Solid Support (A) Having Convex and Concave Properties to which Vinyl Sulfonyl Group has been Introduced </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0256" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0256&rsqb;</number> 75 mg of polyvinyl alcohol was dissolved in 1000 ml of ultrapure water. After the dissolving, 500 &mgr;l of a silane coupling agent (KBE 903; made by Shinetsu Chemical Industry, Co., Ltd.) was added, and stirred for 10 minutes by a magnetic stirrer. The glass substrate (76 mm&times;26 mm) was immersed in the solution for 30 seconds, then drawn up. After its excessive liquid was drained off, it was dried by the drier at 45&deg; C. Next, this glass substrate was heated in an oven set at 110&deg; C. for 10 minutes to fix the silane on the glass substrate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0257" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0257&rsqb;</number> Further, after cooling the above-described glass substrate, it was reacted with 3% by weight of 1,2-bis (vinyl sulfonyl acetamide) ethane/pH 8.0 borate buffer solution for 120 minutes using the slide washer. After the completion of the reaction, a 20 second washing was carried our three times with ultrapure water. The drying was performed for 30 minutes by the drier set at 25&deg; C. to obtain the solid support having the convex and concave properties (A). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0258" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0258&rsqb;</number> (2) Fixation of Antibody </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0259" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0259&rsqb;</number> Goat Anti-Human IgG (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with PBS (100, 20, 4, 0.8, 0.16 ng/&mgr;L, 1 &mgr;L), and dotted on the solid support (A) prepared in the above-described (1) Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left at 25&deg; C. for 3 hours in a saturated common salt chamber. Then the blocking treatment was performed by immersing it in 1% BSA/0.05% Tween 20-PBS (PBS-T) for 1 hour to obtain an antibody slide (B) </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0260" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0260&rsqb;</number> (3) Reaction with Ligand and Detection of It </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0261" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0261&rsqb;</number> HybriWell (Grace Bio-Labs) was intimately contacted to the antibody slide (B) prepared in the above-described (2). Human IgG-Cy5 (Jackson ImmunoResearch) was diluted with 1% BSA/PBS-T into 2 &mgr;g/ml. After 100 &mgr;L of the diluted solution was added within HybriWell, it was incubated at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour within a moisture chamber. Subsequently, it was washed with PBS-T three times, rinsed with PBS, and dried by a centrifuge treatment at 700 rpm for 5 minutes. When the fluorescence intensity of the slide glass surface was measured by a fluorescence scanning device, it was 40.2 at the position where the antibody was spotted at 100 ng/&mgr;L, indicating a large increase from a background fluorescence intensity. Therefore, it is understood that by employing the antibody fixed solid support of the present invention consisted of the solid support having the convex and concave properties comprising an organic substance, to which antibodies have been bound via sulfonyl group, a ligand having reactivity with the antibody fixed on the antibody fixed solid support can be efficiently detected. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Example 11 </heading>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Detection of Ligand by Antibody Fixed Slide </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0262" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0262&rsqb;</number> (1) Fixation of Antibody </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0263" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0263&rsqb;</number> Rabbit Anti Streptavidin (Polysienece) was diluted with PBS (100 ng/&mgr;L), and each 10 &mgr;L of it was pipetted into 384 wells plate. It was dotted on the solid support (A) prepared in the above-described Example 10 (1) using an arrayer made by Cartecyan (PixSys 5500). Immediately, the solid support after the dotting was left at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour in a saturated common salt chamber, then the blocking treatment was performed by immersing it in &frac14;&times;Block Ace (Dainippon Pharmaceuticals)/0.05% Tween 20-PBS (PBS-T) for 1 hour to obtain an antibody slide (C). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0264" lvl="7"><number>&lsqb;0264&rsqb;</number> (2) Labeling of Ligand </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0265" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0265&rsqb;</number> 1 mg of Streptavidin (Wako Junyaku) was dissolved in 400 &mgr;l of 0.1 M NaHCO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>(pH 8.0). It was transferred to a Cy3-monofunctional tube (Amersham Pharmacia Biotech) and incubated at room temperature for 30 minutes. 100 &mgr;l of 1 M Tris/HCl (pH 8.0) was added to it, and further incubated at room temperature for 30 minutes to stop the reaction. The reacted solution was purified by NAP-5 column (Amersham Pharmacia Biotech), and Cy3-labeled Streptavidin was obtained. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0266" lvl="3"><number>&lsqb;0266&rsqb;</number> (3) Reaction with Ligand and Detection of It </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0267" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0267&rsqb;</number> SecureSeal Hybridization Chamber (SA 500, Grace Bio-Labs) was intimately contacted to the antibody slide (C) prepared in the above-described (1). Cy3-labeled Streptavidin obtained in the above-described (2) was diluted with &frac14;&times;Block Ace/PBS-T into 2 &mgr;g/ml. After 500 &mgr;L of it was added within SA 500, it was incubated at 25&deg; C. for 1 hour within a moisture chamber. Subsequently, it was washed with PBS-T three times, rinsed with PBS, and dried by a centrifuge treatment at 700 rpm for 5 minutes. When the fluorescence intensity of the slide glass surface was measured by a fluorescence scanning device, it was 26,300, indicating a large increase from the background fluorescence intensity. Therefore, it is understood that by employing the antibody fixed solid support of the present invention consisted of the solid support having the convex and concave properties comprising an organic substance to which antibodies have been bound via sulfonyl group, a ligand having reactivity with the antibody fixed on the antibody fixed solid support can be efficiently detected also in a microarray system. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">Industrial Applicability </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0268" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0268&rsqb;</number> By utilizing a fixation method of the present invention, a probe of a nucleotide derivative or its analog nucleotide such as an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide, or a peptide nucleic acid can be fixed in high density with high stability on the surface of a solid support having the convex and concave portions. Therefore, the solid support to which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is fixed by the fixation method of the present invention forms the solid support with high stability, in which release of the probe resulted from hydrolysis hardly occurs. Particularly, in the case where an amino group or the like is introduced using a silane coupling agent to surface of the solid support, the probe can be firmly fixed to the solid support, since both of the binding of the amino group or the like to the surface of the solid support and the binding of the probe are formed by the covalent bond. A detection tool having a high detection limit which is capable of being utilized for gene analysis or the like can be obtained by this stable fixation of the probe. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0269" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0269&rsqb;</number> As one example of it, a nucleic acid fragment sample having complementarity to the probe fixed on an oligonucleotide fixed solid support can be detected in a high sensitivity by performing the hybridization with the sample nucleic acid fragment using an oligonucleotide fixed solid support prepared according to the present invention. Moreover, a non-specific absorption of the sample nucleic acid fragment can be prevented by performing the treatment of the solid support surface with an anionic compound such as glycine after the probe sample such as the oligonucleotide is dotted on the surface of the reactive solid support, thereby exerting a larger effect on the detection with a high sensibility of a nucleic acid fragment sample having the complementarity.</paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">Furthermore, according to the present invention, there can be provided a biological material chip wherein at least one member of specific binding partners is bound and fixed on a reactive solid support which is capable of rapidly and stably binding and fixing </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A reactive solid support having convex and concave portions on its surface, to which a group of vinyl sulfonyl groups or their reactive precursor groups are fixed by covalent bond via a linking group, respectively. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the convex and concave portions comprise particles formed by an inorganic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the convex and concave portions comprise a particle of silicon, alumina or titanium having the average diameter of 50 &mgr;m or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the convex and concave portions are formed by an organic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the organic substance is a macromolecular polymer or an aggregate of a macromolecular polymer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> , wherein a linked body of the vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group and the linking group is represented by the following formula: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the above-described formula, X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms, and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L represents a linking group. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The, reactive solid support : as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein X represents a vinyl group represented by &mdash;CH&boxH;CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support : as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein L represents a linking group containing an atom of a bivalence or more except for carbon atom. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein L represents a linking group having a linking portion selected from the group consisted of &mdash;NH&mdash;, &mdash;S&mdash; and &mdash;O&mdash;. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein L represents a linking group represented by &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;NH&mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; or &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;S&mdash;(CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; wherein R<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents the same meanings as described above, L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group, and n represents either 0 or 1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein L represents a linking group represented by &mdash;(L<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)<highlight><subscript>n</subscript></highlight>&mdash;NHCH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>CH<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash; wherein L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group, and n represents either 0 or 1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein L<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group containing a group represented by &mdash;OSi&mdash;, and n represents 1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said solid support is a substrate in a sheet shape selected from the group consisted of a glass substrate, a resin substrate, a glass substrate or a resin substrate surface-treated with a silane coupling agent and a glass substrate or a resin substrate having a covering layer on its surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said solid support is a substrate in a sheet shape selected from the group consisted of a silicate glass substrate, a silicate glass substrate surface-treated with a silane coupling agent and a silicate glass substrate covered by an organic covering layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A method of manufacturing the reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a disulfone compound represented by the following formula is brought into contact with a reactive solid support to the surface of which a reactive group is introduced: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>X<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;L<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight></in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the above-described formula, each of X<highlight><superscript>1 </superscript></highlight>and X<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR<highlight><superscript>12</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>represents a linking group. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a reactive solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, in which the reactive group introduced to the surface of said solid support is an amino group, a mercapto group or a hydroxyl group. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A manufacturing method of a solid support comprising a nucleotide derivative or its analog bound to the surface of the support via a linking group having a sulfonyl group, wherein a surface of a reactive solid support having a convex and concave portion on which each of a group of vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group is fixed by covalent bond, is contacted with a nucleotide derivative or its analog having a reactive group which is capable of reacting with said reactive group to form a covalent bond. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The manufacturing method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said nucleotide derivative or its analog is selected from the group consisted of an oligonucleotide, a polynucleotide and a peptide nucleic acid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The manufacturing method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a reactive solid support that a linked body of a vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group represented by the following formula and a linking group is bound to and fixed on, is used as a reactive solid support having a convex and concave portion: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the above-described formula, X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>or &mdash;CHR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>Y, each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; Y represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a halogen atom, &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>11</superscript></highlight>, &mdash;OCOR , &mdash;OSO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>M and a quaternary pyridinium group; R<highlight><superscript>11 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms and an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; R<highlight><superscript>12 </superscript></highlight>represents a group selected from the group consisted of an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms and a halogenated alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; M represents an atom or a group selected from the group consisted of a hydrogen atom, an alkali metallic atom and an ammonium group; and L represents a linking group or a single bond. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The manufacturing method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 19</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein X represents a reactive group represented by &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>wherein each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents the same meanings as described above. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. A solid support having a convex and concave portion, in which a nucleotide derivative or its analog obtained by a manufacturing method claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00017">claims 17</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00020">20</dependent-claim-reference> is bound and fixed to surface of the solid support. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. A method of binding and fixing a complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide, wherein the solid support having the convex and concave portion to which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference> is contacted with an oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity to said fixed nucleotide derivative or its analog in the presence of an aqueous medium. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>23</bold></highlight>. The method as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a detectable label is bound to said complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. A solid support to which a oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity is bound and fixed wherein the solid support having the convex and concave portion to which, to the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 21</dependent-claim-reference>, a oligonucleotide or a polynucleotide having complementarity to said nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound in a complementary manner. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. The solid support as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 24</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein a detectable label is bound to said oligonucleotide or polynucleotide having the complementarity. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. A method of identifying or screening a gene, wherein the solid support having a convex and concave portion to the surface of which the nucleotide derivative or its analog is bound and fixed as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference>, or the solid support to which the complementary oligonucleotide or polynucleotide is bound and fixed as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 22</dependent-claim-reference> is utilized. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight>. A biological material chip, wherein A, which represents a residue of at least one protein or protein binding substance, is bound to a solid support having a convex and concave portion by covalent bond via a sulfonyl group as the following formula (I): </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>Solid support-L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&mdash;A &emsp;&emsp;(I) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the formula (I) , L represents a linking group; X represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>4</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;; each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>4 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and A represents a residue of a protein or protein binding substance except for nucleic acid. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein or protein binding substance bounded to the surface is an antibody, an antibody fragment, a ligand, an antigen, a hapten or a receptor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>29</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is avidins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 29</dependent-claim-reference>, in which avidins are an avidin, a streptoavidin or altered bodies thereof which are capable of forming a stable complex with a biotin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein bound to the surface is a nucleic acid recognition protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 31</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said nucleic acid recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition antibody. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a DNA transcription factor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 32</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a protein having a Zinc finger motif or a Ring finger motif. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in any one of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00027">claims 27</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00035">35</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle formed by an inorganic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle containing silicon, alumina or titanium of which average particle diameter is 50 &mgr;m or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in any of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00027">claims 27</dependent-claim-reference> to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00035">35</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said convex and concave portion is formed by an organic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>39</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 38</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said organic substance comprises a high molecular polymer or an aggregate of a high molecular polymer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>. The chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said solid support is a glass, a plastic, an electrode surface or a sensor chip surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight>. A method of detecting a target substance, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>contacting the chip claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> with a sample containing a target substance which specifically binds to said protein or protein binding substance except for nucleic acid supported on the surface of said chip; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting formation of reciprocal binding between said protein or protein binding substance and said target substance. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The method of detecting a target substance as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said target substance is labeled with at least one component capable of generating a detectable signal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>43</bold></highlight>. The method of detecting a target substance as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 41</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising a step of performing blocking processing of the chip with an aqueous solution of an amino acid, a peptide or a protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing the chip claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 27</dependent-claim-reference> comprising a step in which a solid support having a convex and concave portion containing a vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group represented by the following formula (II) on its surface is contacted with at least one protein or protein binding substance having a reactive group which forms a covalent bond by reacting with said vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group: </claim-text>
<claim-text><in-line-formula>&mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime;&emsp;&emsp;(II) </in-line-formula></claim-text>
<claim-text>in the above-described formula (II), L represents a linking group which binds &mdash;L&mdash;SO<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>&mdash;X&prime; to a solid support; X&prime; represents &mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>&boxH;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) or &mdash;CH(R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>)&mdash;CR<highlight><superscript>2</superscript></highlight>(R<highlight><superscript>3</superscript></highlight>) (Y); each of R<highlight><superscript>1</superscript></highlight>, R<highlight><superscript>2 </superscript></highlight>and R<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>represents independently from each other a hydrogen atom, an alkyl group having 1 to 6 carbon atoms, an aryl group having 6 to 20 carbon atoms or an aralkyl group having 7 to 26 carbon atoms in total containing an alkyl chain having 1 to 6 carbon atoms; and Y represents a group which is substituted by a neucleophilic reagent or a group which is eliminated as a &ldquo;HY&rdquo; by a base </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>45</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is an antibody, an antibody fragment, a ligand, an antigen, a hapten or a receptor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein or protein binding substance bound to the surface is avidins. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>47</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 46</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein avidins are an avidin, a streptoavidin or altered bodies thereof which are capable of forming a stable complex with a biotin. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said protein bound to the surface is a nucleic acid recognition protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>49</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 48</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said nucleic acid recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition protein. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a double stranded DNA recognition antibody. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a DNA transcription factor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 49</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said double stranded DNA recognition protein is a protein having a Zinc finger motif or a Ring finger motif. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle formed by an inorganic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00033">claim 36</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said convex and concave portion comprises a particle containing silicon, alumina or titanium of which average particle diameter is 50 &mgr;m or less. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, in which said convex and concave portion is formed by an organic substance. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00055">claim 55</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein said organic substance is a high molecular polymer or an aggregate of a high molecular polymer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>57</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, in which a solid support is a glass, a plastic, an electrode surface or a sensor chip surface. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight>. The method of manufacturing a chip as claimed in <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00044">claim 44</dependent-claim-reference>, comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>fixing at least one protein or protein binding substance to a solid support having convex and concave portions by contacting said protein or protein binding substance to said solid support; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>performing blocking process of a free vinylsulfonyl group or its reactive precursor group located on the surface of said solid support with an amino acid, a peptide or a protein aqueous solution.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030003480A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
