<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001207</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09859700</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010516</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L027/01</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>347000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Structure and method for fabricating semiconductor structures and devices utilizing the formation of a compliant subtrate for materials used to form the same</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<continuations>
<continuation-in-part-of>
<parent-child>
<child>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09859700</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20010516</document-date>
</document-id>
</child>
<parent>
<document-id>
<doc-number>09721566</doc-number>
<document-date>20001122</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</parent>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-child>
</continuation-in-part-of>
</continuations>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Jamal</given-name>
<family-name>Ramdani</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Alexander</given-name>
<middle-name>A.</middle-name>
<family-name>Demkov</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Phoenix</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Lyndee</given-name>
<middle-name>L.</middle-name>
<family-name>Hilt</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Chandler</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Motorola, Inc.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MOTOROLA, INC.</name-1>
<name-2>CORPORATE LAW DEPARTMENT - #56-238</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>3102 NORTH 56TH STREET</address-1>
<city>PHOENIX</city>
<state>AZ</state>
<postalcode>85018</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">High quality epitaxial layers of monocrystalline materials can be grown overlying monocrystalline substrates such as large silicon wafers by forming a compliant substrate for growing the monocrystalline layers. One way to achieve the formation of a compliant substrate includes first growing an accommodating buffer layer on a silicon wafer. The accommodating buffer layer is a layer of monocrystalline oxide spaced apart from the silicon wafer by an amorphous interface layer of silicon oxide. The amorphous interface layer dissipates strain and permits the growth of a high quality monocrystalline oxide accommodating buffer layer. The accommodating buffer layer is lattice matched to both the underlying silicon wafer and the overlying monocrystalline material layer. Any lattice mismatch between the accommodating buffer layer and the underlying silicon substrate is taken care of by the amorphous interface layer. In addition, formation of a compliant substrate may include utilizing surfactant enhanced epitaxy, epitaxial growth of single crystal silicon onto single crystal oxide, and epitaxial growth of Zintl phase materials. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> This application is a continuation-in-part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/721,566, filed Nov. 22, 2000, by the assignee hereof.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> This invention relates generally to semiconductor structures and devices and to a method for their fabrication, and more specifically to semiconductor structures and devices and to the fabrication and use of semiconductor structures, devices, and integrated circuits that include a monocrystalline material layer comprised of semiconductor material, compound semiconductor material, and/or other types of material such as metals and non-metals. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> Semiconductor devices often include multiple layers of conductive, insulating, and semiconductive layers. Often, the desirable properties of such layers improve with the crystallinity of the layer. For example, the electron mobility and band gap of semiconductive layers improves as the crystallinity of the layer increases. Similarly, the free electron concentration of conductive layers and the electron charge displacement and electron energy recoverability of insulative or dielectric films improves as the crystallinity of these layers increases. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> For many years, attempts have been made to grow various monolithic thin films on a foreign substrate such as silicon (Si). To achieve optimal characteristics of the various monolithic layers, however, a monocrystalline film of high crystalline quality is desired. Attempts have been made, for example, to grow various monocrystalline layers on a substrate such as germanium, silicon, and various insulators. These attempts have generally been unsuccessful because lattice mismatches between the host crystal and the grown crystal have caused the resulting layer of monocrystalline material to be of low crystalline quality. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> If a large area thin film of high quality monocrystalline material was available at low cost, a variety of semiconductor devices could advantageously be fabricated in or using that film at a low cost compared to the cost of fabricating such devices beginning with a bulk wafer of semiconductor material or in an epitaxial film of such material on a bulk wafer of semiconductor material. In addition, if a thin film of high quality monocrystalline material could be realized beginning with a bulk wafer such as a silicon wafer, an integrated device structure could be achieved that took advantage of the best properties of both the silicon and the high quality monocrystalline material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Accordingly, a need exists for a semiconductor structure that provides a high quality monocrystalline film or layer over another monocrystalline material and for a process for making such a structure. In other words, there is a need for providing the formation of a monocrystalline substrate that is compliant with a high quality monocrystalline material layer so that true two-dimensional growth can be achieved for the formation of quality semiconductor structures, devices and integrated circuits having grown monocrystalline film the same crystal orientation as an underlying substrate. This monocrystalline material layer may be comprised of a semiconductor material, a compound semiconductor material, and other types of material such as metals and non-metals.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is illustrated by way of example and not limitation in the accompanying figures, in which like references indicate similar elements, and in which: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1, 2</cross-reference>, and <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> illustrate schematically, in cross section, device structures in accordance with various embodiments of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates graphically the relationship between maximum attainable film thickness and lattice mismatch between a host crystal and a grown crystalline overlayer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> illustrates a high resolution Transmission Electron Micrograph of a structure including a monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an x-ray diffraction spectrum of a structure including a monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> illustrates a high resolution Transmission Electron Micrograph of a structure including an amorphous oxide layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates an x-ray diffraction spectrum of a structure including an amorphous oxide layer; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D illustrate schematically, in cross-section, the formation of a device structure in accordance with another embodiment of the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D illustrate a probable molecular bonding structure of the device structures illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> illustrate schematically, in cross-section, the formation of a device structure in accordance with still another embodiment of the invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> illustrate schematically, in cross-section, the formation of yet another embodiment of a device structure in accordance with the invention.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> Skilled artisans will appreciate that elements in the figures are illustrated for simplicity and clarity and have not necessarily been drawn to scale. For example, the dimensions of some of the elements in the figures may be exaggerated relative to other elements to help to improve understanding of embodiments of the present invention. </paragraph>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates schematically, in cross section, a portion of a semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> in accordance with an embodiment of the invention. Semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> includes a monocrystalline substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> comprising a monocrystalline material, and a monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In this context, the term &ldquo;monocrystalline&rdquo; shall have the meaning commonly used within the semiconductor industry. The term shall refer to materials that are a single crystal or that are substantially a single crystal and shall include those materials having a relatively small number of defects such as dislocations and the like as are commonly found in substrates of silicon or germanium or mixtures of silicon and germanium and epitaxial layers of such materials commonly found in the semiconductor industry. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> also includes an amorphous intermediate layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> positioned between substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight> may also include a template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> between the accommodating buffer layer and monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. As will be explained more fully below, the template layer helps to initiate the growth of the monocrystalline material layer on the accommodating buffer layer. The amorphous intermediate layer helps to relieve the strain in the accommodating buffer layer and by doing so, aids in the growth of a high crystalline quality accommodating buffer layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> Substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention, is a monocrystalline semiconductor or compound semiconductor wafer, preferably of large diameter. The wafer can be of, for example, a material from Group IV of the periodic table, and preferably a material from Group IVB. Examples of Group IV semiconductor materials include silicon, germanium, mixed silicon and germanium, mixed silicon and carbon, mixed silicon, germanium and carbon, and the like. Preferably substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a wafer containing silicon or germanium, and most preferably is a high quality monocrystalline silicon wafer as used in the semiconductor industry. Accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is preferably a monocrystalline oxide or nitride material epitaxially grown on the underlying substrate. In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, amorphous intermediate layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is grown on substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> at the interface between substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and the growing accommodating buffer layer by the oxidation of substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> during the growth of layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The amorphous intermediate layer serves to relieve strain that might otherwise occur in the monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer as a result of differences in the lattice constants of the substrate and the buffer layer. As used herein, lattice constant refers to the distance between atoms of a cell measured in the plane of the surface. If such strain is not relieved by the amorphous intermediate layer, the strain may cause defects in the crystalline structure of the accommodating buffer layer. Defects in the crystalline structure of the accommodating buffer layer, in turn, would make it difficult to achieve a high quality crystalline structure in monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> which may comprise a semiconductor material, a compound semiconductor material, or another type of material such as a metal or a non-metal. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> Accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is preferably a monocrystalline oxide or nitride material selected for its crystalline compatibility with the underlying substrate and with the overlying material layer. For example, the material could be an oxide or nitride having a lattice structure closely matched to the substrate and to the subsequently applied monocrystalline material layer. Materials that are suitable for the accommodating buffer layer include metal oxides such as the alkaline earth metal titanates, alkaline earth metal zirconates, alkaline earth metal hafnates, alkaline earth metal tantalates, alkaline earth metal ruthenates, alkaline earth metal niobates, alkaline earth metal vanadates, perovskite oxides such as alkaline earth metal tin-based perovskites, lanthanum aluminate, lanthanum scandium oxide, and gadolinium oxide. Additionally, various nitrides such as gallium nitride, aluminum nitride, and boron nitride may also be used for the accommodating buffer layer. Most of these materials are insulators, although strontium ruthenate, for example, is a conductor. Generally, these materials are metal oxides or metal nitrides, and more particularly, these metal oxide or nitrides typically include at least two different metallic elements. In some specific applications, the metal oxides or nitrides may include three or more different metallic elements. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> Amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is preferably an oxide formed by the oxidation of the surface of substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and more preferably is composed of a silicon oxide. The thickness of layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is sufficient to relieve strain attributed to mismatches between the lattice constants of substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. Typically, layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> has a thickness in the range of approximately 0.5-5 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> The material for monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be selected, as desired, for a particular structure or application. For example, the monocrystalline material of layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may comprise a compound semiconductor which can be selected, as needed for a particular semiconductor structure, from any of the Group IIIA and VA elements (III-V semiconductor compounds), mixed III-V compounds, Group II(A or B) and VIA elements (II-VI semiconductor compounds), and mixed II-VI compounds. Examples include gallium arsenide (GaAs), gallium indium arsenide (GaInAs), gallium aluminum arsenide (GaAIAs), indium phosphide (InP), cadmium sulfide (CdS), cadmium mercury telluride (CdHgTe), zinc selenide (ZnSe), zinc sulfur selenide (ZnSSe), and the like. However, monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may also comprise other semiconductor materials, metals, or non-metal materials which are used in the formation of semiconductor structures, devices and/or integrated circuits. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> Appropriate materials for template <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> are discussed below. Suitable template materials chemically bond to the surface of the accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> at selected sites and provide sites for the nucleation of the epitaxial growth of monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. When used, template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> has a thickness ranging form about 1 to about 10 monolayers. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> illustrates, in cross section, a portion of a semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> in accordance with a further embodiment of the invention. Structure <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> is similar to the previously described semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, except that an additional buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is positioned between accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Specifically, the additional buffer layer is positioned between template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> and the overlying layer of monocrystalline material. The additional buffer layer, formed of a semiconductor or compound semiconductor material when the monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> comprises a semiconductor or compound semiconductor material, serves to provide a lattice compensation when the lattice constant of the accommodating buffer layer cannot be adequately matched to the overlying monocrystalline semiconductor or compound semiconductor material layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> schematically illustrates, in cross section, a portion of a semiconductor structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in accordance with another exemplary embodiment of the invention. Structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is similar to structure <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, except that structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> includes an amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, rather than accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, and an additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> As explained in greater detail below, amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may be formed by first forming an accommodating buffer layer and an amorphous interface layer in a similar manner to that described above. Monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is then formed (by epitaxial growth) overlying the monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer. The accommodating buffer layer is then exposed to an anneal process to convert the monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer to an amorphous layer. Amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formed in this manner comprises materials from both the accommodating buffer and interface layers, which amorphous layers may or may not amalgamate. Thus, layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may comprise one or two amorphous layers. Formation of amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> between substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> (subsequent to layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> formation) relieves stresses between layers <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> and provides a true compliant substrate for subsequent processing--e.g., monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> formation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The processes previously described above in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> are adequate for growing monocrystalline material layers over a monocrystalline substrate. However, the process described in connection with <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, which includes transforming a monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer to an amorphous oxide layer, may be better for growing monocrystalline material layers because it allows any strain in layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> to relax. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> Additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may include any of the materials described throughout this application in connection with either of monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> or additional buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. For example, when monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> comprises a semiconductor or compound semiconductor material, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may include monocrystalline Group IV or monocrystalline compound semiconductor materials. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of the present invention, additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> serves as an anneal cap during layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formation and as a template for subsequent monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> formation. Accordingly, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is preferably thick enough to provide a suitable template for layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> growth (at least one monolayer) and thin enough to allow layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to form as a substantially defect free monocrystalline material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> In accordance with another embodiment of the invention, additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> comprises monocrystalline material (e.g., a material discussed above in connection with monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>) that is thick enough to form devices within layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. In this case, a semiconductor structure in accordance with the present invention does not include monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In other words, the semiconductor structure in accordance with this embodiment only includes one monocrystalline layer disposed above amorphous oxide layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> The following non-limiting, illustrative examples illustrate various combinations of materials useful in structures <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in accordance with various alternative embodiments of the invention. These examples are merely illustrative, and it is not intended that the invention be limited to these illustrative examples. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 1 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, monocrystalline substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a silicon substrate oriented in the (100) direction. The silicon substrate can be, for example, a silicon substrate as is commonly used in making complementary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) integrated circuits having a diameter of about 200-300 mm. In accordance with this embodiment of the invention, accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is a monocrystalline layer of Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where z ranges from 0 to 1 and the amorphous intermediate layer is a layer of silicon oxide (SiO<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>) formed at the interface between the silicon substrate and the accommodating buffer layer. The value of z is selected to obtain one or more lattice constants closely matched to corresponding lattice constants of the subsequently formed layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. The accommodating buffer layer can have a thickness of about 2 to about 100 nanometers (nm) and preferably has a thickness of about 5 nm. In general, it is desired to have an accommodating buffer layer thick enough to isolate the compound semiconductor layer from the substrate to obtain the desired electrical and optical properties. Layers thicker than 100 nm usually provide little additional benefit while increasing cost unnecessarily; however, thicker layers may be fabricated if needed. The amorphous intermediate layer of silicon oxide can have a thickness of about 0.5-5 nm, and preferably a thickness of about 1 to 2 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> In accordance with this embodiment of the invention, monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is a compound semiconductor layer of gallium arsenide (GaAs) or aluminum gallium arsenide (AlGaAs) having a thickness of about 1 nm to about 100 micrometers (&mgr;m) and preferably a thickness of about 0.5&mgr;m to 10&mgr;m. The thickness generally depends on the application for which the layer is being prepared. To facilitate the epitaxial growth of the gallium arsenide or aluminum gallium arsenide on the monocrystalline oxide, a template layer is formed by capping the oxide layer. The template layer is preferably 1 &mdash;10 monolayers of Ti&mdash;As, Sr&mdash;O&mdash;As, Sr&mdash;Ga&mdash;O, or Sr&mdash;Al&mdash;O. By way of a preferred example, 1-2 monolayers of Ti&mdash;As or Sr&mdash;Ga&mdash;O have been illustrated to successfully grow GaAs layers. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 2 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further embodiment of the invention, monocrystalline substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a silicon substrate as described above. The accommodating buffer layer is a monocrystalline oxide of strontium or barium zirconate or hafnate in a cubic or orthorhombic phase with an amorphous intermediate layer of silicon oxide formed at the interface between the silicon substrate and the accommodating buffer layer. The accommodating buffer layer can have a thickness of about 2-100 nm and preferably has a thickness of at least 5 nm to ensure adequate crystalline and surface quality and is formed of a monocrystalline SrZrO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, BaZrO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, SrHfO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, BaSnO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>or BaHfO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>. For example, a monocrystalline oxide layer of BaZrO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>can grow at a temperature of about 700 degrees C. The lattice structure of the resulting crystalline oxide exhibits a 45 degree rotation with respect to the substrate silicon lattice structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> An accommodating buffer layer formed of these zirconate or hafnate materials is suitable for the growth of a monocrystalline material layer which comprises compound semiconductor materials in the indium phosphide (InP) system. In this system, the compound semiconductor material can be, for example, indium phosphide (InP), indium gallium arsenide (InGaAs), aluminum indium arsenide, (AlInAs), or aluminum gallium indium arsenic phosphide (AlGaInAsP), having a thickness of about 1.0 nm to 10&mgr;m. A suitable template for this structure is 1-10 monolayers of zirconium-arsenic (Zr&mdash;As), zirconium-phosphorus (Zr&mdash;P), hafnium-arsenic (Hf&mdash;As), hafnium-phosphorus (Hf&mdash;P), strontium-oxygen-arsenic (Sr&mdash;O&mdash;As), strontium-oxygen-phosphorus (Sr&mdash;O&mdash;P), barium-oxygen-arsenic (Ba&mdash;O&mdash;As), indium-strontium-oxygen (In&mdash;Sr&mdash;O), or barium-oxygen-phosphorus (Ba&mdash;O&mdash;P), and preferably 1-2 monolayers of one of these materials. By way of an example, for a barium zirconate accommodating buffer layer, the surface is terminated with 1-2 monolayers of zirconium followed by deposition of 1-2 monolayers of arsenic to form a Zr&mdash;As template. A monocrystalline layer of the compound semiconductor material from the indium phosphide system is then grown on the template layer. The resulting lattice structure of the compound semiconductor material exhibits a 45 degree rotation with respect to the accommodating buffer layer lattice structure and a lattice mismatch to (100) InP of less than 2.5%, and preferably less than about 1.0%. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 3 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> In accordance with a further embodiment of the invention, a structure is provided that is suitable for the growth of an epitaxial film of a monocrystalline material comprising a II-VI material overlying a silicon substrate. The substrate is preferably a silicon wafer as described above. A suitable accommodating buffer layer material is Sr<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, where x ranges from 0 to 1, having a thickness of about 2-100 nm and preferably a thickness of about 5-15 nm. Where the monocrystalline layer comprises a compound semiconductor material, the II-VI compound semiconductor material can be, for example, zinc selenide (ZnSe) or zinc sulfur selenide (ZnSSe). A suitable template for this material system includes 1-10 monolayers of zinc-oxygen (Zn&mdash;O) followed by 1-2 monolayers of an excess of zinc followed by the selenidation of zinc on the surface. Alternatively, a template can be, for example, 1-10 monolayers of strontium-sulfur (Sr&mdash;S) followed by the ZnSeS. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 4 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> This embodiment of the invention is an example of structure <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, and monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> can be similar to those described in example 1. In addition, an additional buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> serves to alleviate any strains that might result from a mismatch of the crystal lattice of the accommodating buffer layer and the lattice of the monocrystalline material. Buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be a layer of germanium or a GaAs, an aluminum gallium arsenide (AlGaAs), an indium gallium phosphide (InGaP), an aluminum gallium phosphide (AlGaP), an indium gallium arsenide (InGaAs), an aluminum indium phosphide (AlInP), a gallium arsenide phosphide (GaAsP), or an indium gallium phosphide (InGaP) strain compensated superlattice. In accordance with one aspect of this embodiment, buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes a GaAs<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>P<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x </subscript></highlight>superlattice, wherein the value of x ranges from 0 to 1. In accordance with another aspect, buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> indudes an In<highlight><subscript>y</subscript></highlight>Ga<highlight><subscript>1&minus;y</subscript></highlight>P superlattice, wherein the value of y ranges from 0 to 1. By varying the value of x or y, as the case may be, the lattice constant is varied from bottom to top across the superlattice to create a match between lattice constants of the underlying oxide and the overlying monocrystalline material which in this example is a compound semiconductor material. The compositions of other compound semiconductor materials, such as those listed above, may also be similarly varied to manipulate the lattice constant of layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> in a like manner. The superlattice can have a thickness of about 50-500 nm and preferably has a thickness of about 100-200 nm. The template for this structure can be the same of that described in example 1. Alternatively, buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> can be a layer of monocrystalline germanium having a thickness of 1-50 nm and preferably having a thickness of about 2-20 nm. In using a germanium buffer layer, a template layer of either germanium-strontium (Ge&mdash;Sr) or germanium-titanium (Ge&mdash;Ti) having a thickness of about one monolayer can be used as a nucleating site for the subsequent growth of the monocrystalline material layer which in this example is a compound semiconductor material. The formation of the oxide layer is capped with either a monolayer of strontium or a monolayer of titanium to act as a nucleating site for the subsequent deposition of the monocrystalline germanium. The monolayer of strontium or titanium provides a nucleating site to which the first monolayer of germanium can bond. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 5 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> This example also illustrates materials useful in a structure <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>. Substrate material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>, monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> can be the same as those described above in example 2. In addition, additional buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is inserted between the accommodating buffer layer and the overlying monocrystalline material layer. The buffer layer, a further monocrystalline material which in this instance comprises a semiconductor material, can be, for example, a graded layer of indium gallium arsenide (InGaAs) or indium aluminum arsenide (InAlAs). In accordance with one aspect of this embodiment, additional buffer layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> includes InGaAs, in which the indium composition varies from 0 to about 50%. The buffer layer preferably has a thickness of about 10-30 nm. Varying the composition of the buffer layer from GaAs to InGaAs serves to provide a lattice match between the underlying monocrystalline oxide material and the overlying layer of monocrystalline material which in this example is a compound semiconductor material. Such a buffer layer is especially advantageous if there is a lattice mismatch between accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">EXAMPLE 6 </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> This example provides exemplary materials useful in structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. Substrate material <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, and monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> may be the same as those described above in connection with example 1. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is an amorphous oxide layer which is suitably formed of a combination of amorphous intermediate layer materials (e.g., layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> materials as described above) and accommodating buffer layer materials (e.g., layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> materials, described above). For example, amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may include a combination of Siq and Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>(where z ranges from 0 to 1),which combine or mix, at least partially, during an anneal process to form amorphous oxide layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The thickness of amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> may vary from application to application and may depend on such factors as desired insulating properties of layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, type of monocrystalline material comprising layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, and the like. In accordance with one exemplary aspect of the present embodiment, layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> thickness is about 2 nm to about 100 nm, preferably about 2-10 nm, and more preferably about 5-6 nm. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> Layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> comprises a monocrystalline material that can be grown epitaxially over a monocrystalline oxide material such as material used to form accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> includes the same materials as those comprising layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. For example, if layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> includes GaAs, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> also includes GaAs. However, in accordance with other embodiments of the present invention, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> may include materials different from those used to form layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. In accordance with one exemplary embodiment of the invention, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is about 1 monolayer to about 100 nm thick. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> Referring again to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a monocrystalline substrate such as a monocrystalline silicon or gallium arsenide substrate. The crystalline structure of the monocrystalline substrate is characterized by a lattice constant and by a lattice orientation. In similar manner, accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is also a monocrystalline material and the lattice of that monocrystalline material is characterized by a lattice constant and a crystal orientation. The lattice constants of the accommodating buffer layer and the monocrystalline substrate must be closely matched or, alternatively, must be such that upon rotation of one crystal orientation with respect to the other crystal orientation, a substantial match in lattice constants is achieved. In this context the terms &ldquo;substantially equal&rdquo; and &ldquo;substantially matched&rdquo; mean that there is sufficient similarity between the lattice constants to permit the growth of a high quality crystalline layer on the underlying layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> illustrates graphically the relationship of the achievable thickness of a grown crystal layer of high crystalline quality as a function of the mismatch between the lattice constants of the host crystal and the grown crystal. Curve <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> illustrates the boundary of high crystalline quality material. The area to the right of curve <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight> represents layers that have a large number of defects. With no lattice mismatch, it is theoretically possible to grow an infinitely thick, high quality epitaxial layer on the host crystal. As the mismatch in lattice constants increases, the thickness of achievable, high quality crystalline layer decreases rapidly. As a reference point, for example, if the lattice constants between the host crystal and the grown layer are mismatched by more than about 2%, monocrystalline epitaxial layers in excess of about 20 nm cannot be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> is a (100) or (111) oriented monocrystalline silicon wafer and accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> is a layer of strontium barium titanate. Substantial matching of lattice constants between these two materials is achieved by rotating the crystal orientation of the titanate material by 45&deg; with respect to the crystal orientation of the silicon substrate wafer. The inclusion in the structure of amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>, a silicon oxide layer in this example, if it is of sufficient thickness, serves to reduce strain in the titanate monocrystalline layer that might result from any mismatch in the lattice constants of the host silicon wafer and the grown titanate layer. As a result, in accordance with an embodiment of the invention, a high quality, thick, monocrystalline titanate layer is achievable. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> Still referring to FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is a layer of epitaxially grown monocrystalline material and that crystalline material is also characterized by a crystal lattice constant and a crystal orientation. In accordance with one embodiment of the invention, the lattice constant of layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> differs from the lattice constant of substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. To achieve high crystalline quality in this epitaxially grown monocrystalline layer, the accommodating buffer layer must be of high crystalline quality. In addition, in order to achieve high crystalline quality in layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, substantial matching between the crystal lattice constant of the host crystal, in this case, the monocrystalline accommodating buffer layer, and the grown crystal is desired. With properly selected materials this substantial matching of lattice constants is achieved as a result of rotation of the crystal orientation of the grown crystal with respect to the orientation of the host crystal. For example, if the grown crystal is gallium arsenide, aluminum gallium arsenide, zinc selenide, or zinc sulfur selenide and the accommodating buffer layer is monocrystalline Sr<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3</subscript></highlight>, substantial matching of crystal lattice constants of the two materials is achieved, wherein the crystal orientation of the grown layer is rotated by 45&deg; with respect to the orientation of the host monocrystalline oxide. Similarly, if the host material is a strontium or barium zirconate or a strontium or barium hafnate or barium tin oxide and the compound semiconductor layer is indium phosphide or gallium indium arsenide or aluminum indium arsenide, substantial matching of crystal lattice constants can be achieved by rotating the orientation of the grown crystal layer by 45&deg; with respect to the host oxide crystal. In some instances, a crystalline semiconductor buffer layer between the host oxide and the grown monocrystalline material layer can be used to reduce strain in the grown monocrystalline material layer that might result from small differences in lattice constants. Better crystalline quality in the grown monocrystalline material layer can thereby be achieved. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> The following example illustrates a process, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention, for fabricating a semiconductor structure such as the structures depicted in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The process starts by providing a monocrystalline semiconductor substrate comprising silicon or germanium. In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention, the semiconductor substrate is a silicon wafer having a (100) orientation. The substrate is preferably oriented on axis or, at most, about 4&deg; off axis. At least a portion of the semiconductor substrate has a bare surface, although other portions of the substrate, as described below, may encompass other structures. The term &ldquo;bare&rdquo; in this context means that the surface in the portion of the substrate has been cleaned to remove any oxides, contaminants, or other foreign material. As is well known, bare silicon is highly reactive and readily forms a native oxide. The term &ldquo;bare&rdquo; is intended to encompass such a native oxide. A thin silicon oxide may also be intentionally grown on the semiconductor substrate, although such a grown oxide is not essential to the process in accordance with the invention. In order to epitaxially grow a monocrystalline oxide layer overlying the monocrystalline substrate the native oxide layer must first be removed to expose the crystalline structure of the underlying substrate. The following process is preferably carried out by molecular beam epitaxy (MBE), although other epitaxial processes may also be used in accordance with the present invention. The native oxide can be removed by first thermally depositing a thin layer of strontium, barium, a combination of strontium and barium, or other alkali earth metals or combinations of alkali earth metals in an MBE apparatus. In the case where strontium is used, the substrate is then heated to a temperature of about 850&deg; C. to cause the strontium to react with the native silicon oxide layer. The strontium serves to reduce the silicon oxide to leave a silicon oxide-free surface. The resultant surface, which exhibits an ordered 2&times;1 structure, includes strontium, oxygen, and silicon. The ordered 2&times;1 structure forms a template for the ordered growth of an overlying layer of a monocrystalline oxide. The template provides the necessary chemical and physical properties to nucleate the crystalline growth of an overlying layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> In accordance with an alternate embodiment of the invention, the native silicon oxide can be converted and the substrate surface can be prepared for the growth of a monocrystalline oxide layer by depositing an alkali earth metal oxide, such as strontium oxide, strontium barium oxide, or barium oxide, onto the substrate surface by MBE at a low temperature and by subsequently heating the structure to a temperature of about 850&deg; C. At this temperature a solid state reaction takes place between the strontium oxide and the native silicon oxide causing the reduction of the native silicon oxide and leaving an ordered 2&times;1 structure with strontium, oxygen, and silicon remaining on the substrate surface. Again, this forms a template for the subsequent growth of an ordered monocrystalline oxide layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> Following the removal of the silicon oxide from the surface of the substrate, in accordance with one embodiment of the invention, the substrate is cooled to a temperature in the range of about 200-800&deg; C. and a layer of strontium titanate is grown on the template layer by molecular beam epitaxy. The MBE process is initiated by opening shutters in the MBE apparatus to expose strontium, titanium and oxygen sources. The ratio of strontium and titanium is approximately 1:1. The partial pressure of oxygen is initially set at a minimum value to grow stoichiometric strontium titanate at a growth rate of about 0.3-0.5 nm per minute. After initiating growth of the strontium titanate, the partial pressure of oxygen is increased above the initial minimum value. The overpressure of oxygen causes the growth of an amorphous silicon oxide layer at the interface between the underlying substrate and the growing strontium titanate layer. The growth of the silicon oxide layer results from the diffusion of oxygen through the growing strontium titanate layer to the interface where the oxygen reacts with silicon at the surface of the underlying substrate. The strontium titanate grows as an ordered monocrystal with the crystalline orientation rotated by 45&deg; with respect to the ordered 2&times;1 crystalline structure of the underlying substrate. Strain that otherwise might exist in the strontium titanate layer because of the small mismatch in lattice constant between the silicon substrate and the growing crystal is relieved in the amorphous silicon oxide intermediate layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> After the strontium titanate layer has been grown to the desired thickness, the monocrystalline strontium titanate is capped by a template layer that is conducive to the subsequent growth of an epitaxial layer of a desired monocrystalline material. For example, for the subsequent growth of a monocrystalline compound semiconductor material layer of gallium arsenide, the MBE growth of the strontium titanate monocrystalline layer can be capped by terminating the growth with 1-2 monolayers of titanium, 1-2 monolayers of titanium-oxygen or with 1-2 monolayers of strontium-oxygen. Following the formation of this capping layer, arsenic is deposited to form a Ti&mdash;As bond, a Ti&mdash;O&mdash;As bond or a Sr&mdash;O&mdash;As. Any of these form an appropriate template for deposition and formation of a gallium arsenide monocrystalline layer. Following the formation of the template, gallium is subsequently introduced to the reaction with the arsenic and gallium arsenide forms. Alternatively, gallium can be deposited on the capping layer to form a Sr&mdash;O&mdash;Ga bond, and arsenic is subsequently introduced with the gallium to form the GaAs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a high resolution Transmission Electron Micrograph (TEM) of semiconductor material manufactured in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. Single crystal SrTiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> was grown epitaxially on silicon substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. During this growth process, amorphous interfacial layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> is formed which relieves strain due to lattice mismatch. GaAs compound semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> was then grown epitaxially using template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> illustrates an x-ray diffraction spectrum taken on a structure including GaAs monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> comprising GaAs grown on silicon substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> using accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. The peaks in the spectrum indicate that both the accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and GaAs compound semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> are single crystal and (100) orientated. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> The structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> can be formed by the process discussed above with the addition of an additional buffer layer deposition step. The buffer layer is formed overlying the template layer before the deposition of the monocrystalline material layer. If the buffer layer is a monocrystalline material comprising a compound semiconductor superlattice, such a superlattice can be deposited, by MBE for example, on the template described above. If instead the buffer layer is a monocrystalline material layer comprising a layer of germanium, the process above is modified to cap the strontium titanate monocrystalline layer with a final layer of either strontium or titanium and then by depositing germanium to react with the strontium or titanium. The germanium buffer layer can then be deposited directly on this template. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> Structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, may be formed by growing an accommodating buffer layer, forming an amorphous oxide layer over substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and growing semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> over the accommodating buffer layer, as described above. The accommodating buffer layer and the amorphous oxide layer are then exposed to an anneal process sufficient to change the crystalline structure of the accommodating buffer layer from monocrystalline to amorphous, thereby forming an amorphous layer such that the combination of the amorphous oxide layer and the now amorphous accommodating buffer layer form a single amorphous oxide layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. Layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> is then subsequently grown over layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. Alternatively, the anneal process may be carried out subsequent to growth of layer <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one aspect of this embodiment, layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is formned by exposing substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, the accommodating buffer layer, the amorphous oxide layer, and monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> to a rapid thermal anneal process with a peak temperature of about 700&deg; C. to about 1000&deg; C. and a process time of about 5 seconds to about 10 minutes. However, other suitable anneal processes may be employed to convert the accommodating buffer layer to an amorphous layer in accordance with the present invention. For example, laser annealing, electron beam annealing, or &ldquo;conventional&rdquo; thermal annealing processes (in the proper environment) may be used to form layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. When conventional thermal annealing is employed to form layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>, an overpressure of one or more constituents of layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> may be required to prevent degradation of layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> during the anneal process. For example, when layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> includes GaAs, the anneal environment preferably includes an overpressure of arsenic to mitigate degradation of layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> As noted above, layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> of structure <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> may include any materials suitable for either of layers <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>. Accordingly, any deposition or growth methods described in connection with either layer <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight>, may be employed to deposit layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> is a high resolution TEM of semiconductor material manufactured in accordance with the embodiment of the invention illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. In Accordance with this embodiment, a single crystal SrTia, accommodating buffer layer was grown epitaxially on silicon substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. During this growth process, an amorphous interfacial layer forms as described above. Next, additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> comprising a compound semiconductor layer of GaAs is formed above the accommodating buffer layer and the accommodating buffer layer is exposed to an anneal process to form amorphous oxide layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> illustrates an x-ray diffraction spectrum taken on a structure including additional monocrystalline layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> comprising a GaAs compound semiconductor layer and amorphous oxide layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> formed on silicon substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The peaks in the spectrum indicate that GaAs compound semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>38</bold></highlight> is single crystal and (100) orientated and the lack of peaks around 40 to 50 degrees indicates that layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> is amorphous. The process described above illustrates a process for forming a semiconductor structure including a silicon substrate, an overlying oxide layer, and a monocrystalline material layer comprising a gallium arsenide compound semiconductor layer by the process of molecular beam epitaxy. The process can also be carried out by the process of chemical vapor deposition (CVD), metal organic chemical vapor deposition (MOCVD), migration enhanced epitaxy (MEE), atomic layer epitaxy (ALE), physical vapor deposition (PVD), chemical solution deposition (CSD), pulsed laser deposition (PLD), or the like. Further, by a similar process, other monocrystalline accommodating buffer layers such as alkaline earth metal titanates, zirconates, hafnates, tantalates, vanadates, ruthenates, and niobates, peroskite oxides such as alkaline earth metal tin-based perovskites, lanthanum aluminate, lanthanum scandium oxide, and gadolinium oxide can also be grown. Further, by a similar process such as MBE, other monocrystalline material layers comprising other III-V and II-VI monocrystalline compound semiconductors, semiconductors, metals and non-metals can be deposited overlying the monocrystalline oxide accommodating buffer layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> Each of the variations of monocrystalline material layer and monocrystalline oxide accommodating buffer layer uses an appropriate template for initiating the growth of the monocrystalline material layer. For example, if the accommodating buffer layer is an alkaline earth metal zirconate, the oxide can be capped by a thin layer of zirconium. The deposition of zirconium can be followed by the deposition of arsenic or phosphorus to react with the zirconium as a precursor to depositing indium gallium arsenide, indium aluminum arsenide, or indium phosphide respectively. Similarly, if the monocrystalline oxide accommodating buffer layer is an alkaline earth metal hafnate, the oxide layer can be capped by a thin layer of hafnium. The deposition of hafnium is followed by the deposition of arsenic or phosphorous to react with the hafnium as a precursor to the growth of an indium gallium arsenide, indium aluminum arsenide, or indium phosphide layer, respectively. In a similar manner, strontium titanate can be capped with a layer of strontium or strontium and oxygen and barium titanate can be capped with a layer of barium or barium and oxygen. Each of these depositions can be followed by the deposition of arsenic or phosphorus to react with the capping material to form a template for the deposition of a monocrystalline material layer comprising compound semiconductors such as indium gallium arsenide, indium aluminum arsenide, or indium phosphide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The formation of a device structure in accordance with another embodiment of the invention is illustrated schematically in cross-section in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D. Like the previously described embodiments referred to in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, this embodiment of the invention involves the process of forming a compliant substrate utilizing the epitaxial growth of single crystal oxides, such as the formation of accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> previously described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> and amorphous layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> previously described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, and the formation of a template layer <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. However, the embodiment illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D utilizes a template that includes a surfactant to facilitate layer-by-layer monocrystalline material growth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> Turning now to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>A, an amorphous intermediate layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> is formed on substrate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> at the interface between substrate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and a growing accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> which is preferably a monocrystalline crystal oxide layer, by the oxidation of substrate <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> during the growth of layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is preferably a monocrystalline oxide material such as a monocrystalline layer of Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where z ranges from 0 to 1. However, layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> may also comprise any of those compounds previously described with reference layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> and any of those compounds previously described with reference to layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> which is formed from layers <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> referenced in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> is grown with a strontium (Sr) terminated surface represented in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9A</cross-reference> by hatched line <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> which is followed by the addition of a template layer <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> which includes a surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and capping layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9B and 9C</cross-reference>. Surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> may comprise, but is not limited to, elements such as Al, In and Ga, or a combination of one of those three elements and either Sr or Ba but will be dependent upon the composition of layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and the overlying layer of monocrystalline material for optimal results. In one exemplary embodiment, aluminum (Al) and strontium (Sr) are used simultaneously for surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and functions to modify the surface and surface energy of layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. Preferably, surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is epitaxially grown, to a thickness of one to two monolayers, over layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG.9B</cross-reference> by way of molecular beam epitaxy (MBE), although other epitaxial processes may also be performed including chemical vapor deposition (CVD), metal organic chemical vapor deposition (MOCVD), migration enhanced epitaxy (MEE), atomic layer epitaxy (ALE), physical vapor deposition (PVD), chemical solution deposition (CSD), pulsed laser deposition (PLD), or the like. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> is then exposed to a halogen such as arsenic, for example, to form capping layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9C</cross-reference>. Surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> may be exposed to a number of materials to create capping layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> such as elements which include, but are not limited to, As, P, Sb and N. Surfactant layer <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and capping layer <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> combine to form template layer <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> Monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>, which in this example is a compound semiconductor such as GaAs, is then deposited via MBE, CVD, MOCVD, MEE, ALE, PVD, CSD, PLD, and the like to form the final structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9D</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0067" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0067&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D illustrate possible molecular bond structures for a specific example of a compound semiconductor structure formed in accordance with the embodiment of the invention illustrated in FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D. More specifically, FIGS. <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>A-<highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>D illustrate the growth of GaAs (layer <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>) on the strontium terminated surface of a strontium titanate monocrystalline oxide (layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>) using a surfactant containing template (layer <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0068" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0068&rsqb;</number> The growth of a monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> such as GaAs on an accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> such as a strontium titanium oxide over amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> and substrate layer <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, both of which may comprise materials previously described with reference to layers <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, respectively in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, illustrates a critical thickness of about <highlight><bold>1000</bold></highlight> Angstroms where the two-dimensional (2D) and three-dimensional (3D) growth shifts because of the surface energies involved. In order to maintain a true layer by layer growth (Frank Van der Mere growth), the following relationship must be satisfied:</paragraph>
<paragraph lvl="0"><in-line-formula>&dgr;<highlight><subscript>STO</subscript></highlight>&gt;(&dgr;<highlight><subscript>INT&plus;&dgr;</subscript></highlight><highlight><subscript>GaAs</subscript></highlight>)</in-line-formula></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0069" lvl="2"><number>&lsqb;0069&rsqb;</number> where the surface energy of the monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> must be greater than the surface energy of the amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> added to the surface energy of the GaAs layer <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight>. Since it is impracticable to satisfy this equation, a surfactant containing template was used, as described above with reference to FIGS. <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>B-<highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>D, to increase the surface energy of the monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and also to shift the crystalline structure of the template to a diamond-like structure that is in compliance with the original GaAs layer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0070" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0070&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10A</cross-reference> illustrates the molecular bond structure of a strontium terminated surface of a strontium titanate monocrystalline oxide layer. An aluminum surfactant layer, or a codeposition of aluminum and strontium surfactant layer is deposited on top of the strontium terminated surface and bonds with that surface as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>B, which reacts to form a capping layer comprising a monolayer of Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Sr having the molecular bond structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10B</cross-reference> which forms a diamond-like structure with an sp<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>hybrid terminated surface that is compliant with compound semiconductors such as GaAs. The structure is then exposed to As to form a layer of AlAs as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10C</cross-reference>. GaAs is then deposited to complete the molecular bond structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10D</cross-reference> which has been obtained by 2D growth. The GaAs can be grown to any thickness for forming other semiconductor structures, devices, or integrated circuits. Alkaline earth metals such as those in Group IIA are those elements preferably used to form the capping surface of the monocrystal line oxide layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> because they are capable of forming a desired molecular structure with aluminum. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0071" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0071&rsqb;</number> In this embodiment, a surfactant containing template layer aids in the formation of a compliant substrate for the monolithic integration of various material layers including those comprised of Group III-V compounds to form high quality semiconductor structures, devices and integrated circuits. For example, a surfactant containing template may be used for the monolithic integration of a monocrystalline material layer such as a layer comprising Germanium (Ge), for example, to form high efficiency photocells. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0072" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0072&rsqb;</number> Turning now to FIGS. <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>, the formation of a device structure in accordance with still another embodiment of the invention is illustrated in cross-section. This embodiment utilizes the formation of a compliant substrate which relies on the epitaxial growth of single crystal oxides on silicon followed by the epitaxial growth of single crystal silicon onto the oxide. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0073" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0073&rsqb;</number> An accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> such as a monocrystalline oxide layer is first grown on a substrate layer <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, such as silicon, with an amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. Monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> may be comprised of any of those materials previously discussed with reference to layer <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, while amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>78</bold></highlight> is preferably comprised of any of those materials previously described with reference to the layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Substrate <highlight><bold>72</bold></highlight>, although preferably silicon, may also comprise any of those materials previously described with reference to substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0074" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0074&rsqb;</number> Next, a silicon layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> is deposited over monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> via MBE, CVD, MOCVD, MEE, ALE, PVD, CSD, PLD, and the like as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> with a thickness of a few hundred Angstroms but preferably with a thickness of about 50 Angstroms. Monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> preferably has a thickness of about 20 to 100 Angstroms. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0075" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0075&rsqb;</number> Rapid thermal annealing is then conducted in the presence of a carbon source such as acetylene or methane, for example at a temperature within a range of about 800&deg; C. to 1000&deg; C. to form capping layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and silicate amorphous layer <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight>. However, other suitable carbon sources may be used as long as the rapid thermal annealing step functions to amorphize the monocrystalline oxide layer <highlight><bold>74</bold></highlight> into a silicate amorphous layer <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and carbonize the top silicon layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight> to form capping layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> which in this example would be a silicon carbide (SiC) layer as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference>. The formation of amorphous layer <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> is similar to the formation of layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> and may comprise any of those materials described with reference to layer <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> but the preferable material will be dependent upon the capping layer <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> used for silicon layer <highlight><bold>81</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0076" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0076&rsqb;</number> Finally, a compound semiconductor layer <highlight><bold>96</bold></highlight>, such as gallium nitride (GaN) is grown over the SiC surface by way of MBE, CVD, MOCVD, MEE, ALE, PVD, CSD, PLD, or the like to form a high quality compound semicondcutor material for device formation. More specifically, the deposition of GaN and GaN based systems such as GaInN and AlGaN will result in the formation of dislocation nets confined at the silicon/amorphous region. The resulting nitride containing compound semiconductor material may comprise elements from groups III, IV and V of the periodic table and is defect free. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0077" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0077&rsqb;</number> Although GaN has been grown on SiC substrate in the past, this embodiment of the invention possesses a one step formation of the compliant substrate containing a SiC top surface and an amorphous layer on a Si surface. More specifically, this embodiment of the invention uses an intermediate single crystal oxide layer that is amorphosized to form a silicate layer which adsorbs the strain between the layers. Moroever, unlike past use of a SiC substrate, this embodiment of the invention is not limited by wafer size which is usually less than 2 inches in diameter for SiC substrates. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0078" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0078&rsqb;</number> The monolithic integration of nitride containing semiconductor compounds containing group III-V nitrides and silicon devices can be used for high temperature RF applications and optoelectronics. GaN systems have particular use in the photonic industry for the blue/green and UV light sources and detection. High brightness light emitting diodes (LEDs) and lasers may also be formed within the GaN system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0079" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0079&rsqb;</number> FIGS. <highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight> schematically illustrate, in cross-section, the formation of another embodiment of a device structure in accordance with the invention. This embodiment includes a compliant layer that functions as a transition layer that uses clathrate or Zintl type bonding. More specifically, this embodiment utilizes an intermetallic template layer to reduce the surface energy of the interface between material layers thereby allowing for two dimensional layer by layer growth. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0080" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0080&rsqb;</number> The structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> includes a monocrystalline substrate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight>, an amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> and an accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight>. Amorphous intermediate layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> is grown on substrate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> at the interface between substrate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as previously described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>. Amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> may comprise any of those materials previously described with reference to amorphous interface layer <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference> but preferably comprises a monocrystalline oxide material such as a monocrystalline layer of Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where z ranges from 0 to 1. Substrate <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> is preferably silicon but may also comprise any of those materials previously described with reference to substrate <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight> in FIGS. <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>-<highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0081" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0081&rsqb;</number> A template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is deposited over accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> as illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</cross-reference> and preferably comprises a thin layer of Zintl type phase material composed of metals and metalloids having a great deal of ionic character. As in previously described embodiments, template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> is deposited by way of MBE, CVD, MOCVD, MEE, ALE, PVD, CSD, PLD, or the like to achieve a thickness of one monolayer. Template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> functions as a &ldquo;soft&rdquo; layer with non-directional bonding but high crystallinity which absorbs stress build up between layers having lattice mismatch. Materials for template <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> may include, but are not limited to, materials containing Si, Ga, In, and Sb such as, for example, AlSr<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>(MgCaYb)Ga<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, (Ca,Sr,Eu,Yb)In<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>, BaGe<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>As, and SrSn<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>As<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight></paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0082" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0082&rsqb;</number> A monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> is epitaxially grown over template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> to achieve the final structure illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</cross-reference>. As a specific example, an SrAl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>layer may be used as template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> and an appropriate monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> such as a compound semiconductor material GaAs is grown over the SrAl<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0083" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0083&rsqb;</number> The Al&mdash;Ti (from the accommodating buffer layer of layer of Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where z ranges from 0 to 1) bond is mostly metallic while the Al&mdash;As (from the GaAs layer) bond is weakly covalent. The Sr participates in two distinct types of bonding with part of its electric charge going to the oxygen atoms in the lower accommodating buffer layer <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> comprising Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>to participate in ionic bonding and the other part of its valence charge being donated to Al in a way that is typically carried out with Zintl phase materials. The amount of the charge transfer depends on the relative electronegativity of elements comprising the template layer <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> as well as on the interatomic distance. In this example, Al assumes an Sp<highlight><superscript>3 </superscript></highlight>hybridization and can readily form bonds with monocrystalline material layer <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight>, which in this example, comprises compound semiconductor material GaAs. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0084" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0084&rsqb;</number> The compliant substrate produced by use of the Zintl type template layer used in this embodiment can absorb a large strain without a significant energy cost. In the above example, the bond strength of the Al is adjusted by changing the volume of the SrAl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>layer thereby making the device tunable for specific applications which include the monolithic integration of III-V and Si devices and the monolithic integration of high-k dielectric materials for CMOS technology. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0085" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0085&rsqb;</number> Clearly, those embodiments specifically describing structures having compound semiconductor portions and Group IV semiconductor portions, are meant to illustrate embodiments of the present invention and not limit the present invention. There area multiplicity of other combinations and other embodiments of the present invention. For example, the present invention includes structures and methods for fabricating material layers which form semiconductor structures, devices and integrated circuits including other layers such as metal and non-metal layers. More specifically, the invention includes structures and methods for forming a compliant substrate which is used in the fabrication of semiconductor structures, devices and integrated circuits and the material layers suitable for fabricating those structures, devices, and integrated circuits. By using embodiments of the present invention, it is now simpler to integrate devices that include monocrystalline layers comprising semiconductor and compound semiconductor materials as well as other material layers that are used to form those devices with other components that work better or are easily and/or inexpensively formed within semiconductor or compound semiconductor materials. This allows a device to be shrunk, the manufacturing costs to decrease, and yield and reliability to increase. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0086" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0086&rsqb;</number> In accordance with one embodiment of this invention, a monocrystalline semiconductor or compound semiconductor wafer can be used in forming monocrystalline material layers over the wafer. In this manner, the wafer is essentially a &ldquo;handle&rdquo; wafer used during the fabrication of semiconductor electrical components within a monocrystalline layer overlying the wafer. Therefore, electrical components can be formed within semiconductor materials over a wafer of at least approximately 200 millimeters in diameter and possibly at least approximately 300 millimeters. By the use of this type of substrate, a relatively inexpensive &ldquo;handle&rdquo; wafer overcomes the fragile nature of compound semiconductor or other monocrystalline material wafers by placing them over a relatively more durable and easy to fabricate base material. Therefore, an integrated circuit can be formed such that all electrical components, and particularly all active electronic devices, can be formed within or using the monocrystalline material layer even though the substrate itself may include a monocrystalline semiconductor material. Fabrication costs for compound semiconductor devices and other devices employing non-silicon monocrystalline materials should decrease because larger substrates can be processed more economically and more readily compared to the relatively smaller and more fragile substrates (e.g. conventional compound semiconductor wafers). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0087" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0087&rsqb;</number> In the foregoing specification, the invention has been described with reference to specific embodiments. However, one of ordinary skill in the art appreciates that various modifications and changes can be made without departing from the scope of the present invention as set forth in the claims below. Accordingly, the specification and figures are to be regarded in an illustrative rather than a restrictive sense, and all such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of present invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0088" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0088&rsqb;</number> Benefits, other advantages, and solutions to problems have been described above with regard to specific embodiments. However, the benefits, advantages, solutions to problems, and any element(s) that may cause any benefit, advantage, or solution to occur or become more pronounced are not to be construed as a critical, required, or essential features or elements of any or all the claims. As used herein, the terms &ldquo;comprises,&rdquo;&ldquo;comprising,&rdquo; or any other variation thereof, are intended to cover a non-exclusive inclusion, such that a process, method, article, or apparatus that comprises a list of elements does not include only those elements but may include other elements not expressly listed or inherent to such process, method, article, or apparatus. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">We claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A semiconductor structure comprising: 
<claim-text>a monocrystalline substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a buffer layer formed on the substrate; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a template formed on the buffer layer, the template comprising one of Ba and Sr combined with one of Al, In, and Ga; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a monocrystalline material layer formed overlying the template. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the template layer comprises a Zintl type phase material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the buffer layer comprises Sr<highlight><subscript>z</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;z</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where z ranges from 0 to 1, the template comprises SrAl<highlight><subscript>2 </subscript></highlight>and the mononcrystalline material layer comprises GaAs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the template layer comprises a surfactant material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the template layer further comprises a capping layer. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the capping layer is formed by exposing the surfactant material to a cap inducing material. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the cap inducing material comprises at least one of As, P, Sb, and N. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the capping layer comprises Al<highlight><subscript>2</subscript></highlight>Sr, and the monocrystalline material layer comprises GaAs. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the buffer layer comprises an oxide selected from the group consisting of alkaline earth metal titanates, alkaline earth metal zirconates, alkaline earth metal hafniates, alkaline earth metal tantalates, alkaline earth metal ruthenates, and alkaline earth metal niobates. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the buffer layer comprises Sr<highlight><subscript>x</subscript></highlight>Ba<highlight><subscript>1&minus;x</subscript></highlight>TiO<highlight><subscript>3 </subscript></highlight>where x ranges from 0 to 1. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the buffer layer comprises an oxide formed as a monocrystalline oxide and subsequently heat treated to convert the monocrystalline oxide to an amorphous oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline Group IV substrate is characterized by a first lattice constant and the monocrystalline material layer is characterized by a second lattice constant different than the first lattice constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline oxide is characterized by a third lattice constant different than the second lattice constant. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline Group IV substrate is characterized by a first crystalline orientation and the monocrystalline oxide is characterized by a second crystalline orientation and wherein the second crystalline orientation is rotated with respect to the first crystalline orientation. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference> further comprising a second amorphous oxide layer formed between the Group IV substrate and the monocrystalline oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the Group IV substrate comprises silicon and the second amorphous oxide layer comprises a silicon oxide. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline material layer comprises at least one of a semiconductor material, a compound semiconductor material, a metal, and a non-metal. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline material layer is a compound semiconductor material selected from the group consisting of: III-V compounds, mixed III-V compounds, II-VI compounds, and mixed II-VI compounds. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>19</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline material layer comprises a material selected from the group consisting of: GaAs, AlGaAs, InP, InGaAs, InGaP, ZnSe, and ZnSeS. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the buffer layer has a thickness of about 2-10 nm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>21</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00022">claim 20</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the amorphous oxide layer has a thickness of about 5-6 nm. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>. The semiconductor structure of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein the monocrystalline material layer comprises a semiconductor or a compound semiconductor.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001207A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
