<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001209A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001209A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001209A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001209A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001209A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001209A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001209A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001209A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001209A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001209A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001209</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>09894083</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>09</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20010628</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>H01L021/84</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L021/8222</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-secondary>
<ipc>H01L027/12</ipc>
</classification-ipc-secondary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>350000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>257</class>
<subclass>347000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>152000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>155000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
<classification-us-secondary>
<uspc>
<class>438</class>
<subclass>309000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-secondary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>HV-SOI LDMOS device with integrated diode to improve reliability and avalanche ruggedness</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Petruzzello</given-name>
<family-name>John</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Carmel</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Letavic</given-name>
<middle-name>Theodore</middle-name>
<family-name>James</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Putnam Valley</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Simpson</given-name>
<family-name>Mark</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>White Plains</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS ELECTRONICS N.V.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>02</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>Corporate Patent Counsel</name-1>
<name-2>U.S. Philips Corporation</name-2>
<address>
<address-1>580 White Plains Road</address-1>
<city>Tarrytown</city>
<state>NY</state>
<postalcode>10591</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A hybrid semiconductor device is presented in which one or more diode regions are integrated into a transistor region. In a preferred embodiment the transistor region is a continuous (self-terminating) SOI LDMOS device in which are integrated one or more diode portions. Within the diode portions, since there is only one PN junction, the mechanism for breakdown failure due to bipolar turn-on is nonexistent. The diode regions are formed such that they have a lower breakdown voltage than the transistor region, and thus any transient voltage (or current) induced breakdown is necessarily contained in the diode regions. In a preferred embodiment, the breakdown voltage of the diode portions is lowered by narrowing their field plate length relative to the transistor portion of the device. This allows the device to survive any such breakdown without being destroyed, resulting in a more rugged and more reliable device. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to the field of semiconductor devices, and more particularly to silicon-on-insulator lateral drift metal oxide semiconductor (SOI-LDMOS) devices suitable for high-voltage applications. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates generally to, and has features in common with, an invention disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 09/794,562, filed Feb. 27, 2001 by the same applicants (the &ldquo;&apos;562 Application&rdquo;), which prior-filed application is incorporated herein by reference as if fully set forth. The &apos;562 Application dealt generally with SOI LDMOS devices exemplary of the devices discussed herein. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> In known MOSFET devices, a conductive path is established between two regions of the same conductivity type, i.e. the source and drain, through a body region of the opposite conductivity type. The current flows in such channel region, or in LDMOS devices, through such body region and a &ldquo;lateral drift&rdquo; region, in response to an applied gate voltage which creates an inversion channel in the body region, and a drain to source voltage which regulates the current which flows therein. In normal MOSFET operation, both the drain and the source regions are reverse biased vis-&agrave;-vis the body region. Due to this reverse biasing, no current flows between the drain and source except in the channel region. Thus, current can only flow from drain to source, and electrons thus flow from source to drain, as controlled by the voltage on the gate and the drain to source voltage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> If during device operation the reverse bias between the source and body regions changes to forward bias, a significant current can develop where the source region injects electrons into the body region and back to the drain region. Since this current is not directly controlled by the gate voltage or any other mechanism, it is in effect a runaway current, and can destroy the device. Such breakdown is generally referred to as &ldquo;bipolar second breakdown.&rdquo;</paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> For example, in a lighting application, a typical drain to source voltage is 400 V; if a surge in such drain to source voltage reaches 500 V or more, the semiconductor device may breakdown due to such bipolar turn-on, when a significant current develops between the source and drain regions, and ultimately the device will be destroyed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Therefore, it is an object of the present invention to provide an improved semiconductor device in which it is possible to control and contain any electrical breakdown such as to obviate destruction of the device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> It is a further object of the present invention to provide an improved semiconductor device which is highly resistant to bipolar second breakdown. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> These and other objects will become more apparent from the description of the invention to follow. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The present invention achieves the foregoing objects by providing a hybrid semiconductor device in which one or more diode regions are integrated into a transistor region. In a preferred embodiment the transistor region is a continuous (self-terminating) device in which are integrated one or more diode portions. Within the diode portions, since there is only one PN junction, the mechanism for breakdown failure due to bipolar turn-on is nonexistent. The diode regions are formed such that they have a lower breakdown voltage than the transistor region, and thus any transient voltage (or current) induced breakdown is necessarily contained in the diode regions. In a preferred embodiment, the breakdown voltage of the diode portions is lowered by narrowing their field plate length relative to the transistor portion of the device. This allows the device to survive any such breakdown without being destroyed, resulting in a more rugged and more reliable SOI LDMOS device.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a schematic top plan view of a high voltage SOI MOSFET hybrid device according to the invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a cross sectional view of the hybrid device taken along line A-A&prime;of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> to portray its diode portion; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> depicts a cross section of an exemplary SOI LDMOS structure such as may be used for the transistor portion; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is a plot of breakdown voltage as a function of the field plate length.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> The motivation of the present invention is a simple idea. Given that power transistors can be seriously damaged by bipolar second breakdown, such breakdowns need to be prevented, and any overvoltage breakdowns contained and controlled. Since avalanche breakdown in diodes cannot lead to bipolar second breakdown, a diode structure is integrated within a transistor device, and engineered so as to have a lower breakdown voltage than the transistor. Thus, any breakdown is contained only to the diode device, rendering the overall transistor more rugged and robust. The diode regions serve as a kind of shock absorber or lightning rod for a transient current or voltage spike and the avalanche breakdown that may result therefrom. They absorb the overvoltage and survive it, leaving the transistor unscathed. The transistor structure can be easily modified to form the diode structure, by simply deleting the source region of the transistor structure. Thus, merely a simple modification to the fabrication of the transistor structure is needed to create the integrated device. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> In accordance with the objects of the invention, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> illustrates a high voltage silicon-on-insulator (SOI) hybrid semiconductor device <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> in top plan view. The device is self terminating&mdash;i.e., the width is a continuous connected path, with &ldquo;fingers&rdquo; <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> at the bottom of the figure for achieving larger device width within a smaller area. It is noted that if greater device width is desired fingers could be added at the top and sides of the shown structure as well, the depicted structure being solely an exemplary one of numerous possible embodiments. As will be clearer from a comparison of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</cross-reference>, the latter figure being a cross section along the arrow A-A&prime; in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>, the source <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> comprises the exterior of the device, the drain <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> comprises the interior, and the gate <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> lies in between the source and drain, and is electrically connected to a field plate which extends drainward, or towards the interior of the device, for most of the length of the device, which is the direction perpendicular to the continuous path at any point along the depicted path. Where the gap appears in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> between the drain region <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> on the interior and the source region on the exterior of the device is the area between the drainward edge of the field plate and the drain <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>. The gate <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> is located in the middle of the source <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and drain <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight> regions. The diode portions <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> of the integrated device (the left side diode region in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shown in cross section in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>) are here depicted as two regions, but more or less could be fashioned as desired by the user. The diode regions are delineated from the remainder of the transistor by upper lines <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and lower lines <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> Inasmuch as <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</cross-reference> depict very similar structures, and the structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is derived from that of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> with a deletion, <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> will next be described. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> In the simplified cross-sectional view of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3, a</cross-reference> lateral thin film SOI LDMOS transistor includes a semiconductor substrate <highlight><bold>322</bold></highlight>, a buried insulating layer <highlight><bold>324</bold></highlight>, and a semiconductor surface layer <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> in which the device is fabricated. The MOS transistor includes a source region <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> of one conductivity type (here shown, for example, as n-type), a body region <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> of a second, opposite conductivity type (here, for example, as p-type), a lateral drift region <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> of the first conductivity type and a drain region <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>, also of the first conductivity type. The edge of the body region adjoining the drift region is denoted by reference number <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>A. The basic device structure is completed by a gate electrode <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>, insulated from the semiconductor surface layer <highlight><bold>326</bold></highlight> by an oxide insulation region <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>. Within the scope of the invention, the MOS transistor structure used in the present invention will preferably have various performance enhancing features such as a stepped oxide region <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>338</bold></highlight>B, an extended gate electrode structure forming a field portion <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>A, an insulating oxide layer <highlight><bold>342</bold></highlight> covering the gate electrode <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight> and extended gate electrode <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>A, a top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> made of a metal or equivalently conductive material, an extended portion of the top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>A protruding laterally towards the drain side of the device, as well as numerous and various other performance enhancing features as may be desired, without departing from the spirit or scope of the invention. As well, the depicted MOS transistor includes a surface contact region <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight>, in contact with the source region <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>, located in the body region <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and being of the same conductivity type as the body region but more highly doped. It is noted that for use with high voltage applications, where the drain to source voltage is on the order of hundreds of volts, the conducting top field plate is a necessity in order to hold the voltage. The voltage that can be held is proportional to the length of the field plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> additionally shows a metal top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight> connected to the extended polysilicon gate electrode structure <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>A, an extension of the top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>A, an insulating layer <highlight><bold>351</bold></highlight> above the top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>, and extended top field plate <highlight><bold>344</bold></highlight>A, and the three metal contacts to the gate <highlight><bold>336</bold></highlight>, source <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>, and drain <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> of the device, being items <highlight><bold>352</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>353</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>354</bold></highlight>, respectively. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> Additionally, the increase in shading from light to dark of the lateral drift region <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight> from the left to the right of the figure, i.e., from the source side to the drain side of the drift region, indicates an increasing doping profile with drainward proximity as is known in the art. Such increased doping may be linear, or some other profile as may be useful in given circumstances and uses, as is known, or may be known, in the art. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> depicts the derived diode device, and is identical in structure to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> except for the absence of the source region on the left side of the figure. All that remains in its stead, with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, is the surface contact region <highlight><bold>240</bold></highlight>. Another exception, as shall be described, is the length of the field plate <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, which does not extend as far drainward, or to the right, in the diode structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> as it does in the transistor structure of <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> It is understood that the simplified representative devices shown in the Figures herein depict particular device structures, but that wide variations in both device geometry and configuration can be used within the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> As described above, the diode regions serve as a kind of lightning rod or shock absorber of any overvoltage breakdown. By creating one or more diode portions within the overall semiconductor device, if an overvoltage breakdown occurs, it will occur in diode regions. The current flow will be held to a level such that a breakdown will not mean a device failure. It is noted, however, that if the voltage is high enough even a diode can fail. This would occur as the result of an avalanche breakdown, where the current reaches high enough levels for the temperature to rise significantly, and the metal in the device melts. This is generally a rare occurrence, however. In any event, a diode avalanche can never lead to a bipolar second breakdown, as described above. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> On the other hand, in the transistor region, if a bipolar second breakdown occurs this could well destroy the device. The reason is as follows. Referring to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, if the current is large enough&mdash;due, for example, to a voltage spike on the drain&mdash;numerous holes in the body region <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> will travel underneath the source region <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> towards the surface <highlight><bold>340</bold></highlight> contact, and forward bias the PN junction between the body region <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and the source <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>. This will turn on the NPN transistor comprising the drift region (N) <highlight><bold>332</bold></highlight>, the body region (P) <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight>, and the source region (N) <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight>. This results in the source <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> injecting electrons into the body region <highlight><bold>330</bold></highlight> and out to the drain <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight>, at the operating gain of such NPN transistor. This current is thus uncontrolled (as the &ldquo;base&rdquo; current from the body region into the source is uncontrolled) and thus the flow of electrons from &ldquo;emitter to collector&rdquo;, i.e., from the source <highlight><bold>328</bold></highlight> to the drain <highlight><bold>334</bold></highlight> results in an avalanche and destroys the device. Removing the source leaves only one PN junction, and obviates the NPN gain, and thus the bipolar second breakdown, from ever occurring, and the resulting diode region can handle the avalanche through it, provided the breakdown is controlled to occur only in the diode regions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> To insure that the breakdown occurs in the diode regions, the diode field plate <highlight><bold>244</bold></highlight>, with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, has a shorter length. A shorter field plate implies a lower breakdown voltage, as seen in graphical form in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference>. As shown, with a field plate length L of approximately 45 &mgr;m, a breakdown will occur at approximately 675 volts, whereas at a field plate length L of approximately 24 &mgr;m, breakdown will occur at 470 volts. In other words, the product designer can, with the aid of the invention, predetermine the level of breakdown voltage, providing a predictable degree of protection. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> While the present invention is described with respect to specific embodiments thereof, it is recognized that various modifications and variations thereof may be made without departing from the scope and spirit of the invention, which is more clearly understood by reference to the claims appended hereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. A hybrid semiconductor device, comprising: 
<claim-text>a first portion being relatively resistant to breakdown; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a second portion being less resistant to breakdown. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first portion comprises a MOSFET transistor device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the second portion comprises a diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein the first portion comprises a MOS transistor and the second portion comprises a diode. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, where the diode has the identical structure as the MOS transistor, except for a source region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, where breakdown occurs at a higher voltage in the first portion, and at a lower voltage in the second portion. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00006">claim 6</dependent-claim-reference>, where the breakdown voltage differential is due to a difference in field plate length. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, where the transistor is an SOI-LDMOS device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00008">claim 8</dependent-claim-reference>, where the transistor is any of an NMOS or PMOS device. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. A method of constructing a rugged transistor device, comprising: 
<claim-text>integrating in the device one or more nontransistor regions whose future performance is not damaged by an overvoltage breakdown; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>arranging the device such that overvoltage breakdown always occurs in said nontransistor region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, where the nontransistor regions each comprises a diode; </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, where the nontransistor regions have a lower breakdown voltage than that of the transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 13</dependent-claim-reference>, where the nontransistor regions have a shorter field plate length than that of the transistor. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference> where the diode regions have a nearly identical structure as the transistor regions. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. A hybrid lateral thin-film Silicon-on-Insulator device comprising: 
<claim-text>a first region comprising: 
<claim-text>a semiconductor substrate, a buried insulating layer on said substrate, and a lateral MOS device in an SOI layer on said buried insulating layer and having a source region of a first conductivity type formed in a body region of a second conductivity type opposite to that of the first, a lateral drift region of said first conductivity type adjacent to said body region, a drain region of said first conductivity type and laterally spaced apart from said body region by said lateral drift region, a gate electrode over a part of said body region and over a first part of said lateral drift region adjacent to said body region, said gate electrode being insulated from said body region and drift region by a first insulation region, with a field plate comprised of conducting material extending laterally over said lateral drift region and being electrically connected to said gate electrode; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>one or more second regions integrated with the first region, said second regions being identical to the first region, except not comprising said source region, and having a field plate of shorter length than that of the first region. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight>. The device of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 15</dependent-claim-reference>, where the width of each of the second regions is at least as long as the lateral drift region. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>17</bold></highlight>. A method of obviating bipolar second breakdown in MOS transistor devices, comprising: 
<claim-text>integrating one or more diode regions in the MOS device; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>setting the breakdown voltage of the diode devices to be lower than that of the MOS transistor regions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight>. The method of <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 17</dependent-claim-reference>, where the lower breakdown voltage of the diode regions is set by shortening the field plate relative to the transistor regions.</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>2</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001209A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001209A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001209A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001209A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001209A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
