<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00006.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00007.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00008.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00009.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00010.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00011.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00012.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00013.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030001946A1-20030102-D00014.TIF SYSTEM "US20030001946A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030001946</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10175380</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020620</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<foreign-priority-data>
<priority-application-number>
<doc-number>P2001-199082</doc-number>
</priority-application-number>
<filing-date>20010629</filing-date>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</foreign-priority-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>B41J002/47</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>347</class>
<subclass>254000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Image recorder and method of recording image</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Hiroshi</given-name>
<family-name>Nomoto</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
<inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Takahide</given-name>
<family-name>Hirawa</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-non-us>
<city>Kyoto</city>
<country-code>JP</country-code>
</residence-non-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</inventor>
</inventors>
<assignee>
<organization-name>Dainippon Screen Mfg. Co., Ltd.</organization-name>
<assignee-type>03</assignee-type>
</assignee>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>MCDERMOTT, WILL &amp; EMERY</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>600 13th Street, N.W.</address-1>
<city>WASHINGTON</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postalcode>20005-3096</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">An image quality on a recording material is influenced by, for example, the sensitivity of a developer for use in developing the recording material. Compensating for the lowering of the sensitivity of the developer requires increasing the amount of emission of a laser beam. However, there is a difference in the amount of change between dimensions, in a main scanning direction and in a sub-scanning direction, of a dot blackened depending on the increase in the amount of emission of the laser beam. Increasing or decreasing the time duration of emission of the laser beam by a predetermined amount achieves adjustment of the dimension of the dot in the main scanning direction. Specifically, there is provided a memory for storing therein the sensitivity of the developer, the amount of emission of the laser beam and the time duration of emission of the laser beam in corresponding relation to each other, and the emission from a laser light source is adjusted by reading the amount and time duration of emission corresponding to the sensitivity of the developer from the memory. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to an image recorder for directing a laser beam onto a recording material to record information about an image on the recording material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Background Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> An example of background art image recorders directs a laser beam modulated in accordance with an image signal onto a recording material to selectively form a plurality of dots (or a latent image of dots) on the recording medium, thereby recording information about a two-dimensional image thereon. After development, a region on the recording material in which energy exceeding a predetermined threshold is stored is blackened to become a visible dot. For high-quality image recording, it is necessary to record information about an image so that a plurality of dots to be formed have a desired size. Factors which influence the size of dots to be formed on the recording material are roughly divided into three types: factors inherent in a characteristic of the recording material (such as a gamma characteristic of the recording material); factors dependent upon the image recorder (such as the time duration of light emission from a laser light source per dot, and an energy amount (density) of a laser beam or the amount of light emitted from the laser light source); and factors dependent upon a recording material developing apparatus (such as a developer (developing solution) sensitivity, a developer temperature, and developing time). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> The influence of the sensitivity of a recording material upon a dot density and a dot size will be described with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows a correlation between the amount of energy provided to the recording material by the laser beam and a black density of the recording material. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference>, producing an image at a desired density D on a recording material having a gamma characteristic GO requires irradiation of the recording material with a laser beam having an energy amount E<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, whereas producing an image at a desired density D on a recording material having a gamma characteristic G<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> requires irradiation of the recording material with a laser beam having an energy amount E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Thus, there are variations in required energy amount depending on the sensitivity of the recording material. Further, the energy amount of a beam spot, in general, shows a concentric intensity distribution. Thus, irradiation of the recording material with the laser beam having an energy amount held at E<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> in spite of a change in the gamma characteristic of the recording material from G<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to G<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> results in the recorded dots having a relatively small size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> Of the three factors (the developer temperature, the developing time and the developer sensitivity) dependent upon the recording material developing apparatus, the developer temperature and the developing time are relatively easily controlled optimally by the developing apparatus. It has been, however, difficult to control the developer sensitivity to be held constant because of its characteristic. This presents a problem such that, even if the image recorder forms a correct latent image of dots on the recording material, the developing apparatus cannot correctly develop the recording material to fail to form dots of desired density and size on the recording material. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> The present invention is intended for an image recorder for recording information about a two-dimensional image made up of a plurality of dots on a recording material by relatively moving a laser spot in a main scanning direction and in a sub-scanning direction, the laser spot being formed on the recording material by irradiation with a laser beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> According to the present invention, the image recorder comprises: a laser light source for emitting the laser beam; a laser light source drive part for driving the laser light source, based on an image signal; an input part for inputting factor information influencing the size of the dots; and a setting part for adjusting and setting a light emission duration per dot and a light emission amount of the laser light source in accordance with the factor information inputted by the input part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> The image recorder can adjust and set the light emission duration per dot and the light emission amount of the laser light source to individually adjust the dimensions, in the main scanning direction and in the sub-scanning direction, of the dots to be formed on the recording material. This allows the proper recording of the information about the two-dimensional image even if a change occurs in the factor information influencing the dot dimensions to cause non-uniform changes in the dot dimensions in the main scanning direction and the sub-scanning direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> According to one aspect of the present invention, the factor information includes at least one of a first factor related to a characteristic of the recording material and a second factor related to processing of a recorded material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> This allows the proper recording of the information about the two-dimensional image even if a change occurs in at least one of the first factor related to the characteristic of the recording material and the second factor related to processing of the recorded material to cause a change in the dot dimensions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, the image recorder further comprises an image signal correction part for correcting the image signal to be provided to the laser light source drive part, wherein the setting part is capable of providing a light emission timing correction signal for correcting the light emission duration of the laser light source to the image signal correction part, and of providing a light amount setting signal for setting the light emission amount of the laser light source to the laser light source drive part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> This simplifies the adjustment of the light emission duration and the light emission amount of the laser light source. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> According to another aspect of the present invention, the image recorder further comprises a memory for storing therein the factor information, the light emission timing correction signal and the light amount setting signal in corresponding relation to each other, wherein the setting part reads from the memory the light emission timing correction signal and the light amount setting signal corresponding to the factor information inputted by the input part. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> This facilitates the obtainment of the proper light emission duration and light emission amount of the laser light source corresponding to the factor information. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> The present invention is also intended for a method of recording information about a two-dimensional image made up of a plurality of dots on a recording material by relatively moving a laser spot in a main scanning direction and in a sub-scanning direction, the laser spot being formed on the recording material by irradiation with a laser beam. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide an image recorder capable of constantly recording information about a desired two-dimensional image on a recording material independently of a change in factor information influencing the size of dots. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> These and other objects, features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a conceptual view of a beam profile of a laser beam; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> shows a waveform of a laser light source drive signal; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> shows an energy distribution of the laser beam; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> shows energy storage caused by laser beam irradiation; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a graph representing the energy distribution of the laser beam in a sub-scanning direction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</cross-reference> are graphs representing the energy distribution of the laser beam in a main scanning direction; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a top view of an image recording system applied to a preferred embodiment according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side view of the image recording system applied to the preferred embodiment according to the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram of a processing section in an image recorder; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows the memory contents in a memory; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a construction of an image signal correction circuit; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 13 and 14</cross-reference> are diagrams showing an example of processing in the image signal correction circuit; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</cross-reference> shows a relation between a gamma characteristic of a recording material and a required energy amount. </paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The principles of the present invention will be described first. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> For stable image quality, it is necessary that a dimension (referred to hereinafter as a sub-scanning dimension) of a dot in a sub-scanning direction and a dimension (referred to hereinafter as a main scanning dimension) thereof in a main scanning direction are held constant independently of a change in the aforementioned various factors (the recording material sensitivity, the developer sensitivity, and the like) which influence the dot size. This is achieved by adjusting the balance between the factors. However, if the developer sensitivity is lowered, this problem is not solved by a simple technique such as to increase the amount of light to compensate for the lowered developer sensitivity. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> shows an example of the profile of a laser beam held stationary. When a pulse having a waveform as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is applied as a laser light source drive signal to drive a laser light source while moving the laser beam relative to a recording material, energy having a distribution as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is stored in the recording material. As a result, energy exceeding a blackening threshold is stored in a region indicated by the reference character b in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> showing the energy storage resulting from the laser beam irradiation. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> The lowering of the developer sensitivity causes the region b to be insufficiently blackened, resulting in the formation of a dot having an insufficient size. In this case, the amount of light emitted from the laser light source may be increased to change the energy distribution of a beam spot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> It should be noted, however, that the adjustment of the amount of light emitted from the laser light source has different degrees of influence upon the main scanning dimension and the sub-scanning dimension, respectively, of the dot. Specifically, the sub-scanning dimension of the region to be blackened is approximately equal to the dimension of a section, taken on the blackening threshold, of the energy distribution of a laser spot moving on the recording material. However, in order to determine the main scanning dimension of the region, it is necessary to consider more than one factor. Since the image formation position of the laser spot on the recording material is always moving in the main scanning direction even during the exposure of the same dot, not only the shape of the laser spot but also the waveform of the laser light source drive signal is closely related to the main scanning dimension of the region to be blackened. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> The foregoing will be detailed with reference to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</cross-reference>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> shows the position of the laser beam in the sub-scanning direction (along the horizontal axis) versus the amount of energy stored by the laser beam directed onto various positions (along the vertical axis). <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> shows the position of the laser beam in the main scanning direction (along the horizontal axis) versus the amount of energy stored by the laser beam directed onto various positions (along the vertical axis). It is now assumed that a required sub-scanning dimension of a dot is WX<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. A change in the developer sensitivity changes the amount of energy required to blacken the recording material (referred to simply as a &ldquo;required energy amount&rdquo; hereinafter). When the developer sensitivity has a value (assumed to be C<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>) corresponding to a required energy amount E<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, exposure to (or irradiation with) a laser beam having an energy distribution indicated by E&equals;F(X) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> produces a dot having the sub-scanning dimension WX<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>. When the developer sensitivity is relatively lowered to a value (assumed to be C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>) corresponding to a required energy amount E<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, exposure to a laser beam increased in the amount of emitted light and having an energy distribution indicated by E&equals;F&prime;(X) produces a dot having a sub-scanning dimension WX<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; (approximately equal to WX<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> Such an adjustment of the amount of emitted light changes an energy distribution in the main scanning direction from E&equals;G(Y) to E&equals;G&prime;(Y) in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>. This increases the amount of energy stored in the recording material to provide a main scanning dimension WY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; approximately equal to an original main scanning dimension WY<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> even if the developer sensitivity is lowered from the value C<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> to the value C<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. However, there arises a deviation &Dgr;WY between WY<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> (the required main scanning dimension) and WY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&prime; (the main scanning dimension after only the adjustment of the amount of emitted light) because of the energy storage effect in the main scanning direction as described above which need not be considered for the sub-scanning direction. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> The deviation &Dgr;WY of the main scanning dimension can be eliminated by adjusting a main scanning rate or adjusting the time duration of light emission from the laser light source per dot. Assuming the main scanning rate to be V, increasing or decreasing (in the above example, increasing) the time duration of light emission from the laser light source per dot by an amount (assumed to be a correction amount &Dgr;T) obtained by dividing the deviation &Dgr;WY by the main scanning rate V allows the recording of a dot having a proper main scanning dimension as well on the recording material. This eliminates the deviation &Dgr;WY without any influence upon the sub-scanning dimension of the dot. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference> shows a stored energy distribution in the main scanning direction when an output waveform of the laser light source drive signal is increased by the correction amount &Dgr;T to eliminate the deviation &Dgr;WY. The energy distribution at this time is indicated by E&equals;G&Prime;(Y) as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>, and the main scanning dimension of a dot is adjusted to WY<highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>&Prime;(&equals;WY<highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> Thus, even if a change occurs in at least one of the factors which influence the dot size on the recording material, the combination of adjustment items having different degrees of influence upon the main scanning dimension and the sub-scanning dimension allows the recording of a dot of proper size at all times. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Although the change in the developer sensitivity is compensated for by the combination of the adjustment of the amount of emission of the laser beam and the adjustment of the time duration of light emission per dot in the above description, it is needless to say that a different combination of adjustment items may be used. For example, the change in developer sensitivity may be compensated for by changing the amount of emission of the laser beam and the main scanning rate. Although the compensation for the change in the developer sensitivity is described above as an example, other changes may be compensated for. For example, the present invention is applicable when a changes is made in the developer temperature and developing time in the developing apparatus or in the sensitivity of the recording material. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> An image recording system to which the present invention is applied will now be described with reference to the drawings. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</cross-reference> is a top view of an image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to which the present invention is applied, and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference> is a side view thereof. The image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> comprises a plate supply apparatus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, an image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and an automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Plates for use in the image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> include a heat-sensitive material (generally referred to as a &ldquo;thermal plate&rdquo;) which responds to heat generated by laser beam irradiation to record information about an image thereon. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The plate supply apparatus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> extracts a plate stored in a cassette <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> and transports the plate to a feed passage <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> of the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. Typically, a plurality of plates are stored in the cassette <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is provided to record information about a two-dimensional image comprised of a plurality of dots onto the plate supplied from the plate supply apparatus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. As illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</cross-reference>, the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> comprises a recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> rotating with the supplied plate wound around an outer periphery thereof, a recording head <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> for irradiating the plate wound around the outer periphery of the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with a laser beam modulated in accordance with an image signal, and a discharge passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> for moving the information-recorded plate in a switch-backing manner to transport the information-recorded plate to the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> in the next stage. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> The automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> develops with a developer the plate on which information about an image is recorded, and then dries the plate. The automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> comprises a developer tank and a drying section both not shown. The automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> performs feedback control so that the temperature of the developer in the developer tank and the developing time (the time required for the plate to pass through the developer tank and the drying section) are maintained constant. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0048" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0048&rsqb;</number> In such an image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the plate stored in the cassette <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight> of the plate supply apparatus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> is transported to the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> while part of the plate is fixedly held under suction by a movable suction arm <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> of an autoloader mechanism <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> in the plate supply apparatus <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0049" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0049&rsqb;</number> Then, this plate passes through the feed passage <highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight> in the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and is wound around the outer periphery of the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. In this state, the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> rotates at high speeds. A laser light source incorporated in the recording head <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> irradiates a surface of the rotating plate wound around the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> with the laser beam modulated in accordance with the image signal. Thus, the recording head <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> records information about an image in the main scanning direction of the plate. The recording head <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> also moves along the axis of rotation of the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> in synchronism with the rotation of the recording drum. Thus, the recording head <highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight> records information about the image in the sub-scanning direction of the plate. In this manner, the information about a desired two-dimensional image is recorded on the surface of the plate. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0050" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0050&rsqb;</number> The plate on which the information about an image is recorded is transported through the discharge passage <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> of the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> to the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. This plate is developed in the developer tank of the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, dried by the drying section, and is then discharged out of the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The developer tank is equipped with a sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> (see <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference>) for measuring the electric conductivity of the developer. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0051" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0051&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</cross-reference> is a block diagram showing a construction of a processing section of the image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to which the present invention is applied. The processing section includes the sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> as an element included in the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The processing section further includes a developer sensitivity input part <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight>, a plate type input part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, a setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, a memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, an image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, a laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> and a laser light source <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> all of which are elements included in the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0052" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0052&rsqb;</number> The sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> measures the electric conductivity <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> of the developer in the developer tank in the above-mentioned automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. Since the electric conductivity, in general, is highly correlated with the developer sensitivity, the developer sensitivity is detected by measuring the electric conductivity of the developer. The developer sensitivity input part <highlight><bold>31</bold></highlight> inputs the electric conductivity <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> measured by the sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> to the setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>. The plate type input part <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> inputs a plate type <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> of a plate <highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight> wounded around the recording drum <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, and includes a known keyboard or mouse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0053" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0053&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference> shows the memory contents in the memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> stores therein the electric conductivity <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight>, a light emission timing correction signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> and a laser light amount signal <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> in corresponding relation to each plate type <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight>, the laser light amount signal <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> being provided for attaining the amount of light emitted from the laser light source <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> required to form dots of proper size. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0054" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0054&rsqb;</number> The plate types <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> in the memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are classified according to the degree of response to laser irradiation or the developer, such as the above-mentioned gamma characteristic. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0055" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0055&rsqb;</number> An increase/decrease indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and a correction amount indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>in the memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> constitute the above-mentioned light emission timing correction signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight>. The correction amount indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is a signal for specifying the amount of delay of the image signal to be caused by delay circuits <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to be described later. The amount of delay corresponds to the above-mentioned correction amount &Dgr;T. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0056" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0056&rsqb;</number> The setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> inputs the electric conductivity <highlight><bold>61</bold></highlight> and the plate type <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> to the memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. The setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> also sends the light emission timing correction signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> outputted from the memory <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> to the image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight>, and sends the laser light amount signal <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> to the laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0057" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0057&rsqb;</number> The image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> corrects an image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> sent from an image processing apparatus not shown to output a corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. The laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> generates a laser light source drive signal <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, based on the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> and the laser light amount signal <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>. The laser light source <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight> emits a laser beam <highlight><bold>69</bold></highlight>, based on the laser light source drive signal <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0058" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0058&rsqb;</number> The image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> comprises a switch circuit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight>, the delay circuits <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight>, an AND gate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> and an OR gate <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>; as typically illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</cross-reference>. The light emission timing correction signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight> includes the increase/decrease indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>and the correction amount indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b, </italic></highlight>as shown in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</cross-reference>. The increase/decrease indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>controls the switch circuit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to determine whether to send the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> inputted to the image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> to the delay circuit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and the AND gate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> or to the delay circuit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> and the OR gate <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The correction amount indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>b </italic></highlight>is sent to the delay circuits <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> to cause the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> inputted thereto via the switch circuit <highlight><bold>51</bold></highlight> to delay by a length of time corresponding to the above-mentioned correction amount &Dgr;T. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0059" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0059&rsqb;</number> If a need exists to decrease the main scanning dimension of dots, a decreasing correction is performed on the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. For the decreasing correction, the increase/decrease indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>indicates &ldquo;decrease (D),&rdquo; and the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is sent to a branch including the AND gate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. On the other hand, if a need exists to increase the main scanning dimension of dots, an increasing correction is performed on the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. For the increasing correction, the increase/decrease indication signal <highlight><bold>63</bold></highlight><highlight><italic>a </italic></highlight>indicates &ldquo;increase (A),&rdquo; and the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is sent to a branch including the OR gate <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0060" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0060&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> is a diagram for illustrating the image signal correction when the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is sent to the branch including the AND gate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight>. The delay circuit <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> outputs a delayed image signal <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> which lags the delay time &Dgr;T behind the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The AND gate <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> performs an AND operation on the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the delayed image signal <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to output the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. It will be apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</cross-reference> that the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is shorter by the correction amount &Dgr;T than the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0061" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0061&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> is a diagram for illustrating the image signal correction when the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> is sent to the branch including the OR gate <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight>. The delay circuit <highlight><bold>53</bold></highlight> outputs the delayed image signal <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> which lags the delay time &Dgr;T behind the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. The OR gate <highlight><bold>55</bold></highlight> performs an OR operation on the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the delayed image signal <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> to output the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight>. It will be apparent from <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</cross-reference> that the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is longer by the correction amount &Dgr;T than the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0062" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0062&rsqb;</number> The corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> is outputted to the laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight>. The laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> generates the laser light source drive signal <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight> for emitting a laser beam to be turned on/off by the corrected image signal <highlight><bold>67</bold></highlight> with power responsive to the laser light amount signal <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight> sent from the setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight>, thereby to drive the laser light source <highlight><bold>37</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0063" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0063&rsqb;</number> In the image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> as discussed above, if a change occurs in at least one of the sensitivity of the plate (recording material) and the developer sensitivity of the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, the setting part <highlight><bold>33</bold></highlight> sets conditions depending on the change for the image signal correction circuit <highlight><bold>35</bold></highlight> and the laser light source drive signal generator <highlight><bold>36</bold></highlight> which in turn adjust the image signal <highlight><bold>65</bold></highlight> and the laser beam amount, respectively. Therefore, the image recording system <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> is capable of always recording a high-quality image on the plate (recording material). </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0064" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0064&rsqb;</number> Although the sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> equipped with the developer tank for measuring the electric conductivity automatically detects the sensitivity of the developer in the above preferred embodiment, the present invention is not limited to such a configuration. For example, the automatic developing apparatus <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> may develop a sample (known as a control strip) on which a standard image of stepwise varying densities is formed, thereby to measure the sensitivity of the developer. In this case, the sensor <highlight><bold>41</bold></highlight> is not used, but a user manually enters a value indicating the sensitivity of the developer through an input part including a known keyboard or mouse. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0065" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0065&rsqb;</number> Although the image recorder <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> is of the external drum recording type in the above-mentioned preferred embodiment, it is needless to say that the present invention is also applicable to an internal drum recording type and to a plane scanning type. Thus, the present invention is widely applicable independently of recording methods. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0066" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0066&rsqb;</number> While the invention has been described in detail, the foregoing description is in all aspects illustrative and not restrictive. It is understood that numerous other modifications and variations can be devised without departing from the scope of the invention. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">What is claimed is: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An image recorder for recording information about a two-dimensional image made up of a plurality of dots on a recording material by relatively moving a laser spot in a main scanning direction and in a sub-scanning direction, said laser spot being formed on said recording material by irradiation with a laser beam, said image recorder comprising: 
<claim-text>a laser light source for emitting said laser beam; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a laser light source drive part for driving said laser light source, based on an image signal; </claim-text>
<claim-text>an input part for inputting factor information influencing the size of said dots; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>a setting part for adjusting and setting a light emission duration per dot and a light emission amount of said laser light source in accordance with said factor information inputted by said input part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said factor information includes at least one of a first factor related to a characteristic of said recording material and a second factor related to processing of a recorded material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>an image signal correction part for correcting said image signal to be provided to said laser light source drive part, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said setting part is capable of providing a light emission timing correction signal for correcting the light emission duration per dot of said laser light source to said image signal correction part, and of providing a light amount setting signal for setting the light emission amount of said laser light source to said laser light source drive part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00003">claim 3</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising 
<claim-text>a memory for storing therein said factor information, said light emission timing correction signal and said light amount setting signal in corresponding relation to each other, </claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said setting part reads from said memory said light emission timing correction signal and said light amount setting signal corresponding to said factor information inputted by said input part. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>the processing of said recorded material includes a developing process of said recorded material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00005">claim 5</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second factor includes information indicating the sensitivity of a developer for use in said developing process. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00004">claim 4</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said recording material includes a heat-sensitive material responsive to heat generated by irradiation with said laser beam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. The image recorder according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00007">claim 7</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first factor includes information indicating the sensitivity of said recording material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>9</bold></highlight>. A method of recording information about a two-dimensional image made up of a plurality of dots on a recording material by relatively moving a laser spot in a main scanning direction and in a sub-scanning direction, said laser spot being formed on said recording material by irradiation with a laser beam, said method comprising the steps of: 
<claim-text>inputting factor information influencing the size of said dots; </claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting and setting an emission duration per dot and an emission amount of said laser beam in accordance with said factor information inputted; and </claim-text>
<claim-text>emitting said laser beam, based on said emission duration per dot and said emission amount both adjusted and set. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00009">claim 9</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said factor information includes at least one of a first factor related to a characteristic of said recording material and a second factor related to processing of a recorded material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>11</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 10</dependent-claim-reference>, further comprising the step of 
<claim-text>reading, from a memory for storing therein said factor information, a light emission timing correction signal for correcting the emission duration per dot of said laser beam and a light amount setting signal for setting the emission amount of said laser beam in corresponding relation to each other, said light emission timing correction signal and said light amount setting signal corresponding to said factor information inputted. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>the processing of said recorded material includes a developing process of said recorded material. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>13</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 12</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said second factor includes information indicating the sensitivity of a developer for use in said developing process. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 11</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said recording material includes a heat-sensitive material responsive to heat generated by irradiation with said laser beam. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>15</bold></highlight>. The method according to <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00011">claim 14</dependent-claim-reference>, wherein 
<claim-text>said first factor includes information indicating the sensitivity of said recording material.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>10</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00006">
<image id="EMI-D00006" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00006.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00007">
<image id="EMI-D00007" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00007.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00008">
<image id="EMI-D00008" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00008.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00009">
<image id="EMI-D00009" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00009.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00010">
<image id="EMI-D00010" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00010.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00011">
<image id="EMI-D00011" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00011.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00012">
<image id="EMI-D00012" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00012.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00013">
<image id="EMI-D00013" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00013.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00014">
<image id="EMI-D00014" file="US20030001946A1-20030102-D00014.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
