<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE patent-application-publication SYSTEM "pap-v16-2002-01-01.dtd" [
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00000.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00001.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00002.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00003.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00004.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" NDATA TIF>
<!ENTITY US20030002963A1-20030102-D00005.TIF SYSTEM "US20030002963A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" NDATA TIF>
]>
<patent-application-publication>
<subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<document-id>
<doc-number>20030002963</doc-number>
<kind-code>A1</kind-code>
<document-date>20030102</document-date>
</document-id>
<publication-filing-type>new</publication-filing-type>
<domestic-filing-data>
<application-number>
<doc-number>10177981</doc-number>
</application-number>
<application-number-series-code>10</application-number-series-code>
<filing-date>20020621</filing-date>
</domestic-filing-data>
<technical-information>
<classification-ipc>
<classification-ipc-primary>
<ipc>E04H006/00</ipc>
</classification-ipc-primary>
<classification-ipc-edition>07</classification-ipc-edition>
</classification-ipc>
<classification-us>
<classification-us-primary>
<uspc>
<class>414</class>
<subclass>253000</subclass>
</uspc>
</classification-us-primary>
</classification-us>
<title-of-invention>Material handling assembly</title-of-invention>
</technical-information>
<continuity-data>
<non-provisional-of-provisional>
<document-id>
<doc-number>60300490</doc-number>
<document-date>20010625</document-date>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</document-id>
</non-provisional-of-provisional>
</continuity-data>
<inventors>
<first-named-inventor>
<name>
<given-name>Van</given-name>
<family-name>Stokes</family-name>
</name>
<residence>
<residence-us>
<city>Little Falls</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</residence-us>
</residence>
<authority-applicant>INV</authority-applicant>
</first-named-inventor>
</inventors>
<correspondence-address>
<name-1>CLIFFORD G. FRAYNE</name-1>
<name-2></name-2>
<address>
<address-1>Suite 7A</address-1>
<address-2>136 Drum Point Road</address-2>
<city>Brick</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<postalcode>08723</postalcode>
<country>
<country-code>US</country-code>
</country>
</address>
</correspondence-address>
</subdoc-bibliographic-information>
<subdoc-abstract>
<paragraph id="A-0001" lvl="0">A vertical lift system for storage and in particular for parking motor vehicles comprising a multi-level frame comprising structural means extending upward from a base, and a lifting means centrally positioned within the frame and in communication with each level, and a plurality of platforms positioned on each level about the lifting means, the plurality of platforms for the receipt of a vehicle. The lifting means has capability to retrieve a selected vacant platform and transport it to an entrance/exit level, which can be located at any level within the structure, for positioning of a vehicle thereon, and subsequent transportation to its position on the frame. The lifting means provides means for shifting the platform and the vehicle thereon either forwardly or rearwardly on the structural means into a parking space, laterally to either side into a parking space, and either a forward and lateral or rearward and lateral movement into a parking space thereby providing eight parking spaces surrounding the lifting means on each level for vehicles. </paragraph>
</subdoc-abstract>
<subdoc-description>
<cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<heading lvl="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0001" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0001&rsqb;</number> Applicant claims the benefit of provisional application Serial No. 60/300,490 filed Jun. 25, 2001.</paragraph>
</cross-reference-to-related-applications>
<summary-of-invention>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0002" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0002&rsqb;</number> 1. Field of the Invention </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0003" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0003&rsqb;</number> The present invention relates to a material handling system and in particular to a vertical lift system particularly adaptable for parking motor vehicles in a vertical configuration on limited area. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0004" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0004&rsqb;</number> 2. Description of the Prior Art </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0005" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0005&rsqb;</number> Single level and multi-level parking systems for automobiles, trucks, etc., have been used for many years. Single level parking is not cost effective, especially in urban areas. Multi-story parking buildings are utilized but are expensive to construct. Vertical lift systems have been employed, but the known systems are either too complex or too expensive. U.S. Pat. Nos. 2,579,688; 3,387,722; 3,706,356; 3,750,899; and 4,209,276 disclose different types of vertical lift systems. Applicant is also the co-holder of U.S. Pat. No. 4,674,938 for a vertical parking system. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0006" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0006&rsqb;</number> The difficulty with vertical lift systems heretofore was that the vehicle could be lifted to a certain level, but then the vehicle was limited in its movement to a parking space by the mechanicals of the system. The vehicles could be stacked one above the other or the vehicle could be moved off of the vertical lift either forwardly or rearwardly to a parking space or laterally to either side. Therefore while the vehicle vertical lift system could park more vehicles within a foot print of land by parking the vehicles vertically, the systems could not take advance of the entire foot print of land by parking cars in the four corners of the foot print of land. Thus the vertical lift systems could not take advantage of all the vertical space provided. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0007" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0007&rsqb;</number> Still further, in urban areas, the zoning laws oftentimes prescribe spacing required for ingress and egress into parking garages and the size of parking spaces. The present system is adaptable to design compliance with the myriad of zoning laws that are present in various urban areas. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0008" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0008&rsqb;</number> A vertical lift system for transport and storage and in particular for parking motor vehicles comprising a multi-level frame comprising structural means extending upward from a base, and a lifting means centrally positioned within the frame and in communication with each level, and a plurality of platforms positioned on each level about the lifting means, the plurality of platforms for the receipt of a vehicle. The lifting means has capability to retrieve a selected vacant platform and transport it to an entrance/exit level, which can be located at any level within the structure, for positioning of a vehicle thereon, and subsequent transportation to its position on the frame. The lifting means provides means for shifting the platform and the vehicle thereon either forwardly or rearwardly on the structural means into a parking space, laterally to either side into a parking space, and either a forward and lateral or rearward and lateral movement into a parking space thereby providing eight parking spaces surrounding the lifting means on each level for vehicles. </paragraph>
</section>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">OBJECTS OF THE INVENTION </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0009" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0009&rsqb;</number> An object of the present invention is to provide a simple and cost effective vertical lift system for material handling and storage including parking motor vehicles at different levels. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0010" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0010&rsqb;</number> Another object of the present invention is to provide a novel and cost effective vertical lift system which allows for parking eight vehicles on each level of the structure. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0011" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0011&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel, cost effective vertical lift system which allows vehicles on the vertical lift to be parked either forwardly or rearwardly, laterally or forwardly laterally, or rearwardly laterally, thus providing eight parking spaces per level. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0012" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0012&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel vertical lift system for parking motor vehicles in which all movement to a parking space is activated from the vertical lift. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0013" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0013&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel vertical lift system for parking motor vehicles which conserves energy by using storage devices, accumulators, on the vertical lift system which will allow for much faster operation than is possible with just the energy provided by the small power source contained on the vertical lift system itself. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0014" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0014&rsqb;</number> A further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel vertical lift system for parking motor vehicles in which all movement to a parking space is activated from the vertical lift which stores enough energy, in accumulators, so that all movements on any level can be completed even if the main power to the unit is lost. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0015" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0015&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel, cost effective vertical lift system which can incorporate two vertical lifts to operate independently of each other in the same frame. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0016" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0016&rsqb;</number> A still further object of the present invention is to provide for a novel, cost effective vertical lift system which can incorporate an empty platform retrieval system incorporated in the vertical lift system to operate independently of the vertical lift system used for parking vehicles thereby allowing a platform with a vehicle thereupon and an empty platform to be positioned thereon at the same time.</paragraph>
</section>
</summary-of-invention>
<brief-description-of-drawings>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0017" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0017&rsqb;</number> These and other objects of the present invention will become apparent, particularly when taken in view of the following drawings wherein: </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0018" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0018&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a vertical lift parking facility of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0019" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0019&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top plan view of one level of a multi-level, vertical lift parking facility of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0020" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0020&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one level of the frame of a multi-level parking facility of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0021" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0021&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an end view of a parking platform of the present invention; </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0022" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0022&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a bottom view of a parking platform of the present invention; and </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0023" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0023&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference> is a schematic view of the transport mechanicals located on the frame structure and underside of the transport means.</paragraph>
</section>
</brief-description-of-drawings>
<detailed-description>
<section>
<heading lvl="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </heading>
<paragraph id="P-0024" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0024&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> is a perspective view of a vertical lift parking facility designated generally <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference> is a top view of one level and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> is a perspective view of one level of the frame. In this particular perspective view, the parking facility illustrates three levels of elevated parking as will be discussed in detail hereafter. The vertical lift parking facility consists of a ground foot print <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight> upon which a structural frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is constructed. The constructual frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> consists of a plurality of vertical support members <highlight><bold>16</bold></highlight> and horizontal support members <highlight><bold>18</bold></highlight> such that levels <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> are formed to support vehicles <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0025" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0025&rsqb;</number> The ingress and/or egress level <highlight><bold>12</bold></highlight>, is shown in this diagram at the ground level but can be positioned at any level desired. The ingress is from a first end <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> and the egress from a second end <highlight><bold>28</bold></highlight>. However, it can be reconfigured to allow the ingress and/or egress to be positioned at any parking space on any level. Centrally disposed in the frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> is a transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> (<cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>) in communication with each of the levels <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight>. While the present invention has been disclosed in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</cross-reference> with respect to three levels, it will be recognized by one of ordinary skill in the art that more levels are available either above or below the ground level dependent upon the materials used in the frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight>. As can be seen in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</cross-reference>, each level is divided into nine positions labeled <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight> being the transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0026" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0026&rsqb;</number> Heretofore, vehicles could be moved on multi-level, vertical lift parking facilities as disclosed, but the vehicles could only be moved from the transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight> either forward or backward or laterally for parking. Thus the parking positions <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> could not be utilized and the structure itself was under utilized because of the inability to move vehicles to these locations. Applicant&apos;s novel contribution in the present invention is for a transporter elevator system which allows vehicles to be maneuvered at each level, from the transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, position <highlight><bold>0</bold></highlight>, to one of these corner parking units, thereby fully utilizing the foot print of the vertical lift parking facility on the ground upon which it is constructed. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0027" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0027&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> presents a perspective view of one level of the parking facility frame. In operation, a vehicle would be driven into the ingress <highlight><bold>26</bold></highlight> of the parking facility and positioned on a movable parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>, which would be positioned on a transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, in communication with an elevator lift mechanism <highlight><bold>27</bold></highlight> of the type described in U.S. Pat. No. 4,674,938, which is incorporated herein by reference and is operational within the transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. Once a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is positioned on the transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the elevator lift mechanism would lift the transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to the desired level. The transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> incorporates all of the necessary transport equipment to move the vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to one of the locations <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> on any one of the levels <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the parking facility <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0028" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0028&rsqb;</number> In <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference> it will be noted that each level <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of the vertical lift parking facility <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> has a plurality of cross members positioned about transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. These cross members support and guide parking platforms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and the vehicles <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> associated therewith as will be described more fully hereafter. For identification purposes with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</cross-reference>, if we assume that a transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> was positioned at this level of the vehicle parking facility <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> with a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight>, the transport mechanism could move platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> by sliding the platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> on support members <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>. The transport mechanism could then move the platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to either position <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> by sliding the platform along support members <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> respectively. Platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> could be transported laterally from transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> by sliding on support members <highlight><bold>52</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>54</bold></highlight> with respect to position <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>56</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>58</bold></highlight> with respect to position <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0029" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0029&rsqb;</number> The parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> could be moved rearwardly to position <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> on support members <highlight><bold>60</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>62</bold></highlight> and could thence be moved laterally into positions <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight> by support members <highlight><bold>64</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>66</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>68</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>70</bold></highlight>. The retrieval of the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> would be accomplished in the reverse process with respect to the respective parking positions. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0030" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0030&rsqb;</number> <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</cross-reference> is an end view and <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</cross-reference> is a bottom view of parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is constructed of suitable gauge steel and dimensioned such that a vehicle can be driven upon it. Parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> has an upper surface <highlight><bold>80</bold></highlight> upon which vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> is positioned, depending flanges <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> along the longitudinal sides of parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> defining channels <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> extending intermittently along the longitudinal sides of platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Depending flanges <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> have positioned thereon a plurality of plastic sliders <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> which sliders contact the various cross members at each level heretofore discussed and which allows the transporter means described hereafter to slide the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> along the paths of those various cross members. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0031" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0031&rsqb;</number> The positioning of the plastic sliders <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> on the underside of parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is such that if parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> are slid forwardly into position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, the four plastic sliders <highlight><bold>88</bold></highlight> would be positioned at the intersection of support members <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>; <highlight><bold>40</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>; <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>; and <highlight><bold>42</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight>. This positioning thus facilitates the transport of parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to either position <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> on support members <highlight><bold>44</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>46</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>48</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>50</bold></highlight> respectively, as will be more fully described hereafter. The same holds forth for the opposing end of each level <highlight><bold>20</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>22</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>24</bold></highlight> of vertical lift parking facility <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight>. There is also formed on the underside surface <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> a plurality of spaced apart forward/rearward engagement members <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> in parallel alignment for the length of platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. These engagement members <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> cooperate in the movement of platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> either forwardly to position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or rearwardly to position <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0032" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0032&rsqb;</number> The transporter operation is best understood with respect to <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</cross-reference>, which is a schematic diagram of the mechanicals associated with the frame <highlight><bold>14</bold></highlight> and transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in order to move a parking platform and vehicle or parking platform alone to one of the parking positions designated <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> through <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0033" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0033&rsqb;</number> Transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> has positioned thereon all of the necessary mechanicals in order to slidably move a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> into the parking positions <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. Additional mechanicals are mounted in parking positions <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> to enable a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> to be positioned into the corner positions <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0034" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0034&rsqb;</number> On one end of transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, there is mounted a first hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> in communication with a pair of gears <highlight><bold>102</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>104</bold></highlight> and sprockets <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> by means of a worm gear <highlight><bold>110</bold></highlight> or equivalent, the sprockets <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight> driving two separate chain drives <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> in counter-rotation with idler sprockets <highlight><bold>105</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>107</bold></highlight>, the chain drives <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> having a plurality of upstanding fingers <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> which are cooperable with the forward/rearward engagement members <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> on the underside <highlight><bold>90</bold></highlight> of the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. The upstanding fingers <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight> on the counter-rotational chain drives <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> sequentially engage the engagement members <highlight><bold>92</bold></highlight> to either slide the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> forwardly into parking position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> or to engage and slidably remove the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> from parking position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> to the transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0035" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0035&rsqb;</number> An identical arrangement of hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight>A, sprockets <highlight><bold>106</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>108</bold></highlight>A, chain drives <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight>A and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight>A and upstanding fingers <highlight><bold>116</bold></highlight>A on the chain drives is found at the opposing end of the transporter for movement of a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> into position <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0036" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0036&rsqb;</number> A third hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>120</bold></highlight> means is mounted on a transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> and has a drive shaft <highlight><bold>122</bold></highlight> in communication with two lateral drive sprockets <highlight><bold>124</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>126</bold></highlight> having chain drives <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> mounted thereon in communication with respective idler sprockets <highlight><bold>132</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>134</bold></highlight> on idler shaft <highlight><bold>133</bold></highlight>. On each respective chain drive <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> there are two lateral engagement members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight>A, <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight>A positioned in 180 degrees relationship to each other. Chain drives <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> also operate in counter-rotation. The lateral engagement members <highlight><bold>136</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>138</bold></highlight> on chain drives <highlight><bold>128</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>130</bold></highlight> are designed to engage or contact the inner wall of depending flange <highlight><bold>82</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>84</bold></highlight> on parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> to slidably move or remove parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> from positions <highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>7</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0037" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0037&rsqb;</number> Positioned at each corner of transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> are four additional hydraulic motors <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight> each having a retractable coupling <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0038" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0038&rsqb;</number> The frame mounted mechanicals to slidably move or remove parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> from the corner positions <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> is the same for each corner and one such mechanical is illustrated in <cross-reference target="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</cross-reference>. The mechanicals consist of a drive shaft <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> upon which two sprockets <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> are mounted and about which a two chain drive <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> are positioned in communication with two additional idler sprockets <highlight><bold>170</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>172</bold></highlight> mounted proximate the periphery of the parking facility. Each drive shaft <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> has a coupling member <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> complimentary with the retractable coupling member <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>152</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>154</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>156</bold></highlight> on the hydraulic motors <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>142</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>144</bold></highlight>, or <highlight><bold>146</bold></highlight>. Mounted on the parallel chain drives <highlight><bold>166</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>168</bold></highlight> is a lateral engagement bar <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0039" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0039&rsqb;</number> In operation, the hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>100</bold></highlight> and chain drives <highlight><bold>112</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>114</bold></highlight> at the first end of transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> would engage the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> and slidably move it to position <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. Hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> and retractable coupling <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> would engage coupling member <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> on the drive shaft <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> with lateral engagement bar <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> positioned to slide within channel <highlight><bold>86</bold></highlight> or <highlight><bold>87</bold></highlight> on the underside of the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight>. Hydraulic motor <highlight><bold>140</bold></highlight> in cooperation with retractable coupling <highlight><bold>150</bold></highlight> and coupling member <highlight><bold>174</bold></highlight> would rotate drive shaft <highlight><bold>160</bold></highlight> and sprockets <highlight><bold>162</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>164</bold></highlight> with lateral engagement bar <highlight><bold>176</bold></highlight> contacting the inner flange surface of parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and move the parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> laterally into position <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The reverse would occur when one wished to remove parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> or parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> and vehicle <highlight><bold>25</bold></highlight> from parking position <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. Identical assemblies and operation would occur with respect to parking positions <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight>. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0040" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0040&rsqb;</number> It will be noted that in the operation of the vertical lift parking facility as described herein, the vehicles being elevated would be positioned in parking spaces <highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>, <highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>, and <highlight><bold>8</bold></highlight> initially before parking spaces <highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight> and <highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight> were filled so as to allow for the temporary use of these two parking spaces to maneuver cars. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0041" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0041&rsqb;</number> The facility is shown operating with one transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the transport elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>. However, since the entire facility is to be computer operated, it would be possible to locate two transporters <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> in the transporter elevator shaft <highlight><bold>30</bold></highlight>, each with its own elevator lift mechanism, with the upper tier of the vertical lift parking facility having an extended shaft for the temporary location of the upper transporter and the lower tier of the vertical lift parking facility having an extended shaft for the temporary location of the lower transporter. In this regard, depending upon the size of the facility, one transporter could be parking or retrieving vehicles at a lower level and a second transporter might be rearranging vehicles at the upper levels and when not in use the upper transporter elevator could be sent upwardly to remain in a stable but unused position above the upper level of the vehicle parking facility or the lower transporter elevator could be sent downwardly to remain in a stable but unused position below the lower level of the vehicle parking facility. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0042" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0042&rsqb;</number> Two transporter elevator mechanisms can be connected together, using only one elevator lift mechanism, such that the upper unit can be used for the movement of parking platforms containing vehicles and a lower unit can be used for positioning and repositioning of empty parking platforms. This method would reduce the number of trips up and down the transporter elevator shaft to store and retrieve empty platforms thereby reducing the amount of time required for parking vehicles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0043" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0043&rsqb;</number> The transporter lift <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> contains a series of hydraulic motors and valves connected to a small hydraulic pump <highlight><bold>200</bold></highlight> and a series of hydraulic accumulators <highlight><bold>202</bold></highlight>, which are controlled by a computer system. The system is designed so that whenever a parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> is being moved by the hydraulic motors on the transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight>, the computer system regulates the amount of energy being delivered to the motor, which is greater than the amount of energy that the hydraulic pump is capable of providing, and supervises the recharging of the accumulator system. In this method the energy supplied to the transporter <highlight><bold>34</bold></highlight> is approximately &frac16; of the energy required to move a fully loaded parking platform <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> therefore the hydraulic pump contained on the transporter elevator is &frac16; the size that would otherwise be required. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0044" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0044&rsqb;</number> An additional feature of this hydraulic system is that the accumulators store enough energy to complete all required movements on any level, even if the main power is lost, which insures that the parking platforms <highlight><bold>32</bold></highlight> are not left in an intermediary position which could be dangerous or cause damage to vehicles. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0045" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0045&rsqb;</number> The vehicle parking facility of the present invention as disclosed herein, discloses a multi-level, vertical parking facility that can accommodate 8 cars per level and the number of levels being limited by the strength of the framing mechanism constructed. It will be recognized that these vertical parking facilities <highlight><bold>10</bold></highlight> can be erected in modules, immediate adjacent each other such that each has its own ingress and egress and transporter elevator means associated therewith. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0046" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0046&rsqb;</number> The design construction and operation of the facility provides for the total use of the ground foot print upon which the structure is constructed so as to better utilize the land and offer a greater return on investment, particularly in areas where real estate is expensive. </paragraph>
<paragraph id="P-0047" lvl="0"><number>&lsqb;0047&rsqb;</number> While the present invention has been disclosed with regard to the exemplary embodiment thereof, it will be recognized by those of ordinary skill in the trade that modifications to the invention can and may be made without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. Therefore it is manifestly intended that the scope of the invention be limited only by the scope of the claims and the equivalents thereto. </paragraph>
</section>
</detailed-description>
</subdoc-description>
<subdoc-claims>
<heading lvl="1">I claim: </heading>
<claim id="CLM-00001">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>1</bold></highlight>. An automated, multi-level vehicle parking assembly comprising: 
<claim-text>a frame defining a multi-level parking facility having an elevator shaft and elevator means in communication with each level of said multi-level parking facility, said frame having a ingress and egress means for a vehicle; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of parking positions on said frame on each said level disposed about said elevator shaft for positioning said vehicle forwardly, rearwardly, laterally, forwardly laterally, and rearwardly laterally of said elevator shaft, said forwardly and rearwardly positions having lateral transfer means for said forwardly laterally and said rearwardly laterally movement; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a parking platform associated with each said parking position, said parking platform slidably removable from said parking position, said parking platform for receipt and transfer of said vehicle from said ingress means to said parking position and from said parking position to said egress means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transport means positioned in said elevator shaft, said transport means in selective communication with each level of said multi-level parking facility, said transport means having a plurality of motors and transport engagement members mounted thereon to engage said parking platform from said parking position and transport said parking platform to said ingress means for receipt of said vehicle and engaging said parking platform and said vehicle from said ingress means and transfer to said parking position and to engage said parking platform and said vehicle from said parking position and transfer to said egress means, said plurality of motors in communication with a power source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>2</bold></highlight>. The automated multi-level vehicle parking assembly in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said parking platform is dimensioned to receive a vehicle, said parking platform having longitudinal L-shaped inwardly facing flanges there being mounted on the lower surface of said L-shaped flanges a plurality of slide members cooperable with said frame for sliding said parking platform, there being formed on the underside of said parking platform a plurality of engagement members in parallel, spaced apart relationship. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>3</bold></highlight>. The automated multi-level vehicle parking assembly in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said transport means comprises: 
<claim-text>a transport frame member having a first end and a second end for receipt on said frame member of said parking platform, said transport frame member and said parking platform cooperable to allow ingress of a vehicle onto said parking platform and transport frame member and egress of a vehicle from said transport frame member and said parking platform, said transport frame member having mounted thereon a first and second hydraulic motor means disposed on opposing ends of said transport frame member, said first and second hydraulic motor means in communication with a hydraulic fluid source, said first and second motor means in further communication with a pair of drive sprocket means, each of said drive sprocket means in communication with an idler sprocket means, there being disposed about said drive sprocket means and said idler sprocket means a chain drive in counter-rotational relationship, each of said chain drives having a plurality of upstanding fingers engagable with said engagement member on said underside of said parking platform, said idler sprockets extending and said chain drive extending beyond said first end and said second end of said transport frame member so as to transport said parking platform forwardly and rewardly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third lateral hydraulic motor means mounted on said frame member in communication with a source of hydraulic fluid, said third lateral hydraulic motor means having a shaft member in communication with a third pair of drive sprockets, said third pair of drive sprockets in communication with a third pair of idler sprockets by means of a third pair of chain drives, each of said chain drives having a pair of engagement stops mounted in 180 degree relationship thereon, said engagement stops cooperable with said longitudinal L-shaped flanges of said parking platform for lateral movement of said parking platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth hydraulic motor means comprising four hydraulic motors in communication with a source of hydraulic fluid, said four hydraulic motors are mounted on said transport frame, one each, in each corner of said transport frame facing forwardly and rewardly, each of said motors having a rotatable, extensible, retractable coupling means cooperable with said lateral transfer means mounted on said frame defining said multi-level parking facility, said lateral transfer means comprising a pair of shaft mounted drive sprockets mounted in alignment with each of said fourth hydraulic motor means and having a complimentary coupling cooperable with said rotatable, extensible, retractable coupling of said fourth hydraulic motor means for rotation of said shaft and drive sprocket, said drive sprockets in communication with a pair of shaft mounted idler sprockets mounted proximate the periphery of said frame defining said multi-level parking facility and in communication with said drive sprockets by means of chain drives, said chain drives having mounted thereon a lateral engaging transfer bar for engagement with said parking platform to slide said parking platform laterally from said rearward or forward parking positions. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>4</bold></highlight>. An automated, multi-level storage facility comprising: 
<claim-text>a frame defining a multi-level storage facility having an elevator shaft and elevator means in communication with each level of said multi-level storage facility, said frame having a ingress and egress means for stored material; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of storage positions on said frame on each said level disposed about said elevator shaft for positioning said stored material forwardly, rearwardly, laterally, forwardly laterally, and rearwardly laterally of said elevator shaft, said forwardly and rearwardly positions having lateral transfer means for said forwardly laterally and said rearwardly laterally movement; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a parking platform associated with each said storage position, said parking platform slidably removable from said storage position, said parking platform for receipt and transfer of said stored material from said ingress means to said storage position and from said storage position to said egress means; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a transport means positioned in said elevator shaft, said transport means in selective communication with each level of said multi-level storage facility, said transport means having a plurality of motors and transport engagement members mounted thereon to engage said parking platform from said storage position and transport said parking platform to said ingress means for receipt of said stored material and engaging said parking platform and said stored material from said ingress means and transfer to said storage position and to engage said parking platform and said stored material from said storage position and transfer to said egress means, said plurality of motors in communication with a power source. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>5</bold></highlight>. The automated multi-level storage facility in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00001">claim 1</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said parking platform is dimensioned to receive stored material, said parking platform having longitudinal L-shaped inwardly facing flanges there being mounted on the lower surface of said L-shaped flanges a plurality of slide members cooperable with said frame for sliding said parking platform, there being formed on the underside of said parking platform a plurality of engagement members in parallel, spaced apart relationship. </claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006">
<claim-text><highlight><bold>6</bold></highlight>. The automated multi-level storage facility in accordance with <dependent-claim-reference depends_on="CLM-00002">claim 2</dependent-claim-reference> wherein said transport means comprises: 
<claim-text>a transport frame member having a first end and a second end for receipt on said frame member of said parking platform, said transport frame member and said parking platform cooperable to allow ingress of stored material onto said parking platform and transport frame member and egress of stored material from said transport frame member and said parking platform, said transport frame member having mounted thereon a first and second hydraulic motor means disposed on opposing ends of said transport frame member, said first and second hydraulic motor means in communication with a hydraulic fluid source, said first and second motor means in further communication with a pair of drive sprocket means, each of said drive sprocket means in communication with an idler sprocket means, there being disposed about said drive sprocket means and said idler sprocket means a chain drive in counter-rotational relationship, each of said chain drives having a plurality of upstanding fingers engagable with said engagement member on said underside of said parking platform, said idler sprockets extending and said chain drive extending beyond said first end and said second end of said transport frame member so as to transport said parking platform forwardly and rewardly; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a third lateral hydraulic motor means mounted on said frame member in communication with a source of hydraulic fluid, said third lateral hydraulic motor means having a shaft member in communication with a third pair of drive sprockets, said third pair of drive sprockets in communication with a third pair of idler sprockets by means of a third pair of chain drives, each of said chain drives having a pair of engagement stops mounted in 180 degree relationship thereon, said engagement stops cooperable with said longitudinal L-shaped flanges of said parking platform for lateral movement of said parking platform; </claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth hydraulic motor means comprising four hydraulic motors in communication with a source of hydraulic fluid, said four hydraulic motors are mounted on said transport frame, one each, in each corner of said transport frame facing forwardly and rewardly, each of said motors having a rotatable, extensible, retractable coupling means cooperable with said lateral transfer means mounted on said frame defining said multi-level parking facility, said lateral transfer means comprising a pair of shaft mounted drive sprockets mounted in alignment with each of said fourth hydraulic motor means and having a complimentary coupling cooperable with said rotatable, extensible, retractable coupling of said fourth hydraulic motor means for rotation of said shaft and drive sprocket, said drive sprockets in communication with a pair of shaft mounted idler sprockets mounted proximate the periphery of said frame defining said multi-level parking facility and in communication with said drive sprockets by means of chain drives, said chain drives having mounted thereon a lateral engaging transfer bar for engagement with said parking platform to slide said parking platform laterally from said rearward or forward parking positions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</subdoc-claims>
<subdoc-drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<heading lvl="0" align="CENTER">Drawings</heading>
<representative-figure>1</representative-figure>
<figure id="figure-D00000">
<image id="EMI-D00000" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00000.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00001">
<image id="EMI-D00001" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00001.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00002">
<image id="EMI-D00002" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00002.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00003">
<image id="EMI-D00003" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00003.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00004">
<image id="EMI-D00004" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00004.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
<figure id="figure-D00005">
<image id="EMI-D00005" file="US20030002963A1-20030102-D00005.TIF" imf="TIFF" ti="DR"/>
</figure>
</subdoc-drawings>
</patent-application-publication>
